



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTEGRITY</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restoring Trust</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Business</ENAMEX> and the
Accounting Profession
(This document was written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David M. Walker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller</ENAMEX>
General of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, based on a speech he gave to the
conference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2002</TIMEX>)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 26, 2002</TIMEX>
Our profession, the performance and accountability profession,
currently faces a "crisis of confidence" that must be addressed not
only for the good of our profession but also for the good of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital markets. We are not, however, the
only ones who are under the microscope as recent events in the
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> have made clear. Restoring public trust and
confidence in a manner that can be sustained over the long-term
will require concerted actions by a various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in order to
address some very real systemic weaknesses plaguing our current
corporate governance, accountability, and related systems.


RECENT <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACCOUNTABILITY BREAKDOWNS</ENAMEX>:
Recent accountability breakdowns in the private sector have come
in a variety of forms and bear many names, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX>,
WorldCom, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Qwest, Tyco, Adelphia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Crossing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waste Management</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Micro Strategy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Federal Savings Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX>, just to
name a few. A recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>) report
highlighted the increasing frequency and changing nature of
corporate earnings restatements. Furthermore, the rapid decline and
fall of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Andersen LLP</ENAMEX> has served as a dramatic lesson that
will no doubt be the subject of many books and business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> case
studies.
Clearly, some of these breakdowns are more complex and harder to
understand than others. The <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">WorldCom failure</ENAMEX> appears to be a simple
matter of not following basic accounting principles in connection
with capitalizing versus expensing certain items. Although all the
facts are not known, it is perplexing how such a basic error
involving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> could go undetected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>.
On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX> situation involved complex
transactions with a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and a now apparent weakness
involved simple matters of greed by corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and
inadequate oversight and accountability actions by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARTHUR ANDERSEN LLP</ENAMEX>:
Although there are many dimensions to the current challenge,
let's start with one of our own: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Andersen LLP</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX> may have been the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> for more than its fair share of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> associated with the most recent accountability
failures, but it was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> for all of them. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>) data disclosed that until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX> generally had a lower rate of earnings restatements
for its public company audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> than did other major
accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. In addition, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX> had certain unusual
audit related policies and practices that were not widely known by
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> and may not be shared by many other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, it was
hardly a rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in the profession and any assertions to the
contrary are not only inaccurate but also inappropriate. Such
assertions serve to disparage the reputations of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> who did their job right <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and to the
very end. Such assertions also serve as an attempt to discount the
need for meaningful reform to help prevent future accountability
failures.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX> story illustrates how a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can do the wrong
thing with catastrophic consequences for many innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. It
was not long ago that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Andersen</ENAMEX> was viewed by many as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> professional services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in the world. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX> had the reputation of "thinking straight and talking
straight" and doing what it felt was right in connection with
challenging accounting and reporting issues - even if the client
didn't like the answer. From global gold standard to GONE in less
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>! What happened?
As a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> who severed all ties with the firm
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, I believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX> got caught up with a never-ending
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quest</ENAMEX> to grow the top line, grow the bottom line and grow the
income of it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>. Stated differently, it was primarily focused
on maximizing earnings and not enough on managing risk, including
risk relating to its hardearned and priceless reputation. I
observed some of these tendencies during the later stages of my
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 10-year</TIMEX> tenure with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. These tendencies had not yet
reached a critical level and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> had not experienced a major
public accountability failure when I left to return to public
service as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.
Evidently these trends became much more pronounced after I left the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.
During the later part of my tenure with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX>, I expressed my
concerns publicly in several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> meetings and privately to
various internal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>; however, as someone who had not "grown
up" with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, I found that my actions to speak up - -
especially when my views were not consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Andersen</ENAMEX>
business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit leadership</ENAMEX>'s preferences - - were somewhat
counter-cultural. This was most apparent when I expressed my
support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Shaheen</ENAMEX>, the ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Partner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX>
Consulting business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> (now known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accenture</ENAMEX>), to succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
Weinbach as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Partner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen Worldwide</ENAMEX>, rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Andersen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s choice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Wadia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Partner</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Andersen</ENAMEX> business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>.
Ironically, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Shaheen rather than Jim Wadia</ENAMEX> who
publicly stated his support for modernizing the attest and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assurance</ENAMEX> model for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>! This, along with his
leadership skills, had a lot to do with my support for his
candidacy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX> is not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to be captured by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">siren</ENAMEX>'s song calling for more money, more money and more money.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>, certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> strayed from the core
values of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, integrity, service and stewardship that made
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Andersen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great</ENAMEX> and caused me to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. The
result was that a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>' actions served to bet the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> in
connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s reputation, and they lost the bet!
Although some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> may have
violated the law and should be held accountable, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>'s indictment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> resulted in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Five</ENAMEX>"
accounting and consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> becoming the "Big Four." This
served to further reduce competition in a profession of critical
importance to the public that had already consolidated from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major global <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. It was more than a little ironic that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> that opposed the consolidation of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six</TIMEX>" into the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Five</ENAMEX>" caused the further consolidation in the
profession. Regardless of the methods and motivations of the
various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, the deed is done, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Andersen</ENAMEX> is
essentially dead.
I am proud to have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Andersen</ENAMEX> in its
glory <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, but I'm shocked and saddened by what happened to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>. Clearly, one of the big lessons
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersen</ENAMEX>'s fall is that it may take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to create a
reputation of quality and integrity but that hard-earned reputation
can be lost very quickly if there is a real or perceived breach of
trust. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX>'s case, it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX> to climb to
the top and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two years</TIMEX> for it to decline into extinction.
Hopefully, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will take that lesson to heart.


(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>):
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX>'s fall, along with the recent business accountability
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breakdowns</ENAMEX> and other integrity failures, has served to adversely
impact the public's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> and confidence not just in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX>, but also
in other performance and accountability <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, corporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and a variety of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. They have also served to
adversely affect public confidence in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital markets.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> have also shown increasing concern with recent actions
and inactions of our own professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
What are these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>? First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>'s actions in
connection with the recent accounting reform legislation and
certain other reform related administrative actions have damaged
its reputation in government and elsewhere. Some of its external
actions may have been designed to serve the economic interests of
some of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> but they were not necessarily consistent with
the broader public interest, especially in connection with audits
involving public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and public funds. Furthermore, some of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>'s recent internal actions have been questioned by its own
membership. For example, the membership <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">soundly</ENAMEX> rejected the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>'s efforts to further stretch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> brand name and allow
others to benefit from our profession's hard-earned reputation
through the so-called "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XYZ</ENAMEX> initiative." Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> actions
designed to enhance the value of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> have met
with mixed results. In addition, some of these have not been a
model of transparency or integrity given delayed disclosures and
potential conflicts of interest.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would expect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> to lead by example in connection with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transparency</ENAMEX> and conflict issues given the role and nature of the
profession that it represents. In my view, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> must set the standard for professional conduct and be
beyond reproach because they represent all of us and, as a result
their actions, reflect on all of us.
Clearly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>'s value-enhancement and trade-oriented
efforts have dominated its agenda in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. Although
value-enhancement to the membership is clearly a legitimate role
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>, as a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> it also has a
responsibility to aggressively address a range of professional risk
management issues. In my view, not enough has been done to manage
the current and emerging risks associated with our profession,
especially in connection with modernizing the attest and assurance
model and related auditing standards, including the independence
standard for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>. Yes, some steps have been taken but
not nearly enough or as quickly as is called for, given recent
events and the vital role that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> play in our overall
accountability system.
As a result, some are questioning the future role of the AICPA
and whether they should continue to renew their membership. I, for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, have renewed my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX>. Why? Because I believe that it is
better to be an active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> who tries to make needed and
constructive changes from the inside rather than voting with my
feet and simply walking away. I hope that most of my fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>
will agree with me. However, I believe that additional actions by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> will be needed to restore trust and
confidence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> over the longer-term.


CORPORATE GOVERNANCE:
Outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> bear varying degrees of responsibility for
these recent failures, but they don't bear all the responsibility.
Where were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>) and what was the role
of top corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in connection with these business
breakdowns? What involvement did other key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> have in
connection with these accountability failures? These and other
questions are worth exploring to determine what changes are needed
on a going-forward basis to minimize the possibility that these
types of events will occur in the future.
In my view, the most critical element that needs to be addressed
to help ensure that these failures do not proliferate in the future
is the overall governance model for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. Many believe, and I am one of them, that the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> corporate governance model for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> is not
adequate to protect the interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> and other key
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX>. Specifically, although most public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are
required to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> that is comprised of a majority of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">independent directors</ENAMEX>" and certain key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> are required to
be comprised solely of outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>, a closer look reveals
that the independence of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> may be more a matter of form
than substance.
The issues of concern start at the top of the corporate
governance pyramid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of many major public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> also
serves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of directors. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>,
this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> has a huge impact on the direction of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, the role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, and the composition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.
All too frequently, such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> will have significant
influence over who is asked to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and who is asked to
leave it. Boards are often comprised primarily of internal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management officials</ENAMEX>, high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
and major service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> to and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
Interlocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> are also fairly common. Under such
arrangements, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> from different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> who know each
other will sit on each other's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>. Although all these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> have valuable experience and perspective to bring to
the table, they are not well positioned to address all of the key
roles and responsibilities of an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.
What should public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company boards</ENAMEX> be doing? Under modern
governance theory, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> works for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
works for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. But how can this be if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> also serves as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>? Boards have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> roles that they
need to play. First, they should provide strategic advice to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in order to help maximize shareholder value. Most boards
have historically spent most of their time on this role. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
they need to help manage risk, including risk related to attempts
to maximize current value at the expense of mortgaging the future.
Risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> must also consider the interests of key stakeholder
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> operates. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> have a clear responsibility
to hold management accountable for results. This later element is a
major reason why having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> that is both qualified and
independent is so important. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> qualifications are more
than a matter of education and experience, they are also a matter
of personal attributes of which integrity is number one. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX>
independence does not require the elimination of all inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> but it would seem to call for ensuring that a
super-majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are truly independent both in fact
and appearance.
Having a qualified and independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> is important but not
enough. Boards need to have adequate resources, including having
access to their own independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> when they
believe it is appropriate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> also must have the time
needed to address their various roles and responsibilities. From a
practical standpoint, this means that active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> should
limit the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> they sit on, and all board <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> need
to be comfortable that they can dedicate the time needed to
properly discharge their fiduciary responsibilities.
Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have a fiduciary responsibility to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> that they represent. They must do their best to do the
right thing and not breach their fiduciary duties through either
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-mission or omission. After all, it's not just what you do that
counts, it's also what you fail to do when circumstances dictate
that you should act.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EXECUTIVE COMPENSATION</ENAMEX>:
Having the right governance structure is of critical importance.
It's also important to consider the nature and reasonableness of
the incentives provided to top management and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Much
has been written regarding the meteoric rise of executive
compensation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Various studies have shown how
the ratio of executive compensation to average employee
compensation has risen to levels of irrationality and levels that
far exceed those of other major industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>.
How much is a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> worth? After all, unlike
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventors</ENAMEX> who should be rewarded for innovation resulting from
their personal efforts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of a major public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> effort. Despite the assertions of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>, while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> key
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> can make a difference, it requires a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of talented
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to add shareholder value and manage shareholder risk
over time. In some cases, one wonders what some highly compensated
top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> were doing to earn their pay given their public
statements and testimonies subsequent to the decline of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Certain former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WorldCom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> come to
mind in this regard.
It's not just the total amount of compensation but the form and
structure of executive compensation arrangements that is important
as well. It is well known that the behavior of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> is
affected by the nature of their compensation arrangements; top
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are no exception. For example, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> may be
tempted to accelerate income or expense recognition in ways that
will serve to help them maximize their bonus compensation in the
current or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following year</TIMEX>, respectively. Boards and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> need
to be vigilant to ensure that any inappropriate actions are
avoided.
Recently, a significant amount of attention has been focused on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> of "stock options" and the related accounting
treatment. Clearly, some amount of stock compensation makes sense
in order to tie the interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> with the
interests of top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>; however, the amount and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> are
both important to ensure equity and avoid perverse incentives to
maximize value in the short-term at the expense of the
longer-term.
There is little question that some abuse of stock compensation
has occurred. In a large number of cases, key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> have been
granted additional stock options or their existing options have
been re-priced (i.e., lower strike price) because of a decline in
the market value of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stock. Part of the decline may
have been due to general market conditions, but it's doubtful that
all of it was. In fact, some or most of the decline could have been
due to the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to deliver on their promises. The
result is that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can make huge sums if the stock
price rebounds.
Although some have argued that stock option re-loads and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-pricing were necessary to keep their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, I wonder how
many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> wanted to give up options or raise the
strike price of their options when general market conditions were
causing all <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> to rise? I don't know of any, but maybe you do!
We should not have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>-I-win and tails-you-lose compensation
structure. This situation could be mitigated if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> had
qualified, independent, and adequately resourced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX>; however,
as I noted previously, this is all too often not the case.
Boards have a responsibility to ensure the reasonableness of
overall executive compensation. It's clear that a number of them
are not doing an adequate job in his regard. At the same time, the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> bears some responsibility for the movement to
stock-based compensation due to tax changes that limited the
deductibility of certain types and amounts of executive
compensation. These provisions may have to be reexamined as
well.
From a more strategic perspective, there is both a need and an
opportunity to forge a realignment of interests between the board
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> in ways that can help to enhance value
and manage risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> and other key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>. In
theory, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> work directly for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and
indirectly for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>. Yes, audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> of the board
interact with and recommend which audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to retain for approval
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>. In the real world, however, top management has
much more influence on and interaction with the outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>.
This must change and under the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarbanes-Oxley</ENAMEX> accounting
reform legislation, some related changes will be required.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, once additional needed corporate governance reforms
are made to enhance the independence and capacity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, the
opportunity to implement the needed realignment will be greatly
enhanced.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACCOUNTING AND REPORTING MODEL</ENAMEX>:
What about the current accounting and reporting model? We have
recently seen how current accounting and reporting requirements are
inadequate. For example, the collapse of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX> showed how
accounting and reporting for so-called "special purpose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEs</ENAMEX>) is hard to understand, much less defend. Does it make sense
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to be able to keep significant financial transactions
off their books when unrelated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> provide <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 3 percent</NUMEX> of
the related <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> at risk? I think not! Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX> may have
violated this <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> requirement, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-percent level would seem
to be way too low in a environment in which we should be focusing
on economic substance versus legal form in accounting and reporting
as well as attest and assurance matters.
There has also been a considerable amount of discussion and
debate regarding the appropriate accounting and reporting treatment
for stock options. Strong views are held on both sides of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> debate. From a practical perspective, if stock options aren't
compensation, what are they? In my view, it's not on the issue of
whether they should be recorded as compensation expense; it's more
a matter of how it should be done.
From a broader perspective, I believe that the current
accounting and reporting model is not well suited for our 21st
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> knowledge-based economy. Unlike the industrial age in which
tangible assets were of great value and importance, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
knowledge-based economy it's intellectual capital that is driving
the market value of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>. Intellectual capital is
created by the efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> represent the
most valuable asset in the knowledge age. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are the source of
all process improvement, technological innovation, and
environmental enhancements. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are our most valuable asset,
then why are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> treated primarily as a cost and a liability
under our current accounting and reporting model?
What about historical cost? Although it's nice to know what
something costs, it's arguably more important to know what it is
worth! Furthermore, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when historical financial statements
were viewed as being of critical importance are gone. It's not that
they aren't important, it's that they aren't as important as they
used to be. Today, it's important to have access to timely and
reliable financial and non-financial performance information. In
addition, it's important to not just know what has happened but
what is likely to happen based on key performance indicators,
projection, information and sensitivity analyses.
We live in an increasingly inter-dependent world. Our markets
are global in nature and no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
can go it alone. And yet, we still lack a set of global accounting
and reporting standards that reflects the globalization of
economies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>, and markets. We need a set of global
standards, and various interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> need to work together to
help make this become a reality sooner rather than later.
These new accounting and reporting standards should not just be
global in nature, they should be principle-based rather than
rule-based. Current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> accounting and reporting standards have
become much too complex. Too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> are looking for special
treatment and loopholes and are focusing on legal form rather than
economic substance. Furthermore, too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> are busy
checking boxes rather than turning on their brains and using their
professional judgment to get to the right answer. We must remember
that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX>, we get paid for our judgment, so let's exercise
it.
New principle-based accounting and reporting standards should be
focused on value and risk. Related disclosures should focus more on
key performance indicators along with selected projection
information and sensitivity analyses. In addition, all disclosures
need to be stated as clearly and concisely as possible. Too many
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' disclosures are written in legal language and are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> too long. They seem to be designed more to confuse rather than
inform the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>.
Some have recently advocated a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-pronged approach to future
financial and performance reporting. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> prong would
represent basic reporting applicable to all public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> prong would include key benchmark information based on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s industry. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> prong would include supplemental
information on key value and risk elements affecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. I
believe that such an approach has conceptual merit and should be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">explored</ENAMEX> along with the other key concepts outlined above.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATTEST AND ASSURANCE STANDARDS</ENAMEX>:
Although the accounting and reporting model needs to be updated,
in my view, the current attest and assurance model is also out of
date. The current model relies heavily on an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX>'s expression
of an opinion on historical cost-based financial statements after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX>. For public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, audited financial statements
generally are required to be filed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s fiscal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX>. This report has some value but it
is not as valuable as it once was.
More needs to done to enhance the scope and improve the
timeliness of various attest and assurance services and related
reporting. More also needs to be done to address the continuing
"expectations gap" regarding what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> are doing in connection
with the detection of fraud and internal controls, and to audit
through electronic information systems rather than around them. In
this regard, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas A&M University</ENAMEX> has recently formed a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Continuous Auditing</ENAMEX> involving a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 12</NUMEX>
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and others to help address these issues.
Currently, outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> reports are not required to provide
any level of assurance with regard to key internal controls. Such
controls are critical to determining the reliability of interim
reporting and various ongoing assertions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> throughout
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, opinion level of reporting on internal
controls over financial reporting will be required by the
Sarbanes-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oxley</ENAMEX> accounting reform legislation that was passed in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2002</TIMEX>. It is designed, among other things, to enhance oversight
of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company auditors</ENAMEX> in light of recent accountability
failures.
However, the current audit-reporting model does not provide any
level of assurance regarding key risk and value-based performance
and projection information that are important to a wide range of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX>. We also need to take steps to do so in conjunction
with the needed enhancements to the current accounting and
reporting model.
It's important to enhance the scope and timing of any related
audit reports, but it's also important to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are
both qualified and independent to perform such audits. Contrary to
assertions by some, independence is more than a state of mind.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Auditors</ENAMEX> must be independent both in fact and appearance in order
to be credible. In my view, current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> independence standards do
not adequately ensure the independence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> who provide
certain non-audit or consulting services to their audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. As
a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> issued new independence standards applicable to
audits of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that
receive federal funds, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarbanes-Oxley</ENAMEX> legislation limited
the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to perform certain
non-audit services for their audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarbanes</ENAMEX>-Oxley provisions were based in large part on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
new independence standards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Importantly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> saw the need for a
change in his area and we began the process to make related changes
long before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX> and other recent business failures came to light.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> took a lot of heat in being out front on this
controversial issue, in part due to recent events, we're getting a
lot of accolades now!
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> and many accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> put
too much emphasis on how they could grow their top line, bottom
line, and earnings through pushing non-audit/consulting services
and not enough time modernizing attest and assurance services that
represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> on which the public relies. This
must change, and recent events are likely to force both the
accounting profession and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to place much more emphasis on
their core services. At the same time, many major accounting firms
are spinning off the portions of their consulting practices that
pose the greatest potential independence problems.
In my view, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> should able to provide some consulting
services to their audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, but there are certain services
that would clearly be inappropriate for them to provide.
Specifically, under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s new independence standards auditors
must not violate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> basic principles. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> should not
perform management functions or make management decisions. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> should not audit their own work when the work involved is
material to the subject matter of the audit. These principles are
simple, straightforward, and timeless in nature. We also need to
take this type of approach in connection with key
accounting/reporting and audit issues.
As I noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> should have a
strategic alignment of interests. Furthermore, for any system to
function effectively, there must be incentives for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> to do
the right thing, adequate transparency to provide reasonable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assurance</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will do the right thing, and appropriate
accountability when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do not do the right thing. This
strategic realignment and convergence of interests between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and the outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> would help to achieve these
objectives.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGAL</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FINANCIAL AND OTHER ADVISORS</ENAMEX>:
A variety of outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> have been
involved in and bear differing degrees of responsibility for some
of the recent business failures. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys</ENAMEX>, investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> have played major roles in
structuring or engineering business transactions in order to
achieve not just a desired business result but also a desired
accounting and reporting result. In some cases, this has resulted
in changing the form of certain arrangements in order to meet the
minimum technical requirements of any related accounting and
reporting requirements while coming close to the line of what is
legal. Some might call this aiding and abetting.
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> try to help their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> meet a short-term
value-oriented objective. However, in doing so they must remember
that short-term gain can come at a huge longterm cost if the
transaction unravels or otherwise comes under close regulatory
review or public scrutiny. Such was clearly the case in connection
with certain recent business failures.
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have used such aggressive approaches to deal
with a variety of tax issues and other matters. For example, a
number of major multi-national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> based in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
are trying to have their legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> located in another
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for tax reasons. Typically, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX>
try to minimize the visibility of such techniques in order to avoid
public criticism. Sometimes they succeed, and sometimes they
don't.
In my view, too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are trying to structure
transactions and other business dealings so they are technically
acceptable rather than doing what is right. It is time for people
to realize that things like the law and accounting and reporting
standards represent the floor of acceptable behavior and not the
ceiling! Values like integrity, morality, compassion and
stewardship represent higher callings that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should
strive to achieve. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, we all need to be more responsible
for our actions and inactions. The simple rule is, if in doubt
about what to do, then check it out both from a technical and value
oriented perspective. If still in doubt, don't do it! It's not
worth betting your reputation or the reputation of your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>. Just ask the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX>.
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are subject to these same tendencies. They
also have certain conflicts in connection with their investment
banking and brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> that need to be addressed just as
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> do in connection with their consulting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. The independence and objectivity of stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>
reporting is also a matter of concern. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and several states
are looking into these issues. Hopefully, Wall Street will take
voluntary steps to address these issues before it is forced to
act.
In the final analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> need to keep
in mind that their actions can have an adverse affect on their
reputations as well as the public. Given the lessons from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andersen</ENAMEX>'s fall, they need to keep this in the forefront rather
than the back of their minds.


FEDERAL <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">REGULATION AND ENFORCEMENT</ENAMEX>:
The primary federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> in connection with financial
accounting and reporting for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Securities and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange Commission</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> promulgates and enforces the
registration requirements dealing with public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>
has vast responsibilities and finite resources. As a result, they
need to constantly look for process improvements and technological
enhancements to leverage their finite resources to maximize their
effectiveness. In light of recent events, a consensus has emerged
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> needs significant additional resources to help ensure
that it can do its job properly.
Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> has the authority to issue certain
accounting/reporting and auditing standards for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
it has historically relied to a great extent on certain
selfregulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> to help maintain trust and confidence in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital markets. For example, it has historically relied
accepted accounting principles and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auditing Standards</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> (ASB) to set generally accepted auditing standards. In
addition, other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> such as the major stock exchanges play a
role by imposing various requirements for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to attain and
maintain their listings.
While self-regulatory approaches can and have worked in various
situations, there are certain instances in which it is unrealistic
for them to work as effectively as needed in order to adequately
protect the public interest. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example of this is in connection
with what type of non-audit or consulting services that outside
audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> can provide to their audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and still maintain
their independence. History has shown that the present
self-regulatory structure has not been adequate in this regard.
There is too much of a tendency for self-regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> to
rationalize how the provision of a broad range of services can add
value to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> and does not present an independence problem.
This has clearly been the case in connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>'s
current independence standards.
Another area where the current self-regulatory structure has
proved to be inadequate is in connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX>'s
self-disciplinary function. The process usually takes too long, and
in the final analysis, the most severe sanction the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> can
impose is expulsion from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>. Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> are not required
to belong to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> in order to conduct public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> audits,
the most severe sanction would only serve to save the CPA some dues
without any other practical effect. This is clearly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ineffective</ENAMEX>!
While the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of accountancy have the ability to impose
much stiffer sanctions, including revoking a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX>'s license to
practice in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> have not exercised this sanction
very frequently.
While I believe that it is not always desirable to have the
government intervene, at times it is necessary in order to protect
the public interest, especially when others who could act fail to
do so. Recent examples include actions taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to address areas of concern that each felt
warranted government action. Hopefully, government intervention can
be minimized in the future; but for that to occur, others must take
steps to address serious public interest issues before they reach
crisis proportions. If they fail to do so, I have little doubt that
government will eventually act.
From an enforcement perspective, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> has certain civil
enforcement powers that it can use to address violations of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s securities laws. In some cases its sanctions are adequate,
but not always. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corporate officials</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of ability and integrity who try to do the
right thing. At the same time, every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and sector has "bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>" that take short cuts and push the envelope to achieve a
desired result. Many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> tend to be arrogant and
believe that the end justifies the means. In addition, as we have
seen in the case of various derivatives transactions involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Qwest and Global Crossing</ENAMEX>, sometimes bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> join forces
to help achieve their goals. To effectively deal with these types
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, civil sanctions must be strong enough and targeted
enough to discourage potential bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> from doing things that
harm others. Too many existing civil sanctions are imposed directly
or indirectly (through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> paid premiums on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> insurance) on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and ultimately the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>. In this case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> can pay twice for the sins
of others.
While more meaningful and targeted civil penalties can help to
discourage many bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, in my view, civil sanctions aren't
enough in some cases. You need to be able to issue a few so-called
"wide-striped suits" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> who violate criminal statutes.
Nothing will focus someone's mind like looking at the world from
the inside of a prison cell. In addition, we need to be sure that
white collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> are not merely detained in so-called
"country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>" federal prison <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> for relatively short
prison terms. The price for criminal behavior must be high for
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> as well.


PENSION AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAVINGS</ENAMEX> PLANS:
The recent business failures have also served to harm a number
of innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, including pension and savings plan
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>. A number of defined benefit pension plans lost
significant sums as a result of the decline in the value of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holdings</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WorldCom</ENAMEX>, etc. When defined benefit pension
plans lose money the plan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>, typically the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>, will
ultimately bear the cost of the loss. However, when defined
contribution plans, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">401</ENAMEX>(k) plans, incur such losses, the
individual plan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> are directly affected and bear the
losses themselves.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">401</TIMEX>(k) plans can be particularly harmed in
situations where their accounts are heavily invested in employer
stock, either because their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> matches their employee
contributions in the form of such stock or because they themselves
make significant investments in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>'s stock using their
own voluntary contributions. In these cases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> risk
losing not only their jobs but also a significant portion of their
retirement savings if their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> files for bankruptcy. This was
the case in connection with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX> and certain other business
failures. In addition, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX> case, plan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were
not allowed to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> stock in their 401(k) account when the
stock price was declining rapidly due to a pending change in plan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">administrators</ENAMEX>. At the same time, top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> were free to
exercise their stock options, and some did. This inappropriate and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">un</ENAMEX>-level playing field was addressed in part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarbanes</ENAMEX>-Oxley
legislation. Some suits are likely in order to attempt to right
alleged fiduciary breaches. Additional legislation has also been
proposed that would, among other things, give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> the ability
to diversify their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> matching contributions out of company
stock more rapidly than they can under current law.


<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PAST AND FUTURE ACTIONS:</ENAMEX>
A variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> have already taken some steps in light of
these recent business accountability failures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange</ENAMEX> is moving to adopt certain changes in its listing
requirements relating to governance matters; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> and audit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX> are taking their related responsibilities much more
exploring a principles-based approach to accounting standards and
is reconsidering the current accounting and reporting treatment for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEs</ENAMEX> and stock options; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> has issued a new fraud detection
audit standard and is beginning to assess the need for other
enhanced attest and assurance standards but it clearly needs to
pick up the pace; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX> has passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sarbanes</ENAMEX>-Oxley
legislation which included establishment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Company</ENAMEX>
Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oversight Board</ENAMEX> (PCAOB), tougher independence standards
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and independent funding sources
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASB</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> has taken a number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regulatory</ENAMEX> and enforcement actions and made initial appointments to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCAOB</ENAMEX>; various <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys</ENAMEX> have filed charges against
several key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> associated with some of the recent integrity
and accountability failures; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State Attorney General</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> are taking steps to address certain conflicts within
the investment banking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has taken a number of
steps as discussed below.
These actions are clearly steps in the right direction. However,
as noted above, additional actions are necessary in order to
address several remaining systemic issues. Hopefully, the
appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> will take steps to address these issues. If
they don't, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> may chose to act again in order to fill
any related voids.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'S ROLE:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is a professional services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> within the
legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. Our job is to help
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> discharge its constitutional responsibilities and
improve the performance and assure the accountability of the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. To do
so, we perform a variety of oversight, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insight</ENAMEX>, foresight and
adjudicatory functions spanning everything the federal government
does or is thinking about doing anywhere in the world. Simply
stated, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> we speak truth to power. Power comes in many forms,
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Congress</ENAMEX>, various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, the
press and ultimately the greatest source of power in our democracy
- the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Today, I'm speaking what I believe to be the
truth about how to restore confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business and our
profession to each of you. I will continue to speak out on these
issues in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming months</TIMEX>.
Among other things, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> serves as the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> of the
largest, most diverse and most important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> on the face of the
earth - the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>. We conduct financial statement,
performance and compliance audits of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promulgate</ENAMEX> generally accepted auditing standards for audits of
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that receive federal funds. We also
help to promulgate generally accepted accounting principles for
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government entities</ENAMEX>.
As the leading performance and accountability <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and arguably the world, we believe that we have
an obligation to lead by example and practice what we preach. We
take these obligations very seriously with all of our
responsibilities, including those relating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'
concerns regarding the recent accountability failures in the
private sector. We held a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corporate Governance and Accountability</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 2002</TIMEX> involving prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>,
private and not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> to discuss the recent
accountability failures in the private sector and what actions may
be necessary to help prevent such failures in the future. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forum</ENAMEX> served to help inform the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work and other efforts to
support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, including our efforts that helped lead to the
eventual passage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Sarbanes-Oxley legislation</ENAMEX>. We are holding
a follow-up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 9, 2002</TIMEX> to discuss what actions have
been taken by a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and those that remain in order
to help restore public trust and confidence.
In addition to these actions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has voluntarily decided to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> an opinion on internal controls and key compliance issues
in connection with our audit of the consolidated financial
statements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> and various other federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>. We are also advocating enhanced reporting in connection
with key federal performance and projection information. As
previously noted, we published new independence standards dealing
with non-audit/consulting services when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AICPA</ENAMEX> failed to act. We
are working with others within the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, including
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX>, to modernize federal financial management
and promote expanded performance and accountability reporting.
Furthermore, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, we are using the "bully pulpit" and speaking
out to encourage others to do their part to help restore public
trust and confidence and we will continue to do so.


CLOSING:
In the final analysis, for any system to work you need to assure
that the key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have integrity, that the information provided
to key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> is timely and reliable, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> or
entities that are providing assurance as to the reliability of any
financial and non-financial information are qualified and
independent both in fact and appearance. The importance of
integrity can not be overstated, if the key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> don't have
integrity, not much else matters. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> should
incorporate incentives for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do the right thing, adequate
transparency mechanisms to provide reasonable assurance that people
will do the right thing, and appropriate accountability mechanisms
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't do the right thing. These basic principles are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">timeless</ENAMEX> and can be applied to a broad range of professional,
business, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and personal issues, including how to restore
trust and confidence not only in the performance and accountability
profession but also in the broader business community and our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital markets.
I hope that all key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> will take the necessary steps to
address any real and perceived problems that serve to undercut
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> and confidence. As recent events illustrate, trust
takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to gain but can be lost in an instant. The performance
and accountability profession, and in my opinion, our corporate
governance system are at a critical crossroads. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> we must
chose the right path. If we do, we will not only regain any lost
public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> and confidence in our profession but we can position
ourselves to help add value and manage risk in a whole new range of
areas that are both needed and which we are well positioned to
address a whole new range of performance, projection and compliance
issues.
During these challenging times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> must look to what we share
in common and how we can help to create the future of our
profession. I would suggest that all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> regardless of what
position they hold or what sector they work in share certain roles,
responsibilities and values. With regard to roles, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> are in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of maximizing the performance and assuring the
accountability of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> and areas of responsibility.
With regard to responsibility, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> should be mindful of the
broader public interest in connection with all their activities.
With regard to values, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> share certain basic values such as
integrity, objectivity, competence and professionalism.
In my view, we all need to return to a set of core values and
timeless principles that can help us to do the right thing, at the
right time, all the time. These core values serve as both beliefs
and boundaries; beliefs in the form of positive concepts one can be
committed to, and boundaries in the form of limits that should not
be violated. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> our core values are accountability, integrity
and reliability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accountability</ENAMEX> describes what we do, integrity
describes how we do our work, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reliability</ENAMEX> describes how we want
our work to be received. Every world-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> should have
a set of core values, and so should our profession. I touched on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these earlier</TIMEX>.
In addition to core values, we all need to keep certain timeless
principles in mind at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">al</ENAMEX> times. First, don't believe what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gordon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gecko</ENAMEX> said in the film, Wall Street. Greed is not good - greed is
bad!! <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, remember that the law and other standards set the
floor of acceptable behavior and not the ceiling. Don't lie on the
floor - reach for the ceiling! Don't just do what is acceptable, do
what you think is right! <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> are
paid for their judgment. Turn on your brain rather than checking
boxes in connection with key accounting, reporting and auditing
issues. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Fourth</NUMEX>, say what you mean, mean what you say, practice what
you preach and lead by example in everything that you do. Finally,
remember that your reputation is priceless. It takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> to
build a reputation which can be lost very quickly if you breach the
trust that others hold in you. In addition, if you act improperly
or fail to properly discharge your duties, you can harm a number of
innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. As a result, if it doesn't seem right, don't do
it!!
In closing, we all have a stake in the future of our profession
and the reputation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CPAs</ENAMEX>. I can assure you that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and I will do
our part to practice what we preach and lead by example in our
roles, responsibilities and values. I hope that I can count on each
of you and others to do the same. After all, the time to act is
now! Let's do it!!



