



Preface
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> assists congressional decisionmakers in their deliberative
process by furnishing analytical information on issues and options
under consideration. Many diverse methodologies are needed to
develop sound and timely answers to the questions that are posed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. To provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluators with basic information
about the more commonly used methodologies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s policy guidance
includes documents such as methodology transfer papers and
technical guidelines.
This methodology transfer paper on case study evaluations
describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evaluators</ENAMEX> could use case study methods in
performing our work. It describes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> applications of case study
methods, including the purposes and pitfalls of each, and explains
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">similarities</ENAMEX> and differences among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>. This paper presents an
evaluation perspective on case studies, defines them, and
determines their appropriateness in terms of the type of evaluation
question posed. The original report was authored by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lois</ENAMEX>-ellin
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Datta</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1987</TIMEX>. This reissued (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>) version supersedes the
earlier edition.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX> is one of a series of papers issued
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program Evaluation and Methodology Division</ENAMEX> (PEMD). The
purpose of the series is to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluators with guides to
various aspects of audit and evaluation methodology, to illustrate
applications, and to indicate where more detailed information is
available.
We look forward to receiving comments from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of this
paper. They should be addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Chelimsky</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202-275-1854</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werner Grosshans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Comptroller General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
Policy

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Chelimsky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Comptroller General</ENAMEX> for Program
Evaluation and
Methodology
Contents

Preface




Chapter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 63</NUMEX> 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data Collection</ENAMEX>
63


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data Collection</ENAMEX> 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data Analysis</ENAMEX>


67
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX> 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handling Multisite Data Sets</ENAMEX>
70

<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Basic Models</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data Analysis</ENAMEX>

73

Pitfalls and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booby Traps</ENAMEX>

74

Where to Go for More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>

78




<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 579</ENAMEX> 
What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Are Case Studies</ENAMEX>?
79
Summary 
When <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are Case Studies Appropriately Used</ENAMEX>
79in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evaluation</ENAMEX>? 

What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Distinguishes a Good From a</ENAMEX>
80Not-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Case Study</ENAMEX>?

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impartiality</ENAMEX> and Generalizability

84
Appendixes 
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Appendix I: Theory and History 86</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Appendix II: Site Selection Example 106</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appendix III</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Guidelines for Reviewing Case</ENAMEX> 113Study
Reports 
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Bibliography 121</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Glossary 145</ENAMEX>
Papers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This</TIMEX> Series 150

Tables

Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: What Is a Case Study</ENAMEX>? Exercise. 13
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Complexity of Questions 18</ENAMEX>
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Methods of Obtaining Description 20</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Studies</ENAMEX>
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4</NUMEX>: Some Common <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Benefits Expected 24 From Case Study</ENAMEX>
Evaluations
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Instance Selection in Case Studies 27</ENAMEX>
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.6</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hypothetical Data</ENAMEX> on Instance 30Selection 
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.1</NUMEX>: Illustrative Case <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Studies</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.2</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exploratory Case Studies 42</ENAMEX>
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Critical Instance Case Studies</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX>: Program Implementation Case 51Studies 
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Illustration of Differences in</ENAMEX>
53Note-Taking 
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.6</NUMEX>: Program <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Effects Case Studies 56</ENAMEX>
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.7</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cumulative Case Studies 59</ENAMEX>
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.8</NUMEX>: Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Design Decisions</ENAMEX> in Case 61Study
Methods 
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ways of Analyzing Case Study</ENAMEX> 69Data 
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5.1</NUMEX>: Some Common Pitfalls in Case 81Study
Evaluation 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table I.1</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Criteria of Good Research 88</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table I.2</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evaluation Adaptations</ENAMEX> of the 103Research
Case Study 
Table II.<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I: Hypothetical Data on Unfiled 107 Corporate Income</ENAMEX>
Tax Returns for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Income Tax Returns</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Table III</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Checklist for Reviewing Case Study</ENAMEX>
Reports

Abbreviations

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 1</ENAMEX>



Introduction
At his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>-required anti-terrorist training session
recently, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX> for a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> said,
"The <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of information were so few and far between that people
weren't even paying attention. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight-hour</TIMEX>
course entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> only to change videotapes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> were
talking; they were doing other things, including reading the
paper." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Inquirer</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>)
This is a case instance. It is an effective way of drawing
attention to a problem such as training quality. Such anecdotes are
remembered and they are convincing. What they are not, however, is
generalizable: that is, an anecdote doesn't tell whether it is the
only such instance or whether the problem is wide-spread. And
anecdotes usually don't show the reasons for a situation, and thus
are of limited value in suggesting solutions.
The challenge for evaluators is how to use those aspects of an
anecdote that are effective for our work-the immediacy, the
convincingness, the attention-getting quality-and, at the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, fulfill other informational requirements for our jobs, such
as generalizability and reliability. Case study methods, while not
without their limitations in this regard, can help us answer this
challenge.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> already does a lot of case studies-or at least, what we
ourselves call case studies in describing our methods. There are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> case studies in many areas-urban housing, weapon systems
testing, community development, military procurement contracts,
influences on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">export-import balances</ENAMEX>, how programs
aimed at improving water quality are working, and the
implementation of block grants-to name <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only a few</NUMEX>.
Most of these case studies are either "illustrative" or
"critical" instance applications. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> type of
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
application illustrates findings established by other
techniques, supplementing, for example, national findings on clean
air from administrative records and other sources, with in-depth
description on how funds have been used and with what results in
selected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> type of application is in-depth
analysis of a case of unique interest, such as whether funds have
been awarded and managed properly in a specific community health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX> or if a certain former government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> had done anything
improper before or after leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. There are,
however, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other applications of case studies that are less
often used at present but that could be appropriate for our jobs.
In brief, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> types of case study, which we examine in chapter
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, are as follows:



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illustrative</ENAMEX>. This case study is descriptive in
character

and intended to add realism and in-depth examples to other
information about a program or policy.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
Exploratory. This is also a descriptive case study but is
aimed at generating hypotheses for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> investigation rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illustrating</ENAMEX>.



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
Critical instance. This examines a single instance
of

unique interest or serves as a critical test of an assertion
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a program, problem, or strategy.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
Program implementation. This case study investigates
operations, often at several <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, and often
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">normatively</ENAMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
Program effects. This application uses the case study to
examine causality and usually involves multisite, multimethod
assessments.


Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. Cumulative. This brings together findings from many case
studies to answer an evaluation question, whether descriptive,
normative, or cause-and-effect.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX> is a review of methodological issues
involved in using case study evaluations. It is not a detailed
guide to case study design. It does, however, explain the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">similarities</ENAMEX> and differences among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> kinds of case study and
discusses ideas for successfully designing them. It also gives
guidance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> who, in reviewing completed case studies,
wants to assess their strengths. Finally, it presents an evaluation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> on case studies, defining them and determining their
appropriateness in terms of the type of evaluation question
posed.
The methods and types of case studies outlined here are not
definitive. The case study as a research method has evolved over
many years of experience but evaluative use of the method has been
more limited. Indeed, the history of the case study as an
evaluation method is little older than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>. Therefore,
discussion of some of the applications described here is based on
relatively extensive field experience (with questions in such
domains as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>, education, welfare, environment, housing, and
foreign aid), while the discussion of some of the other
applications is based on more constrained experience.
We have paid particular attention to the conventional wisdom
that case studies are always subjective and nongeneralizable. In
many uses of case studies, there is no need to generalize.
Nonetheless, we find that there are steps that can be taken to
generalize from case studies when this is desired. However, we did
not devote any particular emphasis to the popular idea that case
studies are inexpensive to conduct (issues of research management
common to all
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
designs were outside the scope of our work). However, one thing
that should emerge quite clearly from the discussion of design
features intrinsic to the case study is that it can be a rather
costly endeavor, given the time required, the rich in-depth nature
of the information sought, and the need to achieve credibility.
This reinforces the importance of weighing carefully the decisions
to employ the case study method in program evaluation.
In this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, we have taken positions on many issues, expecting
to revise these as experience accumulates and as we receive
reactions from evaluators and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is intended
to transfer what we believe to be good practice in case studies and
to help establish the principles of applying case studies to
evaluation. Thus, while the document offers preliminary guidance,
it is also a point of departure. For example, we are developing the
variation that we call the "cumulative" case study. It can entail
prospective and retrospective designs and it permits synthesis of
many individual case studies undertaken at different times and in
different sites.
The quality of case studies can be variable. Some score high on
reasonable tests of quality; others have lower scores. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three</TIMEX>
problems often encountered have to do with matching the question
the evaluator set out to answer and the method for selecting the
instances examined, reporting the basis for selecting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instances</ENAMEX>, and integrating findings across several instances when
the findings in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> were inconsistent with those in another.
The next sections of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> will first present some new ways
of thinking about a familiar method, the case study, and then
introduce the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> applications, describing what is required, in
terms of methodology, to get the benefits case studies can offer.
In the last
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX>, we turn to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> basic questions: What do we need to take
into account with regard to the objectivity of case studies and
their generalizability?
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 2</ENAMEX>


What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Are Case Studies</ENAMEX>?
Almost everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> probably has worked on a case study at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time or another yet may be unfamiliar with what is meant,
methodologically, by a case study. The methodological meaning is
important in understanding what differentiates a case study from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noncase</ENAMEX> study and a good case study from a not-so-good case
study.
What is a case study? The exercise in table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.1</NUMEX> describes a job
we might be asked to do and a design for it and asks you to decide
whether or not this is a case study. Take <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10 minutes</TIMEX> to think
through this example and write out your answer. It is important
that you try this out yourself, so please do it before
continuing.

The answers some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evaluators</ENAMEX> gave may illustrate the range of
definitions surrounding case study methods.
To some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluators, the instance was an application of the
case study method, because we were looking at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only a few</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> or
because we could not generalize or because "actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> are
being used for analysis of a specific question." To some, the
instance was clearly not an application of the case study method,
because "we do not know if the instances are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universe</ENAMEX>," and "there doesn't appear to be enough done at each
site." To still others, it was not possible to tell whether this
was a case study because looking at instances was what we do in all
our methods, and there was no differentiation between this job and
a compliance audit.
The definitions given also varied greatly. To <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, a case
study involves looking at individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. To another, a case
study examines a clearly defined site and reports on that one site,
so that multiple site studies would not be case studies. To
another, case studies involve getting a great deal of information
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a single</NUMEX> site or circumstance, when generalizability isn't
important. To others, "a random sample is necessary for a case
study," "case studies are nonnormative research that investigate a
situation without prejudice," "where we could look at a limited
number of cases that would represent the universe overall," and "a
review of relevant conditions in a specific environment with no
attempt to project to a larger universe." There were almost as many
definitions as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and few of them had elements in common.
While exact uniformity isn't expected or perhaps even possible when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are asked to recall a definition, the extreme variability
illustrates that we could be talking about very different things
in
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>

What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is Meant by "a Case Study"</ENAMEX>?
a proposal or report when we discuss case study methods. Thus a
decision to "do case studies" could lead to the collection of
irreconcilably dissimilar information from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> working on the
same job.
We have developed a definition of case studies that leads to
appropriate uses and says something about how a good case study is
conducted. It is somewhat technical, so we turn next to giving this
definition and to discussing each of its elements.
"A case study is a method for learning about a complex instance,
based on a comprehensive understanding of that instance obtained by
extensive description and analysis of that instance taken as a
whole and in its context."
For example, if we were asked to study what caused the Three
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mile Island</ENAMEX> disaster and scoped the job to describe whether
required safeguards were complied with, this would not be a case
study. If, however, we scoped the job to examine in depth events
leading up to the disaster, what went wrong, and why it went wrong,
this would be a case study. For a second example, if we were asked
to study the safety of nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> in general, we might select
as our method a survey of self-reported compliance with safeguards
in all existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. This would not be a case study. If,
however, we scoped the job to examine in depth recent problems in
appropriately selected nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> including among others Three
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mile Island</ENAMEX>, seeking to understand why the safeguards either were
not complied with or were not sufficient, then we would have
selected the case study method to answer the question.
As we will discuss later, several methods can be used in one
job; these examples are only intended to highlight what is not, and
what is, a case study.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
Examining the elements of the definition also may help make this
distinction clear.
"A complex instance" means that input and output cannot be
readily or very accurately related. There are several reasons why
such a relationship might be difficult. There could be many
influences on what is happening and these influences could interact
in nonlinear ways such that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of change in the input can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with quite different changes in the output, sometimes
increasing it, sometimes decreasing it, and sometimes having no
discernible effect.
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX> gives an example of a less and a more complex
instance. "Are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> following required <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and
international security procedures for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>?" is a less
complex question because the criterion is fairly clear, the focus
is narrow, the influences on compliance are likely to be relatively
few, and the relation of input and output is likely to be fairly
direct. Staff knowledge of procedures ought to play some role in
following these procedures, for instance.
Some questions are more complex, however, such as the question:
"Are security procedures in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> sufficient to protect the
safety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and equipment?" This is more complex because
the criterion of "sufficient protection" is much less certain; the
focus is broader; the influences on actual achievement of
sufficient procedures are likely to be many; and the relation of
input and output is not only likely to be both direct and indirect
but also difficult to measure.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> key element in our definition is "a comprehensive
understanding." Here the situation is more straightforward. This
means that the goal of a
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
case study is to obtain as complete a picture as possible of
what is going on in an instance, and why.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> key element, "obtained by extensive description and
analysis," has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> components. These are summarized in table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX>.
Case studies involve what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">methodologists</ENAMEX> call "thick" descriptions:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX>, full information that should come from multiple data sources,
particularly from firsthand observations. The analysis also is
extensive, and the method compares information from different types
of data sources through a technique called "triangulation." That
is, reliability of the findings is developed through the multiple
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> within each type. This is akin to corroboration as
discussed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Policy Manual</ENAMEX>, chapter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>. The
validity
of the findings, particularly validity with regard to
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.2</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Complexity of Questions Example Characteristic</ENAMEX>
A less complex question
Are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> following required <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> procedures for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Criterion</ENAMEX> is fairly clear: "required <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> procedures"
Focus is narrow: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>"
Influences on compliance are likely to be relatively few: staff
knowledge of procedures, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> training in their implementation,
functioning equipment, number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> compared to workflow, degree
of supervision, staff screening and selection
Relation of input (influences on compliance) to output (that
required security procedures are followed) is fairly direct
(continued)

Example Characteristic
A more complex question
Are security procedures in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airports</ENAMEX> sufficient toprotect the safety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and
equipment?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Criterion</ENAMEX> is less clear: what would be sufficient under present
conditions and with existing and possible technologies? Focus is
broader: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and equipment (although still fairly well
specified)
Influences on achievement of sufficient procedures likely to be
many, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of the art of detection technologies,
number and militancy of potential threats to security, and the
willingness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX>, airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, and airport personnel
to accept different costs and forms of protection
Relation of input (influences on security) and output (safety)
likely to be difficult to measure and to be both indirect and
direct
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Methods of Obtaining Description Technique</ENAMEX>
Methodology
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Analysis in Case Extensive or</ENAMEX> "thick" analysisStudiesa
Analysis of multiple types
of data sources such as -Interviews with all relevant
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">persons</ENAMEX>
-Observations over time -Participant observation -Documents
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-Archives</ENAMEX> -Physical information

aDifferent types of evidence and standards for them are
discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Policy Manual</ENAMEX>, chapter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.0</NUMEX>.
cause and effect, is derived from agreement among the types of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, together with the systematic ruling out of
alternative explanations and the explanation of "outlier" results.
Examining consistency of evidence across different types of data
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> is akin to verification. There are specialized strategies
for making these comparisons-namely, pattern matching, explanation
building, and thematic review. The technical how-tos for these
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> strategies will be summarized later in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>. They
involve techniques such as graphic data displays, tabulations of
event frequencies, and chronological or time series orderings.
Generally, data collection and analysis are concurrent and
interactive-that is, "yoked" in case study methods.
The next element of the definition is "taken as a whole." As
this list indicates, the size of the instance can be as small as
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> or as large as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. The instance as a whole can
be


•
An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferdinand Marcos</ENAMEX>).


•
A site (<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Three Mile Island</ENAMEX>).


•
A function (joint test and evaluation
program1).


•
An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> (program evaluation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX>).


•
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>).


•
An event (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> missile crisis1; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX>
tragedy).


•
A region, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chesapeake</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX> water
cleanup efforts, democracy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNESCO</ENAMEX>).


•
"Nested" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> in a large or complex case study (note
that the instance or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> must be specified and data appropriate to
it collected).


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> case study that examines an individual is
our examination of whether or not a
1These instances have been the subject of case studies. (See
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 22, 1984</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allison</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>.) Others are general illustrations.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> behaved improperly with regard to influence and
accepting money before and since leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> (U.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11, 1986</TIMEX>). Another example would be
a request to examine in detail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos</ENAMEX>' use of funds
intended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for military or civilian purposes for
his personal benefit. At the other extreme, an instance may be as
large as an event, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> missile crisis (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allison</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>)
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">swine</ENAMEX> flu <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neustadt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fineberg</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>), which have
been the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> well-known case studies, or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX>
tragedy. It can be a region (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chesapeake</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX> water cleanup
programs), a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> (democracy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>), or an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNESCO</ENAMEX>). Moreover, it is possible to have questions
that require nested case studies. For example, to answer a question
about how programs to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped children</ENAMEX> are working, we
might select the cases of preschool and elementary programs; we
might further select within preschool programs, those for the
hearing impaired and those for the orthopedically impaired. Each of
these nested studies is treated, in terms of specification of the
unit of study and collection of data appropriate to it, as any
other case study would be.
The last key element of the definition is "and in its context."
Context means all factors that could affect what is happening in an
instance. As an example, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX> tragedy, inquiry began
with trying to locate the technology that failed as the reason for
the explosion. The righthand booster <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket</ENAMEX> was identified as the
source of the explosion and, within the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rocket</ENAMEX>, technological
attention focused on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">O-</ENAMEX>rings. The inquiry expanded very
quickly, however, from asking what technology failed to an
examination of contextual influences, such as
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>


•
decisionmaking on whether or not to go, in relation to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">O-</ENAMEX>rings;


•
decisionmaking on whether or not to go, in relation to
other components, such as tiles;


•
decisionmaking more generally in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> with regard to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor-astronaut</ENAMEX> relations and
responsibilities;


•
influences on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>, such as alleged pressures not to
cancel flights;


•
quality control tradeoffs in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> generally and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>.


That is, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX> inquiry could be seen as similar to a
case study in some ways. The rapid spread of inquiry from an
examination of the technology to an investigation of decisionmaking
on that flight, to inquiry about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> as it affected the
Challenger disaster generally, is what "taking the context into
account" means. In case study methods, to understand what happened
and why, context always is considered, and it is this consideration
that gives the case study its strength as a way of understanding
cause and effect.



Some Common <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Benefits Expected From Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
Doing a good case study is more than just looking at what is
happening in a few instances. It is a special systematic way of
looking at what is happening, of selecting the instances,
collecting the data, analyzing the information, and reporting the
results.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> features of case study evaluations that merit
special discussion. Each of these features-if carried out-confers
certain benefits in terms of the product. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of the features
relate to design, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to data collection, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to analysis, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to reporting. These features and their benefits are shown in
table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4</NUMEX>. For example, with regard to design, information over
time-the longitudinal feature of the
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
design-provides assurance that the final product represents what
is happening and is not registering an atypical situation.

Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.4</NUMEX>: Some Common <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Benefits Expected From Case Study</ENAMEX>
Evaluations
Study feature Benefits expected
Design
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longitudinal Assurance</ENAMEX> that a short-term situation that may be
unrepresentative of what is happening isn't inflated in
importance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Triangulation Assurance</ENAMEX> that reasons given for events properly
reflect influences from many different sources
Purposive instance Ability to match questions asked and later
generalization of findings at level appropriate to the
questions
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Data</ENAMEX> collection
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comprehensive Assurance</ENAMEX> that important conditions, consequences,
and reasons for these have not been overlooked
Flexible Broader perspectives, increased assurance that what is
important on the scene rather than centrally will be examined
Multiple data sources <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assurance</ENAMEX> that a full picture will be
obtained and that bias associated with self-protection or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-interests</ENAMEX> will be reduced
Analysis
"Yoked" or concurrent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data Assurance</ENAMEX> of the ability to
collect data collections needed to test alternative interpretations
and to make rapid adjustments in design
Search for disproving-proving evidence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assurance</ENAMEX> that
alternative interpretations have been thoroughly searched for and
checked; thorough identification of instances that don't fit the
general pattern; and, often, understanding of the reasons for the
outliers


Study feature Benefits expected
Chain-of-evidence and pattern matching Permit fairly direct
assessment of how techniques convincingly the evidence of
conclusions are related
Reporting
Actual instances persuasiveness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assurance</ENAMEX> of authenticity
through and ease of recall; use of the tendency to generalize from
personal experience but via the substitution of more objective
experience for anecdotes of unknown credibility



<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instance Selection</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Studies</ENAMEX>
These features are the price of admission to the expected
benefits. One frequent question about case study methods is how
rigorously these features have to be followed. Obviously, the more
closely the requirements are followed, the more benefits can be
expected. It is a judgment call as to how much the features can be
compromised before the "case study" becomes a site visit or turns
into a survey. Probably the most critical features are appropriate
instance selection, triangulation, and the search for disproving
evidence. And of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>, probably the most critical is
appropriate instance selection.
There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> general bases for selecting instances:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convenience</ENAMEX>, purpose, and probability. Each has its function and
can be used to answer certain questions. A good case study will use
a basis for instance selection that is appropriate for the question
to be answered. Using the wrong basis for selecting an instance is
a fatal error in case study designs, as in all designs. Such a case
study is a not-good case study, and it is irredeemably flawed
despite any methodological virtues it may have in terms of data
collection, analysis, and reporting.
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.5</NUMEX> summarizes the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> general bases for selecting
instances and the questions each basis can answer. Of particular
interest may be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> varieties of purposive site selection:
bracketing, best cases, worst cases, cluster, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>,
typical, and special interest.
Instance selection is crucial to generalizability and to
answering the evaluation questions appropriately. Only rarely will
convenience be a sound basis for instance selection; only rarely
will probability sampling be feasible. Thus, instance selection on
the basis of the purpose of the study is the most appropriate
method in many designs.

Representative "In instances chosen to represent important
variations, what is the program like and why<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
Typical "In a typical site, what is happening and why<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
Special interest "In this particular circumstance, what is
happening and why<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
Probability "What is happening in the program as a whole, and
why?"
The match between the question asked and the method of purposive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sampling</ENAMEX> chosen can be tricky. For example, studies that attain
"representativeness" by conducting a few case studies in a rural
setting, a few in a suburban setting, and a few in an urban setting
will produce a report in which the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> settings receive more or
less equal weight. If, however, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> or sites
for the program are rural, such "representativeness" may
appropriately capture the range of site experiences
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
but be rather unrepresentative of the program as a whole, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> will be needed to generalize only to the range of settings and
not to the program as a whole.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aCosts</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> per day, charged by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> to funder
(hypothetical data).
bProblem rates include all problems considered under contract as
serious, such as escape, acts of violence by or toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vandalism</ENAMEX> requiring more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> to repair, and suicides. Rates
are number of such instances per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100 days</TIMEX> per year (hypothetical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>).
To illustrate what each variety means, and how it might be
operationalized, consider the information in table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.6</NUMEX>. This gives
hypothetical data about a real situation in designing a
study-selecting instances (in
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
this study, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> or locations) for an assessment of the costs
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of federal detention <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> managed by private
contractors under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB Circular</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A-76</ENAMEX>. There are not many such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX>-so the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> hypothetical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> represent what we
might actually find in such a study. The following paragraphs
describe what a sample would look like if it were chosen according
to the bases in table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.6</NUMEX>.
Convenience If our location were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Regional Office</ENAMEX>, a
convenience sample would be sites 8 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
Samples
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salida</ENAMEX>). That is, ease of collecting data and minimizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> required would have driven our choice.

were looking at something about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> rather than about
low-problem <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. We could do this by selecting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
percent), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amarillo</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX>), and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
percent).
Worst <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cases Sites 5</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> problems) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clearwater</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>) stand out as worst cases. Selecting an
out-of-state comparison, if we wanted it, is harder here. The next
highest problem rate (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salida</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9 percent</NUMEX>) is run by a
different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and costs much less. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> has a site in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, which costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-percent
problem rate. The costs of site <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>) are higher,
but this site serves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and has a low problem rate. The best
choice probably is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>): it serves the same group
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>) and is run by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>).
Cluster We might be interested in administrative
arrangements-in, for example, how administration works out when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>
alone is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>, when responsibility is shared with another
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Prisons</ENAMEX>), and when responsibility is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. One cluster of sites (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1, 2, 3, 8, 9</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 11</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 14</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>) is administered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> alone. Another cluster (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4,</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) is shared between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>, and the last cluster (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7,</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8, 12</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>) is run by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. We could pick one or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> from each cluster to get a sense of how agency auspices
may affect program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Representative One</ENAMEX> issue we might need to examine could be
efficiencies of operation-particularly in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> size.
Here we might select numbers 1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> beds), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clearwater</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> beds), and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinas</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> beds). All are run by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAIM</ENAMEX>, and all serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. We would have to limit our
generalizations to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, but
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> should give a good sense of the size and
operations issue.
Typical This would be a challenge. In terms of size, there is a
"typical" bed size (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 beds</ENAMEX>); in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> served, there is
a "typical" population (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>); and in terms of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of
operation, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 years</TIMEX> is "typical," with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 years</TIMEX> a close runner-up. In
terms of costs, however, the distribution is trimodal-that is,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> values appear about equally often-and for percent of
problems, it is almost flat with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> outliers. Also, there is not a
single site that matches <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> "typical" characteristics well.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, for example, has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> beds and serves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, but it
has been in operation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 1 year</TIMEX>, costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> per day,
and has a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>-percent problem rate. The best approach would be to
indicate that it is not possible to pick one site that is "typical"
of such distributions.
Special Interest Any one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> might be examined as a
result of special congressional interest. Such interest usually
would be based on information extraneous to the data in the table:
a complaint might be received, for example, about conditions in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> site, or allegations might be made that the high costs of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> site were due to mismanagement.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probability Samples Probabilistic</ENAMEX> sampling is the method of
choice for answering questions about "how much," or how extensive a
problem is in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Properly carried out, it provides
strong generalizability and assurance of representativeness. A
probability sample is one in which all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the population
have a known and equal chance of being selected. If we used a table
of random numbers, and selected as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sites those
corresponding to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> numbers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1 and 16</TIMEX> in the
table, we would have selected a probability sample. Each site
would
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-in-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> chance of selection, and that chance would be
equal among <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. A fair objection to this statement is that the
laws of probability operate on large numbers, and selecting fewer
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> instances does not always provide the generalizability to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> as a whole that probability samples promise.
However, in terms of actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, which we want to illustrate
here, the method just sketched is a probabilistic one, and some
case studies have involved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> or more sites selected on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">probabilistic</ENAMEX> basis. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEMD</ENAMEX>'s transfer paper entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Using</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Sampling</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General</ENAMEX>
Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15, 1986</TIMEX>) for more information.)
For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who want to check out their skills in applying
different types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">purposive</ENAMEX> selection, appendix <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">II</ENAMEX> gives
information for a job involving the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> (a fairly common
situation for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>), a form for indicating which you would select
for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">purposive</ENAMEX> selection, and our
answers, for comparison against yours.
In many jobs, what is a "case" and what dimensions are important
to consider in selection will be clear. For example, the population
of detention <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> contracts can be defined
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">legally</ENAMEX> (by the contract awarded), and the relevant dimensions
(length of time in operation, facility size, detainee mix) are
straightforward. There are, however, more problematic
circumstances. An example would be a study of the extent to which
voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have taken up any slack in welfare
supports. What is a voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> can be defined broadly,
as "any nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>," or narrowly, as "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">service-oriented</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> do not receive payment for
their work."
Dimensions of potential relevance for the outcome of interest
are many, and the empirical basis for selecting any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> dimension
over others few. In such situations, the evaluator can turn to past
experience, a search of the appropriate theoretical as well as
empirical literature, the advice of knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, an
examination of key issues in proposed or pending legislation,
customer guidance, and similar techniques. That is, while it is
important to recognize the difficulties, there are ways of dealing
with them in case definition.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Chapter 3</ENAMEX>



Case Study Applications
As noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> types of applications for case
study methods-illustrative, exploratory, critical instance,
implementation, program effects, and cumulative. But case study
reports commonly use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> applications: illustrative
and critical instance. Greater use could be made of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> others
in selecting alternative ways of answering questions, because these
may be able to give information that is more valuable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>
than other techniques. Also, improvements can always be made in how
even the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> approaches already used frequently are carried out,
especially in the area of selecting instances for study. The next
sections summarize, for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> types, the evaluation
questions they can answer, the functions they perform, their design
features, and their pitfalls. The last section shows what basis for
selecting sites is appropriate for each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
applications.
As table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.1</NUMEX> indicates, illustrative case studies

Illustrative
primarily describe what is happening and why, in one or two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instances</ENAMEX>, to show what a situation is like. This can help in the
interpretation of other data, particularly if we have reason to
believe most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> know too little about a program or situation
to understand fully the information from surveys or other
methods.

Design features
Site selected as typical or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of important
variations; small number of cases to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s interest; data
often include visual evidence; analysis concerned with data quality
and meaning; and reports use self-contained, separate narratives or
descriptions
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pitfalls May</ENAMEX> be difficult to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s interest while
presenting in-depth information on each illustration; may not
adequately represent situations where considerable diversity exists
(in such situations, it may be impossible to represent variety well
enough to use illustrative case studies); and may not have time
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">on-site for in</ENAMEX>- depth examination
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has many examples of such illustrative use. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, for
instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CED</ENAMEX> examined housing block grants through a survey
supplemented by case studies. The results of the survey were
published in the main report (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 13, 1982</TIMEX>). For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>), individual reports described what each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was like
with regard to housing and housing-related activities and how the
money was
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
used in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and included before-and-after pictures of what
rehabilitation meant for individual neighborhoods and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> (U.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24, 1982</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 30, 1982</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 1982</TIMEX>). In a similar application, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRD</ENAMEX> described the projects
funded under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Emergency Job Appropriations Act of 1983</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 26, 1985</TIMEX>;<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 27, 1985</TIMEX>;
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 25, 1985</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 6, 1985</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illustrative</ENAMEX> case studies are used by evaluators in other
trying out delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> Start services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Home Start</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> supplemented
a formal assessment of the development of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> before and
after the program with case studies (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High/Scope Educational</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Foundation</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>). These case studies described what
services were delivered, the conditions in rural as well as urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, and what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Start</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> did during the home visits
and generally provided a surrogate or vicarious experience for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who might never have visited a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Head Start or a Home Start</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>. The case studies told, too, of the development of the
program over time and helped give a realistic sense of problems in
start-up and implementation, how changes in staffing were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accommodated</ENAMEX>, and the impact of shifting federal guidance on
efforts to carry out the program in the field.
Case studies such as these are well accepted as a valid way of
amplifying a more systematic presentation via the realism and
vividness of anecdotal information. There are, however, pitfalls in
presenting illustrative case studies. The most serious is selecting
the instances. The case or cases must
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
adequately represent the situation or program. This is
relatively easy if the program is small and homogeneous. Where
considerable diversity exists, it may not be possible to select a
"typical" site, and the diversity may be so great that to represent
it adequately would require more case studies than most people
would want to read for illustrative purposes. In the example of
privately operated detention <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, an illustrative case study
might run the risk of oversimplifying a more complex situation. The
example was contrived to illustrate exactly this point: that
sometimes we cannot select a site that fits our needs and thus the
method is not appropriate.
However, in many real-world situations, it is possible to
represent diversity adequately for illustrative purposes and to
obtain the benefits of this application: helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> feel,
hear, see, "be there" when this kind of surrogate site experience
is necessary to undo stereotypes or explain a situation otherwise
inaccessible for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
Such a situation might be a bilingual education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, about
which stereotypes can abound, or life aboard a
nuclear<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-weapon</ENAMEX>-equipped <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX>, a situation few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will
ever experience themselves but may need to get a feel for in order
to understand staff selection, training, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> on modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">submarines</ENAMEX>.
The exploratory case study is a shortened case study,
Exploratory undertaken before launching into a large-scale
investigation. Its function is to develop the evaluation questions,
measures, designs, and analytic strategy for the bigger study. As
table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.2</NUMEX> indicates, it is most helpful where considerable
uncertainty exists about program <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, goals, and results.
Also rather than initiate a job requiring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> staff <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> or
more,
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
when we do not have an adequate on-the-shelf set of designs and
measures, an exploratory case study can save time and money in
implementation as well as improving the confidence we have in our
results. We can aim more precisely and hit the target more
often.

Functions Where considerable uncertainty exists about program
operations, goals, and results, exploratory case studies help
identify questions, select important measurement constructs,
develop actual measures for these, which can be used later in
larger-scale tests; formulate expectations; safeguard investment in
larger studies (for problems or programs that are not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">well-developed</ENAMEX>)
Design features
Site selected: needs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> site that represents each
important variation to make a convenience sample acceptable; number
of cases sufficient to cover diversity; data focus on program
operations and on-site observation, are not longitudinal but need
enough time to find out what is going on; analysis is closely
concurrent with field work but does not require strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> of
evidence or audit trail; reports are usually internal or parts of
larger, longer reports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pitfalls Temptation</ENAMEX> to prolong the exploratory phase; site
selection only for convenience, inadequate coverage of diversity;
prematurity -exploratory findings released as conclusions;
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-involvement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">evaluator</TIMEX>'s own hunches so that initial
findings are confirmed rather than tested
Some of our scoping work already may involve exploratory case
studies. For example, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGD</ENAMEX>, a design study was done as a separate
job, culminating
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
in a briefing, prior to an in-depth study of the implementation
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bail Reform Act of 1984</ENAMEX>. The methodology included <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
interviews, observations, and data analysis from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court districts</ENAMEX> selected purposively for their characteristics
on significant variables. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> in the field were
also interviewed. An expert <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> was used to give feedback at
various points to make sure we had a comprehensive picture of the
situation. The product of this exploratory case study was a
briefing, with the study design choices described, including
detailed research questions, outlines of data sources, significant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variables</ENAMEX>, extant data bases, and site selection criteria. From
this, a larger study was designed to meet the needs of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">requester</ENAMEX>. Other jobs may involve similar efforts that are not,
however, reported as separate jobs and thus are less visible as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploratory</ENAMEX> case studies.
Also reports that include some features of exploratory case
studies have been issued by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, for example, NSIAD
examined emerging issues in export competition through a case study
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> market (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 1985</TIMEX>). Combining site visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Germany</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, interviews with many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> of appropriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
and from the private sector, examination of official government
files, and a questionnaire survey of high technology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> active
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> market, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evaluators</ENAMEX> amassed a rich array of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contextual</ENAMEX> and focal information and identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> trade
practices considered to be key factors in export competitiveness in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> markets. These were bilateral trade accords,
countertrade, export financing, and compliance with trade-related
industrial policy. Although to meet the requirements of the job,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSIAD</ENAMEX> did not need to test these factors for generalizability to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> through a later
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
study, the product would permit such testing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSIAD</ENAMEX> is using the
findings in this way, as part of its ongoing work on bilateral
initiatives. Of particular methodological note in this report is
the detailed explanation of why export competitiveness in Brazilian
markets (the instance) was selected for the case study.
The exploratory case study has been used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>, for example, supported an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploratory</ENAMEX> case study of the career criminal program (Chelimsky
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahmann</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>). The career criminal program aimed at "swift and
certain" justice by trying to expedite and strengthen processing of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who had long criminal histories at the time of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">apprehension</ENAMEX>. The exploratory study looked in depth at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine</TIMEX> demonstration sites prior to conducting a program effects
evaluation. The evaluators identified the key elements of the
programs as implemented and what measurable changes were likely to
occur and developed measures of the outcomes, as well as designs
for testing cause and effect in the subsequent larger study
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelimsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sasfy</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>).
The greatest pitfall in the exploratory study is prematurity:
that is, the findings may seem so convincing that it can be
difficult to resist pressures to report on these as if they had the
strength of the larger study. Also, care must be taken to scope and
sequence the exploratory study so that it yields enough information
to be worthwhile and in time for use in the larger study but does
not unduly delay answering the questions through the larger study.
In addition, it is inappropriate to use the scoping phase as an ad
hoc exploratory case study accompanied by an urge to issue the
product at the end of scoping, when the necessary procedures for an
exploratory
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
case study with regard to such issues as instance selection have
not been followed.
The critical instance is the most frequent application


Critical Instance
of the case study method in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, so much so that it may be seen
as a "usual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> review" rather than recognized as what it can be-a
case study (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 22, 1981</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 1982</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 30, 1985</TIMEX>). The advantage of recognizing the
approach as an application of case study methods is that some
aspects of the method-such as the close yoking of data collection
and analysis-that may not be widely used now could be applied in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> that increases timeliness without reducing quality. (This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">technique</ENAMEX>, discussed in more detail in the section on analysis, can
increase efficiency by reducing collection of data and large-scale
analyses of these data that subsequently do not prove useful.)
The critical instance case study examines <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, or very few,
sites for one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> purposes. First, a very frequent application
is the examination of a situation of unique interest, such as Three
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mile Island</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX> disaster, or allegations concerning
funding for a specific presidential campaign. There is little or no
interest in generalizability. The instance is not "selected" by us;
rather, we are called to it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> conducts many critical instance studies. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example,
already mentioned, was our review of the representation of foreign
interests by former very high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General</ENAMEX>
Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11, 1986</TIMEX>). Another is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEMD</ENAMEX>'s review of the
readiness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Eye Bomb</ENAMEX> for production
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 23, 1986</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yetanother</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCED</ENAMEX>'s review of a construction contract award at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jean Lafitte</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Historical Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26, 1987</TIMEX>) and
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
their examination in a separate report of the park service
actions at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delaware Water Gap National Recreation</ENAMEX> area in awarding
a lease, closing a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp ground</ENAMEX>, and raising a house rent (U.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 28, 1987</TIMEX>).
A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, rare, application is where a highly generalized or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universal</ENAMEX> assertion is being called into question, and we are able
to test it through examining <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> instance.
In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> such study, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGD</ENAMEX> examined whether national policies,
procedures, and practices with regard to cargo imports were causing
problems in port <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1986</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port of New York</ENAMEX> offered a critical test
because, given the diversity of imports and the volume of work, if
problems were occurring, they would be likely to show up clearly in
this site. If no problems were observed, problems in other sites
were unlikely. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GGD</ENAMEX> used observations, interviews, and document
analysis at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port of New York</ENAMEX> and supplemented
these with a small number of less intensive observations at other
sites. The method, in this instance, was sufficient to permit
recommendations that were systemwide and generalizable with the
single case.
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX> summarizes the features of the critical instance case
study. As noted, the method is particularly suited for answering
cause-and-effect questions about the instance of concern. It
provides assurance that we have not prematurely overlooked
important factors, that we have not been swayed by information from
limited or perhaps biased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, and that we have taken context
into account, thus giving a fair and balanced picture of the
situation.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
Perhaps the biggest pitfall in this application is insufficient
specification of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>'s question. That is, the job may be
presented to us as if only that situation is of concern, but the
underlying question may call for a broader look at the issue. A
request to investigate the reasons for the bank failures in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>,
for example, may reflect an interest only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, but it could be
a "tip of the iceberg" question. What the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> may really want
to know is whether other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are likely to have similar
problems. In such a situation, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> might be selected as a site to
examine but we would also need to look at other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> or use other
approaches to achieve the generalizability needed. This then rules
out the critical instance method as appropriate for this job. The
importance of probing the underlying questions in a request to
achieve good specification of the evaluation question is not
unique, of course, to the critical instance case study but it is
crucial in its appropriate application.

We frequently are asked whether a program has been implemented
and, often, whether implementation is in compliance with
congressional intent. The program implementation case study is
helpful where enabling legislation offers considerable flexibility.
In such cases, a wide variety of expenditures or actions could be
consistent with legislation and compliance with
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
Design features
Site selects itself in specific problem-for decisive testing,
have to assume uniform system with regard to issue and so
convenience sample acceptable; number of cases is usually one
instance; comprehensive data for specific problem-for decisive
testing, need more modeling, hypotheses, and targeting to know what
to study; data analysis and collection concurrent and interactive:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> feed new collection, and emphasis on ruling out alternative
causes; report describes instances, presents conclusions about
cause, gives evidence
Pitfalls
Inappropriate selection of this technique as real issue may not
be specific problem (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> bank failure) but more general
questions; premature closure may narrow causal search too early;
overgeneralization from evidence


Program Implementation
intent may be a matter of understanding the process by which
decisions were made, who was involved, and whether the actions are
meeting local needs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> legislation
consolidating many small categorical grants into larger block
grants, the funds for which could be spent very flexibly.
Another situation where program implementation case studies may
be called for is when concern exists about implementation problems.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">In-depth</ENAMEX>, longitudinal reports of what has happened over time and
why can set a context for interpreting a finding of implementation
variability: that is, whether there seem to be basic structural
problems or if the program understandably requires time for
installment, adaptations, and building an infrastructure.
In some instances, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has been able to follow fairly
intensively the implementation of programs or activities. One
example is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GGD</ENAMEX>'s series of reports on how the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> census was
conducted. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> evaluators, in addition to being "on the scene" due
to their location at the major audit site accompanied enumerators
into the field and examined, in depth, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX> procedures at field
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. In other instances, we have spent somewhat less elapsed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in the field, with less direct observation, and with greater
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reliance</ENAMEX> on interview and documentary evidence. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, for
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCED</ENAMEX> was asked how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Interior</ENAMEX> was
dealing with privatization of all appropriate services. The request
overlapped with another similar request. This request reflected a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s special interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Glacier National Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX>.
The evaluators were able to combine the jobs in a review that
eventually involved information from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Park Service</ENAMEX>
regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">402</NUMEX> field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. The report aggregates
findings across these
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
sites and concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have been slow to implement
the circular, although progress has been made since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> (U.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15, 1985</TIMEX>).
Another example is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s review of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' efforts
to implement the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Managers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Financial Integrity Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>.
A series of case studies, together with an overview report, was
produced. Among these, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCED</ENAMEX>'s review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Commerce</ENAMEX>
implementation, to take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> report, examined the actions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>
took that were intended to improve internal controls, such as
training senior financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> in evaluating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX> in the troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDA</ENAMEX> business loan program and overhauling
the way in which computer resources were used for the National
Weather Service. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCED</ENAMEX> also examined the results of these efforts
and highlighted priority areas for further improvement, such as
better information on results for internal management purposes.
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX> summarizes the design, data collection, analysis, and
reporting features of program implementation case studies. Usually,
in such studies, generalization is wanted and care is required to
negotiate the question with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> (best situations? worst?
typical?) and to match instance selection carefully with the
questions. Unless the program is small and homogeneous, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evaluator</ENAMEX> faces <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> possibilities. The first possibility is that
the number of instances will need to be fairly large in order to
achieve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generalizability</ENAMEX> wanted, and, as a consequence, skill
will be needed to manage data collection with sufficient
flexibility to obtain the insights case studies offer and
sufficient structure to permit cross-site aggregation of findings.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> possibility is that the diversity will be so great that
it would be impossible to have enough instances to
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
meet needs for generalizability and still manage the data
collection and analysis.
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4</NUMEX>: Program <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Implementation Case Aspect</ENAMEX> examined
Characteristic
Studies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evaluation Descriptive</ENAMEX>, normative questions
Functions Learn what implementation has been achieved,
understand unexpected aspects; understand reasons why
implementation looks the way it does; useful when enabling
legislation has given flexibility
Design features
Site selection cannot be convenience because usually
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">generalization</ENAMEX> wanted, and purposive sample can be typical and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of diversity and best and worst cases; number of
cases depends on program diversity since generalization usually
wanted; data rely on common instruments, published documents, and
observation; reports are varied in theme, site, chronology, and
narration
Pitfalls
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bias</ENAMEX> detection methods may be inadequate; may fail to take into
account diverse views about program goals and purposes; competence
of all on-site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> may not be sufficiently high; can be
costly due to study size; the demands of data management, data
quality control, validation procedures, and analytic model (within
site, cross site, etc.) may lead to cutting too many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corners</ENAMEX> to
maintain quality
An important requirement for good program implementation case
studies is investment of enough time on site to get longitudinal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> and to obtain
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
breadth of information. If the purpose is to report what is
happening in a descriptive sense only, short site visits together
with administrative records may provide adequate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> for
findings. If, however, the evaluation question requires <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to
report on how satisfactory progress is or the reasons for problems
in implementation, the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> who can be on site over time,
with the richest or "thickest" base for examining the situation as
the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved see it, the sounder our causal conclusions
and subsequent recommendations will be.
The multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> usually required for program implementation
questions impose demands on training and supervision needed for
quality control. Because of tight resources, lack of travel funds,
and the need to use <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> with uneven experience and skills, this
becomes critical in situations involving many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evaluators</ENAMEX> working in
different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>. That is, time is needed to train staff
adequately in such case study techniques as the note-taking
required for thick descriptions, which is in turn required for the
content analysis of themes in the instance. It is possible, for
example, for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> to interview the same informant and find
that one has used a one-sentence summary for a detailed, rich,
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5-minute</TIMEX> discourse while the other captured much more of the
complexity and essence of what was said and what was happening.
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX> illustrates such a difference.
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Illustration of Differences in Note</ENAMEX>-Taking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Situation Technique Characteristic</ENAMEX>
In an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX> notes "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Director</ENAMEX>
indicated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science Foundation</ENAMEX> procedures had
changed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> program for grants to small times since the inception
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>, the following question is program. In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, asked: "How does your program announcements were mailed to
the inform the eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> named as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in the opportunity to apply for grants?" listing, for the
same year, of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Association of Small</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Colleges</ENAMEX>. Because applications were
very sparse, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 30%</NUMEX> of
eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> applying, the
procedure was changed to a
two-stage mailing, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to find out the name of the
official in charge of federal programs
and then to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>. This worked
well for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 5-year</TIMEX> period, in terms of
receipt of applications from over
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> of the eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>, but
when overall federal funding for
research was reduced, the positions
of federal program coordinators
were abolished and applications fell
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40%</NUMEX> of eligible institutions
responding. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, the
decision was made to mail copies to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> listed as chairs of the
relevant science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in
appropriate professional association
listings. This has increased the cost
of outreach by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $15,000</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 25%</NUMEX> more than the prior
system. To date, returns are at the
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> rate again."
Thin notes "The current system is to mail copies of the
announcements to the chairs of relevant science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, such
as chemistry, biology, physics, and computer science."


Program Effects
Case studies can determine the effects of programs and reasons
for success (or failures). In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCED</ENAMEX> examined the
progress made since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970</TIMEX>'s in cleaning up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s air,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, and land, finding that while strides had been made toward
meeting the established goals (cleaner air, properly treated
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wastewater</ENAMEX>, more drinkable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>), deadlines had been extended and
unresolved issues made meeting even these deadlines difficult (U.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 21, 1982</TIMEX>). We pointed to lack of
flexibility as a source of cascading problems and delays. The bases
for these conclusions were in-depth case studies of three sites
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>) together with information
from reports prepared by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and by environmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> and public interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and interviews with
Environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. Particularly notable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">methodologically</ENAMEX> in this report is the integration of case study
findings with other sources of information throughout the first
volume.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PEMD</ENAMEX> report has focused on water quality: the effectiveness of
efforts to improve water quality and the reasons for successes and
failures. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">In-depth</ENAMEX>, very extensive case studies of several water
catchment areas were conducted, and the final report is based on a
synthesis of the findings from the case studies-another example of
integration of findings across diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General</ENAMEX>
Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 17, 1986a</TIMEX>, b; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 19, 1986</TIMEX>). This
series of reports also is useful for illustrating the way in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">causality</ENAMEX> is established in case studies: through development of
internally consistent explanations of what led to what and the
conscientious use of information from within the site and from
contrasting sites to rule out alternative explanations.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
For another example, to determine whether actions taken by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1970</TIMEX>'s to address medical malpractice
insurance reduced insurance costs, the number of claims filed, and
the average amount paid per claim, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRD</ENAMEX> conducted case studies in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> selected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>). Work included obtaining views of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> representing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> on perceived problems, actions taken to deal with them,
results of these actions, and the need for federal involvement.
Other information came from surveys of nonfederal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, coverage limits, and costs and claims from leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and, for comparison, the same type of
information from a nationwide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The results are presented
separately in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> case study reports and aggregated in the overall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 31, 1986</TIMEX>).
Other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have used the case study method
successfully in answering program effects questions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Foundation</ENAMEX>, for example, assessed the effectiveness of a
cooperative science program aimed at increasing innovation and
knowledge transfer between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Ten</TIMEX>
case studies were undertaken of a carefully selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> that ranged from computer language systems through nuclear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> to fisheries biology and chemical engineering. Of note is
the methodological detail given on project selection, data
collection, analysis, and case format. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> report,
results from a survey of grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> are analyzed, giving both
a quantitative and a qualitative sense of how the program was
working. Results from the two methods were not integrated; both
suggested, however, that the program was generally working well
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science Foundation</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/PEMD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1.9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Study Evaluations</ENAMEX>
Table <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.6</NUMEX> summarizes key features of program effects case
studies. Like the program implementation case study, the evaluative
question often requires generalizability and, for a highly diverse
program, it may not be possible to answer the questions adequately
and still have a manageable number of sites.
