



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
Report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Subcommittees</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESULTS-ORIENTED CULTURES</ENAMEX>



Using Balanced Expectations to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manage Senior Executive</ENAMEX>
Performance
a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2002</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RESULTS-ORIENTED CULTURES</ENAMEX>
G <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A O Using Balanced Expectations to Manage</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accountability Integrity Reliability</ENAMEX>



Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Performance</ENAMEX>
Highlights


Why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> Did This Study
Effective performance management systems link individual
performance to organizational goals. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2000</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personnel Management</ENAMEX> amended regulations to require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to
link senior executive performance with organizational goals; to
appraise executive performance by balancing organizational results
with customer satisfaction, employee perspective, and other areas;
and to use performance results as a basis for pay, awards, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> decisions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> were to establish these
performance management systems by their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> senior executive
performance appraisal cycles.
Because they implemented a set of balanced expectations prior to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Personnel Management</ENAMEX> requirement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> studied the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Land Management's</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Highway Administration</ENAMEX>'s,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX>'s, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Benefits Administration</ENAMEX>'s
use of balanced expectations to manage senior executive performance
in order to identify initial approaches that may be helpful to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in holding senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> accountable for
results.


What <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Found</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reviewed developed an initial set of balanced
expectations for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to address in their individual
performance plans. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> found that these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are in the early
stages of using a set of balanced expectations to appraise senior
executive performance and there are significant opportunities to
strengthen their efforts as they move forward in holding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
accountable for results. Specifically, more progress is needed in
explicitly linking executive expectations for performance to
organizational goals. In addition, while these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> address
partnering with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, greater emphasis
should be placed in fostering the collaboration within and across
organizational boundaries to achieve results. Successful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">organizations</ENAMEX> understand that they must often change their culture
to successfully transform themselves, and such change starts with
top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> performance expectations to lead
and facilitate change could be a critical element as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
transform themselves. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> generally agreed with these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conclusions</ENAMEX>, as well as the selected initial implementation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">approaches GAO</ENAMEX> identified, as shown below.

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Selected Initial Implementation Approaches to Manage Senior</ENAMEX>
Executive Performance that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">May Be Helpful</ENAMEX> to Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies</ENAMEX>
Provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Useful Data</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> disaggregated data from
agencywide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and employee surveys. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land Management and Veterans Benefits Administration</ENAMEX> provide
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> with objective data through real-time data
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can track their individual progress
against organizational goals.
Require Follow-up Action. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> requires
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to develop action plans to follow up on customer
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> issues identified through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">agencywide</TIMEX> surveys. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Highway Administration</ENAMEX> requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to use
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">360</NUMEX>-degree feedback instruments to solicit employee views on their
leadership skills and then incorporate action items into their
performance plans for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next fiscal year</TIMEX>.
Make <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meaningful Distinctions in Performance</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are
working at making distinctions in senior executive performance. To
recognize varying levels of significance and complexity among
executive performance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> established an
executive compensation plan that assigns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to bonus levels
with corresponding bonus ranges based on levels of responsibilities
and commitments.

This is a test for developing highlights for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report. The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> report, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s objectives, scope, methodology, and
analysis is available at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/cgi-bin/getrpt</ENAMEX>?<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-966</NUMEX>. For
additional information about the report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Christopher</ENAMEX>
Mihm on (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">512-6806</TIMEX>. To provide comments on this test
highlights, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Fultz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202-512-3200</ENAMEX>) or email 
HighlightsTest@<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gao</TIMEX>.gov.



Contents


Letter1

Results in Brief3 
Background6 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Balanced Expectations</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive</ENAMEX>
Performance9 
Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Implementation Approaches to Manage Senior</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executives</ENAMEX>'
Performance18 
Conclusions26 
Agency Comments27



Appendixes

<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Appendix I: Appendix II:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appendix III</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appendix IV</ENAMEX>:

<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appendix V</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appendix VI</ENAMEX>: 
Objectives, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scope</ENAMEX>, and Methodology29

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance</ENAMEX> Plans31 
Performance Elements31 
Performance Standards for Elements32 
Performance Standards for Summary Ratings32 
Proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revisions for the 2002 Rating Year Performance</ENAMEX>
Plans32

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance</ENAMEX> Plans34 
Performance Elements34 
Performance Standards for Elements35 
Performance Standards for Summary Ratings35

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance</ENAMEX> Plans37 
Performance Elements37 
Performance Standards for Elements38 
Performance Standards for Summary Ratings39

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance</ENAMEX> Plans41 
Performance Elements41 
Performance Standards for Elements42 
Performance Standards for Summary Ratings43 
Revisions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fiscal Year 2002 Performance</ENAMEX>
Plans44



Comments from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX> Service47

<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Examples</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s
Expectations




Tables
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance</ENAMEX> in Contributing to 
Organizational Results10 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Examples</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Customer</ENAMEX>
Satisfaction Expectations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive</ENAMEX>
Performance12

Page i <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-966</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance Management</ENAMEX>
Contents


A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20548</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 27, 2002</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Daniel K. Akaka</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable Thad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cochran Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proliferation</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Services Committee on Governmental Affairs United States</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Richard J. Durbin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">The Honorable George V.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voinovich Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on Oversight of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Management</ENAMEX>,
Restructuring, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmental Affairs United States Senate</ENAMEX>
Leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> have recognized that a critical success
factor in fostering a results-oriented culture is a performance
management system that creates a "line of sight" showing how unit
and individual performance can contribute to overall organizational
goals and helping them understand the connection between their
daily activities and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s success. Effective
performance management systems <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> align <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>'s performance
expectations with organizational goals and then cascade performance
expectations through all levels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. Effective
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> are not merely once-or twice-yearly expectation setting and
appraisal tools, but can help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> manage on a
day-to-day basis. Leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> use their performance
management systems to achieve results, accelerate change, and
facilitate communication throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> so that discussions
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and organizational performance are integrated and
ongoing. Thus, an effective performance management system can be a
strategic tool for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to drive internal change and
achieve external results.
We have observed that modernizing performance management systems
and linking them to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> strategic plans and desired outcomes
should be a top priority as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> seek to transform their
cultures in response to existing and emerging challenges and
opportunities<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> Performance management systems in leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> typically seek to achieve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> key objectives.
First, they strive to provide candid and constructive feedback to
help individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> maximize their contribution and potential
in understanding and realizing the goals and objectives of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, they seek to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> with the objective
and fact-based information it needs to reward top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, performance management systems provide the necessary
information and documentation to deal with poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>. Most
federal performance management systems fail to achieve these
objectives.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> designated strategic human capital
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> as a governmentwide high-risk area<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2 One</NUMEX> of the key
areas challenging federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> is creating results-oriented
organizational cultures. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> lack organizational cultures
that promote high performance and accountability, which are
critical to successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. To help agency leaders
effectively lead and manage their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and integrate human
capital considerations into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> decision making and the program
results they seek to achieve, we developed a strategic human
capital model<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">.3 The</ENAMEX> model highlights the kinds of thinking that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> should apply, as well as some of the steps they can take,
to make progress in managing human capital strategically. As
detailed in that model, one critical success factor is to link unit
and individual performance to organizational goals.
To help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> hold senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> accountable for
organizational results, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Personnel Management</ENAMEX> (OPM)
amended regulations for senior executive performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2000</TIMEX>. These amended regulations on governing performance
appraisals for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to establish
performance management systems
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Managing for Results: Using</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Human Capital Management</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drive</ENAMEX> Transformational
Change, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15,2002</NUMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">High-Risk Series</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Update</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-263 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A Model</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Management</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-373SP</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 2002</TIMEX>).



Results in Brief
that (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) hold senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> accountable for their individual
and organizational performance by linking performance management
with the results-oriented goals of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Performance</ENAMEX> and
Results <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1993</ENAMEX> (GPRA), (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) evaluate senior executive
performance using measures that balance organizational results with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> satisfaction, employee perspectives, and any other
measures <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> decide are appropriate, and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) use performance results as a basis for pay, awards, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> decisions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> were to establish these
performance management systems by their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> senior executive
performance appraisal cycles.
The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> objective of this report was to describe the sets of
balanced expectations selected federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> used to appraise
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> performance for organizational results, customer
satisfaction, and employee perspectives. Our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> objective was
to identify the initial implementation approaches these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
have taken to manage senior executive performance that may be
helpful to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> as they implement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX>'s amended
regulations governing senior executive performance management
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>. We selected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Land Management</ENAMEX> (BLM), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Highway <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> (FHWA), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Benefits Administration</ENAMEX> (VBA) because they used a set of
balanced expectations to manage the performance of all or a
significant portion of their senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> prior to the OPM
requirement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> incorporated balanced expectations into its senior
executive performance management system in response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal</ENAMEX>
Revenue Service Restructuring and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Reform Act of 1998</ENAMEX>; the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> established their systems administratively to emphasize
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>' accountability for organizational results and
other expectations. As appropriate, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> developed the
performance expectations for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> plans to
meet particular program and management objectives and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> needs.
To describe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' expectations for senior executive
performance, we used the categories prescribed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX>'s
regulations-organizational results, customer satisfaction, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> perspective. For additional information on our objectives,
scope, and methodology, see appendix <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> are in the early stages of implementing
new performance management systems for their senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>.
Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has taken the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step in developing an initial set
of expectations for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to address in their
individual performance plans that are intended to balance
accountability for organizational results with a focus on customer
satisfaction and a consideration of employee

Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-966</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance Management</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspectives</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> offered a menu of expectations for
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to choose from and incorporate into their
individual performance plans. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> subsequently used these
expectations as the basis of senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>' performance
appraisals.


•
Organizational results. To appraise senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>'
contributions to organizational results, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> identified
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) core competencies and supporting behaviors for senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to follow that are intended to achieve results, such as
learning about current issues and applying that knowledge to make
sound decisions or pursuing business excellence, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) to only a
limited extent, targets for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to meet that are
directly linked to organizational goals, such as the average return
on sales of acquired properties or the percent of cases meeting
accuracy standards.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Customer</ENAMEX> satisfaction. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> set expectations for
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to address customer satisfaction in their
individual performance plans and appraised their performance on the
basis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> formed, customer feedback, and improved
products and services.



•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employee</ENAMEX> perspectives. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> set expectations for
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to address employee perspectives in their
individual performance plans and appraised their performance on the
basis of the training provided to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, safe and healthy work
environment, teamwork, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> satisfaction, and fairness and
diversity.

In addition, we identified an initial set of selected
implementation approaches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> are taking that
may be helpful to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> as they manage senior executive
performance against balanced expectations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and
VBA:


•
Provide useful data. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> provide senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> with objective data to help them manage their balanced
expectations during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. For example, data systems at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">VBA</ENAMEX> provide real-time data to help senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> track their
individual performance against organizational results and allow
them to compare their performance against others. In addition, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> disaggregated data from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">agencywide</TIMEX> surveys so that the
results were applicable to the senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.


•
Require follow-up action. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX> require senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to identify action items to follow up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> issues. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to hold
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workgroup</ENAMEX> meetings and develop action plans to follow up on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and employee issues identified through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">agencywide</TIMEX> surveys.
In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX> requires senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">360</NUMEX>-degree
feedback instruments to solicit employee views on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>'
leadership skills and then incorporate action items into their
individual performance plans based on the results.


•
Make meaningful distinctions in performance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
are working at implementing effective performance management
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> that make meaningful distinctions in senior executive
performance, such as by identifying varying levels of significance
and complexity among senior executive performance and considering
these levels in awarding bonuses. Towards this end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> established
an executive compensation plan for determining base salary,
performance bonuses, and other awards for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corresponds</ENAMEX> bonus levels to different levels of responsibilities
and commitments. FHWA weights the elements it uses to appraise
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> performance to make distinctions among its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>' performance.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> recognize that they are in the early
stages of implementation in using a balanced set of expectations as
part of their senior executive performance management systems. Not
surprisingly, therefore, there are significant opportunities to
strengthen their efforts as they move forward in holding senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> accountable for results. In particular, more progress is
needed in explicitly linking senior executive expectations for
performance to results-oriented organizational goals. Efforts at
making this direct linkage were often very limited. In addition,
while these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> address partnering with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, greater emphasis should be placed in fostering the
necessary collaboration both within and across organizational
boundaries to achieve results.
Lastly, there is a growing recognition, driven by a variety of
worldwide trends and pressing long-term fiscal challenges, that the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is on the brink of an enormous transformation in
what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does, how it does business, and, in some cases,
who does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s business. Ultimately, successful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">organizations</ENAMEX> understand that they must often change their culture
to successfully transform themselves, and that such a change starts
with top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. Senior



Background
executive performance and accountability for change management
will therefore be critical to the success of the federal
government's transformation. A specific performance expectation to
lead and facilitate change could be a critical element as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
transform themselves to succeed in an environment that is more
results oriented, less hierarchical, and more integrated. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX> provided written comments
generally agreeing with the contents of a draft of this report. In
addition, cognizant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, and VBA
generally agreed with a draft of this report.
Strategic human capital management, and specifically the need to
develop results-oriented organizational cultures, is receiving
increased attention across the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has
underscored the consequences of human capital weaknesses through a
wide range of oversight hearings held over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>. In
addition, to foster a results-oriented culture in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is considering legislative proposals to, among other
things, focus attention on the impact poor performance can have on
the effectiveness of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to have a
chief human capital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> to select, develop, and manage a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">productive</ENAMEX>, high-quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Management</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Agenda</ENAMEX>, released in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>,
identified human capital as one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> key governmentwide
management challenges currently facing the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
Subsequently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX> developed
criteria that recognized the importance of creating a performance
culture that appraises and rewards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> based on their
contributions to organizational goals as a key dimension of
effective human capital management.
We developed a model of strategic human capital management to
highlight the kinds of thinking that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> should apply, as well
as some of the steps they can take, to make progress in managing
human capital strategically<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX> The model consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> critical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> factors, which are organized to correspond with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cornerstones</ENAMEX> of effective strategic human capital management: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) strategic human capital planning, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) acquiring,
developing, and retaining talent, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">4</ENAMEX>) resultsoriented
organizational cultures. Within the cornerstone of
results-oriented
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">373SP</NUMEX>.
organizational cultures, a critical success factor is linking
unit and individual performance to organizational goals.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> way to reinforce accountability and alignment of individual
performance expectations with organizational goals is through the
use of results-oriented performance agreements. We have reported
that other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have begun to use their performance management
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> as a strategic tool to help achieve results.5 In
particular, they use performance agreements to align and cascade
organizational goals to individual performance expectations through
several levels in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. They also use performance
agreements to help identify the crosscutting connections both
within and between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and align the performance commitments
of top-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> with broader governmentwide priorities.
Further, our work has shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have benefited
from their use of results-oriented performance agreements for
political and senior career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>.6 Although each agency
developed and implemented performance agreements that reflected its
specific organizational priorities, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>, and cultures, the
performance agreements met the following characteristics. They


•
strengthened alignment of results-oriented goals with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>,


•
fostered collaboration across organizational
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">boundaries,</ENAMEX>


•
enhanced opportunities to discuss and routinely use
performance information to make program improvements,


•
provided a results-oriented basis for individual
accountability, and


•
maintained continuity of program goals during leadership
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transitions</ENAMEX>.


Prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX> amending its regulations on senior executive
performance management systems, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> implemented
systems
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Results-Oriented Cultures:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insights</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Agencies</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Other Countries' Performance</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Initiatives</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-862(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 2, 2002</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing</ENAMEX> for Results: Emerging
Benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Selected Agencies' Use of Performance Agreements</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-115(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 30, 2000</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-966</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance Management</ENAMEX>
that used a set of balanced expectations to manage senior
executive performance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX> implemented a balanced approach to
manage its senior executive performance to focus attention and
accountability on organizational priorities, make resource
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">allocations</ENAMEX>, and minimize employee frustration. BLM incorporated
performance elements in senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>' individual performance
plans for the rating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year ending June 2000</TIMEX> that were structured
around its strategic goals to (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Restore</ENAMEX> and Maintain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Land</ENAMEX>," (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Serve Current and Future Publics</ENAMEX>," and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Improve Organizational Effectiveness</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX> also included a
performance element in the senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>' plans to "Improve
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Resources Management and Quality of Work Life</ENAMEX>." (For more
information on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s senior executive performance plans, see app.
II.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX> implemented a balanced approach to managing its senior
executive performance in response to its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> satisfaction
survey. Specifically, the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> that responded
indicated that they did not understand their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workgroup</ENAMEX>'s role in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">implementing FHWA</ENAMEX>'s corporate management strategies that were based
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Baldridge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Quality Award</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Presidential Quality Award Criteria-leadership</ENAMEX>, strategic planning,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> focus, information and analysis, human
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX> development and management, process <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and
business results<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">.7 Beginning</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX> appraised
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> on these corporate management strategies. (For
more information on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>'s senior executive performance plans, see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">app</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>.)
In response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service Restructuring</ENAMEX> and
Reform <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act of 1998</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> initiated a method of measuring performance
designed to foster quality service, promote compliance with the tax
laws, and consider the impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> implemented a senior executive performance management system
that aligned the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>' performance expectations with a set of
balanced expectations consisting of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> satisfaction, customer
satisfaction, and business results, and with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> additional areas
of responsibility-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and equal employment opportunity. (For
more information on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s senior executive performance plans, see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">app</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX>.)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Malcolm Baldridge National Quality Award and the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quality Award</ENAMEX> are given to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> for their
overall achievements in quality and performance. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s Quality Award criteria were reoriented to be consistent
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Management</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Agenda</ENAMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-966</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance Management</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> adopted a balanced scorecard approach in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1999</TIMEX> as
a strategic management tool to drive organizational change, provide
feedback to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> on measures they can influence, link
performance appraisal and reward systems to performance measures,
and provide incentives to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to work as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in meeting
performance measures<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX> Its scorecard included measures for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuracy</ENAMEX>, speed and timeliness, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> cost, customer satisfaction,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> development and satisfaction. VBA incorporated these
measures in the performance appraisals for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> in its
regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> where the majority of senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are
located. (For more information on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s senior executive
performance plans, see app. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V.</ENAMEX>)
Effective performance management systems
translate organizational priorities and goals into direct and
specific commitments that senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> will be expected to
achieve during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. To this end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and VBA
developed a set of expectations for senior executive performance
that were intended to balance organizational results, customer
satisfaction, and employee perspectives and offered a menu of
expectations for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to incorporate into their
individual performance plans. They appraised senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>'
contributions to organizational results by the core competencies
and supporting behaviors senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> followed or the targets
they met. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> appraised senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>'
performance against their expectations for customer satisfaction
and employee perspectives.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Balanced Expectations</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive</ENAMEX>
Performance

Organizational Results
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX>'s regulations emphasize holding senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
accountable for their individual and organizational performance by
linking individual performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> with results-oriented
organizational goals. To appraise senior executive contributions to
organizational results, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> identified core
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">competencies</ENAMEX> and supporting behaviors for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to
follow, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> also identified targets for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to
meet that are directly linked to organizational results, as shown
in table 1.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> The balanced scorecard is a tool to measure performance at
various levels of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> to help them achieve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and organizational
results.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-966</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance Management</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Examples</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s
Expectations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance</ENAMEX> in Contributing to
Organizational Results

Basis for senior executive appraisals Examples of expectations
to contribute to organizational results
Core competencies and supporting behaviors


•
Pursue business excellence through effective process
management and the application of balanced measures.


•
Learn about current and emerging issues/developments in
own field of expertise and apply knowledge to make technically
sound operational decisions.


•
Understand and plan for the condition and use of the
public lands by assuring that assessments and land use plans are
completed.


•
Improve program accountability and performance by staying
within the organizational cost targets and assuring the accuracy of
cost data.


•
Make progress in the improved use of existing automation
tools.


•
Develop and execute plans to achieve organizational
goals.


•
Develop critical business metrics to measure the overall
quality of processes and services and report results.


•
Translate strategies into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, and
individual action plans with performance measures based on the
strategic objectives and performance goals.


Targets directly linked to organizational results


•
Proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> who receive planned service and
are rehabilitated, compared with all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> who exit the
program.


•
Average number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> from date of acquisition to the
sale date of properties acquired due to defaults on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX>' guaranteed loans.


•
Average number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> from when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> begins
"employment services" status to when the veteran enters suitable
employment.


•
Percent of original and reopened compensation and pension
claims and appeals completed and determined to be technically
accurate.


•
Cost per compensation claim completed.


•
Average return on sales of acquired
properties.


Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX> guidance.
Core competencies and supporting behaviors: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
identified core competencies and supporting behaviors for senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to follow that are intended to contribute to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' achievement of performance goals. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX> set a
performance expectation for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to develop strategies
to achieve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>'s strategic objectives and performance goals. To
help meet this expectation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Field Services</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
convened the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Executive Safety Summit</ENAMEX>" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> to address
the region's highway fatality rates-the highest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>- and
their impact on FHWA achieving its goal on safety. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, including state and federal transportation and safety
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from the region, learned what each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> was doing to
decrease fatality rates and discussed how to create new safety
strategies for each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and the region as a whole. Following the
summit, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> held subsequent
state safety summits and pursued numerous initiatives to reduce
fatalities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior executive</ENAMEX> reported in his self-assessment
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX> that many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> have
experienced a reduction in the number of highway fatalities since
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Executive Safety Summit</ENAMEX>, which is helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX> meet
its goal of reducing the number of highway-related fatalities by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>.
Similarly, to address <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s performance expectation for senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to develop and execute plans to achieve organizational
goals, a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> who is the area <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for compliance
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> has a performance expectation in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX>
individual performance plan to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> affected by
the events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11, 2001</TIMEX>, are treated and audited according
to their circumstances, and that the compliance guidelines and
policy regarding affected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> are adhered to. In particular,
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>-including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>- were not to
be audited for prior tax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years before the end of March 2002</TIMEX>, if
such an audit was necessary.
To contribute to its strategic goal to restore and maintain the
health of the land, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX> set an expectation for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to
understand and plan for the condition and use of public lands. In
particular, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior executive</ENAMEX> who heads the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> had a performance expectation in her individual performance
plan for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> performance appraisal cycle to conduct land use
assessments and complete plans as scheduled for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gunnison</ENAMEX> Gorge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Conservation Area</ENAMEX>. In her self-assessment for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>
performance appraisal cycle, she stated that she began conducting
land use assessments for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gunnison Gorge</ENAMEX> and approved "pre-plans,"
which outline the anticipated schedule, budget, and stakeholder
involvement to complete a land use plan.
Targets directly linked to organizational results: VBA
identified targets with specific levels of performance for senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to meet. These targets link to the priorities in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s
balanced scorecard and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Veterans Affairs</ENAMEX>' (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>)
strategic goals. For example, to contribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>'s strategic goal
to "provide 'One <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>' world class service to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> through the effective management of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, technology,
processes and financial resources" and to address its priority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuracy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> set a national target of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72 percent</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> for the accuracy rate of original and reopened compensation
and pension claims and appeals that were completed and determined
to be technically accurate. To contribute to that national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>,
the senior executive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> had a
performance expectation for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to meet a target accuracy
rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59.2 percent</NUMEX>. Similarly, to further contribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>'s
strategic goal of world-class service and to address its priority
of speed and



<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Customer Satisfaction</ENAMEX>
timeliness, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> set a national target for property holding
time-the average number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> from date of acquisition to date
of sale of properties acquired due to defaults on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> guaranteed
loans-of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 months</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX>. To contribute to the
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>, the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior executive</ENAMEX> had a performance
expectation for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to meet a target of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8.6 months</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX>'s regulations recognize that senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> in public
sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> face the challenging task of balancing the
needs of multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, who at times may have differing or
ever competing expectations. Customer involvement is important to
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> make senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> aware of differing or competing
expectations and to then build <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> and coalitions to reach
mutual understanding of the issues. To this end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> set expectations for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to address customer
satisfaction in their individual performance plans and appraised
their performance on the basis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX>, customer feedback,
and improved products and services. Examples of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>'
expectations for customer satisfaction are shown in table 2.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Examples</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Customer</ENAMEX>
Satisfaction Expectations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance</ENAMEX>

Basis for senior executive appraisals Examples of customer
satisfaction expectations
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Partnerships • Balance</ENAMEX> a variety of federal, state, and local
interests through timely and enhanced consultation, cooperation,
and communication to build consensus.


•
Establish cooperative and constructive relationships,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, and alliances that facilitate input from a wide range of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> and external stakeholders.


•
Engage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> in alternative dispute
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> to manage and/or resolve conflicts in a positive and
constructive manner.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Customer feedback • Identify</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> needs and
measure their level of satisfaction.


•
Receive and act upon feedback from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> surveys,
listening sessions, focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and other learning
techniques.


•
Percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> giving a high rating on the
satisfaction surveys.


•
Percentage of veterans' satisfaction with the way VBA
handled their claims.


Improved products and services <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE"> Initiate</ENAMEX> actions and manage
risks to develop new products and services within or outside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>.


•
Use customer input to improve products and services to
ensure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> needs are met.


•
Act to continuously improve products and
service.


•
Percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> who get through, but hang up before
being connected to an employee.


•
Average length of time that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> waits before being
connected to the telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.


Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX> guidance.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Partnerships: Partnerships</ENAMEX> and coalitions can help senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> work collaboratively with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to ensure that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> takes into account their multiple interests and
achieves results. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> have relied on resource
advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">councils</ENAMEX> (RAC) consisting of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> with diverse
interests as a way to involve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, identify issues, and reach
a reasonable degree of consensus regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s land management
programs. To meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s expectation to establish cooperative and
constructive relationships that facilitate input from a range of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior executive</ENAMEX> who heads the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> set an expectation to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> and maintain close
working relationships with national interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in his
individual plan for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> performance appraisal cycle. This
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> solicited feedback from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Montana RAC</ENAMEX> to
discuss among his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> how to balance the ongoing, yet
potentially competing uses-including recreation, grazing, and oil
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> leases-of a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150-mile</NUMEX> stretch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Missouri River</ENAMEX> and
surrounding areas. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior executive</ENAMEX>, the RAC
recommended that ongoing uses continue, but that this stretch
receive special protection from further development. In his
self-assessment for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> performance appraisal cycle, the
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> stated that he continues to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RAC</ENAMEX> as a
highly effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that plays a significant
role in land management deliberations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Customer feedback: Customer</ENAMEX> feedback can help senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
determine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>' needs and their levels of satisfaction with
existing products and services. To hold its senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
accountable for customer satisfaction, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s
regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> had performance expectations to meet targets for
veterans giving a high rating on satisfaction surveys.
Specifically, the senior executive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> regional office
had a target in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX> to attain <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85 percent</NUMEX> in overall
satisfaction in a national survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> using vocational
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rehabilitation</ENAMEX> and employment services and support.
In addition, to address his performance expectation for customer
satisfaction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior executive</ENAMEX> who heads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> regional
office convened frequent "town hall" meetings to listen to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">veterans</ENAMEX>' needs and discuss VBA issues, such as legislative changes
that affect the processing of veterans' claims. According to this
executive, the town hall meetings helped improve his customer
satisfaction levels because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> identified the concerns that
were most important to them, gained direct access to the VBA
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> working on their benefit claims, and were better able to
understand the claims process. Specifically, the senior executive
reported in his self-assessment that during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX> he
worked with local service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to identify in advance those
veterans planning to attend the town hall meetings, had their
claims folders available for review at the meetings, and was thus
able to enhance outreach programs.
Improved products and services: Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can use the
feedback from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> to enhance the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>' understanding of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and make improvements in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s
products and services. For example, to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s performance
expectation for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to address customer satisfaction
by continuously improving products and services, a senior executive
responsible for submission processing and taxpayer assistance had a
performance expectation in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX> individual
performance plan to develop a communication plan. This plan was
intended to better serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> by helping improve their
knowledge and understanding of the tax return process.
To hold its senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> accountable for improved products
and services, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> set targets for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to achieve, such as
the abandoned telephone call rate-the percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> who get
through to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>, but are put on hold and hang up before being
connected to an employee. Specifically, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX>, the
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> had a target for
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for an abandoned telephone call rate of not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 5</NUMEX>
percent for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>' inquiries of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s benefit programs, such as
compensation and pension <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employee Perspectives OPM</ENAMEX>'s regulations
recognize that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are vital assets and people
achieve organizational goals and results. Accordingly, the
regulations call for senior executive performance plans and
appraisals to contain performance expectations on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspectives</ENAMEX>. To this end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> set expectations
for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to address employee perspectives in their
individual performance plans and appraised their performance on the
basis of the training provided to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, safe and healthy work
environment, teamwork, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> satisfaction, and fairness and
diversity. Examples of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' expectations for employee
perspectives are shown in table 3.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 3</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Examples</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perspective Expectations for Senior Executive Performance</ENAMEX>


Basis for senior executive appraisals Examples of employee
perspective expectations
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Training • Ensure</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> have the tools and training to
perform their jobs.


•
Create an environment for continuous learning and
development opportunities.


•
Ensure that plans exist and are adequately implemented to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recruit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, retain, motivate, empower, and advance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.


•
Ensure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> has skills aligned with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s
objectives.


•
Help attract and retain well-qualified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.


•
Ensure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> focuses appropriate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' needs.


Safe and healthy work environment • Provide a safe, healthy work
environment.


•
Provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and direction to identify initiatives
that improve the quality of worklife of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.


•
Commit resources to making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> workplace
friendly.


•
Create an environment conducive to performance excellence
and personal and organizational growth.


<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teamwork • Effectively</ENAMEX> use ongoing feedback and coaching to
promote cooperation, teamwork, knowledge/skill sharing, and goal
accomplishment.


•
Motivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to achieve high performance through
open and honest communication and involve them in decision
making.


•
Promote and maintain an effective labor-management
relations program that incorporates the principles of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partnership</ENAMEX>.


•
Create an environment in which knowledge is managed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX>, and used effectively.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employee</ENAMEX> satisfaction • <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX>' satisfaction with their
jobs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• Employees</ENAMEX>' overall satisfaction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.
Fairness and diversity • Take steps to implement equal
employment opportunity goals.


•
Require all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinate managers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> to
receive diversity awareness and equal opportunity
training.


•
Establish a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> tolerance standard for discrimination,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harassment</ENAMEX>, and hostile work environments.


Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX> guidance.
Training: Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> with the
necessary training and continuous developmental opportunities to
perform their jobs more effectively. To address <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s performance
expectation for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to ensure that plans exist and
are adequately implemented to recruit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, retain, motivate,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">empower</ENAMEX>, and advance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, the senior executive in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Office</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outpatient Clinic</ENAMEX>
conducted focus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to identify actions needed to respond to the
results of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> survey. One action was to task a
training <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> to develop and implement a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Training Needs</ENAMEX>
Assessment tool to determine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' training needs and to
schedule training for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior executive</ENAMEX> stated
in his selfassessment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> used the assessment tool to establish individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> plans and the training <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> has been scheduling
training sessions to ensure that individual development plans are
met.
To meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s expectation for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to help attract
and retain well-qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior executive</ENAMEX> who heads
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> set a performance expectation for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> performance appraisal cycle to maintain a trained and
motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> worked with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Resources</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development Committee</ENAMEX>, composed of representatives from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">BLM</ENAMEX> field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> meets regularly to
identify employee issues, make recommendations, and implement
actions. Specifically, with input from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, the senior
executive developed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statewide Mentoring Program</ENAMEX> to enhance and
promote opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' skill development and to
assist them in achieving their career goals. The senior executive
did not discuss the mentoring program in his self-assessment for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> performance appraisal cycle, but generally stated that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> provided training to enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and interpersonal
skills.
Safe and healthy work environment: Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can provide
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> with safe, secure, and healthful work conditions to
ensure that the workspace is conducive to effective performance. To
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">address VBA</ENAMEX>'s expectation for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to provide a safe,
healthy work environment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX>, the senior executive
who heads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manila</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Office</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outpatient</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinic</ENAMEX> worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to improve the security and safety of
the regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Specifically, to prepare the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in case
suspicious materials are received, the senior executive reviewed
and updated its emergency evacuation plan and then met with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to ensure they understood the plan's procedures and were
comfortable with their responsibilities. In addition, he worked
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Security Office</ENAMEX> to provide security awareness
training to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and held several emergency drills to test
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' responses. He stated in his self-assessment for fiscal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2001</TIMEX> that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were still concerned with security,
he believed confidence in their safety and welfare had
improved.
Teamwork: Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can encourage a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>-based approach
to help improve employee morale and job satisfaction by creating an
environment that is open to communication and has a sense of shared
responsibility for accomplishing organizational goals. To create an
environment in which knowledge is managed, shared, and used
effectively, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX> encourages its senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to use
organizational selfassessments to solicit employee perspectives and
gauge their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' work environment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX> provides sample
questions for these selfassessments that are based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm</ENAMEX>
Baldridge criteria. For example, the senior executive heading the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information and Management Services</ENAMEX> required each of her
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> to complete an organizational self-assessment in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> trained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baldridge</ENAMEX> criteria facilitated
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the half-day</TIMEX> sessions for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>. As a result of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sessions</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> consolidated the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">selfassessments</ENAMEX> and summarized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s "strengths" and
"opportunities for improvement" in a report. The report identified
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s strengths to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s support and
approval for training, and one of its opportunities for improvement
to be keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> development plans <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to date</TIMEX>.
In response, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior executive</ENAMEX> identified in her individual
performance plan a specific expectation of updating individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> plans for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 30, 2002</TIMEX>.
To meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s performance expectation for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to
motivate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to achieve high performance through open and
honest communication and involve them in decision making, a senior
executive who is the area <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for compliance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
included an expectation in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX> individual
performance plan to look for partnering opportunities to maximize
problem resolution and employee involvement, while developing and
maintaining effective relationships with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Employees Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> in his area.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employee</ENAMEX> satisfaction: Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can monitor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>'
satisfaction with their work environment to gauge if they feel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">empowered</ENAMEX> and motivated to contribute to organizational goals. For
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> in the regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> set a target for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> satisfaction that senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> were to achieve for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX>. Based on a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1-to-5</NUMEX> scale, the target was set by
estimating the average response on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> questions from the employee
satisfaction survey. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> questions ask about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>'s
satisfaction with his or her job and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>'s overall
satisfaction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> set a national
target score of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.6</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> satisfaction in the compensation
and pension services business line in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX>. All
regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> contribute to the target for this business line.
Specifically, the senior executive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> regional office
had a performance expectation for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to meet a target score
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.5</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> satisfaction.
Fairness and diversity: Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can foster fairness
and diversity by protecting the rights of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, providing
a fair dispute resolution system, and working to prevent
discrimination through equality of




Initial <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Implementation Approaches to</ENAMEX>
Manage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executives</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Performance</ENAMEX>
employment and opportunity. To meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s performance
expectation for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to establish a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> tolerance
standard for discrimination, harassment, and hostile work
environments, a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> who heads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> set an expectation in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> plan for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>
performance appraisal cycle that he would demonstrate commitment to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nondiscrimination</ENAMEX> in the workplace by ensuring fair access to
developmental opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.
While the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> tailored their performance management
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> to fit their organizational and operational needs, we
identified an initial set of implementation approaches that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> are taking that may be helpful to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
as they manage senior executive performance against balanced
expectations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and VBA


•
provide useful data,


•
require follow-up actions, and


•
make meaningful distinctions in performance.


Provide Useful Data Providing objective
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> for organizational results, customer satisfaction, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> perspectives can help senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> manage during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, identify performance gaps, pinpoint improvement
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opportunities</ENAMEX>, and compare their performance to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>.
Specifically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>


•
developed data systems so that senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can
track their individual performance against organizational results,
and


•
disaggregated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> satisfaction survey
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>.


Developed data systems: To help senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> see how they
are contributing to organizational results during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> developed data systems for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to use to track their
individual performance against organizational results. For example,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tracking System collects</ENAMEX> and makes available on a
real-time basis data on each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior executive</ENAMEX>'s progress in their
state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> towards <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>'s national priorities and the resources
expended on each priority. In particular, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX> senior executive in
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> responsible for the wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and burro adoptions
program can use the tracking system to identify where the senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> in the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are against their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> and what
the program costs have been by state. Specifically, as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> had completed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">532</NUMEX>
adoptions at a total cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$460,000</NUMEX> towards his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,150</NUMEX>
adoptions for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX>. Similarly, the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> had completed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> adoptions at a total cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$63,000</NUMEX>
towards his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> adoptions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> also developed a data system that tracks organizational and
individual performance. Its balanced scorecard data are updated
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> can access the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intranet</ENAMEX>. The balanced scorecard compares
actual performance against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> set for the national and
regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> levels. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, the scorecard
helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> understand how they can affect the results of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>. Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> refer to the balanced scorecard
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> at their leadership meetings, discuss how they performed
relative to the scorecard, and identify the causes behind
outstanding and poor performance.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disaggregated</ENAMEX> survey data: Specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and employee
feedback helps senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> pinpoint actions to improve
products and services for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and to enhance employee
satisfaction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> disaggregated the data from
agencywide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> satisfaction surveys so that the
results were applicable to a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. For example, from its Use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Authorization Survey</ENAMEX>
administered to its various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, BLM
disaggregated the survey data to provide the applicable results to
individual senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> who head the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.
Specifically, the senior executive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> state office
received data for his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> showing that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81 percent</NUMEX> of the grazing
permit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> surveyed gave a favorable rating for the
timeliness of permit processing and for service quality. In his
self-assessment for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> performance appraisal cycle, he stated
that issuing grazing permits has progressed without any problem or
backlogs and that permittees have not experienced any delays.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> disaggregates its survey results to the regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and
policy and program support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> that are larger than 15
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in order to allow the senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to determine
actions that are appropriate for their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, VBA
administered its most recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> survey to measure aspects of
organizational climate related to high performance. For each
question on the survey, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> results and the VBA
average, as well as baseline data from surveys conducted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. For example, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">47 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> surveyed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Paul</ENAMEX> regional

Require Follow-up Actions
office either strongly agreed or agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> provided
an environment that supports employee involvement, contributions,
and teamwork. According to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> survey results, this percentage
is slightly higher than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> average of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> and indicated
an improvement from the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33 percent</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> scored on this
question in both the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997 and 1999</TIMEX> employee surveys. VBA compiles a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> report of the results so that senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> can
compare how their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> scored against other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VBA</ENAMEX> as a
whole.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> disaggregates data to the workgroup level from its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS/National Treasury Employees Union Employee Satisfaction Survey</ENAMEX>,
which measures general satisfaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, the workplace, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup Organization</ENAMEX> administers this survey to all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, which is comprised of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> questions ("Q12");9
additional questions unique to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, such as views on local union
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chapters</ENAMEX> and employee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>; as well as questions on issues
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> has been tracking over time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX> provides the results for
each workgroup. For example, a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> can compare how his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">workgroup</ENAMEX> performed to other operating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> as a
whole. Specifically, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>'s workgroup scored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.68</NUMEX>
out of a possible <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> for "having the materials and equipment they
need to do their work right" compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>-wide score of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.58</NUMEX>
on the survey. To allow senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to benchmark
externally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX> compares each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">workgroup</ENAMEX>'s results to the 50th
(median) and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75th</TIMEX> (best practices) percentile scores from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Q-12</ENAMEX> database. To benchmark internally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> provides the
servicewide results from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>'s survey in each
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workgroup</ENAMEX> report.
As part of its senior executive performance management system,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FHWA</ENAMEX> require their senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to follow up on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> and employee issues. To improve customer satisfaction, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX> set an expectation that the
business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, headed by senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, develop action plans
based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> survey data that are relevant to the needs of
their particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> provided guidance to senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to help them understand and interpret the
customer survey data, identify areas for improvement, and develop
action plans to respond to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>' issues and concerns.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX> identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> questions that measure employee
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX> and, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX>, the responses to these
questions link directly to organizational outcomes.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-966</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Performance Management</ENAMEX>
For example, to address the customer satisfaction expectation in
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX> individual performance plan, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> senior
executive who is the area <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for compliance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laguna Niguel</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, requires each of his territory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to present an
action plan identifying ways to improve low scores from customer
surveys. He then rolls up these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>' plans into a consolidated
area action plan for which he is responsible. Specifically, an
expectation in his action plan is to improve how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are
treated during collection and examination activities by ensuring
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examiners</ENAMEX> explain to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> rights, as well
as why they were selected for examination and what they could
expect. Further, the senior executive plans to ensure that
territory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> solicit feedback from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> on their
treatment during these activities and identify specific reasons for
any customer dissatisfaction. In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">midyear</TIMEX> self-assessment for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior executive</ENAMEX> stated that substantial
progress is being made in achieving the collection and examination
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> satisfaction goals.
Similarly, to address employee perspectives, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> requires senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to hold workgroup meetings with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to
discuss the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workgroups</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employee Satisfaction Survey</ENAMEX> results and
develop action plans to address these results. According to a
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'s criminal investigation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workgroup</ENAMEX> meetings were beneficial because they increased
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and identified improvements in the
quality of worklife. For example, through the workgroup meetings,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> identified the need for recruiting supervisory special
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> to even out some of the workload. Subsequently, the senior
executive set an expectation in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX> individual
performance plan to ensure that the field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has a strong
recruitment program to attract viable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. He also has an
expectation to ensure his field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> hold timely workgroup
meetings and develop and implement action plans to address concerns
identified during these meetings.
To reinforce the importance of follow-up action, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> developed a
Webbased database system to track workgroup issues across <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>.
According to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, the system is being upgraded to
improve its usefulness for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and will allow them to
track their progress in completing the actions identified in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workgroup</ENAMEX> meetings. In addition, all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> will be able to
access summary information to help identify trends in the data
across workgroups. The system will also provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> with the
opportunity to share best practice information on resolved
workgroup issues.

