



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STATEMENTS OF FEDERAL FINANCIAL ACCOUNTING CONCEPTS AND</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STANDARDS</ENAMEX>

as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 28, 1997</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFAC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nos. 1-2 SFFAS Nos. 1-8 Selected Materials</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Document #</ENAMEX>


FOREWORD
This volume is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> volume set referred to as the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Codification</ENAMEX>." It contains the original text that currently
constitutes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of accounting concepts and standards for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>. Specifically, the volume incorporates the
following documents published through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 28, 1997</TIMEX>:
-- Statements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Accounting Concepts</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> &
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, and -- Statements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Accounting Standards</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8.1</NUMEX>

Origins of the Statements
The concepts and standards presented in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> volume set
resulted from the joint efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of the Treasury</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>), and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>). These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>,
referred to collectively as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>", established the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Accounting Standards Advisory Board</ENAMEX> (FASAB) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. FASAB
was created to consider and recommend accounting standards and
principles<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> ultimately decide upon the principles
and standards.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Codification</ENAMEX> includes only those principles and standards
agreed to by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX> is publishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Codification</ENAMEX>
as a comprehensive basis of accounting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> reporting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>. It is expected that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX> will continue to recommend
statements on specialized topics. As new statements and
interpretations are adopted, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Codification</ENAMEX> will be updated.


Purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Codification</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Codification of Federal</ENAMEX> accounting concepts and standards is
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> volume set with extensive cross-referencing and indexing. The
volumes are designed to meet the needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> for references to
original statements (Volume I) and to standards alphabetized by
topic (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Volume II</ENAMEX>). Both volumes serve as authoritative references
to the standards and interpretations.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
Statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Accounting Standards No. 8</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Stewardship Reporting</ENAMEX>, has been approved by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> but may not be implemented until it has
undergone a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45-day</TIMEX> review by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review</ENAMEX> was not completed
at the time this Volume was published. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFAS No. 8</ENAMEX> is provided
herein for your convenience and future use. An announcement will be
made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Register</ENAMEX> when the review has been completed and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFAS No. 8</ENAMEX> can be implemented.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
For a more extensive description of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX>'s role, refer to
Statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Accounting Concepts No. 1</ENAMEX>,
Objectives of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Reporting, Paras</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23-29</NUMEX>.
Volume I
This volume, Volume <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Accounting Concepts</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Standards-Original Statements</ENAMEX>, is a compilation of the documents
produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Accounting Standards Advisory Board</ENAMEX> and
adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
Once adopted, the documents are referred to as Statements of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Accounting Concepts</ENAMEX> (SFFAC or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concepts</ENAMEX>) and
Statements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Accounting Standards</ENAMEX> (SFFAS or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standards</ENAMEX>) respectively.
This volume presents the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Concepts</ENAMEX> in their entirety. Concepts do
not establish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> financial accounting standards; rather they
describe the concepts used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX> as a framework as it considers
and recommends accounting principles for the Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
Concepts are meant to guide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> financial
reporting such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preparers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX>.
This volume extracts the authoritative portions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standards</ENAMEX>
originally published in individual statements as well as the
explanatory text contained in any appendices. It does not reprint
the summaries or all introductory and background material since
these sections are not always essential to applying the standards
or understanding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>'s conclusions. The Basis for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>'s
Conclusions for each standard is included since it serves to
explain the specific provisions of the standards.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">glossaries</ENAMEX> originally published with each statement have
been codified in a single glossary. This glossary is presented as
the last appendix to the volume.
Volume II
Volume II of this set, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A User's Guide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial</ENAMEX>
Accounting Standards, is a codification of the standards. Volume II
presents the standards alphabetized by topic, pulls together all
references to a particular topic in one section, and integrates
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illustrative</ENAMEX> material from both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFASs</ENAMEX> and the original
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Exposures Drafts</ENAMEX> wherever possible.


Applicability
The mission of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX> is to recommend accounting concepts and
standards that result in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' financial reports
including understandable, relevant, and reliable information about
the financial position, activities, and results of operations of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> government and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component units</ENAMEX>. In addition,
the standards should foster the improvement of accounting systems
and internal controls that will help provide reasonable assurance
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> that government activities have been conducted
economically, efficiently, and effectively, and in compliance with
applicable laws and regulations. Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX> believes that
federal financial accounting concepts and standards should be
considered in establishing systems and in maintaining day-to-day
financial records as well as being applied to general purpose
financial reports of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. This
belief is consistent with the requirements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial</ENAMEX>
Management <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Improvement Act of 1996</ENAMEX> which states that "each agency
shall implement and maintain financial management systems that
comply substantially with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> financial management systems
requirements, applicable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> accounting standards, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Government Standard General Ledger</ENAMEX> at the transaction
level."<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
The specific applicability of the standards to components of the
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was considered during the development of
Statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Accounting Concepts No. 2</ENAMEX> (SFFAC No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Entity and Display</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFAC No. 2</ENAMEX> lists criteria for including
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">components</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> (see pp. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75-77</NUMEX>) and
provides the following guidance with regard to components required
by law or policy to issue financial statements prepared in
accordance with accounting standards other than those constituting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal GAAP</ENAMEX>. For example, some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> are required to apply
accounting standards issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Accounting Standards</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> or a regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> should continue to
apply the standards required by law or policy for their financial
statements. The reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> are a
part, however, need to be sensitive to differences that may arise
from the different accounting standards. If these differences are
material, the standards constituting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal GAAP</ENAMEX> should be applied
for purposes of including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>-wide statements.
In such cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> may need to provide additional
disclosures or different measurements required to comply with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal GAAP</ENAMEX>.
The standards need not be applied to immaterial items.


Hierarchy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Generally Accepted Accounting</ENAMEX>
Principles
The hierarchy of generally accepted accounting principles4
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAAP</ENAMEX>) governs what constitutes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAAP</ENAMEX> for all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government
reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> publishes the hierarchy in its bulletin
entitled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Form and Content of Agency Financial Statements</ENAMEX>. It lists
the priority sequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> should look to for
accounting and reporting guidance.
3Title <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIII</ENAMEX>--Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Financial Management Improvement Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sec.</ENAMEX> 803(a).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>"Accounting principles" are those conventions, rules, and
procedures necessary to define acceptable accounting practice at a
particular time.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, through the joint efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>, and
covering most transactions was promulgated for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
government. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> may engage in transactions that are
not addressed by these standards. In that event, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> should
view the hierarchy as providing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAAP</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Government. While many of the standards comprising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> GAAP
have already been made effective, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of those standards will not
be effective until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1998</TIMEX>. The following hierarchy5
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">determines GAAP</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> beginning in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1998</TIMEX>:


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
Individual standards agreed to by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> and
published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
Interpretations related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFASs</ENAMEX> issued by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> in
accordance with the procedures outlined in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Circular A-134</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Accounting Principles and Standards</ENAMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
Requirements contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>'s Form and Content Bulletin
in effect for the period covered by the financial
statements.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>.
Accounting principles published by authoritative standard
setting bodies and other authoritative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> (a) in the absence
of other guidance in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> parts of this hierarchy, and
(b) if the use of such accounting principles improves the
meaningfulness of the financial statements.


The above hierarchy may be implemented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier than fiscal year</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> with approval from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>. Until the above hierarchy is
effective, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> will continue to
follow the hierarchy established6 for an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Other Comprehensive Basis</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting</ENAMEX>" (OCBOA) and presented below:


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.
Individual statements agreed to and published by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFMIP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.
Form and content requirements included in OMB Bulletin
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">93-02</NUMEX>, dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 22, 1992</TIMEX>, and subsequent issuances.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>.
Accounting standards contained in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> accounting
policy, procedures manuals, and/or related guidance as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, so long as they are


5The hierarchy was published in OMB Bulletin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97-01</NUMEX> dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1996</TIMEX>.
6The hierarchy was published in OMB Bulletin <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94-01</NUMEX> dated
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 16, 1993</TIMEX>.
prevalent practices.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Accounting principles published by authoritative standard
setting bodies and other authoritative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) in the absence
of other guidance in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> parts of this hierarchy, and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) if the use of such accounting standards improve the
meaningfulness of the financial statements.


Source for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interpretations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Circular A-134</ENAMEX> describes the policies for seeking and
providing interpretations and other advice related to the
standards. An interpretation is a document of narrow scope that
provides clarifications of original meaning, additional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">definitions</ENAMEX>, or other guidance pertaining to an existing SFFAS.
Requests for interpretations should be directed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB's Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Management</ENAMEX> or to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Director</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX> will respond to the request for guidance by
providing technical assistance unless they determine that the
response should be an Interpretation. In that event, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX> staff
will provide written copies of the request to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> will examine, as appropriate, applicable literature and
consult with knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> and draft an Interpretation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Accounting Standards</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX> will consider the
draft interpretation at an open meeting. After a majority agrees
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) approve and sign the interpretation; the interpretation will
be published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>.



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization of the Codification</ENAMEX>
Volume I presents the text of the original statements as
described above. Each statement is presented as a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>.
The issue date and effective date of each statement are presented
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. Next, references to relevant sections within Volume I and to
Volume II are provided. Any interpretations that relate to the
statements are also identified.
In some cases, the statements have been affected by later
statements or affect earlier statements. References direct the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> to the affected paragraphs and indicate the source of the
change. Within the text of the statements, provisions deleted as a
result of other statements are marked with strikeouts and
provisions affected by other statements are doubleunderlined.
Double-underlined text remains as originally published. The
double-underlining is intended to alert the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to the fact that
it has been modified or affected by a later statement.
A brief summary of the statement is presented. A table of
contents referenced to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> and paragraph numbers follows the
summary. Note that the paragraph numbers are those originally
expressed in the individual statements despite the omission of some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paragraphs</ENAMEX>. Any omitted paragraphs are indicated in the table of
contents.
Volume I also presents the following appendices:

Volume II is under development at this time and will be
organized alphabetically by topic. Topics will be specific
financial statement items. Each topical section will be identified
by an alpha-numeric code (for example, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">P10</TIMEX> for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pensions"</ENAMEX>), with
numbers selected to allow addition of future topics.
Paragraphs within each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> will be numbered consecutively.
The following numeric format has been proposed:
Paragraphs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.100</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.599</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standards</ENAMEX> and Potential Note Disclosures
Paragraphs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.600</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.699</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Interpretations Published</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB Paragraphs</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.700</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.799</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nonauthoritative Discussion & Illustrations</ENAMEX>
Source references will be provided in paragraphs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.100</NUMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.599</NUMEX> to
indicate the original statement from which material was drawn. The
references will appear in brackets at the end of each paragraph or
illustration. For example, the reference [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">SFFAS 7</ENAMEX>, para. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX>] refers
to Statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Financial Accounting Standards No. 7</ENAMEX>,
Accounting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revenue</ENAMEX> and Other Financing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concepts</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reconciling Budgetary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Accounting</ENAMEX>, paragraph <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX>.
Source references will be provided in the nonauthoritative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paragraphs</ENAMEX> as footnotes to permit more descriptive identification
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.
Volume II will present the following appendices and may present
others:
-- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Topical Index -- FASAB Active and Future Projects -- Topics</ENAMEX>
Not Yet Addressed -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consolidated</ENAMEX> Glossary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TABLE OF CONTENTS</ENAMEX>
Page

























































































TRANSACTIONS WITH THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PUBLIC</ENAMEX>
Nonexchange transactions with the public
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">242</NUMEX>. Individual income taxes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> income taxes, social
insurance taxes and contributions<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,37</NUMEX> excise taxes, estate and gift
taxes, and customs duties.--Taxes (including customs duties) are
levied through the exercise of the power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> to
compel payment. In broad terms, taxes are "the price we pay for
civilization." More specifically they finance spending of many
types to promote the general welfare, provide for the common
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX>, and ensure domestic tranquillity: national defense, a
judicial system, aid to the elderly, construction of
infrastructure, education and training, and so forth. The
relationship between the tax paid and the value received is too
indirect and disproportionate to relate the revenue that is
received from any identifiable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> to the cost that is
incurred for providing that identifiable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> with benefits.
This is especially the case where the benefits are of a collective
or public nature, such as national defense, in which case
consumption by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> does not reduce the consumption
available for another; or where the benefits are designed to
redistribute income from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to another. Therefore,
tax revenue is nonexchange revenue.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">243</NUMEX>. All excise taxes, like other taxes, are classified as
resulting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nonexchange</TIMEX> revenue. Some excise taxes (considered to
be benefit taxes) are levied on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> that are related to the use
of publicly provided goods and services or the public provision of
other benefits, such as the gasoline tax; certain other excise
taxes are levied on bases related to a cause of some damage and are
dedicated to pay down costs, such as the tax on domestically mined
coal, which is dedicated to the black lung disability trust fund.
Even in these cases, however, the relationship between the tax and
the benefit received by an identifiable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> is relatively
indirect and disproportionate. Moreover, these excise taxes, like
other taxes, are determined through the exercise of the power of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> to compel payment. Therefore, like other taxes, they
are classified as producing nonexchange revenue.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">244</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have differing views on whether social
insurance programs result in exchange or nonexchange
transactions<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.38</NUMEX> However, they agree that social insurance tax
revenue should be reported in the same way as other tax revenue for
the purposes of financial reporting. This is because social
insurance taxes, like other taxes, are determined through the
exercise of the power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> to compel payment.
Furthermore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> subject to social insurance
taxes are subject to them as a byproduct of their decision to enter
covered employment or engage in a covered business, so especially
for the major, broad-based social insurance programs--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> (hospital insurance), and unemployment
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Social</ENAMEX> insurance" does not include programs established
solely or primarily for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, such as pension and
other retirement plans. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> insurance" taxes and contributions
do, however, include payments made by or on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> to social insurance plans, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>.
38See discussion of social insurance programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FASAB</ENAMEX>, Exposure
Draft, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Stewardship Reporting</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1995</TIMEX>).
compensation--they have virtually no legal option except to
pay.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">245</NUMEX>. Tax receipts are generally collected from the public by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX>) and, to a lesser extent, by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> acting as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for the
recipient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> rather than on their own behalf. The collecting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">entity</ENAMEX> receives the cash and then transfers it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Fund</ENAMEX>,
trust <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>, or special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> on whose behalf it was collected. The
amount so collected should be accounted for as a custodial activity
by the collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>. The tax is recognized as a nonexchange
revenue by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that is legally entitled to the amount. This
would be a trust fund or special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> in the case of an earmarked
(i.e., dedicated) tax. If collected on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> as
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a whole</TIMEX>, it would be recognized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>-wide consolidated
financial statements.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">246</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> insurance taxes and contributions paid by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">.39</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> may be covered by social insurance
programs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Security40</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> under the same
terms and conditions as the remainder of the covered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
The payments made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are in the nature of taxes,
compulsory payments demanded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> through the exercise
of its power to compel payment. Insofar as the social insurance
program applies to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, the
terms and conditions are generally the same as the program for
private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> and employee contributions are
generally calculated in the same way; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> contribution is
not earned by the social insurance program; and the benefits are
generally calculated in the same way. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> does not obtain
particular benefits under the plan from rendering service in
Federal employment, because he or she would have been similarly
covered by the program if privately employed and would have
obtained similar benefits. For these reasons, the employee
contribution should have the same classification as contributions
by non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, which is nonexchange revenue.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">247</NUMEX>. Deposits by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> for unemployment trust fund.--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States</ENAMEX>
deposit the receipts from the state unemployment tax to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> for the unemployment trust fund in order to finance most
of the benefits under the unemployment compensation system. The
state unemployment tax differs from state to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in terms of the
tax rate, tax base, and certain other characteristics, and
unemployment benefits also differ from state to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
Nevertheless, the deposit has long been construed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
budget receipt (a governmental receipt), and the unemployment trust
fund has long been included as an account in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">248</NUMEX>. This is for a combination of reasons taken together: (a)
the unemployment compensation system--including the system of
taxes, the system of benefits, and the trust fund--was established
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX> and has been amended by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
law many times; (b) deposits are held in a trust fund operated by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>; (c) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> law specifies extensive
requirements for the state unemployment tax and unemployment
benefits; (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) the Federal unemployment tax finances grants to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to cover their entire cost of administering the
unemployment
39
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> insurance" does not include programs established solely
or primarily for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, such as pension and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retirement</ENAMEX> plans.
40
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> hired before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> are not
covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>.
system; and (e) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> law effectively coerces <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to
participate in the system, with participation requiring them to
levy the state unemployment tax and deposit the collections in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Treasury</ENAMEX>. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> does not participate (or is not certified
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Labor</ENAMEX> as meeting Federal requirements): (i)
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> unemployment tax is levied within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> at its
maximum rate, (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ii</ENAMEX>) the system does not pay any unemployment
compensation benefits within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">iii</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Government provides no grants to state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to pay for the
costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. The deposits of the state tax are
therefore nonexchange revenue of the unemployment trust fund. (The
Federal unemployment tax is levied and collected separately from
the state unemployment tax.)
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">249</NUMEX>. User fees, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Harbor Maintenance</ENAMEX> trust fund. --This is an
example of a tax that is termed a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fee" by law while
classified in the budget as a governmental receipt together with
other taxes and duties. It is an ad valorem tax of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.125 percent</NUMEX>
imposed on commercial cargo loaded and unloaded at specified <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ports</ENAMEX> open to public navigation. The receipt is earmarked to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Harbor Maintenance</ENAMEX> trust fund. It is similar in nature to other
excise taxes that result from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s power to compel
payment and that are dedicated to a trust fund or special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> to
be spent for a designated purpose (for example, the gasoline excise
tax, which is dedicated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highway Trust Fund</ENAMEX>). It therefore
should be recognized as nonexchange revenue by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harbor</ENAMEX>
Maintenance trust fund.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX> fees.--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX> collects revenue
primarily from duties on imported merchandise but also from two
types of fees: the merchandise processing fee and a group of fees
called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees."
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">251</NUMEX>. The merchandise processing fee is primarily an ad valorem
charge on formal merchandise entries into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> (at
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.19 percent</NUMEX>) subject to a maximum and minimum charge. It also
includes flat fees on informally entered goods. The collections are
earmarked by law to a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> from which receipts are made
available to finance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> to the extent
provided by current appropriations.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">252</NUMEX>. The merchandise processing fee is associated with the cost
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX>'s operations. The fee as originally enacted
was modified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Customs and Trade Act of 1990</ENAMEX> to make it
consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> obligations under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GATT</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Agreement</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tariffs and Trade</ENAMEX>) after a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GATT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> had ruled that the
original fee (a straight ad valorem fee) exceeded the cost of
services rendered and was a tax on imports that discriminated
against imports in favor of domestic production. The maximum and
minimum fees and the flat fees were enacted to meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
obligation.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">253</NUMEX>. However, the associated cost is primarily some of the costs
of assessing and collecting duties on imported merchandise, such as
the salaries of import <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> (who classify merchandise) and
the costs of processing paperwork. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">importer</ENAMEX> pays duties that
are required by law; it does not receive anything of value from the
Government in the nature of an exchange. Furthermore, these costs
are not likely to depend significantly on the value of the
merchandise, and the fee is levied through the power of the
Government to compel payment. Therefore, for the purpose of a
classification system for financial reporting, the fee is akin to
dedicated taxes that are also related in the aggregate to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> costs and that are classified as nonexchange revenue
(e.g., the excise tax on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline</ENAMEX>). The merchandise processing fee
is therefore classified as a nonexchange revenue.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">254</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees consist of a group of flat fees charged on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and conveyances entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.41 The collections
are dedicated by law to a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> whose receipts are made
available by permanent indefinite appropriation to finance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">255</NUMEX>. These fees are intended to offset certain inspection costs
that relate to the processing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and conveyances
entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. They are levied through the power of the
Government to compel payment, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that pays
these fees does not receive anything of value from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
in exchange. The inspection activities are for a variety of
purposes: to ensure that dutiable merchandise is declared, to seize
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contraband</ENAMEX> (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX> and illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>), to detect
infringements of patent and copyright laws, and so forth. Some of
these purposes are related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s powers to raise
taxes, which are nonexchange revenue, and to enforce laws. Only to
a limited extent are they like regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees, based on the
Government's power to regulate particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> or activities.
Therefore, like the merchandise processing fee, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees are
classified as nonexchange revenue.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">256</NUMEX>. Deposits of earnings, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve System</ENAMEX>.--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve System</ENAMEX> consists of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Governors of the Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve System</ENAMEX> and twelve regional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Banks</ENAMEX>. Under
Federal accounting concepts, it is not considered to be part of the
Government-wide reporting entity. Therefore, payments made to or
collections received from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve System</ENAMEX> would be
reported in the financial statements of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Government</ENAMEX> and
its component reporting entities<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.42</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> earns large
amounts of interest on its portfolio of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> securities and
deposits to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> all net income after deducting dividends
and the amount necessary to bring the surplus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Banks</ENAMEX> to the level of capital paid-in.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">257</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> was established by <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
pursuant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s sovereign power over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
money, and its investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> securities is necessary for
carrying out its monetary function. It does not receive anything of
value from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> in exchange for its deposit of earnings,
and on occasion it has been required by law to make extra payments.
The revenue from the deposits is therefore nonexchange.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">258</NUMEX>. Donations: except types of property, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, and equipment
that are expensed.--Donations are contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">i.e.</ENAMEX>, voluntary gifts of resources to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government entity</ENAMEX> by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">non-Federal</ENAMEX> entity<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.43</NUMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> does not give anything of
value to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> receives only personal
satisfaction. The donation
41These fees are sometimes called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COBRA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees." This
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, which established these fees.
42SFFAC <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No. 2, Entity and Display</ENAMEX>, para. 47.
43
The term "donations" includes wills disposing of property and
judicial proceedings other than forfeitures.
of cash, other financial resources, or nonfinancial resources
(except stewardship property, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, and equipment) is therefore a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonexchange</ENAMEX> revenue.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">259</NUMEX>. The exception, stewardship <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX>, consists of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission PP&E</ENAMEX>, heritage assets, and stewardship land. Such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> is expensed if purchased, but no amount is recognized if
it is received as a donation<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Correspondingly</ENAMEX>, no revenue is
recognized for such donations.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fines</ENAMEX> and penalties.--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fines</ENAMEX> and penalties are monetary
requirements imposed on those who violate laws or administrative
rules. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that pays a fine or penalty does
not receive anything of value in exchange, nor does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
sacrifice anything of value. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> collects these amounts
through the exercise of its power to compel payment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fines</ENAMEX> and
penalties are therefore a nonexchange revenue.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">261</NUMEX>. Fines from judicial proceedings are collected by the entity
acting as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> as a whole rather than on its
own behalf. They are therefore accounted for as a custodial
activity of the collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> and recognized as a nonexchange
revenue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>-wide consolidated financial
statements.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">262</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fines</ENAMEX> and penalties produced by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>'s
operations--such as inspections to ensure compliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
law and with regulations that are the responsibility of the entity
(e.g., inspections by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Surface Mining</ENAMEX>) or compliance
with regulations for the conduct of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> program--are
recognized as nonexchange revenue by whichever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> is legally
entitled by law to the revenue. In some cases, but not all, this
would be the collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>. If the collecting entity transfers
the nonexchange revenue to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Fund</ENAMEX> or another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>, the
amount is accounted for as a custodial activity by the collecting
entity. If transferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Fund</ENAMEX>, the penalties are
recognized as nonexchange revenue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>-wide
consolidated financial statements; if transferred to another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entity</ENAMEX>, they are recognized as nonexchange revenue by the entity
that receives the transfer.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">263</NUMEX>. Penalties due to delinquent taxes in connection with
custodial activity.--The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or other private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that pays a
penalty on delinquent taxes does not receive anything in exchange,
nor does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> sacrifice anything of value. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>
collects these amounts through its power to compel payment.
Penalties on delinquent taxes are therefore a nonexchange revenue.
The penalties are accounted for as a custodial activity. If
transferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Fund</ENAMEX>, the penalties are recognized as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonexchange</ENAMEX> revenue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>-wide consolidated financial
statements; if transferred to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>, they are recognized
as nonexchange revenue by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that receives the
transfer.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">264</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Forfeitures.</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Property</ENAMEX> may be seized as a consequence of
various laws and regulations and forfeited to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forfeited</ENAMEX> property may be acquired through forfeiture proceedings,
be acquired to satisfy a tax liability, or consist of unclaimed and
abandoned merchandise. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forfeited</ENAMEX> property is principally managed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asset Forfeiture Fund</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Forfeiture Fund</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>. Revenue is
recognized from forfeited property unless the property is
distributed to state or local law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or
foreign
44SFFAS <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No.6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting for Property</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plant</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equipment</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">para</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61 and 71</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> or is received in satisfaction of a previously
recognized revenue (e.g., accrued tax receivables)<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.45</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">265</NUMEX>. The timing of revenue recognition depends on how the
property is forfeited and the nature of the property. In the case
of unclaimed and abandoned merchandise, revenue is recognized in
the amount of the sales proceeds at the time the property is sold.
In the case of property acquired through forfeiture proceedings,
the timing of recognition depends on the nature and disposition of
the property. For monetary instruments, the revenue is recognized
at the time of obtaining forfeiture judgment; for property that is
sold, at the time of sale; and for property that is held for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> use or transferred to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, at the time
of obtaining approval to use the property internally or transfer
it.46
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">266</NUMEX>. The method of measuring revenue depends on the nature of
the property. The amount of revenue recognized for monetary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">instruments</ENAMEX> is the market value when the forfeiture judgment is
obtained. For property that is sold, it is the sales proceeds. For
property that is held for internal use or transferred to another
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, it is the fair value of the property less a
valuation allowance for any liens or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> claims.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">267</NUMEX>. The revenue from forfeiture is nonexchange revenue, because
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> seizes the property through the exercise of its
power. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> does not sacrifice anything of value in
exchange and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that forfeits the property does not receive
anything of value. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than half</NUMEX> of the forfeiture revenue of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> funds mentioned above is from currency and other monetary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">instruments</ENAMEX>. Although other types of forfeited property must be
sold in order to recognize revenue, or constructively sold (if
transferred to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or placed into internal use),
this is the last step in a process that is inherently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonexchange</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">268</NUMEX>. The disposition of the revenue from forfeiture is
determined by law. Revenue or the property itself may ultimately be
distributed to the seizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>, state or local law enforcement
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, or the general fund. Revenue is
recognized as nonexchange revenue by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that is legally
entitled to use the revenue or to use the property itself. If the
property is distributed to a state or local law enforcement agency
or a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, revenue is not recognized by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Government reporting entity. If the revenue is transferred to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Fund</ENAMEX>, it is recognized as nonexchange revenue in the
Government-wide consolidated financial statements.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">269</NUMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> may be involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and
liquidation of forfeited property but not themselves be entitled to
the revenue or to the use of the property. For example, a central
fund created to support the seizure activities of multiple
entities
45This amends <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFAS No. 3</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting for Inventory and Related</ENAMEX>
Property, with respect to forfeitures related to satisfying tax
liabilities.
46
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFAS No. 3</ENAMEX>, para. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">57-78</NUMEX>. The standard also requires deferred
revenue to be recognized when a forfeiture judgment is obtained,
but the deferred revenue is reversed when revenue is recognized.
The amount of revenue ordinarily differs from the amount of
deferred revenue. In some cases, an adjustment subsequent to the
original forfeiture judgment may be necessary when it is later
determined that a portion of the forfeiture is to be distributed to
state or local law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>.
may manage forfeited property and the collection and disposition
of the revenue from that property. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> should account
for the property as a custodial activity. Revenue is shown when it
is recognized, and it is shown as transferred to others when the
cash is disbursed or the property is delivered. The disposition of
property to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Government</ENAMEX> is also
accounted for.
Exchange transactions with the public: revenue
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">270</NUMEX>. Sales of goods and services.--The cost of production for
goods and services such as electricity, mail delivery, and maps is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defrayed</ENAMEX> in whole or in part by revenue from selling the goods or
services provided. The sales may be made by a public enterprise
revolving fund (such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonneville Power Administration</ENAMEX>), an
intragovernmental revolving fund (such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Printing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>), or a fund that is not a revolving fund (such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geological Survey</ENAMEX>). Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> receives and sacrifices something of
value. The sale is therefore an exchange transaction, and the
revenue is exchange revenue for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> making the sale.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">271</NUMEX>. Sales of goods and services in undercover operations.--The
cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> is defrayed in whole
or in part from the proceeds of sales of goods that have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">purchased</ENAMEX> (as opposed to goods that have been forfeited). Each
party receives and sacrifices something of value. These
characteristics of the transaction are not affected by whether the
sale is illegal. The sale is therefore an exchange transactions,
and the revenue is exchange revenue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> making the
sale.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">272</NUMEX>. Interest (unless classified elsewhere), dividends, and
rents (except for mineral rights) on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> property.--Each
party receives and sacrifices something of value, so the inflow of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> is an exchange transaction.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">273</NUMEX>. Interest is classified as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> revenue notwithstanding
the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> may not be charged a cost of capital for
the assets that yield these inflows; or, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> borrowed
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> to acquire the assets, it may have been charged a
below-market interest rate. The gross cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> is
understated in such cases; and to recognize an exchange revenue is
to recognize a revenue without some or all of the related costs,
and hence to understate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>'s net cost of operations.
Nevertheless, in some cases the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> does pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> at
least some interest; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s cost of borrowing to
acquire the assets is recognized as a cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> as a
whole. Since some cost is recognized, even if not always the full
cost of the entity<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,47</NUMEX> an exchange revenue is recognized for the
entity that receives the inflow of interest.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">274</NUMEX>. Rents, royalties, and bonuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outer Continental Shelf</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCS</ENAMEX>) and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">petroleum</ENAMEX> and mineral rights.--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rents</ENAMEX>, royalties,
and bonuses are exchange revenues, because each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> receives and
sacrifices something of value. The amounts are earned by sales in
the market and therefore are exchange revenue. They are collected
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minerals Management Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMS</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>, which
47
The partial recognition of associated cost distinguishes
interest from rents, royalties, and bonuses on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental Shelf</ENAMEX> and the auction of the radio spectrum. For the
latter transactions, see the subsequent paragraphs.
manages the energy and minerals resources on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCS</ENAMEX> and
collects the amounts due the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">minerals</ENAMEX> produced on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OCS</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
lands.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMS</ENAMEX> does not recognize a depletion cost for various
reasons, including the fact that under present accounting standards
natural resources are not recognized as an asset and depletion is
not recognized as a cost. As a result, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> revenue bears
little relationship to the recognized cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMS</ENAMEX> and cannot be
matched against its gross cost of operations. Therefore, although
the inflows are exchange revenue, they should not be subtracted
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMS</ENAMEX>'s gross cost in determining its net cost of
operations.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">276</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMS</ENAMEX> should instead account for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> revenue as a
custodial activity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMS</ENAMEX> collects rents, royalties, and bonuses
acting as an agent on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> designated by law:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Fund</ENAMEX>, certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> to which
amounts are earmarked, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> and allottees.
The amounts of revenue should be recognized and measured under the
exchange revenue standards when they are due pursuant to the
contractual agreement.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">277</NUMEX>. The rents, royalties, and bonuses transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Fund</ENAMEX>, or to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>,
should be recognized by them as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> revenue. However, neither
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> as a whole nor the other recipient entities
recognize the natural resources as an asset and depletion as a
cost. Therefore, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> revenue should not offset their
gross cost in determining their net cost of operations. It should
instead be a financing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> in determining their operating
results and change in net position.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">278</NUMEX>. Proceeds from the auction of the radio spectrum.--The
proceeds from auctioning the right to use the radio spectrum are
exchange revenues, because each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> receives and sacrifices
something of value. The amount of revenue is earned by sales in the
market at auctions. It bears little relationship to the costs
collects the revenue, or to the costs recognized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Government as a whole. Therefore, it should not be offset against
the costs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> in determining its net cost of operations or
against the costs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> as a whole in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>-wide
consolidated financial statements.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">279</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> should therefore account for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> revenue
as a custodial activity, acting as an agent on behalf of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Fund</ENAMEX>; and it should be included as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> revenue in the
Government-wide consolidated financial statements.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">280</NUMEX>. Interest on post-199148 direct loans<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.49</NUMEX>--Interest on direct
loans is an exchange transaction, because it is part of a broader
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exchange</ENAMEX> transaction in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> makes a loan to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrower</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrower</ENAMEX> each receives and sacrifices
something of value. Interest on direct loans that are budgeted
according to the provisions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Credit Reform Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> components: the nominal interest (the stated
interest rate times the nominal principal) and the amortized
interest (change in present value of the loans receivable due to
the passage of time). The combined effect of these components
equals the effective interest, which is directly defined as the
present value of the loans receivable times the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> interest
rate applicable to the particular loans (i.e., the interest rate
used to calculate the present value of the direct loans when the
direct loans were disbursed). The effective interest causes an
equal increase in the aggregate value of the assets on the balance
sheet, and therefore the effective interest is the amount
recognized as exchange
50
revenue.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">281</NUMEX>. Interest on delinquent taxes and other receivables that
arise as the result of custodial operations.--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Receivables</ENAMEX> that
arise as the result of custodial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> are custodial (or
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>) assets, held by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> or another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> as an agent
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> as a whole rather than on its own behalf (e.g.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> tax receivables on which the delinquent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> must pay
interest). The interest is an exchange revenue, because each party
receives and sacrifices something of value, but it is not related
to the costs incurred by the collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>. The interest is
accounted for as a custodial activity by the collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>. If
transferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Fund</ENAMEX>, the interest is recognized as
exchange revenue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>-wide consolidated financial
statements because it is related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s cost of
borrowing; if transferred to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>, it is recognized as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonexchange</ENAMEX> revenue by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that receives the transfer.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">282</NUMEX>. Regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees such as patent and copyright fees;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immigration</ENAMEX> and consular fees; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> registration and filing fees;
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuclear Regulatory Commission</ENAMEX> fees.--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regulatory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees are
charges based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s power to regulate particular
businesses or activities. The revenue is related to the cost in one
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. Special benefits may be provided to identifiable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> who pay the fees, beyond the benefits, if any, that
accrue to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> (e.g., passport fees); or the
Government may incur costs in order to regulate an identifiable
entity for the benefit of the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> or some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
in which case the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> charge compensates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> for its
regulatory costs that were caused by the activity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that
pays the charge (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nuclear Regulatory Commission</ENAMEX>
fees).
48
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Post-1991</ENAMEX> direct loans consist of direct loans that were
obligated after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 30, 1991</TIMEX>, whereas pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> direct loans
consist of direct loans that were obligated before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1, 1991</TIMEX>.
The same accounting that is used for post-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> direct loans is also
used for pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> direct loans that were modified and transferred
to financing accounts; loans receivable arising from defaulted
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">post-1991</ENAMEX> guaranteed loans; and loans receivable arising from
defaulted pre-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1992</NUMEX> guaranteed loans that were modified and
transferred to financing accounts.
49
For interest on pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> direct loans, see the preceding section
on "interest (unless classified elsewhere) . . ."
50See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFAS No. 2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting for Direct Loans and Loan</ENAMEX>
Guarantees, paragraphs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30-31 and 37</NUMEX>; for an illustrative case
study, also see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Appendix B.</ENAMEX>
Because in general the revenue is closely related to the cost of
operations, these fees are classified as exchange transactions and
the revenue is an exchange revenue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that charges the
fee.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">283</NUMEX>. Diversion fees, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>.--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Registrants</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diversion Control Program</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>) pay fees to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enforcement Administration</ENAMEX>, in exchange for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX> provides
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">registrants</ENAMEX> with the authority to prescribe controlled
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX>. The diversion fees are intended to cover the costs of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diversion Control Program</ENAMEX>. Because the revenue is related to
the cost and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">registrants</ENAMEX> both receive and sacrifice value, the
payment of these fees is an exchange revenue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diversion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control Program</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">284</NUMEX>. Premiums for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMI</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Medical Insurance</ENAMEX>), bank
deposit insurance, pension benefit guarantees, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> insurance, life
insurance, and other insurance.--In exchange for a premium and
other considerations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> promises to make payments to
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> if specified events occur. The premium offsets
the cost of the program in whole or in part. The degree to which
participation is voluntary differs from program to program. Because
the revenue is related to the cost of the providing service, it is
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> revenue of the insurance program.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">285</NUMEX>. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> contributions to pension and other
retirement benefit plans<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.51</NUMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Government</ENAMEX>
provide service to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> in exchange for compensation, of
which some is received currently (the salary) and some is deferred
(pensions, retirement health benefits, and other retirement
benefits). This is an exchange transaction, because each party
sacrifices value and receives value in return. As part of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exchange</ENAMEX> transaction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> promises a pension to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> after they retire. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> also promises other
retirement benefits, notably health benefits. In return, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> provides services and, under some plans, makes a
contribution to the retirement fund out of his or her salary. The
financing of these benefits may include contributions paid by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> to the retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">286</NUMEX>. In broad terms, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> contribution is an inflow of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> to the retirement fund as part of this exchange
transaction. More narrowly, it is a payment by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> as part
of an exchange of money and services for a future pension or other
retirement benefit. Therefore, it is an exchange revenue of the
entity that administers the retirement plan and thus is an offset
to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>'s gross cost in calculating its net cost of
operations<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.52</NUMEX>
51Federal employee retirement plans do not include social
insurance, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>.
52For further discussion of the accounting standards for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pensions</ENAMEX> and other retirement benefits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFAS No. 5</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Liabilities of the Federal Government</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">para</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">56-93 and 148-181.</TIMEX> The standards do not cover accounting for
the plan per se as distinct from the administering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>. Nor do
they cover defined contribution plans, or administrative entities
that are not Federal reporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">287</NUMEX>. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> contributions to health benefits plan for
current coverage.--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Employees</ENAMEX> of the Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> provide
services to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> in exchange for compensation, of which
some is received currently in the form of money (the salary); some
is received currently in the form of payments to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer entity</ENAMEX> contribution to the medical insurance plan for
current coverage of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>); and some is deferred (pensions
and other retirement benefits). This is an exchange transaction,
because each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> sacrifices value and receives value in return.
As part of this exchange transaction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> both contribute to a medical insurance plan that provides
current coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">288</NUMEX>. In broad terms, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> contribution out of his or her
salary is an inflow of resources to the health benefits plan as
part of this exchange transaction. More narrowly, it is a payment
in exchange for current coverage by a health benefits plan.
Therefore, it is an exchange revenue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that administers
the health benefits plan and thus is an offset to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>'s
gross cost in calculating its net cost of operations.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">289</NUMEX>. Reimbursement for collecting revenue.--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX>
collects duties on goods imported by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> and the Virgin
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islands</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX> retains an amount equal to the
estimated cost of collecting these duties, including all costs of
operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin Islands</ENAMEX> and an allocation
of overhead; it transfers the remainder to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>, which, in
turn, transfers the collections to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> or the Virgin
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Islands</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">290</NUMEX>. The total amount of duties collected on these goods should
be accounted for as a custodial activity by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX>.
Notwithstanding that duties are a nonexchange revenue, these
particular duties are a nonexchange revenue of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> other than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and therefore are not recognized as a nonexchange
revenue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">291</NUMEX>. The method of disposing of these collections combines two
distinct transactions into one. The entire amount of the duties
could be transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin Islands</ENAMEX>, and
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> could then pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX> to reimburse
it for its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of collecting duties. The payment to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX>
would be exchange revenue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs Service</ENAMEX>. The actual
procedure for reimbursement, whereby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX> retains an amount
equal to the estimated cost, is simpler but equivalent in
substance. Hence, the custodial transfer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> (for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rico</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin Islands</ENAMEX>) and the amount retained by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX>
should be shown as separate components of the disposition of the
revenue from customs duties. The amount retained by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX> to
reimburse itself for its costs is exchange revenue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX>
Service and is offset against its gross cost in calculating its net
cost of operations.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">292</NUMEX>. Reimbursement for cleanup costs.--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX> or other
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> may incur costs to clean up environmental hazards
caused by private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and, in some cases, require these private
parties to reimburse it for the costs incurred. Notwithstanding
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> demands the revenue under its power to compel
payment, the revenue arises from the action of the private parties
and is closely related to the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> incurred as a
result of that action. Therefore, the revenue is an exchange
revenue of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> that incurs the cost.
Exchange transactions with the public: gains and losses
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">293</NUMEX>. Note: As explained in the introduction to this appendix,
transactions that are classified as producing gains or losses
should instead be classified as producing revenue or expense if
they are usual and recurring for a particular reporting entity.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">294</NUMEX>. Sales of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX> assets: other than property, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX> and forfeited and foreclosed property.--The sale of
Government assets (other than property, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, and equipment and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forfeited</ENAMEX> and foreclosed property) is an exchange transaction,
because each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> receives and sacrifices something of value. If
the sales price equals book value, there is no gain or loss,
because a cash inflow equal to book value is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of one
asset for another of equal recorded value and therefore not a net
inflow of resources. If the sales price is more or less than the
book value of the property, a gain or loss, respectively, is
recognized to the extent of the difference. The amount of the
difference between sales price and book value is ordinarily a gain
or loss rather than a revenue or expense, because sales of property
are ordinarily an unusual or nonrecurring inflow of resources.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">295</NUMEX>. Sales of property, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, and equipment.-- The transaction
is an exchange transaction, because each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> receives and
sacrifices something of value. If the sales <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">price53</TIMEX> equals book
value, there is no gain or loss, because a cash inflow equal to
book value is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> asset for another of equal
recorded value and therefore not a net inflow of resources. If the
sales price is more or less than book value, a gain or loss,
respectively, is recognized to the extent of the difference. The
amount of the difference is ordinarily a gain or loss rather than a
revenue or an expense, because sales of property, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, and
equipment are ordinarily an unusual or nonrecurring inflow of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">296</NUMEX>. The entire sales price is a gain if the book value of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asset</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>. The book value is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> (a) if the asset is general
property, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, and equipment (PP&E) that is fully depreciated
or written-off or (b) if the asset is stewardship <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX>, for
which the entire cost is expensed when the asset is
purchased<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.54</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">297</NUMEX>. Acquisition of property, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, and equipment through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exchange</ENAMEX>.--The cost of property, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, and equipment (PP&E)
acquired through an exchange of assets with the public is the fair
value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> surrendered at the time of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>. If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> acquired is more readily determinable
than that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> surrendered, the cost is the fair value
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> acquired. If neither fair value is determinable,
the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> acquired is the cost recorded for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PP&E</ENAMEX> surrendered net of any accumulated depreciation or
amortization. In the event that cash consideration is included in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> acquired is increased (or
53
The sales price may include the fair value of items received in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exchange</ENAMEX>.
54SFFAS <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting for Property</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plant</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equipment</ENAMEX>,
has divided property, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>, and equipment (PP&E) into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
basic categories: general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">PP&E</ENAMEX> and stewardship <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> (which
consists of federal mission <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX>, heritage assets, and
stewardship land). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General PP&E</ENAMEX> is capitalized and recognized
on the balance sheet; stewardship <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> is expensed and thus has
no book value. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewardship PP&E</ENAMEX> is presented in a stewardship
statement.)
decreased) by the amount of the cash surrendered (or
received).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">298</NUMEX>. Any difference between the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> acquired
and the book value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> surrendered is recognized as a
gain or loss.55 It is a gain or loss rather than a revenue or
expense, because ordinarily the amount would be an unusual or
nonrecurring inflow of resources.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">299</NUMEX>. If the fair value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> acquired is less than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> surrendered, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> acquired is
recognized at its cost and subsequently reduced to its fair value.
The difference between the cost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PP&E</ENAMEX> acquired and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fair</ENAMEX> value is recognized as a loss<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.56</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>. Sales of foreclosed property: associated with pre-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1992</NUMEX>
direct loans and loan guarantees.--Foreclosed property associated
with pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> direct loans and loan guarantees is recognized as an
asset at net realizable value. The sale is an exchange transaction,
and any difference between the sales proceeds and book value is
recognized as a gain or loss<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.57</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">301</NUMEX>. Sales of receivables: except direct loans.--The transaction
is an exchange transaction, because each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> receives and
sacrifices something of value. Upon sale, any difference between
the sales proceeds and book value is recognized as a gain or loss.
If the sales price equals book value, there is no gain or loss,
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> asset for another of equal value is not
a net inflow of resources.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">302</NUMEX>. Sales of direct loans.--The sale of a direct loan is a
modification according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990</ENAMEX>,
regardless of whether the loan being sold was obligated after FY
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> or before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. The book value loss (or gain) on a sale of
direct loans equals the book value of the loans sold (prior to
sale) minus the net proceeds of the sale. It normally differs from
the cost of modification, which is recognized as an expense<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.58</NUMEX> Any
difference between the book value loss (or gain) and the cost of
modification is recognized as a gain or loss<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.59</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">303</NUMEX>. Retirement of debt securities prior to maturity.--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Debt</ENAMEX>
securities may be retired prior to maturity if they have a call
feature or if they are eligible for redemption by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> on
demand. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bonds issued before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> are callable;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> bonds, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> account series, the foreign series,
and the state and local series
55See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFAS No. 6</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting for Property</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plant</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equipment</ENAMEX>, para. 32.
56Ibid<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">.</ENAMEX>, footnote <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>.
57See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFAS No. 3</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting for Inventory and Related</ENAMEX>
Property, para. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79-91</NUMEX>.
58
This difference is due to the different interest rates used to
discount future cash flows for calculating the subsidy cost (and
subsidy allowance) when the loan is made and for calculating the
cost of modification at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a later time</TIMEX>. If the sale is with recourse,
the present value of the estimated loss from the recourse is also
recognized as an expense.
59See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SFFAS No. 2</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting for Direct Loans and Loan</ENAMEX>
Guarantees, para. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53-55</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Appendix B, Part II</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B</ENAMEX>).
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> securities are redeemable on demand, although
sometimes with a penalty or other adjustment or only after a
specified period of time.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">304</NUMEX>. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> receives and sacrifices something of value in
buying and selling debt securities that may be retired prior to
maturity. The sales price reflects such features. Therefore, the
transaction is an exchange transaction. The difference, if any,
between the reacquisition price and the net carrying value of the
extinguished debt is recognized as a loss or gain<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.60</NUMEX>
Other financing sources from the public
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">305</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seigniorage</ENAMEX>.--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seigniorage</ENAMEX> is the face value of newly minted
coins less the cost of production (which includes the cost of the
metal, manufacturing, and transportation). It results from the
sovereign power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> to directly create money and,
although not an inflow of resources from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, does increase
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>'s net position in the same manner as an inflow of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>. Because it is not demanded, earned, or donated, it is an
other financing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> rather than revenue. It should be recognized
as an other financing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> when coins are delivered to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Banks</ENAMEX> in return for deposits.
INTRAGOVERNMENTAL TRANSACTIONS
Nonexchange transactions--intragovernmental: revenue
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">306</NUMEX>. Interest on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> securities held by trust funds and
special <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">funds</NUMEX> (except trust revolving funds).--Many trust funds and
special funds hold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> securities on which they receive
interest. In most cases the invested balances of these funds derive
predominantly from the funds' earmarked taxes, which are
nonexchange transactions with the public (e.g., employment taxes
and gasoline taxes), and to a lesser extent from other financing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> received from other government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> (e.g., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
Fund payment appropriated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supplementary Medical Insurance</ENAMEX>
fund). The balances are not earned in exchange transactions by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entity</ENAMEX>'s operations. Most fundamentally, they are not produced by
operations in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> incurs a cost.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">307</NUMEX>. Therefore, in such cases, the interest on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
securities should not be deducted from the gross costs of the trust
fund (or special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>), or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in which it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">administered</ENAMEX>, in determining its net cost of operations. As a
result, that interest should not be classified as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> revenue.
It should instead have the same classification as the predominant
source of the invested balances, which for most trust funds (and
special <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">funds</NUMEX>) is nonexchange revenue. The interest received from
invested balances of trust funds and special <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">funds</NUMEX> (except trust
revolving funds) is therefore normally a nonexchange revenue.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">308</NUMEX>. The source of balances for some trust funds and special
funds may not be predominantly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nonexchange</TIMEX> revenue. For example,
the main source of balances for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major trust funds, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Retirement and Disability</ENAMEX> fund and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military</ENAMEX>
60SFFAS <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 5</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting for Liabilities of the Federal</ENAMEX>
Government, para. 54.
Retirement fund, consists of exchange revenue and other
financing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. In such exceptional cases, as explained in the
Basis for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conclusions</ENAMEX>, the interest should be classified in the
same way as the predominant source of balances--in these cases, as
exchange revenue--rather than according to the normal rule.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">309</NUMEX>. Interest received by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> from another.--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> fund
within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> may borrow from another. For example, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old-Age and Survivors Insurance</ENAMEX> trust fund borrowed from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disability Insurance and Hospital Insurance</ENAMEX> trust funds. When that
occurs, the lending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> sacrifices interest from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
securities on its invested balances and instead receives interest
from the borrowing fund on the amount of the loan. Since the
predominant source of balances to the lending fund is the same
regardless of whether it invests in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> securities or lends to
another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>, the interest received from the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> should be
classified in the same way--as nonexchange or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> revenue--as
the interest received on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> securities.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">310</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Employer entity</ENAMEX> contributions to social insurance
programs<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">.61</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> may be covered by social insurance
programs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Security62</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> under the same
terms and conditions as the rest of the covered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
Intragovernmental contributions to social insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> are nonexchange transactions, just
as payments made by private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to these programs are
nonexchange transactions. Contributions by private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> are in
the nature of taxes; i.e., compulsory payments demanded by the
Government through the exercise of its power to compel payment.
Insofar as the social insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> applies to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, the terms and conditions are generally the same as the
program for private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> and employee
contributions are generally calculated in the same way; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer entity</ENAMEX> contribution is not earned by the social insurance
program; and the benefits are generally calculated in the same way.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> does not obtain particular benefits under the plan
from rendering service in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> employment, because he or she
would have been similarly covered by the program if privately
employed and would have received similar benefits. For these
reasons, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer entity</ENAMEX> contribution should have the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classification</ENAMEX> as private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> contributions, which is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonexchange</ENAMEX> revenue.
Nonexchange transactions--intragovernmental: gains and
losses
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">311</NUMEX>. Retirement of debt securities prior to maturity: trust
funds and special <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">funds</NUMEX> (except trust revolving funds).--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
securities held by trust funds and special funds are primarily
issued in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> account series, which can generally be
redeemed on demand. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> securities held by these funds
may also be callable or redeemable on demand. If these debt
securities are retired before maturity, the difference, if any,
between the reacquisition price and the net carrying value of the
extinguished debt should be recognized as a gain or loss by the
fund that owned the securities. The gain or loss should be
accounted for as a nonexchange gain or loss if
61
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Social</ENAMEX> insurance" does not include programs established solely
or primarily for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, such as pension and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retirement</ENAMEX> plans.
62
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> hired before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> are not
covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>.
the interest on the associated debt securities is classified as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonexchange</ENAMEX> revenue, and it should be accounted for as an exchange
gain or loss if the interest on the associated debt securities is
classified as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> revenue. For trust funds (except trust
revolving funds) and special funds, as explained elsewhere, the
interest is normally but not always a nonexchange revenue.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">312</NUMEX>. The difference, if any, between the reacquisition price and
the net carrying value of the extinguished debt should be
recognized as a loss or gain in accounting for interest on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
debt. The amount should be equal in absolute value but with the
