



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
Testimony
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on the Legislative Branch, Committee on</ENAMEX>
Appropriations,

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX>

For <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Release</ENAMEX> on Delivery
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:00 a.m. EST</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10, 2001</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FISCAL YEAR 2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BUDGET REQUEST</ENAMEX>




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. GeneralAccounting Office</ENAMEX>
Statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David M. Walker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-609T
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX>:
Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>! As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
it is a pleasure to appear before you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to present the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
Accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s) budget request for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX>. I
well in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>. Our work resulted in substantial
financial savings and significant improvements to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that
will benefit all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. I am confident that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX>
will be just as productive.
At the outset, I want to thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> for its support in
helping enact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s human capital legislation. This legislation
will go a long way toward helping us address many of our human
capital requirements and ensuring that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> remains prepared to meet
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' needs in the future. We have issued implementing
regulations for the early retirement and scientific and technical
staff provisions and plan to issue authorizing regulations later
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to guide any potential future buy-outs and
reductions-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX> budget request is critical to our
continuing efforts to reorganize and reshape the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, reengineer
our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> processes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> and equip our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> with
up-to-date technology to help meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' current and future
needs. Congressional mandates and requests continue to represent
over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of our work, and our workload and productivity
remain at near-record levels. Our budget request represents our
needs--not wants--to sustain this level of effort and support to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
Since becoming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> at the beginning of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s appropriations have been insufficient to
fund mandatory and inflation expenses associated with employee
compensation and benefits, and make needed investments in critical
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, such as technology, training, and performance recognition.
We have managed our resource shortages by reducing our staffing
levels and underfunding critical investments. We cannot, and should
not, continue this trend.
The funds we are requesting are essential to helping us remain
prepared to meet the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, controversial, and multidimensional
issues and challenges confronting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> now and in the
future. Our request includes only those funds we need to stabilize
at our approved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,275</NUMEX> fulltime equivalent staffing level and to
incrementally increase investments needed in training, technology,
performance recognition, and other key support items to a level
consistent with best practices of other comparable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and
private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector entities</ENAMEX>.
Before I begin detailing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our fiscal year 2002</TIMEX> budget needs, I
would like to highlight some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s accomplishments and
achievements in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX> and the major challenges
confronting us.

A REVIEW OF <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'S <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FISCAL YEAR 2000</TIMEX> ACCOMPLISHMENTS
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> had a tremendous year in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>. As a result of
actions taken on our work by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and federal departments
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> benefited from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $23 billion</NUMEX> in
financial savings-a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$61</NUMEX> return on every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> invested in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. Our
work also resulted in significant improvements in government
operations and services that will benefit all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Among
other things, by acting on our recommendations, the government
improved public health and safety, strengthened national security,
better protected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, and improved its financial management
and information systems. We also contributed critical information
to public debates on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> reform and called
attention to looming problems, such as the security of government
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> and the knowledge and skills needed in the federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming years</TIMEX>. Other indicators of our performance,
such as the number of testimonies our senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> provided
and recommendations implemented, exceeded that of most recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. I also am pleased to report that we made significant
progress toward addressing many of the organizational, human
capital, and information technology challenges that I outlined for
you at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s hearing. We had a very busy and productive
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxpayers Benefit</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23 Billion</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Savings</ENAMEX>
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> helped achieve <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $23.2 billion</NUMEX> in
direct financial benefits for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>. These benefits
are a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> or federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
implementing our recommendations to make government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> more
efficient, improve the budgeting and spending of tax dollars, and
strengthen the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of federal resources. The estimated
financial benefits include budget reductions, costs avoided,
resources reallocated, and revenue enhancements. These results
exceeded our target of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22 billion</NUMEX> and were greater than that of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous three fiscal years</TIMEX>, as illustrated in the following
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graphic</ENAMEX>.

Dollars in billions

<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23.2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">24 $22.0</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20.9</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19.7 $20.1</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16 12 8</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 0</NUMEX>



<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19 97 1 998 1 999 2 00 0 200 0</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX>

F is cal years
Some examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work that contributed to these financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> include the following.
Helping to Prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fraud</ENAMEX> and Abuse in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> had long
advocated increased funding specifically for activities to prevent
fraud and abuse in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Insurance Portability</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Accountability Act</ENAMEX>,
which provided the additional funding. As a result of these
activities, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
program's net savings were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $3 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
Cutting Costs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Aircraft</ENAMEX> Program: In a series of
reports beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid</TIMEX>
1990s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> questioned various aspects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX> acquisition
program. We reported that the acquisition strategy was risky and
that the program was
experiencing cost growth, manufacturing problems with test
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX>, and testing delays.
Our analysis helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> reduce the final <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> appropriation request
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $552 million</NUMEX> and to identify conditions
that should be met before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> could begin full production.
Supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oversight of the Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>): <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
continued to support
congressional oversight of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' operations, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>'
implementation of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">IRS Restructuring and Reform Act</ENAMEX>, its budget requests, and
administration of various tax
functions. For example, our testimony on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' broad-based
modernization efforts
provided an integrated assessment of the challenges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
continues to face in its tax
enforcement and customer service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and its
modernization of performance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, information systems, and business practices. At the
same time, our work
generated savings and potential reductions in taxpayer burden.
Our work on the
improved use of information returns in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' tax enforcement
operations yielded <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">$</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">83</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in savings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> also agreed to begin tracking
information that has the
potential of clarifying its notices to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> and easing
their task in complying with
those notices.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recapturing Excess HUD Funding</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> identified funding from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX>'s budget, including
unexpended
balances no longer needed, that could be recaptured in fiscal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years 1998 and 1999</TIMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> rescinded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.65 billion</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 8</ENAMEX> housing
program's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1998</TIMEX>
budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> and rejected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> request for housing
assistance for a total reduction of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.95 billion</NUMEX>. Subsequently,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> worked
together to revise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s analysis to show that, by using
recaptured funds, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> had
sufficient funding to meet its needs.




<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Almost 800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Actions Taken To Improve Government Operations or</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s recommendations and audit findings also resulted in or
contributed to many improvements in the effectiveness and
efficiency of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and services during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. While immeasurable in dollar terms, they contributed to
improving public safety and consumer protection, establishing more
effective and efficient government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, and safeguarding the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s physical and information infrastructure. We recorded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">788</NUMEX>
actions taken in response to our recommendations to improve how the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> operates, a number far exceeding that of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">preceding 3 years</TIMEX> as illustrated in the following graphic.

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">788 800 607 620</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">537 600</NUMEX>
Number of actions
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">391 400</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0 1997 1998 1999 2000 2000</ENAMEX>


Target
Fiscal year
Examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work that resulted in these accomplishments
follow.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Improving Nursing Home Quality of Care</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financing Administration</ENAMEX> (HCFA) and several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>-including
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>-improved their oversight and
enforcement of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>' quality of care standards in response
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s recommendations highlighting weaknesses in existing
processes. Improvements included increased funding for nursing home
surveyors, more prompt investigation of complaints alleging serious
harm to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, more immediate enforcement actions for homes
with repeated serious problems, a reorganization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX>'s regional
staff to improve consistency in oversight, and increased funding
for administrative law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> to reduce the backlog of appealed
enforcement actions.
Managing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildfire Prevention</ENAMEX>: -<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Experts Saw Massive</ENAMEX>
Wildfires Coming" read an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 7, 2000</TIMEX>, news headline. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> was referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1999</TIMEX> report on wildfires.
Since then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has used the increased risk of uncontrollable and
often catastrophic wildfires as an example of the need for
"strategic budgeting" to address issues that are not aligned with
the current budget and organizational structures of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> major
federal land management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Responding to the wildfires that
burned <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 6.5 million acres</NUMEX> of public and private land in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> appropriated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $240 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> to reduce hazardous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> in high-risk locations where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wildlands</ENAMEX> and urban areas meet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> testified on the need for the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> land management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to act quickly to develop a framework
to spend funds effectively and to account accurately for what they
accomplish with the funds.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Improving Human Capital Practices</ENAMEX>: Our work on human capital
issues helped focus the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> and legislative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branches</ENAMEX> on the importance of these issues,
particularly in managing for results. We helped spur the
administration to make human
capital a priority management objective in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fiscal year 2001</TIMEX>
budget submission, and
our framework for human capital self-assessment is being used at
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>,
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Administration</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aeronautics and Space Administration</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Protection Agency</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">framework</ENAMEX> also is used throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to help guide our research
and development
work and our congressionally driven examinations of how well
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are pursuing
strategic human capital management in support of their missions
and goals. We have
designated strategic human capital management as one of the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s high
risk areas in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Performance and Accountability Series</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High-Risk Update</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strengthening Information Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has evaluated the
security of critical
information systems at federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and recommended numerous
improvements,
most recently at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
issued a governmentwide perspective on federal information
security that covered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> audit findings reported since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. We concluded that
weak security continues to be a widespread problem that places
critical and sensitive
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> at risk of tampering, disruption, and
inappropriate disclosure. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2000</TIMEX>, government information security reform provisions
were enacted into law
to strengthen information security practices throughout the
government.
Stabilizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>: Despite the presence of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Treaty Organization</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX> remain volatile. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
work has shown that
the international operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> face severe
obstacles to achieving
enduring peace and stability. Most local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
their respective ethnic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have not embraced the political and social reconciliation
needed to build
multiethnic, democratic societies. Our work also has shown that
the international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> has not provided the resources that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
says it needs, particularly for building a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> police
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX>. If progress is not made
with these matters, violence may escalate or armed conflict may
result.



Requests for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Testimony and Implementation of</ENAMEX>
Recommendations Increased
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, the number of times that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> testified before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the rate at which our
recommendations were implemented exceeded that of most recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s primary function is to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in
carrying out its decision-making and oversight responsibilities,
the number of times our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> testify before congressional panels
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> is an indicator of our responsiveness and reflects the
impact, importance, and value of our work. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> testified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">263</NUMEX> times before <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">104</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Subcommittees</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of all congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittees</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> testified on a broad
range of issues of national importance, including arms control,
health care, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, human capital, nuclear waste cleanup,
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">wildfire</ENAMEX> prevention, aviation safety and security, international
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>, computer security, financial management and reform, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> issues.
Our assistance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> at public hearings continues to
remain high, as illustrated below. However, it is clear that the
number of congressional oversight hearings and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> testimony
opportunities will decline significantly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX> as a
result of factors beyond our control. Among these include the slow
start of the 107th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> due to the power sharing arrangements
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, closer margins and committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> changes in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, and delay in filling many <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> policy
positions.

Number of testimonies
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">256 263 270 229 230</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">182</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180</NUMEX>
90
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0 1997 1998 1999 2000 2000</ENAMEX>


Target
Fiscal year
We also exceeded our performance of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">previous years</TIMEX> with respect
to the rate at which the recommendations we made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 years ago</TIMEX> were
implemented. We use a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-year</TIMEX> interval because our historical data
show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> often need time to take action on our
recommendations. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">78 percent</NUMEX> of the
recommendations we made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1996</TIMEX> had been implemented.
As illustrated in the graphic below, this rate exceeds that of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">preceding 3 years</TIMEX>. Implemented recommendations correct the
underlying causes of problems, weaknesses in internal controls,
failures to comply with laws or regulations, or other matters
impeding effective and efficient performance.

74 7378
80
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">69 70 60 40 20</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1997 1998 1999 2000 2000 Target</ENAMEX>

Fiscal year





<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Significant Progress Made Addressing Management and Operational</ENAMEX>
Issues
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, I outlined for you a number of major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and
operational challenges facing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. These challenges included human
capital, information technology, organizational, job processes, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> issues within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. I am pleased to report that
we made significant progress toward addressing many of these
issues.
We continued to enhance our effectiveness and efficiency through
a variety of means during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, including issuing a
strategic plan, establishing congressional protocols, realigning
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, implementing key human capital initiatives, and
increasing the use of information technology. These efforts to
enhance and strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and its services to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> include the following.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Spring of 2000</TIMEX>, we issued our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> strategic plan for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX> based on input from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and supplemented
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s own expertise and other outreach efforts. The plan focuses
on how we intend to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in helping to shape a more
efficient and effective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It describes our role and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> in the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>; the core values that guide our
work; the trends, conditions, and external factors underlying our
plan; and our goals, objectives, and strategies for serving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Our intent is to update the strategic plan every 2 years
for each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
We established a set of congressional protocols to govern our
interactions with and ensure our accountability to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
These protocols, which underwent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9month</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> test, set out
clear, transparent, consistently applied policies and practices for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to reduce miscommunication and
ensure that all requesters are treated equitably. The final
protocols were issued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX>.
We continued our outreach efforts to understand how best to meet
congressional needs and assist the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in using our resources
and services. During each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, I and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> plan
to meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Chairs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranking</ENAMEX> Minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of our oversight
and appropriations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> to obtain feedback on our performance
and information needed to update our strategic plan.
We issued our first-ever <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accountability Report</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
discussing our performance and accountability in serving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1999</TIMEX>. The report
reviews our accomplishments in meeting our mission and sustaining
our core values of accountability, integrity, and reliability. We
also issued a performance plan for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX> that contains
the performance measures and annual performance targets we will use
to gauge progress toward accomplishing our strategic goals and
objectives.
We also realigned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to better support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and
prepare ourselves with current and expected resource levels to meet
the future challenges outlined in our strategic plan. To align
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> with the goals in our strategic plan, we
reorganized both our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> and headquarters operations. The changes
were primarily designed to better align our resources with our
strategic plan, eliminate a layer of managerial hierarchy, reduce
the number of organizational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>, increase internal and external
coordination activities with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and other accountability
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, clarify the roles and responsibilities of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, increase the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who perform rather
than manage or review work, and increase the critical mass and
enhance the flexibility of field resources.
We also began implementing a range of new and enhanced human
capital and information technology strategies to position <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> for
future success. Thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, we now have legislative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> that provides us greater flexibility to effectively
manage our human capital. This legislation, enacted into law in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2000</TIMEX>, grants us the authority to establish new senior-level
scientific and technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX>; offer targeted voluntary
early-outs and buy-outs; and carry out reductions in force to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downsize</ENAMEX>, realign, or correct skills imbalances within our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.
We have issued implementing regulations for early-outs and the
scientific and technical positions and plan to issue buy-out and
reductions-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> authorizing regulations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>.
Other accomplishments within the human capital area include:
Completion of a first-ever electronic knowledge and skills
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment</ENAMEX> and inventory that is being used to help identify skill
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gaps</ENAMEX> and succession planning needs within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. In addition,
staff completed an employee preference survey that is being used
along with the results of the knowledge and skills inventory to
meet our institutional work needs while accommodating staff
preferences for engagements to the extent possible.
Significant recruiting and college relations efforts on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>. Aggressive efforts are underway to attract,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recruit</ENAMEX>, and hire high-caliber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> with the skills and abilities
needed to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> in achieving our strategic goals and
objectives.
Revised performance standards for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> that incorporate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s core values and strategic goals, update descriptions of
performance to better reflect the current nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work, and
include key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and performance concepts, such as leadership
by example, client service, and measurable results. Also, during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, we began a major initiative to develop a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">competency</ENAMEX>-based performance appraisal system for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> to
reflect prevailing best practices. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX>, we will
begin updating the performance systems for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and mission
support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to reflect prevailing best practices.
Enhanced internal communications that remain a vital tool for
change <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, I conducted a number of telecasts to all agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">discuss GAO</ENAMEX>'s strategic plan and congressional protocols, client
service, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> survey results, initiatives to enhance the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s human capital programs and legislative proposals, work
processes, organizational alignment, information technology, and
other areas of interest to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. Also, to engage our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
more fully in improving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s performance, we established
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller General's Employee Advisory Council</ENAMEX> to discuss
current and emerging issues of mutual interest and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> and
implemented an employee suggestion program that received more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> submissions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first year</TIMEX> of operation.
We also made significant gains in strengthening and improving
our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and processes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>. We implemented
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new management strategies: risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and matrix
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s risk management approach allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to
identify and involve key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an</TIMEX> engagement to
transcend traditional organizational boundaries to maximize
institutional value and minimize related risks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s matrix
management approach maximizes our value to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> by
leveraging the knowledge, skills, and experience of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> address the challenging, complex, multidimensional
problems facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX>, we also continued to improve our
use of information technology as a tool for productivity and
knowledge management. To provide our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> with a
mechanism for simplifying and standardizing their work, we launched
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic Assistance Guide</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading Engagements</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EAGLE</ENAMEX>,
which is a prototype of a comprehensive Webbased guide to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conducting GAO</ENAMEX> engagements. We also continued to enhance the
capabilities of our computer network and successfully made our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">compliant</ENAMEX>. In addition, we began a number of projects
on enabling technologies, including software upgrades, the
deployment of notebook computers, and improved remote access to
allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> to work more efficiently in the field. Also, to carry
out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s responsibilities under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Presidential Transition Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, we developed a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> on our Internet web site with
links to key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> contacts and reports on the major executive branch
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, which was completed at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of fiscal year</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.



<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FISCAL YEAR 2001</TIMEX> PLANS AND <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FUTURE CHALLENGES</ENAMEX>
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX>, we will continue to focus our work on
the major issues facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">solvency</ENAMEX>, education, economic development, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> reform,
national security, international affairs, and government management
reforms and computer security. Another top priority <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> will
be working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> strengthen
its approach to oversight, with an emphasis on looking hard at what
government does, how it does it, and the long-term consequences of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s policy choices. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">2001 Performance and Accountability</ENAMEX>
Series and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High-Risk Update</ENAMEX> will serve as a solid foundation for
congressional oversight. Also, as I mentioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>, we have
several key initiatives in progress to improve how we serve the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, among them an expanded client feedback system; protocols
governing our dealings with federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>; new high-level
advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> to gain the expertise of business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>; and new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> for sharing
our own expertise with other accountability <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
We also are preparing to carry out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new responsibilities
mandated by the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. We will chair a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> to review
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s A-76 process for obtaining services through
competitive sourcing. Also, if the needed funding is provided, we
will review the costs and benefits of major regulations under the
Truth in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulating Act</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.L. 106-312</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 17, 2000</TIMEX>). We have a
request pending for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.6 million</NUMEX> in supplemental funding for fiscal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2001</TIMEX> and are requesting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.2 million</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX> to
meet the requirements created by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulating Act</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Internally</ENAMEX>, we will continue to emphasize initiatives to address
our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major management challenges: human capital and information
technology. With <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 80 percent</NUMEX> of our resources devoted to staff
salary and benefits, the area of human capital presents a major
challenge. A significant percentage of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> is nearing
retirement age, while marketplace, demographic, economic, and
technological changes indicate that competition for skilled workers
will be greater in the future. With our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> realigned to
facilitate our work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and new legislative authority
in hand to manage our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> more effectively, we are pursuing
several initiatives to strengthen our human capital. For example,
we are recruiting diverse, highcaliber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> with the skills and
abilities we need to achieve our strategic goals and objectives. We
will be putting into place a competency-based performance appraisal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> and using the results of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> knowledge and skills
inventory to help us in workforce planning. We also have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reestablished</ENAMEX> and are expanding training opportunities for our
staff-from the senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hires</ENAMEX>.
Another major management challenge is building an integrated and
reliable information technology (IT) infrastructure that supports
the achievement of our goals. We are conducting a comprehensive IT
review to identify opportunities to increase our efficiency,
effectiveness, and productivity. We also are mapping our business
processes to our IT architecture and will link future IT
investments to our business goals. In addition, we plan to continue
initiatives to increase our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>' productivity, maximize the
use of technology, and enhance the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webbased</ENAMEX> knowledge-sharing
applications on the desktop. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX>, we also must heighten the
security of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FY 2002 BUDGET REQUEST</ENAMEX>
To fully support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> as outlined in our strategic plan
and the additional congressional mandates received since its
issuance, we are requesting a budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX> of about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$430.3 million</NUMEX>. This funding level will allow us to support and
staff to our approved level of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,275</NUMEX> full-time equivalent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. We will increase our emphasis on areas of congressional
and public interest and, internally, will continue to emphasize
initiatives to address our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major management challenges: human
capital and information technology. Our request also includes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to carry out new responsibilities created by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulating Act</ENAMEX>. In addition, we are seeking <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a nominal</NUMEX> increase in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s representation expenses, from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000 to $12,500</NUMEX>, to
accommodate our expanded role with both domestic and international
accountability <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
Additional funding in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX> is being requested
for:
mandatory pay and benefit costs resulting primarily from federal
cost-of-living and locality pay adjustments, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>) guidance, increased participation in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Employees Retirement System</ENAMEX>, and an increase in the
estimated number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17,554,000</NUMEX>;
uncontrollable inflationary increases in transportation,
lodging, postage, printing, supplies, contracts, and other
essential mission support services, based on OMB's 2percent
inflation index and other factors--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,565,000</NUMEX>; and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uncontrollable</ENAMEX> contract rate increases in building operations
and maintenance and information technology
programs--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,453,000</NUMEX>.
Funding of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,004,000</NUMEX> for salaries and benefits also is being
requested to staff and support our approved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,275</NUMEX> full-time
equivalent staffing level. We plan to use these resources to
enhance our review efforts in areas of congressional and public
interest and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> computer security, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security solvency, education, economic development, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
reform, and international affairs.
The additional funds requested also would be used to continue
initiatives begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX> that are critical to
supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the goals and objectives identified in
our strategic plan. These initiatives include human capital
initiatives and enabling technological advances to enhance the
performance and productivity of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> as follows.
Human capital initiatives--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,324,000</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enabling</ENAMEX> technology
initiatives to increase employee productivity, maximize the use of
technology, and enhance employee tools available at the desktop,
including such initiatives as reengineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> processes,
upgrading hardware and software applications, expanding our
videoconferencing capabilities, and implementing a best practices
network security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,585,000</NUMEX>.

Other efforts include:
Enhancing security and removing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asbestos</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Building</ENAMEX>
to protect the health and safety of our most important asset-our
staff--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,839,000</NUMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upgrading GAO</ENAMEX>'s computer security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> to ensure our
continued ability to conduct effective, comprehensive computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> controls testing of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, diverse, and interconnected
executive branch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> and to attract and retain skilled,
technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750,000</NUMEX>;
Enhancing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Organization of Supreme Audit</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institution</ENAMEX>'s efforts to combat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> related corruption
around the world, multi-lateral training efforts with eastern<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">-bloc</ENAMEX>
and selected <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and bilateral
assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX>; and
Contracting for the development of a requirements document to be
used along with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislative branch agencies</ENAMEX> to jointly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">procure</ENAMEX> and share a common financial management
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX>.
In addition, as previously mentioned, we are requesting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to provide the annual funding requirement specified in the
Truth in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Regulating Act</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BUDGET REQUEST CRITICAL TO SUSTAINING EXISTING LEVEL OF SERVICE</ENAMEX>
TO THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONGRESS</ENAMEX>
The resources we are requesting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX> are
critical to addressing our human capital and information technology
challenges and ensuring our ability to effectively meet the
increasing congressional requests for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> services. We have reached
a point that if sufficient funding is not received to address these
issues and properly support our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, we will need to take actions
that will negatively impact our service and responsiveness to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
Congressional demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> services continues to increase. For
example, as illustrated below, the number of engagements begun as a
result of a congressional request has increased during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 4</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. These numbers do not include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of other requests that
had not yet been started.

We have worked hard over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 3 years</TIMEX> with available
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> to significantly increase our productivity levels to
successfully meet increasing congressional demand. For example, we
realigned our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, reengineered many of our business
processes, retooled our engagement and risk management practices,
revised our performance appraisal and recognition systems, and
updated our information technology infrastructure. However, we have
reached a point that significant additional productivity gains are
unlikely without sufficient funding to further enhance our human
capital and information technology programs.
We are concerned about our ability to continue to increase our
productivity levels, sustain our return on investment, and meet
future congressional demands given the recent trend in our funding
levels. Since becoming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> at the beginning of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1999</TIMEX>, I have not asked for any increase in our approved
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,275</NUMEX> full-time equivalent staffing level. I have only requested
the funding necessary to properly maintain and support this
staffing level and cover mandatory expenses, including inflation
and compensation costs. However, as illustrated in the following
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graphic</ENAMEX>, the funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> received has been significantly less than
what we requested and needed to support our approved staffing
level.

In order to cover our mandatory expenses during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 3</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, we had to staff well below our approved staffing level, as
illustrated below, and delayed or made reduced investments in
important human capital and information technology initiatives. As
a result of these funding shortfalls and the mandated funding
reductions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1990s</TIMEX>, our training, performancebased
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> and rewards programs are not where they need to be.
Consequently, we are at a competitive disadvantage with the
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> in some areas, such as performance rewards. In
addition, we have some management information systems that are
obsolete and incapable of interfacing within our network
environment and a variety of software that needs to be upgraded to
ensure continued vendor maintenance and support. We cannot continue
down this path. We have reached the point at which investments in
these critical programs and other areas must be made in order to
effectively support our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and provide the high level of service
expected and required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.


3,400
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,325 3,275 3,275 3,275</NUMEX>

3,192 3,155



3,000

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1999 2000 2001</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fiscal year</TIMEX> FTEs Requested


FTEs Used
The funds we are requesting are critical to addressing our
succession planning challenges and enhancing the knowledge, skills,
and abilities of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>. A large percentage of our workforce
will become eligible for retirement within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 5 years</TIMEX>. More
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of our senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> will be retirement eligible within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time</TIMEX> period. We
need to aggressively continue our efforts to hire new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>,
develop existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and otherwise build the future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. In
order to be competitive in attracting, hiring, and retaining high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caliber</ENAMEX> and talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, we need to be able to further enhance
our human capital programs. Thus, the funding we are requesting for
training, performance-based recognition and compensation programs,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> loan repayments, mass transit subsidy allowance, and
enabling technology is critical. Without such funding, we will not
be competitive in attracting and retaining the best, brightest, and
expertise needed to effectively serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in addressing
the complex, controversial, and multidimensional issues and
challenges it faces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>.
If the funding trend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 3 years</TIMEX> is continued, we will
need to restrict our work to only responding to requests from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittees</ENAMEX>, thus severely limiting-and
potentially eliminating-work done for individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Such a
restriction also would further reduce the limited flexibility we
have to research and develop expertise on emerging issues, thereby
limiting our ability to respond to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> when related issues
arise on short notice. For example, were it not for the advance
research and development work we had done on computer security,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s presidential
election issues, we would have been unable to be responsive to the
congressional requests and public debates on these real time, event
driven issues. We need sufficient funding to build and ensure we
have the capacity and expertise to address such emerging issues on
short notice in the future.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">s</ENAMEX>
E
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>
F
f
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX>
r



3,200
e
b
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">u</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CONCLUDING REMARKS</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fiscal year 2000</TIMEX> was a tremendous year of accomplishment and
achievement for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of great service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and
of great benefit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>. We have made significant
progress in addressing many of the areas in need of improvement in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and need to continue these efforts. The resources we are
requesting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX> are critical to sustaining our
high-level of performance and service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. We are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation's</ENAMEX> and possibly the world's leading accountability
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>. We need these additional resources to continue our
efforts to further strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> and be a model <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> for
the rest of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and accountability organizations
around the world. In addition, given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s impressive results and
return on investment, it only makes sense for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to receive
resource allocations that are well above average for other federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX>. To do otherwise would send a troubling message to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, the press, and the public.
We look forward to your continued support and working even more
closely with you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2002</TIMEX>.
This concludes my statement. I would be pleased to respond to any
questions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> may have.

Orders by Internet
For information on how to access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reports on the Internet,
send an email message with "info" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to
info@<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>
or visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Web</ENAMEX> home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>


Web site: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gao</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov/fraudnet/fraudnet.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm Email:</ENAMEX>
fraudnet@<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gao</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Automated</ENAMEX> answering system: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">18004245454</ENAMEX>





