



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
Testimony
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>

Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Commission on the Public Service</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volcker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Commission</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Service</ENAMEX>:
I am pleased to be here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to discuss the essential actions
that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> needs to take in order to manage its
most important asset-its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, or human capital. An
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> define its culture, drive its performance,
embody its knowledge base, and are the key to successful merger and
transformation efforts. As such, strategic human capital management
is the critical element to maximizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s performance and
assuring its accountability for the benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years of the 21st century</TIMEX> are proving to be a period
of profound transition for our world, our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and our
government. This transition is being driven by a number of key
trends including: global interdependence; diverse, diffuse, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asymmetrical</ENAMEX> security threats; rapidly evolving science and
technology; dramatic shifts in the age and composition of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>; important quality of life issues; the changing nature
of our economy; and evolving government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> and concepts.
These trends present a range of challenges that have no boundaries.
These trends also contribute to a huge, longer-range fiscal and
budgetary challenge facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Given these trends
and longrange fiscal challenges, the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> needs to
engage in a comprehensive review, reassessment, and
reprioritization of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does, how it does business,
and who does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s business. We must re-examine a range
of government policies, programs, and operations. The status quo is
simply unacceptable. The long-range numbers do not add up. We must
re-examine the base, including our current human capital policies
and practices. This re-examination will in turn require federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to transform their cultures and shift their overall
orientation from:


•
processes to results,


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stovepipes</ENAMEX> to matrixes,


•
hierarchical to flatter and more horizontal
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">structures,</ENAMEX>


•
an inward focus to an external (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stakeholder</ENAMEX>) focus,


•
management control to employee empowerment,


•
reactive behavior to proactive approaches,


•
avoiding new technologies to embracing and leveraging
them,


•
hoarding knowledge to sharing knowledge,


•
avoiding risk to managing risk, and


•
protecting turf to forming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX>.


Leading public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and
abroad have found that strategic human capital <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> must be
the centerpiece of any serious change management initiative and
efforts to transform the cultures of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
Unfortunately, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has made clear, the federal
government is not well positioned to make the needed
transformation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> designated strategic human capital management
as a governmentwide high-risk area in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX> because of a
long-standing lack of a consistent strategic approach to
marshaling, managing, and maintaining the human capital needed for
government to deliver on its promises<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.1</NUMEX> We reported then and still
find <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that serious human capital shortfalls are eroding the
capacity of many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, and threatening the ability of others,
to economically, efficiently, and effectively perform their
missions<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.2</NUMEX> The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s human capital weaknesses did
not emerge <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> and will not be quickly or easily addressed.
The enormous human capital and other transformation challenges that
need to be addressed to transform the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Bureau of</ENAMEX>
Investigation (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>) and create a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Homeland</ENAMEX>
Security are instructive of the critical and difficult task ahead<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.3</NUMEX>
Committed, sustained, highly qualified, and inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>,
and persistent attention by all key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> will be essential if
lasting changes are to be made and the challenges we face across
the federal government successfully addressed.
Fortunately, we are now seeing increased attention to strategic
human capital management and a real and growing momentum for change
is now evident since we placed strategic human capital management
on our High-Risk list.



•
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> placed human capital at
the top of his management agenda.



<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">High-Risk Series</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Update</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-263 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>).


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Performance and Accountability</ENAMEX>
Series-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major Management Challenges</ENAMEX> and Program Risks: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmentwide Perspective</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-241 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). In addition, see the accompanying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX> reports (numbered
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01-242</NUMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01-262</NUMEX>) on specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: Proposal
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet Agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Has Merit</ENAMEX>, But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Implementation Will be Pivotal</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-886T (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25, 2002</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
Reorganization: Initial Steps Encouraging but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broad Transformation</ENAMEX>
Needed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-865T (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21, 2002</TIMEX>).




•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' progress in addressing their individual human capital
challenges as part of its management scorecard and mid-point review
process.


•
As one of its many efforts to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with these
issues, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Personnel Management</ENAMEX> (OPM) released a human
capital scorecard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX> to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in responding to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> scorecard.


•
Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has underscored the consequences of
human capital weaknesses in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and pinpointed
solutions through the oversight process and a wide range of
hearings held over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>
Therefore, the key question <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is how do we best seize the
opportunity and build on the current momentum? I have often noted
that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step toward meeting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s human capital
challenges is for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to identify and make use of all
the appropriate administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> available to them to
manage their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for results both effectively and equitably.
Much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> need to manage human capital
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strategically</ENAMEX> is already available under current laws and
regulations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> should not wait for comprehensive human
capital legislative reforms to happen. The use of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>
often needs to be undertaken as part of, and consistent with,
proven change management practices. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> step is for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">policymakers</ENAMEX> to pursue incremental legislative reforms to give
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> additional tools and flexibilities to hire, manage, and
retain the human capital they need, particularly in critical
occupations. Key provisions of legislative proposals under
consideration in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> represent an important step to helping
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> address their human capital management challenges. Many of
the provisions contained in the bills are consistent with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> we have been urging for other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.4 The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> step toward meeting the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s human capital
challenges is for all interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> to work together to
identify the kinds of comprehensive legislative reforms in the
human capital area that should be enacted over time. These reforms
should place greater emphasis on knowledge, skills, and performance
in connection with federal employment, promotion, and compensation
decisions, rather than on the passage of time, the rate of
inflation, or geographic location, as is often the case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
Shockingly, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 80</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing</ENAMEX> for Results: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building</ENAMEX>
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Momentum for Strategic Human Capital Reform</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-528T
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: Mar. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18, 2002</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T



Using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Performance Management Systems</ENAMEX> to
Help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transform Agencies</ENAMEX>
percent of the cost associated with the annual increases in
federal salaries is due to cost-of-living and locality pay
adjustment. This must change.
Today, I will discuss <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> broad human capital reform
opportunities that are instrumental to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> transformation
efforts and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> may want to consider as its work
moves forward. These broad opportunities include: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, aligning
individual and organizational performance; <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and directly
related to that, implementing resultsoriented pay reform; and
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, sustaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> transformation efforts. I will conclude
with some comments on how we in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> are playing a constructive role
in helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> address its human capital challenges,
including our efforts to "lead by example" in this critically
important area.
Leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> use their performance management systems
as a key tool for aligning institutional, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, and employee
performance; achieving results; accelerating change; managing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> on a day-to-day basis; and facilitating communication
throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> so that discussions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and
organizational performance are integrated and ongoing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Performance</ENAMEX>
management systems in these leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> typically seek to
achieve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> key objectives. First, they strive to provide candid
and constructive feedback to help individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> maximize
their potential in understanding and realizing the goals and
objectives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, they seek to provide management
with the objective and fact-based information it needs to reward
top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, performance management systems provide the
necessary information and documentation to deal with poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX>. Most federal performance management systems fail to
achieve these objectives. In addition, many federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> are
just beginning to recognize that their performance management
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> can be strategic tools to achieve success. In my opinion,
modernizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> performance appraisal and management systems and
linking them to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> strategic plans and desired outcomes should
be a top priority.
Results-oriented performance agreements are one mechanism in a
performance management system that creates a "line of sight"
showing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Capital</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Principles</ENAMEX>
From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine Private Sector Organizations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-28</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31, 2000</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T
how individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> can contribute to overall
organizational goals. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies</ENAMEX> that effectively implement such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> must first align agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>' performance expectations
with organizational goals and then cascade performance expectations
to other organizational levels. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are then held
accountable for their contributions to achieve desired results. Our
work has shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have benefited from their use of
results-oriented performance agreements for political and senior
career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. The performance agreements


•
strengthened alignment of results-oriented goals with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>,


•
fostered collaboration across organizational
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">boundaries,</ENAMEX>


•
enhanced opportunities to discuss and routinely use
performance information to make program improvements,


•
provided a results-oriented basis for individual
accountability, and


•
maintained continuity of program goals during leadership
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transitions</ENAMEX>.


Governmentwide, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> need to place increased emphasis on
holding senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> accountable for organizational goals. OPM
amended regulations that change the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> evaluate the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX>). While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> will
need to tailor their performance management systems to their unique
organizational requirements and climates, they nonetheless are to:
hold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> accountable for results; appraise executive
performance on those results balanced against other dimensions,
including customer satisfaction and employee perspective; and use
those results as the basis for performance awards and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">personnel</ENAMEX> decisions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> were to implement the new policies
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> appraisal cycles that began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
Ultimately, an effective performance management system must link
pay and incentive programs to individual knowledge, skills, and
contributions to achieving organizational results. The affect of
poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' performance and morale can far exceed
their small numbers. Still, while important, dealing with poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">performers</ENAMEX> is only part of the challenge; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> need to create
additional incentives and rewards for valuable and high-performing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who represent the vast majority of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> have repeatedly expressed a
commitment to more fully link resources to results. The American
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> expect and deserve this linkage as well. However, we
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing</ENAMEX> for Results: Emerging
Benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Selected Agencies' Use of Performance Agreements</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-115 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 30, 2000</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T
will never achieve this linkage without modern and effective
performance management strategies. Additional information on the
performance management programs in use in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and the relative
strengths and weaknesses of those programs, along with best
practice information, would prove very helpful as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> seek to
link pay to individual knowledge, skills, and performance.
Efforts to link federal pay to knowledge, skills, and
performance should be part of a broader effort to align resource
decisions to results. As I noted, fostered in part by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Performance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Results Act</ENAMEX> (GPRA), there has been an
increasing interest within the executive branch and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in
linking performance and results to resource allocation and other
decisions. Consistent with that view, we need to continue efforts
to shift agency accountability-with appropriate safeguards and
oversight- to budgeted resources and results and away from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inputs</ENAMEX> and processes. The work of the recently completed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Activities Panel</ENAMEX>, which I had the privilege of chairing, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">illustrative</ENAMEX> in this regard<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7 One</NUMEX> of the sourcing principles
adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Panel</ENAMEX> was that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s sourcing
policy should avoid arbitrary full-time equivalent (FTE) or other
numerical goals. The principle is based on the unarguable point
that the success of government programs should be measured by the
results achieved in terms of providing value to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>, not
the size of the in-house or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor workforce</ENAMEX>. I believe that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Panel</ENAMEX>'s principle should also apply to resource allocation
generally. We need to continue- and even augment-efforts to shift
the focus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, resource allocation, and decisionmaking
from inputs and process to a greater focus on results and outcomes
and to provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> reasonable flexibility while
incorporating appropriate safeguards to prevent abuse. In this
regard, holding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> accountable for results based on a
specific dollar allocation versus FTE caps would be a major step in
the right direction.

As you
know, I believe that a greater emphasis should be placed on
knowledge, skills, and performance in connection with federal
Oriented Approach to employment promotion and compensation
decisions at all levels, rather

than the passage of time, the rate of
inflation, or geographic location, as so often is the case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, widespread concern has been
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>
Commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Activities Panel, Improving the Sourcing Decisions of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final Report</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2002</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T


Ensuring <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leadership and Accountability for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agencies' Transformation</ENAMEX> Efforts
expressed about the methodology and results of the procedures to
determine the federal pay gap. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> are among the reasons
that the pay gap has never been fully addressed. I believe that
careful study is needed to develop more realistic and workable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">methodologies</ENAMEX> and solutions to federal pay issues. Part of that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment</ENAMEX> should focus on options for moving away from a
compensation system that contains governmentwide pay increases with
locality adjustments, and toward a system that is based to a
greater degree on the knowledge, skills, and performance of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> involved.
I fully appreciate that much work may be needed before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>'
respective performance management systems are able to support a
more direct link between pay and individual knowledge, skills, and
performance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX> certainly has a continuing and vital role to play
in connection with these issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX>'s recently released white
paper on federal pay provides a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> for the
results-oriented pay reform discussion that must now take place<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX>
The greater use of "broadbanding" is one of the options that
deserves to be discussed. In the short term, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may wish to
explore the benefits of (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) providing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX> with additional
flexibility that would enable it to grant governmentwide authority
for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> (i.e., class exemptions) to use broadbanding for
certain critical occupations and/or (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to apply
to OPM (i.e., case exemptions) for broadbanding authority for their
specific critical occupations. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> should be required
to demonstrate to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX>'s satisfaction that they have modern,
effective, and validated performance management systems before they
are allowed to use broadbanding.
The nature and scope of the cultural transformation that needs
to take place in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> across the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will
take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to accomplish-easily outrunning the tenures of most
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointees</ENAMEX>. At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>,
most prominently in our <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">High-Risk and Performance</ENAMEX> and
Accountability <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Series</ENAMEX>, has amply documented that many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
suffer from a range of long-standing management challenges and a
lack of attention to basic stewardship responsibilities,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personnel Management</ENAMEX>, A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Paper</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fresh Start</ENAMEX> for
Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pay: The Case for Modernization</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T
requiring concerted action and sustained top-level attention if
they are to be addressed<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> option for addressing the issues <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> face is to create
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Operating Officer</ENAMEX> (COO) position for selected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that
would provide the sustained management attention essential for
addressing key stewardship responsibilities in an integrated manner
while helping to facilitate the transformation process within an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency.10</ENAMEX> These long-term responsibilities are professional and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonpartisan</ENAMEX> in nature. They cover a range of "good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>"
responsibilities that are fundamental to effectively executing any
administration's program agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statutory COOs</ENAMEX> would differ
from-but hopefully complement-the roles often assumed by the
current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Secretaries</ENAMEX> in assisting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretaries</ENAMEX> in
executing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s policy and program agenda and
achieving an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s mission. The good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> responsibilities
that could be led by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COO</ENAMEX> include:


•
strategic planning, • organizational
alignment,


•
core values stewardship,


•
human capital strategy,


•
performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> (aligning institutional, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, and
individual measurement and reward systems to achieve overall
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,


•
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,


•
acquisition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,


•
risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,


•
knowledge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">matrix</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and


•
change management.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>
For example, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Markets</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concerted Actions Needed</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FERC</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Confront Challenges That Impede</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Effective Oversight</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-656 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14, 2002</TIMEX>);
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD Management</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress Made on Management Reforms</ENAMEX>, but Challenges
Remain, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-45</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 31, 2001</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Challenges</ENAMEX> and Program Risks: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-246 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>); and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>: 21st
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Century Challenges Prompt Fresh Thinking About Program</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Administrative Structure</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-HEHS-00-108</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4, 2000</TIMEX>).
10
See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Architect</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>:
Management and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Accountability Framework Needed to Lead and Execute</ENAMEX>
Change, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-632T (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2002</TIMEX>); and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">528T</NUMEX>.
While various <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> for structuring such a position could be
used, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> option would be to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COO</ENAMEX> who is appointed, subject
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> confirmation, to a term of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 to 7 years</TIMEX> (generally
considered to be the minimum time needed for major change
initiatives to provide meaningful and sustainable results). The COO
should be at an organizational level equivalent to the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deputies</ENAMEX> in major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in order to help assure
the effectiveness of this position. A term appointment would help
to provide continuity that spans the tenure of the political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> to ensure that long-term stewardship issues are
addressed and change management initiatives are successfully
completed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> would be selected without regard to
political affiliation based on (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) demonstrated leadership skills
in managing large and complex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) experience
achieving results in connection with a number of the above
responsibilities. To further clarify accountability, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COO</ENAMEX> could
be subject to a clearly defined, results-oriented performance
contract with appropriate incentive, reward, and accountability
mechanisms.
If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the executive branch decide to move forward with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COO</ENAMEX> approach, it may make sense to use a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> in a select
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> using a value and risk-based approach. For
example, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that is experiencing particularly significant
challenges in integrating disparate organizational cultures (such
as the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Homeland Security</ENAMEX>) may be an
especially appropriate first phase <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> engaged in
major transformation efforts, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue</ENAMEX>
Administration (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>) could also benefit from such an approach.
Similarly, a "challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>''-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that has longstanding
management weaknesses and high-risk operations or functions, such
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> (DOD)-may also be a good first phase
candidate<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX> The point would be for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, executive branch
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, and others to gain experience
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COO</ENAMEX> approach before deciding how and where it should be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">applied</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
More generally, we need to comprehensively examine opportunities
for better using the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s career <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.
This examination should focus on a number of issues that have been
suggested
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD Financial Management</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated Approach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accountability</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Transparency</ENAMEX>, and Incentives
Are <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keys to Effective Reform</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-497T (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: Mar.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6, 2002</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Constructive Efforts to Help
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Agencies Address Their Human Capital Challenges</ENAMEX>
to strengthen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> and thereby improve federal performance
and foster transformation efforts. These issues include, for
example, concerns over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> compensation and pay compression. I
believe that the issue of whether and how much to increase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> pay
must be discussed within the context of how to make any pay
increases variable and performance-based rather than
across-the-board and fixed. We also must carefully examine the
composition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX>. It seems to me that, in general, current
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> fill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> broad roles: executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>,
program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and senior technical and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> positions.
We need to look at the implications that these differing roles have
for a range of issues, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> core competencies, performance
standards, recruitment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, mobility, and training and
development programs. We also need to look at whether the number of
levels within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX> (i.e. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ES</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">6</ENAMEX>) are necessary and
appropriate.
As the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s leading accountability <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>,
we have made a concerted effort to identify and encourage the
implementation of human capital practices that improve the
efficiency, effectiveness, and accountability of the federal
government. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>, we have issued numerous
reports with practical recommendations on the steps individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> can take to address their specific human capital
challenges<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.12</NUMEX> In addition, we have reported on governmentwide
trends and lessons learned by successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.13 We also
understand that we have a responsibility to "lead by example" and
"practice what we preach" in all key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> areas, including
strategic human capital management.
12
For example, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Capital</ENAMEX>:
Practices <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That Empowered and Involved Employees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1070</NUMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 14, 2001</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Capital: The Role of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ombudsmen</ENAMEX> in Dispute Resolution, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-466 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: Apr.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13, 2001</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Capital</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self-Assessment Checklist for Agency</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/OCG-00-14G</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2000</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selected Agencies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-GGD-00-131</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 18</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Human Capital: Using Incentives to Motivate and Reward High</ENAMEX>
Performance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-GGD-00-118</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2, 2000</TIMEX>); and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Reform</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elements of Successful Improvement Initiatives</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-GGD-00-26</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 15, 1999</TIMEX>).
13
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Employee Retirements</ENAMEX>:
Expected <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Increase Over the Next 5 Years Illustrates Need for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workforce Planning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-509 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: Apr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27, 2001</TIMEX>);
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Executive Service</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Retirement Trends Underscore the</ENAMEX>
Importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Succession Planning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/GGD-00-113BR</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12, 2000</TIMEX>).
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15, 2002</TIMEX>, we released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A Model</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Management</ENAMEX>, the latest in a series of tools designed to
assist agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in effectively managing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.14 Our
model is designed to help agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> effectively lead and
manage their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and integrate human capital considerations into
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> decision making and the program results they seek to achieve.
In so doing, the model highlights the importance of a sustained
commitment by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to maximize the value of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' human capital and to manage related risks. Accordingly,
it raises the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> for all of us-those in positions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>,
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, and human capital executives
and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>.
Consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>'s views, our model of strategic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human capital</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> embodies an approach that is fact-based,
focused on strategic results, and incorporates merit principles and
other national goals. As such, the model reflects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> principles
central to the human capital idea:


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are assets whose value can be enhanced through
investment. As with any investment, the goal is to maximize value
while managing risk.


•
An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s human capital approaches should be
designed, implemented, and assessed by the standard of how well
they help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> pursue its mission and achieve desired
results or outcomes.


The model highlights the kinds of thinking that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> should
apply, as well as some of the steps they can take, to make progress
in managing human capital strategically. The concepts presented in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> are arranged around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> critical success factors, which
are organized in pairs to correspond with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cornerstones</ENAMEX> of
effective strategic human capital management. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A Model</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Management</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-373SP (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mar.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T

Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Critical Success Factors Organized</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cornerstones</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4 Human Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornerstones 8 Critical Success Factors</ENAMEX>

As I noted before, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> also have developed tools that
are being used to assess human capital management efforts. We
provided drafts of our human capital model to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX> for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> to help ensure that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> efforts
are conceptually consistent. We hope that the perspective and
information provided in our
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Efforts to Lead by Example</ENAMEX>
model will help inform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' efforts to respond to the
administration's management initiatives, such as "getting to green"
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>'s management scorecard and using the tools developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX>.
While we remain sensitive of the need to maintain our institutional
independence, we are working constructively with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>, and
others to explore opportunities to develop a more fully integrated
set of guidance and tools for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to address their human
capital challenges<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX>
In addition to providing tools to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> help themselves,
we believe it is our responsibility to lead by example. We are in
the vanguard of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s efforts to modernize
existing human capital strategies and we are committed to staying
in this position. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are our most valuable asset and it is
only through their combined efforts that we can effectively serve
our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. By managing our workforce
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">strategically</ENAMEX> and focusing on results, we are helping to maximize
our own performance and ensure our own accountability. By doing so,
we also hope to demonstrate to other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that they can
make similar improvements in the way they manage their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
We have identified and made use of a variety of tools and
flexibilities, some of which were made available to us through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Personnel</ENAMEX> Act of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> and our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> legislation, but most of
which are available to federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
The most prominent change in human capital management that we
implemented as a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">GAO Personnel Act of 1980</ENAMEX> was a
broadbanded pay-for-performance system. The primary goal of this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> is to base employee compensation primarily on the knowledge,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skills</ENAMEX>, and performance of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. It provides
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> flexibility to assign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> in a manner that is more
suitable to multi-tasking and the full use of staff. Under our
current broadbanded system, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Grades 7</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX> were placed in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> bands. We expect to modify
our banded system in the future based on our experience to
date.
15
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing</ENAMEX> for Results: Next Steps
to Improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Government's Management and Performance</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-439T (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15, 2002</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2002</TIMEX>, we implemented a new competency-based
performance management system that is intended to create a clear
linkage between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> performance and our strategic plan and
core values. It includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> competencies that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
overwhelmingly validated as the keys to meaningful performance at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fig</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>.)
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Competency</ENAMEX>-Based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Model</ENAMEX>

Our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2000</TIMEX> legislation gave us additional tools to:
realign our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> in light of mission needs and overall
budgetary constraints; correct skills imbalances; and reduce
high-grade, managerial, or supervisory positions without reducing
the overall number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. This legislation allowed us to
create a technical and scientific career track at a compensation
level consistent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX>. It also allowed us to give greater
consideration to performance and employee skills and knowledge in
any Reduction-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force</ENAMEX> actions. We believe that other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
could benefit from these additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>.
Since the legislation was enacted, we have established agency
regulations and conducted and completed our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> offering of
voluntary early retirement opportunities. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> registered
their interest in participating in the program, we considered a
number of factors including: employee knowledge, skills,
performance, and competencies; the organizational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> or subunit
in which an employee worked; an employee's occupational series,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grade</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> level, as appropriate; and the geographic location
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>. As authorized by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> legislation, employee
performance was just one of many factors we considered when
deciding which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> would be allowed to receive the
incentives. However, let me assure you, we did not use performance
to target certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
We are also using many recruiting flexibilities that are
available to most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, including an extensive campaign to
increase our competitiveness on college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX> and extending
offers of employment during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall semester</TIMEX> to prospective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who will come on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following spring</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.
We are also using our internship program in a strategic fashion and
we often offer permanent positions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> interns with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 10</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of highly successful work experience. Moreover, we are
building and maintaining a strong presence of both senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> on targeted college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>. We
have also taken steps to streamline and expedite our hiring
process. In this regard, the current length of time that it takes
to hire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in most other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> is much too long
and must be addressed.
Even after we hire good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, we need to take steps to retain
them. We have taken a number of steps to empower and invest in our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. For example, we have active employee feedback and
suggestion programs. In addition, we are in the midst of
implementing our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> student loan repayment assistance program
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who have indicated interest and are willing
to make a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> commitment to staying with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>.
Overall, we have implemented the following initiatives and
targeted investments, some of which are relatively recent and some
of which are longstanding:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>


•
Prepared a human capital profile and needs assessment to
understand employee demographics and distribution.


•
Conducted an employee survey in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999 and 2002</TIMEX> to
understand the status and progress of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and the areas in
which we need to improve.


•
Completed a knowledge and skills inventory for all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.


•
Conducted an employee preference survey so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
could be given the opportunity to work in the areas that interest
and energize them in light of our institutional needs.


•
Implemented an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Candidate Development Program</ENAMEX> to
prepare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for assignments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SES</ENAMEX>.


•
Initiated a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Development Program</ENAMEX> for newly
hired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> to help them transition and progress.


•
Initiated a redesign of our training curriculum to
directly link and support our validated core
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">competencies</ENAMEX>.


•
Established an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employee Advisory Council</ENAMEX> to facilitate
open communication and direct input from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line employees</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.


•
Provided an on-site child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiny</ENAMEX>
Findings" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wellness and Fitness Center</ENAMEX>.


•
Implemented additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>-friendly benefits such as
business casual dress, flextime, and public transportation
subsidies.


•
Used recruitment bonuses, retention allowances, and
student loan repayment assistance to attract and retain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
with specialized skills.


•
Implemented a new "state of the art" performance
appraisal system that is linked to our strategic plan and based on
key competencies.


As we engage in these changes, we also know that we are not
perfect and we never will be. This is a work-in-progress for us as
it is for others. Our approaches are not the only way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
to proceed, but they can help others identify ways to address their
individual human capital challenges. In this regard, we have shared
our lessons and experiences with others, and are happy to do
so.
16 For more information on these efforts, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Capital</ENAMEX>:
Taking <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Steps to Meet Current and Emerging Human Capital Challenges</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-965T (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17, 2001</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T
In summary, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, I believe that there is no more
important management reform than for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to transform their
cultures to respond to the transition that is taking place in the
role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>. Strategic human capital
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> must be at the center of this transformation effort. We
all need to seize the momentum that has recently emerged-agencies
must use existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> to strategically manage their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> needs to consider some statutory changes in the short
term; and all interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> need to work together toward
enactment of more comprehensive civil service reform over time. I
look forward to continuing to work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OPM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMB</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Commission on the Public Service</ENAMEX>, and other
interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> as we jointly seek to ensure that the federal
government modernizes its human capital strategies in order to
maximize performance, assure accountability, transform itself, and
prepare for the future.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volcker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, this concludes
my statement. I would be pleased to respond to any questions that
you may have.
statement, please contact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>


Contact and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Mihm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Issues</ENAMEX>, on (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">202</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">512-6806</ENAMEX>
or at
Acknowledgments mihmj@<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">gao</TIMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gov. Individuals</ENAMEX> making key
contributions to this testimony included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Choi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rebecka Derr</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Kordahl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Rubin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Shames</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Stephenson</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">450140</ENAMEX>)




