



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
Testimony
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>

Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on Government Management</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Government Reform</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>/TOCG0010


Evolution of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turner</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX>:
I am pleased to appear before you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to discuss the work of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>). We welcome this opportunity to
highlight the important role that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> plays to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
for the benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
In my testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, I will discuss the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">national</ENAMEX> and
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> that confront our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
the ways in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> can support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> now and in the
future, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s performance in accomplishing its mission. While
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has evolved over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, its current mission is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">straightforward</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> exists to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in meeting its
constitutional responsibilities and to help improve the performance
and accountability of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the benefit of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> was created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX> as a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accounting</ENAMEX>
Act, a law designed to improve government financial controls and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in the aftermath of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I. Wartime</ENAMEX> spending had
increased the national debt, escalated costs for many government
purchases, and created substantial disarray in the financial
operations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">War Department</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
also recognized a need for better financial information and
controls over costs. As a result, the new law required the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to prepare an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget, and it transferred from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s auditing,
accounting, and claims functions.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s and 1930s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> focused on preaudit payment work
and whether government spending had been handled legally. The bulk
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work centered on the auditing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> vouchers; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> checked vouchers and settled the accounts of executive
branch disbursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Departments</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> sent their
vouchers to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, which checked the legality, propriety, and
accuracy of expenditures.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s workload increased in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> as federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">money</ENAMEX> poured
into New Deal recovery and relief efforts to combat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Depression</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin D. Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, which started out with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, had a workforce
that numbered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 5,000</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> remained
the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s activities, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> first began
doing fieldwork in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid1930s</TIMEX>. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> early fieldwork
assignment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> looked at the operation of government agriculture
programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and several southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
With the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> entry into <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> faced enormous
challenges. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> continued to do the same type of work it had
done before the war but with vastly increased volume. Defense
production soared after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> geared up to
meet the demands of war. Government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> expanded, churning out
mountains of expenditure forms for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to examine. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reviewed
defense contracts and audited the accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disbursing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. The war effort created a blizzard of
transportation vouchers for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to review as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> used
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s rails and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> to carry freight and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> hired
additional audit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> and freight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">examiners</ENAMEX>, nearly tripling the
size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 15,000</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>. The paperwork was so
intense that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> faced a backlog of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">35 million</NUMEX> unaudited vouchers
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX> and had to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> catching up on work.
Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> handled a staggering backlog of paperwork as a result
of the war: in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reconciled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">490 million</NUMEX> checks and audited
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92,000</NUMEX> accountable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>' accounts, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 million</NUMEX> transportation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vouchers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.5 million</NUMEX> contracts, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260 million</NUMEX> postal money
orders.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wartime</ENAMEX> experiences spelled the end of the voucherchecking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>. The increase in paperwork showed how difficult it was for a
single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to keep up with examining every government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disbursement</ENAMEX>. The war also highlighted a number of accountability
issues. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940s</TIMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> repeatedly
pointed to the lack of accountability of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>
and problems with contract fraud. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> applauded the passage in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Government Corporation Control Act</ENAMEX>, which authorized
the auditing of wholly owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government corporations</ENAMEX> and mixed
ownership <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. Responding to the requirements of the act,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> created a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation Audits Division</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. He began
hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> to perform <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> audits of government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>.
With passage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Budget and Accounting Procedures Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> as a whole shifted to comprehensive auditing of
government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Instead of concentrating on individual fiscal
transactions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> began reviewing financial management and internal
controls at government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Responsibility for checking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vouchers</ENAMEX> shifted to the various executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> focused
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prescribing</TIMEX> accounting principles, performing audits on agency
sites, and checking financial controls and procedures.
The move to comprehensive auditing represented a major turning
point for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>. At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> returned to its prewar size.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> reduced the number of voucher <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> in its employ and
began hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> began to emerge in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s and 1960s</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> responded to its new mission by recruiting and training a
broader array of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and working to set standards that
professionalized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>. To keep a watchful eye on spending
at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and abroad, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> formally established a network of field
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1950s</TIMEX> and opened
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>. The scope of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work expanded again
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> initiated the Great Society's
War on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty</ENAMEX>. The number of federal grantsinaid rose sharply and
the rapid growth in federally assisted programs placed enormous
administrative control burdens on government at all levels.
Let me note at this point that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptrollers General</ENAMEX> made
substantial contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, and I am particularly pleased to
be here with my immediate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elmer Staats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
Bowsher- both made enormous contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> came
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller General Staats</ENAMEX>, who took office in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>, and was a
driving force behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s emphasis on program evaluation and
making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s work more useful to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
The growth in congressionally based work, combined with the
expansion of government programs, was responsible for a significant
change in the makeup of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, mostly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accountants</ENAMEX>, began to change to fit these new assignments. In the
1970s, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> started recruiting social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> in such fields as health care, science,
public policy, and information <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, most of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> and management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> were reclassified as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evaluators</ENAMEX> to reflect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s varied work. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Staats'</TIMEX> tenure, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
relied on new technological tools as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> with diverse
academic degrees. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s and 1980s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> made
increasing use of computers in its audit and administrative
operations.
Staats was also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in recognizing the importance of
international interaction in the accountability field. He made
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization of Supreme Audit Institutions</ENAMEX> (INTOSAI), which
includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">179</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and he also created an international
fellows program at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to provide support, training, and guidance
to a cadre of key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> from accountability organizations
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worldwide</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eightynine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have participated in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Auditor Fellowship Program</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">279</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> have
graduated from the program since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>. Indeed, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> former fellows
have since become the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Auditors General</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and many more have served
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deputies</ENAMEX> or in other highlevel posts.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comptroller General Bowsher</ENAMEX> also made major contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
and to the improvement of financial management and government
operations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowsher</ENAMEX> continued the emphasis on personnel
improvement, strengthening the recruitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with diverse
professional backgrounds and providing them with improved tools and
work incentives. He expanded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s training curriculum and
strengthened the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Training Institute</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowsher</ENAMEX> also helped to lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s growing emphasis on
management reform and performance and accountability issues. During
his tenure, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowsher</ENAMEX> paid close attention to budget issues, warned
about the dangers of the increasing deficit, and worked to improve
federal financial management. In part due to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed a series of laws designed to
improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,


•
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Financial Officers</ENAMEX> Act-which created <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFOs</ENAMEX> in
all major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>;


•
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Government Performance and Results Act</ENAMEX>-which created
a requirement for measuring and reporting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>'
performance;


•
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995</ENAMEX>-which streamlined
government paperwork and reporting requirements;


•
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Government Management Reform Act</ENAMEX>-which requires the
government to prepare an annual consolidated financial statement
audited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>;


•
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Acquisition Streamlining Act</ENAMEX>-which is helping
to make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> acquisition more efficient and effective;
and


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">theSingleAudit Act</ENAMEX>.


During <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowsher</ENAMEX>'s tenure, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first</ENAMEX> began doing general
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">management</ENAMEX> reviews, which looked at broad organizational and
management issues at government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> also initiated a
series of highrisk reports, now issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every 2 years</TIMEX>, to provide
information on federal activities susceptible to waste, fraud,
abuse, and mismanagement.
When I became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1998</TIMEX>, I committed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> address issues that will define the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st century</TIMEX>.


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s Accomplishments
Today, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> conducts a wide range of financial and performance
audits and program evaluations and reviews the business and mission
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work covers everything from the challenges of
an aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and the demands of the information age to
emerging national security threats and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">complexities</ENAMEX> of
globalization. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is also committed to management reform-to
helping government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resultsoriented</ENAMEX> and accountable to the public.
Ultimately, we may find that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> needs a new name-the words
"general accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>" do not really capture our more complex
role anymore. It might be more appropriate to consider something
closer to "government accountability <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>." It more clearly
conveys our role and the expectations of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the press, and the public. It might also help us in our
recruiting efforts in the increasingly competitive marketplace.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s core values of accountability, integrity, and reliability
reflect its dedication to good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and professional
standards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Accountability</ENAMEX> describes the nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work in
helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> oversee federal programs and operations to ensure
effective and efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>'s work reflects integrity because it is professional,
objective, factbased, nonpartisan, nonideological, fair and
balanced. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> strives also for reliability by providing highquality
information that is timely, accurate, useful, clear, and
candid.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> relies on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> of highly trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> who
hold degrees in many academic disciplines, such as accounting, law,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">engineering</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, economics, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> and physical sciences. I am extremely proud of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">workforce</ENAMEX>, of its dedication and excellence, and of its service to
the betterment of government and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my principal
goals for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is that we not only work to improve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, but
that we also work to improve ourselves. I look for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to become a
model <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and I am convinced
that, because of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, we will achieve that goal.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, I am also proud of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s accomplishments in
supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and helping improve the performance and
accountability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for the benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> made substantial contributions to
help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the executive branch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> improve
government programs and services. It provided <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $20 billion</NUMEX>
in direct financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Page 5 GAO/</ENAMEX>TOCG0010
benefits, recommended <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 600</NUMEX> actions that have led to
improvements in government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, and provided <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">229</NUMEX> testimonies
requested by congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX>. While many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
contributions cannot be quantified in dollar terms, those that can
be quantified show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> returned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $57</NUMEX> for every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
appropriated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1999</TIMEX>.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Benefits</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> succeeds in its mission when its findings and
recommendations lead to improvements wherever federal dollars are
spent. The following examples illustrate some of the financial
benefits that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the executive branch
achieve:


•
To help the government better realize the value of its
assets, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> suggested ways the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
Energy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>) could increase the profitability of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> sold from the
federally owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Petroleum Reserve</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elk Hills</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> testified before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> would see a
greater return from the sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Elk Hills</ENAMEX> than from retaining
ownership. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s suggestions for changes to the sale process were
adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>, resulting in proceeds of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $1.5 billion</NUMEX> above
the original sale price.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to achieve greater savings from
more efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> recently enacted
legislation based in part on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s recommendations to strengthen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>'s safeguards against fraud and abuse. These improvements
saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $2.2 billion</NUMEX> over fiscal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years 1998 and 1999</TIMEX>. Similarly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> recommendations included in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> program legislation will produce a gradual reduction,
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2001</TIMEX>, in the overly generous "adjustment
factor" designed to compensate teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> for higher
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> costs. This legislative change is estimated to produce
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 billion</NUMEX> in savings for the program in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal years 1999</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has made recommendations to streamline the tax system
and help support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in its longterm fiscal decisions.
Based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s evaluations, for instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> changed the
tax laws pertaining to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned Income Tax Credit</ENAMEX>. Specifically,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> avoided <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated $1.3 billion</NUMEX> in payments for
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">5year</NUMEX> period ending in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 2000</TIMEX> through changes to the
wealth, capital gains, and passive income tests for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earned</ENAMEX>
Income <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Credit</ENAMEX> eligibility criteria. Similarly, as part of the
Small <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Business Job Protection Act</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> phased out tax
credits to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> for certain income earned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">possessions</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work on this issue contributed to an
estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX> in financial benefits for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal years 1996</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> also helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> identify and
reduce unnecessary spending. As part of its ongoing work in housing
issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has provided assistance to improve the accuracy of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>) budget and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resource</ENAMEX> estimates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s method for estimating
funding for its <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Section 8</ENAMEX> housing assistance resulted in requests
that exceeded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s needs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> directed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> to
submit revised estimates, after which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1998</TIMEX> budget
was reduced by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.3 billion</NUMEX> in light of the streamlined
projections. As a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> also rescinded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 billion</NUMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1998</TIMEX> supplemental request. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
recommendations helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> avoid additional costs of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $1.1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1999</TIMEX>. Based in part on these examples, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
audits and recommendations helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> save an estimated
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.3 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal years 1998 and 1999</TIMEX>.


•
Similarly, as part of its assistance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in
reviewing the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> (DOD) budget
request for military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> identified areas where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> could be reduced. These included excess manpower costs due
to over estimated military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> levels, unnecessary advance
pay, and funds not needed due to gains from changes in foreign
currency exchange rates. As a result of




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health and Safety</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> reduced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fiscal year 1999</TIMEX> military
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">personnel</ENAMEX> budget for active and reserve forces by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $609</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> without compromising overall readiness.
In addition to the financial benefits resulting from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s efforts also contribute to numerous qualitative
improvements in government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and services. During fiscal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> contributed to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">607</NUMEX> such benefits achieved by the
government, a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">13percent</NUMEX> increase over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year 1998</TIMEX>. Benefits
resulting from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s recommendations included better public safety
and consumer protection, more efficient and effective government
operations and services, help in ensuring <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year 2000 readiness</ENAMEX>, and
improvements to computer security.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>: Improved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Operations Resulting From GAO</ENAMEX>
Recommendations

Some examples of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s contributions to improved government
operations follow:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• GAO</ENAMEX> has assisted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in efforts to
improve public health. For example, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has issued a
series of reports on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> highlighting widespread inadequate
health care quality in some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. As part
of its evaluation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> made a series of recommendations to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Financing Administration</ENAMEX> (HCFA) for improvements to its
nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> survey process and for stronger enforcement in
instances when nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> repeatedly violate regulations and do
not correct deficiencies. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> developed a


More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Efficient Government</ENAMEX>
set of initiatives designed to improve patient care and
eliminate deficiencies. Based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HCFA</ENAMEX> now requires
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to investigate serious complaints alleging harm to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 days</TIMEX>, has proposed an expansion of its enforcement
programs by subjecting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> with repeated serious deficiencies to
immediate sanctions, and has revised the protocols that state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surveyors</ENAMEX> use to inspect nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> to better focus the
reviews.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s reports have also convinced some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to improve their
oversight of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. In response to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s finding that
serious complaints of poor nursing home care frequently are not
investigated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> approved funding
for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent</NUMEX> increase in its surveyor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and the state
agency revamped its processes to emphasize a faster review of
serious complaints.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has also made significant contributions to improving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal justice</ENAMEX>. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has reported on the prevalence
and costs of identity fraud involving the illegal use of another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s identifying information (such as name, date of birth, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> number) to commit financial crimes. Illegal
activities range from the unauthorized use of a credit card to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> takeover of financial accounts. Largely in response
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacted legislation that criminalized
the theft and misuse of personal identifying information and
provided legal recognition for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of fraud.


•
Transportation safety is another important area in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has helped to improve government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and the public's
quality of life. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> (FRA) had few regulations involving
passenger car safety for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> or commuter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rail</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. As a
result, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> provided little oversight of passenger car
safety. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> recommended that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> establish appropriate
criteria for the condition of safety control components on
passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. Addressing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s recommendation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRA</ENAMEX> established
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> structural safety standards for passenger equipment
and created more stringent safety standards for highspeed passenger
rail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>.


•
Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s large entitlement programs are
susceptible to fraud, waste, and mismanagement. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s contribution to improving government performance and
preventing fraud and waste is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Supplemental Security Income</ENAMEX>
(SSI) program-the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest cash assistance program for the
poor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> reported that the program's financial integrity was
ineffective because the program has overpaid


<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Page 9 GAO/</ENAMEX>TOCG0010
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $3.3 billion</NUMEX>. The magnitude of
overpayments, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Administration</ENAMEX>'s (SSA)
inability to recover outstanding SSI debt, led to the program's
inclusion on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s highrisk list. Based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSA</ENAMEX> is
expanding its use of online data to better verify financial
information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> and prevent future overpayments. SSA
is also seeking statutory authority for additional tools to recover
current overpayments.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">• GAO</ENAMEX> has played an important role in helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s computer security and make
more effective use of technology in the delivery of federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has been extremely concerned about the
government's ability to prevent intruders from accessing
government's extensive computer and information systems. As a
result, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has issued <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 80</NUMEX>
reports on data and systems security including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
recommendations for correcting both individual weaknesses and the
systemic causes of security problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work has led to
improvements in many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, including the development of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">entitywide</ENAMEX> security management practices. It has also led to
computer security and other information technologyrelated
legislation.
In addition to its reviews of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has
developed techniques and practices that can be applied across the
government. This work has made significant contributions to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>' abilities to develop and implement sound security
policies. The information security management practices identified
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s executive guides have been incorporated into policy
guidance at many federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. Additionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FederalInformationSystemControlsAuditManualis</ENAMEX> now used by most
major federal audit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> to evaluate computerrelated
controls.
In discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s contributions and accomplishments, it is
important that we engage in a select amount of research and
development work to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> can meet the institutional
needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> over the long term. This investment has made
major contributions to the performance, stability, and
accountability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the protection of tax dollars.
As I will discuss later in this testimony, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s flexibility to
engage in this important component of our work has been
increasingly constrained by other demands on our resources.
Among the most important work that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has done are reviews
related to the Year <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Y2K</NUMEX>) computing challenge. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work on
Y2K began through its research and development program, but the
vital importance of this issue has manifested itself in many
congressional requests for work that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> received in fiscal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years 1998 and 1999</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> designated Y2K as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">highrisk</ENAMEX> area to highlight the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s exposure. Throughout
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997, 1998</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> worked closely with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on Y2K
issues-including this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> created the Special
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year 2000 Technology Problem</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> called on
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee on Technology</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee on Science</ENAMEX> to lead its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Y2K</ENAMEX> monitoring. With leadership
from you, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, congressional
committees examined the implications of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> on various government
operations and in key economic sectors.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> produced a set of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> guides to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> confront
the problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> also issued <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 160</NUMEX> reports detailing specific
findings and made over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> recommendations to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Conversion</ENAMEX> for improving the
government's readiness. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> recommended that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Conversion</ENAMEX> require <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to
develop contingency plans for all critical core business processes.
Accordingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX> clarified its
contingency plan instructions and, along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Information</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers Council</ENAMEX>, adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s business continuity and contingency
planning guide for federal use, thus reducing the risks of
disruption to major programs and services.
Finally, let me note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is proud of its record in
providing timely service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. As figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> indicates,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has consistently improved its ability to promptly meet
congressional requests. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">96</TIMEX>
percent of its products on time.


Complex Issues and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Governance Challenges</ENAMEX>
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Product Timeliness</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Percent 100 9193 96</ENAMEX>
80
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67 60 40 20 0</NUMEX>


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FISCAL YEARS</ENAMEX>
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, as I am sure you appreciate, the issues
confronting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have grown more
complex in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. The pace of change has accelerated for
government and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as a whole. The increasing
challenges facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> over the long term have had a
longlasting impact on the nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and on
how it supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Where, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
existence, changes to its roles and responsibilities and to the
demands placed on it occurred more slowly, there is no question
that the environmental changes affecting its mission in recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> have been more persistent and have occurred more rapidly. In
fact, the timeline of major events in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s existence (see figure
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) reveals the increasing development, complexity and influence of
difficult public policy issues related to government activity and
our accountability mission:
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> History: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX> to the Present


Major



Renewed government

focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> financial laws created: Workload
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yellowbook</ENAMEX>_ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CFO Act GAO</ENAMEX>'s mission again due auditing

expands government deficit,

GPRA

and budget
Paperwork
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Workload</ENAMEX> expands-to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> standards issues
Reduction Act Begins field

exploads
shifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> and established
broadens
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinger-Cohen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and work during
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act Accounting the Great Management Reform Act</ENAMEX>
Act establishes <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Acquisition</ENAMEX>
Streamlining
Act
all add to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> workload while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> contracts
Likewise, it comes as no surprise that as a result of the
increasing complexity and breadth of issues facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> is availing itself of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s services and support on
an unprecedented and accelerating basis. While <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
work was done as a result of congressional requests in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, it was
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Overall, congressional requests for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> work
have increased from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>, at the start of the Staats
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>, to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX>, at the beginning of my term. Part of the reason
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'s increased reliance on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> is the
result of our ability to add unique value to the products and
service we provide. With the advent of agency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> general
and other similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is no longer the only federal
entity charged with improving the accountability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
Nevertheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that can consistently provide
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the executive branch with analysis, options, and
recommendations that are long range, broad, in coverage, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">integrated</ENAMEX> in the development and presentation of critical
information. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s efforts are multilateral and cognizant of the
international implications of issues ranging from security to the
environment. And they also reflect the nuances of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">federalism</ENAMEX>, ensuring that implications of service delivery and
devolution on state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and on the private and
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> are factored into all of its work. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>,
there is no question that effective stewardship must consider how
increasingly diverse approaches to public sector responsibilities
are leading to diffuse accountability.
I am convinced that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> is now entering another significant era
that will take its place on the timeline of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s historic
key events. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has worked hard to make the transition from an
accounting and preaudit environment to become a diversified,
multidisciplinary accountability and professional services
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>. As I have discussed, my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX> did a tremendous
amount to ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> had the capacity and capabilities to
serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and prepare for the future during their tenure.
And I,atthe startofthe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st century</TIMEX>, have begun to do the same
thing.
Clearly, much has already changed as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has grappled with this
critical transition. As the following graphs show, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> seen considerable changes in its staffing and budget
allocations-levels that, unfortunately, did not generally reflect
its workload and the growing demands placed on it by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
Reductions in its resource levels, combined with increases and
shifts in its workload have in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> to take
strong measures to more efficiently accomplish its mission. For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has taken significant steps to consolidate its field
office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has been able to close field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> both in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and overseas-much of it through attrition-and
achieve gains in productivity and collaborative work environments.
At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s flexibility has been reduced by extensive
changes to the mix of its products-as mentioned, virtually all of
its work is done at the request of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and an increasing
amount of that stems from mandates.
The following charts highlights the changes I am discussing:
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> Staff Levels
Number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTE</ENAMEX> staff
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6000</TIMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1966 1981 1999</ENAMEX> Fiscal Year
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">History of Field Office Structure</ENAMEX>
Number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Offices</ENAMEX>
50
46
40
30
20

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 11</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1988 1990 1992 1994</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1996 1998 2000</ENAMEX>
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Work Conducted</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>

In a nutshell, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> currently stands at an important crossroads
in its history and in its ability to provide the unique support the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> expect from it. Many of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">activities GAO</ENAMEX> has undertaken are designed to ensure that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> is properly positioned to fully support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> as it
faces the future.
Since I became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX>, one of the most important
activities in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has been engaged is the development of its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> strategic plan for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>. This document is a
blueprint for how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> as it continues to
face complex issues and challenges. Building on global changes that
are impacting society on a variety of levels, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s strategic plan
develops a comprehensive and focused structure of longterm goals
and objectives to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in its legislative,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oversight</ENAMEX>, and investigative roles. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> worked closely with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislative</ENAMEX> and committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, and staff
in the development of this strategic plan. Thus, this plan not only
incorporates congressional views about what it believes to be
important and emerging issues, it also establishes a framework for
seeing fundamental constitutional responsibilities in the context
of current challenges and emerging changes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming years</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has developed a set of strategic goals and objectives that
will help to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in its decisionmaking and improve
the performance and accountability of the executive branch. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
plan presents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> strategic goals that will help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
perform its constitutional responsibilities and ensure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s
ability to continue providing effective, quality support to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>.
The due diligence that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has expended to develop its strategic
plan in concert with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has identified a number of
complex issues that are not easily solved. These issues are
reflected in the goals and objectives of the plan and will serve as
the guide for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s work priorities in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming years</TIMEX>. Many of
these issues will take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to resolve satisfactorily, but by
focusing on these issues now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will be much better
positioned to meet its responsibilities for governing as it begins
to confront these current and emerging challenges.
There is no question that the cold war has ended, and we won. In
addition, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 30 years</TIMEX> of budget deficits, the combination
of hard choices and remarkable economic growth has led to budget
surpluses. As a result, we transition into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this new century</TIMEX> with
different security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> and an improved financial position
relatively free of the deficit constraints of the recent past. In
order to prepare effectively for the future, however, we must fully
explore the major dynamic that will shape the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and its
place in the world and adequately prepare the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to
meet the challenges that lie ahead. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX> is uniquely
positioned to consider these broadbased and crosscutting challenges
and what needs to be done to address them.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s strategic plan goals focus on how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> can help
support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in dealing with many complex issues and the
challenges of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. These goals, the strategic objectives,
and the major thematic issues that influence them are as
follows:
Provide Timely, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quality GAO</ENAMEX>'s first strategic goal focuses on
several of the aspirations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> defined by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Founders</ENAMEX>: "toestablishjustice,insure



Service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">domestictranquility…promotethegeneralwelfare</ENAMEX>,andsecurethe and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> blessingoflibertytoourselvesandourposterity…"The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s aging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> to Address and increasingly diverse
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, rapid technological change, and Current and Emerging
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' desire to improve the quality of life all have major
policy and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Challenges to the Wellbudgetary</ENAMEX> implications for the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In particular, growing
commitments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> will make it difficult for a smaller
generation


Being and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial</ENAMEX>
Security of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to finance competing claims
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s future.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> To support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in its decisionmaking in this
area, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> will focus significant resources on the following
important strategic objectives:


•
researching possible options to meet the health care
needs of an aging and diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>;


•
examining ways to ensure a secure retirement for older
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>;


•
reviewing the social safety net for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in
need;


•
supporting efforts to provide for an educated citizenry
and a productive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>;


•
helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> strengthen a system of justice that
is effective in controlling crime, illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, and illegal
immigration;


•
providing analysis and other support concerning the
effectiveness of investments in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">communities</ENAMEX> and economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>;


•
researching ways to increase responsible stewardship of
natural resources and the environment; and


•
helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> maintain a safe and efficient
national physical infrastructure.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the important issues that reflect this goal and its
objectives is Demographics. The profound changes forecast in the
age and composition of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> will have enormous
consequences for the retirement and health care entitlement
programs as well as programs supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is growing older. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2030</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is projected to be over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 65</TIMEX>, compared with about
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. Also by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2030</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX>, who
include the disabled as well as the elderly, are expected to
account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The result will be that
fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> will be paying into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> for every person
receiving benefits. As shown in figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>
were paying into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> receiving
benefits. Today, the ratio is down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.4 to 1</NUMEX>, and, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2030</TIMEX>, it is
projected to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2 to 1</NUMEX>.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Workers per Beneficiary</ENAMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1955 1965 1975 1985 1995 2005 2015 2025 2035 2045 2055 2065</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2075</TIMEX>
Note: Projections based on intermediate assumptions of The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> Report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Board of Trustees of the Federal OldAge and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Survivors Insurance and Disability Insurance Trust Funds</ENAMEX>.
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of the Actuary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
Administration.
These trends will have enormous financial repercussions for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">solvency</ENAMEX> and sustainability of federal entitlement programs. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Hospital Trust Fund</ENAMEX> has operated in the red since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> and
is projected to face insolvency in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2025</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
expenditures are expected to exceed payroll tax revenues beginning
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2015</TIMEX>, with trust funds being depleted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2037</TIMEX>.
But crafting a solution to financing these entitlement programs
involves more than the traditional approach of closing the gap
between projected expenditures and revenues over a fixed time
period, such as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75 years</TIMEX>. Rather, any financing solution needs to
achieve sustainablesolvency that balances projected expenditures
and revenues without requiring us to frequently revisit the
financing of these programs.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare's Hospital Insurance Trust Fund Faces</ENAMEX>
Insolvency in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50 0</NUMEX>
Billio ns o f <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 0 0 0</NUMEX> d olla rs
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 0</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500 19 90 19 95 20 00 20 05 20 10 20 15 20 20 20 25 20 30 20 35</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 40 20 45 20 50</NUMEX>

C ash surplus/d eficit H o s pital <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insura</ENAMEX> nce trus t fund b ala
nc e
Note: Projections based on intermediate assumptions of The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> Report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Board of Trustees of the Federal</ENAMEX> Hospital
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insurance Trust Fund</ENAMEX>.
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> analysis of data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office Management</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of the Actuary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Financing</ENAMEX>
Administration.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 00</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> ollar sin Billion s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 0 0</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 0 0</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 0 0</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 0 0</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 0 0 20 0 5 20 1 0 20 1 5 20 2 0 20 2 5 20 3 0 20 3 5 20 40 20</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 5 20 5 0</NUMEX>
C a s h s u rplu s/d e f icit <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Tru st fu</ENAMEX> nds bal a n c e
Note: Projections based on intermediate assumptions of The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> Report of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal OldAge and Survivors Insurance</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disability Trust Funds</ENAMEX>.
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> analysis of data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of the Chief</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Actuary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Administration</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is also becoming more diverse. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> as a proportion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX> have grown
significantly. This trend, along with the increased use of parttime
and other flexible work arrangements, has implications for federal
policies and programs related to education, training, childcare,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immigration</ENAMEX>, and retirement, and other areas. Although the
increased presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> caused substantial
growth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent decades</TIMEX>, this trend seems
to be changing. Projections for the future are that the annual
growth in the labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> will be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 1 percent</NUMEX> in the short
term and that this growth rate may even decline over the long term.
These trends further exacerbate the current tight labor market for
specialized skills and key sections of the economy, suggesting the
need for more policies designed to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to retreat
gradually from work rather than plunge into retirement.
Another major concern is Quality of life. It has improved for
many but not for all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. At the same time, prosperity is
placing greater stresses on the quality of life.
The long period of strong economic performance has been
accompanied by economic prosperity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are typically living
longer, with average life expectancy rising to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 76</TIMEX> over the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>, while unemployment has fallen to low levels, and violent
crimes have dropped by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. The quality of the
physical environment has also improved, as levels of major air and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water pollutants</ENAMEX> have dropped since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>.
However, many challenges remain. For example, the disparities
between the net worth of those without a high school education and
those with more education increased <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1989 and 1998</TIMEX>. While
unemployment has reached record or nearrecord lows for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AfricanAmericans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>, unemployment rates for these two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> still stand at nearly twice the rate for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, and more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> lack health insurance. Given the large
federal role in health care delivery and financing, there is a need
to weigh the needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> against their wants and the overall
affordability of health care considered by policymakers.
At the same time prosperity is placing greater stresses on
quality of life. Greater economic activity, for example, increases
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">air</ENAMEX> and highway traffic and heightens concerns about congestion,
safety, and environmental quality. The shift to a more
technologically based economy raises long term concerns about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, while population growth and geographic shifts, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> sprawl, place greater strains on transportation and other
infrastructure. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming years</TIMEX>, these demands for new
investment will increasingly come into competition with other
national priorities, creating difficult choices for the federal
government.
Provide Timely, Quality As the world grows more interconnected
through open markets and technology, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> faces
threats to its national security and


Service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> economy from new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Simultaneously, the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is
trying to promote foreign policy goals, sound trade policies,
and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> to Respond to strategies to help nations
around the world that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> now Changing Threats to
depends on as military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> and trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> expects to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security</ENAMEX> and the continue its role in supporting efforts
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the executive
branch to assess and respond to changing threats to national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> and


Challenges of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global</ENAMEX>
Interdependence the challenges of global interdependence.
To support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in its decisionmaking in this area, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
will focus significant resources on the following important
strategic objectives:


•
helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> respond to diffuse threats to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> and global security,


•
providing analysis and other support to ensure military
capabilities and readiness,


•
supporting efforts to advance and protect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
international interests, and


•
reviewing ways to recognize and respond to the impact of
global market forces on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economic and security
interests.


Several of the important themes influencing this goal and its
objectives include globalization and national security.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Globalization</ENAMEX>, or the interdependence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>, economies,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, presents new opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>, but also new challenges for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
With rapid advances in technology and the ease with which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>, and goods can cross borders, the economies and
activities of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> have become increasingly interdependent. From
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960 through 1997</TIMEX>, world exports increased from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 12 percent</NUMEX> to
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 24 percent</NUMEX> of world GDP (gross domestic product).
Multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> are an important part of the trend
towards globalization. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63 percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exports and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> imports were associated with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent corporations</ENAMEX> or their foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX>.

10
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">0 1960 1965 1970 1975 1980 1985 1990 1995</ENAMEX>
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has been a principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of an open
world trading system and has benefited greatly. However, open trade
has increased the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">complexities</ENAMEX> of maintaining the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy.
Interdependence of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and foreign economies is illustrated by foreign investment
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
business, which has increased to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $200 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, an
amount <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly three</NUMEX> times that invested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX>.
As the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy becomes increasingly linked with the global
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>, international trade is growing in importance as a foreign
policy issue. At the same time, significant national security
issues also need to be considered. The effectiveness of regional
and global trade arrangements in achieving their desired outcomes
is being questioned at home and abroad. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> have expressed
concern that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has not been sufficiently aggressive
in monitoring and enforcing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over 300</NUMEX> international trade agreements
that cover <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of billions of dollars</NUMEX> in trade and affect
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> jobs, and that some decisions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> could compromise <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sovereignty.
Recent financial crises in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> highlight the
implications of the interdependence of economies and financial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>. For example, the emergence of financial difficulties in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> was followed by financial crises in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, and eventually <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>. Fear that these crises
could severely affect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economic and security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> have (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>)
focused attention on the interdependence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and global
economies and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) raised questions about what can be done to
prevent or contain the spread of such crises. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monetary Fund</ENAMEX> is a key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
cooperates with to maintain global economic stability. Prompted by
financial crises and government corruption in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>,
questions have been raised regarding their effectiveness and roles
in maintaining the health of the global finance and trade systems
and resolving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' financial crises.
Economic and financial interdependence are not the only global
trends with implications for this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Increased globalization
of information technology has resulted in significant new security
and privacy threats to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s information network. Similarly,
the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> around the world, like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, and the global
nature of environmental problems affect us and also call for a
coordinated international response. Thus, in the future, federal
responses to problems will increasingly have to consider
international as well as national dimensions.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> reflect new, diverse, and diffuse
threats of national, economic, and personal dimensions. Less
restricted trade, expanding democracy and capitalism, and rapidly
developing technology have broadened security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> and changed
the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> prepares for conflict. In addition to
more conventional military threats, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is
confronting threats from terrorism; the proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX> destruction; information warfare; the international drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX>; and other more diffuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, which are harder to
identify, respond to, and contain. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> shows the countries
that possess <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction posing national security
concerns to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>.
The bombings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> have elevated concerns about the spread of terrorism to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 40</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, and bureaus
spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $10 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to combat terrorism.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> armed forces has been reviewed a number of
times since the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, resulting in substantial
reductions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has expressed concern that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> that
remain may not be sufficient to implement the national military
strategy and may not be sufficiently prepared to respond to the
threats of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
proposed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> begin the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sustained increase in defense
spending in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX>, calling for additional resources totaling
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$112 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 6 years</TIMEX>. In particular, defending the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> against an intercontinental ballistic missile attack
from a rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and allied deployed forces
from theater missile attacks is receiving considerable attention.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, activities leading to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s deployment
decision on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Missile Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> are moving ahead and
improvements to key theater missile defense systems, such as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater High Altitude Area Defense</ENAMEX> system, are being instituted.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> has proposed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $24 billion</NUMEX> in total funding of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> and theater missile defense from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001 through 2005</TIMEX>.
Should disruptions occur, increasing reliance on complex
interconnected computer systems essential to public wellbeing and
the economy has created serious new vulnerabilities. Protection of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX>, energy, emergency services, financial services, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> systems is becoming increasingly important because
they rely heavily on information technology. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Criminals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>,
and others, working anonymously from remote locations and with
relatively limited resources, can now use computers to severely
disrupt this infrastructure. An example of disruptions that could
occur is provided by recent denialofservice attacks on popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">websites</ENAMEX>.
Support the Transition to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> are increasingly
demanding improved government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> and better stewardship of
public resources. The federal


More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ResultsOriented</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Accountable Federal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is adopting the principles of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">performancebased</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> in an effort to address these demands.
This approach to managing
Government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> systematically integrates thinking about
organizational <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>; program and service delivery strategies;
and the use of technology, reliable financial information, and
effective human capital practices into government decisions. Many
initiatives now under way across <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to improve operations
and strengthen accountability are being driven by management
reforms statutorily established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
The reforms that have been adopted so far have profound
implications for what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does, how it is organized, and how
it performs its services to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
Consequently, government decisionmakers and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> are adopting
new ways of thinking, considering different ways of achieving
goals, and using new information to guide decisions. At the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, with budget surpluses now projected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming years</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> faces a new set of challenges, in both the near and
long terms, in making budget decisions.
To support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in its decisionmaking in this area, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
will focus significant resources on the following important
strategic objectives:


•
analyzing the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s longterm and nearterm
fiscal position, outlook, and options;


•
examining ways to strengthen approaches for financing the
government and determining accountability for the use of taxpayer
dollars;


•
facilitating governmentwide management and institutional
reforms needed to build and sustain highperforming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
and more effective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>; and


•
recommending economy, efficiency, and effectiveness
improvements in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> programs.


A number of important issues influence this goal and its
objectives. They include a stable federal budgetary future,
technological innovation, and improvements in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> and
service provision of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
Future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> Issues. Our federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has gone from
budget deficit to surplus as a result of a burgeoning economy and
difficult decisions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the executive branch to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> spending. Compared to the deficits of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent decades</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s surplus represents a historic turnaround, and current
projections show surpluses continuing over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 10year</TIMEX> budget
window, as figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> illustrates.
Percentage of GDP
25
20
15
10
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1950 1955 1960 1965 1970 1975 1980 1985 1990 1995 2000 2005</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX>

Surplus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO Projection</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Growth of Spending Federal Revenues</ENAMEX>
Federal Spending

at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rate of Inflation</ENAMEX>)
Deficit
Note: These projections assume that discretionary spending grows
at the rate of inflation after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>, Fiscal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> 2001,Office
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management and Budget</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX> projections.
This picture of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s fiscal good fortune, however, masks a
change in the composition of federal spending during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. Relative to federal spending subject to annual
appropriations-defense and nondefense discretionary spending-the
share devoted to federal health programs and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
payments has grown steadily over time. Correspondingly, the share
available for all other programs, including defense, has decreased,
as shown in figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>.
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Distribution of Federal</ENAMEX> Spending, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">196299</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">196 2 1974</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX>




<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 %</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De</ENAMEX> fense
So cial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Se</ENAMEX> curity <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX>
Health <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1%</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ne t Inte</ENAMEX> rest
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX>

Othe r <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">198 6</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>

<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11% 20 %</NUMEX>
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>, Fiscal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2001</TIMEX>.
Our longterm projections illustrate the consequences for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> budget, assuming that these trends continue. While we may
enjoy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> surpluses for some time, longterm projections show a
resumption of a pattern of deficits emerging after the anticipated
demographic tidal wave hits. Because of this coming demographic
shift, to move into the future without making changes to federal
retirement and health programs- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>-is to envision a very different role for the federal
government. Even assuming, for example, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> adhere to the oftenstated goal of saving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security surpluses, our longterm model shows a world by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2030</TIMEX> in
which these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> programs alone would require almost threequarters
of total federal revenue. Budgetary flexibility would be
drastically constrained, and little room would be left for such
spending on programs for national defense, the young,
infrastructure, and law enforcement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> will increasingly need to distinguish between wants,
needs, and affordability of programs and services in the coming
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> shows spending as a share of GDP under the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eliminate NonSocial Security Surpluses" simulation</ENAMEX>.
P e rce nto fG D P
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Composition</ENAMEX> of Spending as a Share of GDP Under
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eliminate NonSocial Security Surpluses</ENAMEX>" Simulation
40
30
Revenue
20
10
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0</NUMEX>

<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2000 2030 2050</ENAMEX>
So cial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Se c urity Medica re & M</ENAMEX> edicaid

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ne t Interest</ENAMEX>
All o ther spending
Note: Revenue as a share of GDP falls from its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> level of
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20.3 percent</NUMEX> to slightly below <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX>'s level due to unspecified
permanent policy actions that reduce revenue and increase spending
to eliminate the nonSocial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> surpluses. The "Eliminate
NonSocial Security Surpluses" simulation can only be run through
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2068</TIMEX> due to the elimination of the capital stock.
Source: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2000</TIMEX> analysis.
In addition there are other looming fiscal pressures, such
as:


•
cleanup costs from federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> that yield
hazardous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wastes</ENAMEX>, including defense <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and weapon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>;


•
future claims on federal insurance programs by an
increasing number of retired federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>; and


•
demands for new investment to modernize physical
infrastructure, public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, transportation systems, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sewage</ENAMEX> and water treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> that are beginning to deteriorate
or become obsolete.


<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s surplus represents both opportunity and obligation.
While the new surplus projections offer an opportunity to address
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s needs, we should not forget our stewardship responsibility
to reduce the debt burden and increase the choices we leave to
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>, to provide a strong foundation for future
economic growth and to ensure that future commitments are both
adequate and affordable. Continued debt reduction and entitlement
reforms are both critical to promoting a more sustainable budget
and economy for the long term. In the nearand mediumterm, surpluses
will depend on continued economic growth and fiscal restraint.
Technological innovation, especially in information technology,
has enhanced productivity, but also created new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vulnerabilities</ENAMEX>.
Information technology has transformed the ways we communicate,
learn, use information, conduct commerce, practice health care, and
build and design products. This trend is expected to accelerate,
with investment in information technology expected to account for
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of all capital investment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Roughly 172 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around the world will have Internet
access in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> and that number is expected to
double. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Businesses</ENAMEX> that produce computers, software,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">semiconductors</ENAMEX>, and communications equipment have accounted for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a third</NUMEX> of the growth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.
Government too is being affected, with information technology
providing new, more responsive and efficient ways of delivering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> and information to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, in such areas as tax
administration, higher education, transportation safety, and
environmental protection.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions 350.0</NUMEX>
