



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>
Testimony
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>

Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Select Committee on Homeland Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX>
For <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Release</ENAMEX> on Delivery Expected at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:00 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17, 2002</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HOMELAND SECURITY</ENAMEX>



Critical Design and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Implementation</ENAMEX> Issues

Statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Walker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Comptroller General</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>
a


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-957T

Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Select Committee</ENAMEX>:

Thank you for the opportunity to appear before
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Select Committee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to discuss one of the most important
issues of our time, the reorganization of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and
the reorientation of their missions to improve our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s ability
to better protect our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX>. It is important to recognize that
this transition to a more effective <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security approach is
part of a larger transformation effort that our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must
make to address emerging security, economic, demographic,
scientific, technological, fiscal and other challenges of the st
timely, quality and cost-effective public services.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the months</TIMEX> since the horrible events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11th</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> have responded with important and
aggressive actions to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, including creating an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX> (OHS), passing new laws such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Patriot Act</ENAMEX> and an initial emergency supplemental spending bill,
establishing a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> to improve transportation security, and
working with unprecedented collaboration with federal, state, and
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, private sector <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, non-governmental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to prevent future terrorist acts
and to bring to justice those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> responsible for such
terrible acts.
More recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> have sought to
remedy longstanding issues and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
homeland security functions by proposing greater consolidation and
coordination of various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and activities. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 6th</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> announced a proposal to establish a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX> (DHS) and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 18th</TIMEX> he transmitted draft
legislation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for its consideration. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> have worked diligently on these issues and this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Select Committee</ENAMEX> is now deliberating on a variety of proposals and
issues raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittees</ENAMEX>.
In my testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, I will focus on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major issues that we
believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should consider creating a new cabinet
department principally dedicated to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> strategy and criteria needed to guide any reorganization
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security activities and to help evaluate which agencies
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> should be included in or left out of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX>; and
(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) key issues related to the successful implementation of, and
transition to, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, cost and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phasing</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> challenges. Our testimony is based
largely on our previous and ongoing work on national preparedness
issues1, as well as a review of the proposed legislation.
In response to global challenges the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> faces in the
coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, we have a unique opportunity to create an extremely
effective and performance-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that can strengthen
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s ability to protect its borders and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> against
terrorism. There is likely to be considerable benefit over time
from restructuring some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security functions,
including reducing risk and improving the economy, efficiency, and
effectiveness of these consolidated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and programs. Sorting
out those programs and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that would most benefit from
consolidation versus those in which dual missions must be balanced
in order to achieve a more effective fit in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> is a difficult but
critical task. Moreover, the magnitude of the challenges that the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> faces will clearly require substantial time and
effort, and will take institutional continuity and additional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> to make it fully effective. Numerous complicated issues
will need to be resolved in the short term, including a
harmonization of the communication systems, information technology
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX>, human capital systems, the physical location of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
other assets, and many other factors. Implementation of the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> will be an extremely complex task and will ultimately
take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to achieve. Given the magnitude of the endeavor, not
everything can be achieved at the same time and a deliberate
phasing of some operations will be necessary. As a result, it will
be important for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to focus on: articulating a
clear overarching mission and core values; establishing a short
list of initial critical priorities; assuring effective
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> and information systems; and developing an overall
implementation plan for the new national strategy and related
reorganization. Further, effective performance and risk management
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> must be established, and work must be completed on threat
and vulnerability assessments.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> See "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Related GAO Products</ENAMEX>" at the end of this testimony.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, in its deliberations on creating
a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, should pay



<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>

special attention to
strategy, criteria and priorities for reorganization critical to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s efforts to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> from terrorism.


Reorganization
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security Strategy</ENAMEX>
In recent testimony before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> urged that the
proposal for establishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> should not be considered a substitute
for, nor should it supplant, the timely issuance of a national
homeland security strategy.2 Based on our prior work, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> believes
that the consolidation of some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security functions makes
sense and will, if properly organized and implemented, over time
lead to more efficient, effective, and coordinated programs; better
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> sharing; and a more robust protection of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
borders, and critical infrastructure. At the same time, the
proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet department</ENAMEX>, even with its multiple missions, will
still be just one of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> with important roles and
responsibilities for ensuring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security. At the federal
level, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> will require the involvement of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Intelligence Agency</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Bureau of</ENAMEX>
Investigation (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Marshals Service</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> (DOD), and a myriad of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. In addition, state
and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>, including law enforcement and first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">responder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, and the private sector also have critical
roles to play.
If anything, the multiplicity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> only reinforces the
recommendations that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has made in the past regarding the urgent
need for a comprehensive threat, risk, and vulnerability assessment
and a national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security strategy that can provide
direction and utility at all levels of government and across all
sectors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.3
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: Proposal
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet Agency</ENAMEX> Has <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Merit But Implementation Will Be Pivotal to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-886T(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25, 2002</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Combating Terrorism: Selected</ENAMEX>
Challenges and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Related Recommendations</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-822(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 20, 2001</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-957T
We are pleased that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> has just released the
national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security strategy and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> stands ready to work
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> to ensure that a sound and
strong strategy can be effectively implemented to protect the
country against terrorism. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has not had time to
thoroughly analyze the strategy yet, we previously suggested that
certain key elements be incorporated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security
strategy<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.4</NUMEX> We have indicated that a national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security
strategy should: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) clearly define and establish the need for
homeland security and its operational components, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) clarify the
appropriate roles and responsibilities of federal, state, and local
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entities</ENAMEX> and build a framework for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> for coordination,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX>, and collaboration, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) create specific
expectations for performance and accountability, including
establishing goals and performance indicators. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has
said the national strategy development and implementation should
include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) a regular update of a national-level threat and risk
assessment effort, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) formulate realistic budget and resource plans
to eliminate gaps, avoid duplicate effort, avoid "hitchhiker"
spending, and protect against federal funds being used to
substitute for funding that would have occurred anyway, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
coordinate the strategy for combating terrorism with efforts to
prevent, detect, and respond to computer-based attacks, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
coordinate agency implementation by reviewing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and
interagency programs to accomplish the national strategy, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>)
carefully choose the most appropriate policy tools of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to
best implement the national strategy and achieve national
goals.
Based on our preliminary review, some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> have
been addressed in the national strategy. In the past, the absence
of a broadbased <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security definition or the ad hoc creation
of a definition by individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government departments</ENAMEX> suggest that a
consistent and transparent definition be applied to help create a
more integrated approach and unified purpose. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s
national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security strategy does provide for a proposed
definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security, which should help the government
to more effectively administer, fund and coordinate activities both
inside and outside a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and to ensure that all parties
are focused on the same goals and objectives, results and outcomes.
It is critically important that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX>
agree on a definition since it serves as the foundation for a
number of key organizational, operational and funding
decisions.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">886T</NUMEX>.


Need for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criteria</ENAMEX> and Reorganization
Finally, I would also note that, in the past, we have suggested
that a central focal point such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OHS</ENAMEX> be established statutorily
in order to coordinate and oversee <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security policy within
a national framework<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.5</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, we re-emphasize the need for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OHS</ENAMEX> to
be established statutorily in order to effectively coordinate
activities beyond the scope of the proposed DHS and to assure
reasonable congressional oversight.
Often it has taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> for the consolidated functions in new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX> to effectively build on their combined strengths, and
it is not uncommon for these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> to remain as management
challenges for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. It is instructive to note that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>
legislation creating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> was further changed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949, 1953, 1958</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> in order to improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s
structural effectiveness. Despite these and other changes made by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has consistently reported over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 50 years</TIMEX> after the reorganization --
continues to face a number of serious management challenges. In
fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> government wide high-risk areas based on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s latest list, including the governmentwide high-risk areas of
human capital and computer security<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.6</NUMEX> This note of caution is not
intended to dissuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> from seeking logical and
important consolidations in government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and programs in
order to improve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX>. Rather, it is meant to
suggest that reorganizations of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> frequently
encounter start-up problems and unanticipated consequences that
result from the consolidations are unlikely to fully overcome
obstacles and challenges, and may require additional modifications
in the future to effectively achieve our collective goals for
defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> against terrorism<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.7</NUMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> faces a challenging and complex job in its
consideration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX>. On the one hand, there exists a certain
urgency to move rapidly in order to remedy known problems relating
to intelligence and information sharing and leveraging like
activities that have in the past and even today prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> from exercising as strong a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> defense as
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>:
Responsibility and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Accountability for Achieving National Goals</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-627T(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 11, 2002</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">High-Risk Series</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Update</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-263(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Implementation: The Missing</ENAMEX>
Link in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Reorganizations</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-GGD-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81-57</NUMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20, 1981</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-957T
emerging and potential threats warrant. Simultaneously, that
same urgency of purpose would suggest that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> be
extremely careful and deliberate in how it creates a new department
for defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> against terrorism. The urge to "do it
quickly" must be balanced by an equal need to "do it right." This
is necessary to ensure a consensus on identified problems and
needs, and to be sure that the solutions our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> legislates
and implements can effectively remedy the problems we face in a
timely manner. It is clear that fixing the wrong problems, or even
worse, fixing the right problems poorly, could cause more harm than
good in our efforts to defend our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> against terrorism.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has previously recommended that reorganizations should
emphasize an integrated approach; that reorganization plans should
be designed to achieve specific, identifiable goals; and that
careful attention to fundamental public sector management practices
and principles, such as strong financial, technology, and human
capital management, are critical to the successful implementation
of government reorganizations<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Similarly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has also suggested
that reorganizations may be warranted based on the significance of
the problems requiring resolution, as well as the extent and level
of coordination and interaction necessary with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> in
order to resolve problems or achieve overall objectives<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.9</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>, based on its own work as well as a review of other
applicable studies of approaches to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and structure
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, has concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should consider
utilizing specific criteria as a guide to creating and implementing
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. Specifically, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has developed a framework
that will help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the Administration create and
implement a strong and effective new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet department</ENAMEX> by
establishing criteria to be considered for constructing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> itself, determining which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> should be included
and excluded, and leveraging numerous key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> that, after completion of the revised organizational
structure, will be critical to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s success. Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
depicts the proposed framework:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Reorganization</ENAMEX>:
Issues and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Principles</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-GGD/AIMD-95-166</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observations on Elevating</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet Status</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> 
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21, 2002</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">552T</NUMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-957T
Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accountability Criteria</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>

With respect to criteria that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should consider for
constructing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> itself, the following questions about
the overall purpose and structure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> should be
evaluated:


•
Definition: Is there a clear and consistently applied
definition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security that will be used as a basis for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizing</ENAMEX> and managing the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>?


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Statutory Basis</ENAMEX>: Are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> of the new
department clear and complete in how they articulate roles and
responsibilities and do they sufficiently describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s
relationship with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>?


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clear Mission</ENAMEX>: What will the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> of the new
DHS be and how will it define success?



•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Performance-based Organization</ENAMEX>: Does the new department
have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> (e.g., Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Operating Officer</ENAMEX> (COO), etc.) and
statutory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> (e.g., human capital, sourcing) necessary to
meet performance expectations, be held accountable for results, and
leverage effective management approaches for achieving its mission
on a national basis?

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should also consider several very specific criteria in
its evaluation of whether individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or programs should be
included or excluded from the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. Those criteria
include the following:


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission Relevancy</ENAMEX>: Is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security a major part of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or program mission? Is it the primary mission of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> or program?


•
Similar <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Goals and Objectives</ENAMEX>: Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or program
being considered for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> share primary goals and
objectives with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or programs being
consolidated?


•
Leverage Effectiveness: Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or program being
considered for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> create synergy and help to
leverage the effectiveness of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and programs or the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> as a whole? In other words, is the whole greater
than the sum of the parts?


•
Gains Through Consolidation: Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or program
being considered for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> improve the efficiency and
effectiveness of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> through eliminating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">duplications</ENAMEX> and overlaps, closing gaps, and aligning or merging
common roles and responsibilities?


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Integrated Information Sharing/Coordination</ENAMEX>: Does the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> or program being considered for the new department
contribute to or leverage the ability of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to
enhance the sharing of critical information or otherwise improve
the coordination of missions and activities related to homeland
security?


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Compatible Cultures</ENAMEX>: Can the organizational culture of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or program being considered for the new department
effectively meld with


the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> that will be consolidated? Field structures
and
approaches to achieving missions vary considerably between
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.



•
Impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excluded Agencies</ENAMEX>: What is the impact on
departments losing components to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX>? What is the impact on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> left out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX>?

In addition to the above criteria that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should
consider when evaluating what to include and exclude from the
proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX>, there are certain critical success factors the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> should emphasize in its initial implementation phase.
Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has made observations and recommendations about
many of these success factors, based on effective management of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, technology, financial, and other issues, especially in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biannual Performance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Accountability Series</ENAMEX> on major government
departments<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.10</NUMEX> These factors include the following:


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Planning</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leading</ENAMEX> results-oriented
organizations focus on the process of strategic planning that
includes involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX>, assessment of internal and
external environments, and an alignment of activities, core
processes and resources to support mission-related
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outcomes</ENAMEX>.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Organizational Alignment</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> should be aligned to be consistent with the goals and
objectives established in the strategic plan.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications</ENAMEX>: Effective communication strategies are
key to any major consolidation or transformation effort.


•
Building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Partnerships</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the key challenges of this
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> will be the development and maintenance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX>
security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> at all levels of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the private
sector, both in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and overseas.


•
Performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX>: An effective performance
management system fosters institutional, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> and individual
accountability.


<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Major Management Challenges</ENAMEX>
and Program Risks: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmentwide Perspective</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-241(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-957T


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Capital Strategy</ENAMEX>: The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> must ensure
that its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> are not adversely impacted by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s pending human capital crisis, and that it can
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recruit</ENAMEX>, retain, and reward a talented and motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>,
which has required core competencies, to achieve its mission and
objectives. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> factor is a critical element in any major
consolidation or transformation.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Management and Technology</ENAMEX>: The new department
should leverage state-of-the art enabling technology to enhance its
ability to transform capabilities and capacities to share and act
upon timely, quality information about terrorist
threats.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knowledge Management</ENAMEX>: The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> must ensure it
makes maximum use of the collective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of knowledge that will be
brought together in the consolidation.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Management</ENAMEX>: The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> has a
stewardship obligation to prevent fraud, waste and abuse; to use
tax dollars appropriately; and to ensure financial accountability
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.


•
Acquisition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX>: Anticipated as one of the largest
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, the proposed DHS will potentially have some of
the most extensive acquisition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> needs. Early attention to
strong systems and controls for acquisition and related business
processes will be critical both to ensuring success and maintaining
integrity and accountability.


•
Risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Management</ENAMEX>: The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> must be able to
maintain and enhance current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security readiness
while transitioning and transforming itself into a more effective
and efficient structural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>. The proposed DHS will also need to
immediately improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s overall ability to perform
risk management activities that can help to prevent, defend
against, and respond to terrorist acts.


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Change Management</ENAMEX>: Assembling a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> out of
separate pieces and reorienting all of its processes and assets to
deliver the desired results while managing related risks will take
an organized, systematic approach to change. The new department
will require both




<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security Reorganization</ENAMEX> and
Missions
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> and operational capability to encourage and manage
change.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s proposal for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> indicates that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX>, in addition to its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security responsibilities, will
also be responsible for carrying out all other functions of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> and programs that are transferred to it. In fact, quite a
number of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> proposed to be transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> have
multiple functions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Agencies</ENAMEX> or programs that balance multiple
missions present the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> with significant issues that must be
evaluated in order to determine how best to achieve all of the
goals and objectives for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> was created. While we
have not found any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> that would appear to be in fundamental
conflict with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s primary mission of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>, as presented in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s proposal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
will need to consider whether many of the non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security
missions of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> will receive adequate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">funding</ENAMEX>, attention, visibility, and support when subsumed into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> that will be under tremendous pressure to succeed in its
primary mission. As important and vital as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> is to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s future, the other non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security
missions transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> for the most part are not small or
trivial responsibilities. Rather, they represent extremely
important functions executed by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that, absent
sufficient attention, could have serious implications for their
effective delivery and consequences for sectors of our economy,
health and safety, research programs and other significant
government functions. Some of these responsibilities include:


•
maritime safety and drug interdiction by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guard</ENAMEX>,


•
collection of commercial tariffs by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX>
Service,


•
public health research by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Services</ENAMEX>,


•
advanced energy and environmental research by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lawrence Livermore and Environmental Measurements</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>,


•
responding to floods and other natural disasters by the


•
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> over processing visas by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consular</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>.


These examples reveal that many non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security missions
could be integrated into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet department</ENAMEX> overwhelmingly
dedicated to protecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> from terrorism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may
wish to consider whether the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, as proposed, will
dedicate sufficient management capacity and accountability to
ensure the execution of nonhomeland security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX>, as well as
consider potential alternatives to the current framework for
handling these important functions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> alternative might be to
create a special accountability track that ensures that
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security functions are well supported and executed in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX>, including milestones for monitoring performance. Conversely,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> might separate out some of these functions. In doing
so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will still need to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> accountable for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> that are not incorporated in the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. In making these decisions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should consider the
criteria presented earlier in my testimony, especially those
related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> transitions, such as mission relevancy, similar
goals and objectives, leveraging effectiveness, and creating gains
through consolidation. There are clearly advantages and
disadvantages to all of the decisions about placing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or
programs with multiple missions in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> must carefully
weigh numerous important factors related to performance and
accountability in crafting the legislation.
For example, we have indicated in recent testimony that DHS
could serve to improve biomedical research and development
coordination because of the current fragmented state of disparate
activities. Yet, we remain concerned that the proposed transfer of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> and priority setting for research from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
where the research would be conducted could be disruptive to dual
purpose programs, which have important synergies for public health
programs that need to be maintained<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Similarly</ENAMEX>, we have testified
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s proposal, in tasking the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> with
developing national policy for and coordinating the federal
government's research and development efforts for responding to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemical</ENAMEX>, biological, radiological, and nuclear weapons threats,
also transfers some of the civilian research programs of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy.12 Again</ENAMEX>, there may be implications for
research synergy.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">New</ENAMEX>
Department Could <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Improve Biomedical R&D Coordination</ENAMEX> but May
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disrupt Dual-Purpose</ENAMEX> Efforts, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-924T(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9, 2002</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Title III</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Homeland Security Act of 2002</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-927T(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9, 2002</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-957T
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may also craft compromises that strengthen homeland
security while reducing concerns of program disruption or
unanticipated consequences. One such example is seen in recent
deliberations about the appropriate location for visa processing.
Congressional debate has focused on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of our criteria, mission
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relevancy</ENAMEX> and gains through consolidation. The visa function
attempts to facilitate legitimate travel while at the same time
denying entry to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> of certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>,
including potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. Some have argued that the mission
of the visa function is primarily related to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security and
that therefore the function should be located within the proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. Others have advocated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of State</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>) should retain the visa function because they believe that
there would be no gains from consolidation. They point out that
State has an established <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field structure</ENAMEX> and that it may be
impractical to create a similar field <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in the proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. The compromise position of several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> has been
to transfer responsibility for visa policy to the proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, while retaining the cadre of overseas visa officers
within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>.
As part of these deliberations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should consider not
only the mission and role that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> fulfill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> and role that they should fulfill in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming years</TIMEX>.
Thus, while it may be accurate that large portions of the missions
engaged in by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA</ENAMEX> today do not relate primarily
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security, it is wholly appropriate for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to
determine whether the future missions of such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> should focus
principally on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security. Such decisions, of course, would
require the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to determine the best approach for carrying
out a range of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> and operations, in order
to see that non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security activities of these departments
are still achieved. In fact, given the key trends identified in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>'s recent strategic plan for supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and our
long range fiscal challenges, it is appropriate to ask <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> key
questions: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) what should the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> do in the 21st
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>? (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) how should the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> do business in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st century</TIMEX>? and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) who should do the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
business in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>? These questions are relevant for DHS
and every other federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> and activity.
As the proposal to create <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> demonstrates, the terrorist events
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> have provided an impetus for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to look at
the larger picture of how it provides <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security and how it
can best accomplish associated missions. Yet, even for those
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that are not being integrated into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX>, there remains a
very real need and possibly a unique opportunity to rethink
approaches and priorities to enable them to better target their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> to address our most urgent needs. In some cases, the new
emphasis on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security has prompted attention to
longstanding problems that have suddenly become more pressing. For
example, we've mentioned in previous testimony the overlapping and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">duplicative</ENAMEX> food safety programs in the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.13</NUMEX> While
such overlap and duplication has been responsible for poor
coordination and inefficient allocation of resources, these issues
assume a new, and potentially more foreboding, meaning after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 11th</TIMEX> given the threat from bio-terrorism. In another
example, we have recommended combining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Domestic Preparedness</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA</ENAMEX> to improve
coordination<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.14</NUMEX> A consolidated approach to many of these issues can
facilitate a concerted and effective response to new threats and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> performance.
Similarly, we have conducted a number of reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>'s visa
function over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and, based on our work, we believe that
there are a number of areas in which the visa function can be
strengthened. For example, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> needs to ensure that there are sufficient staff
at overseas posts with the right training and experience to make
good decisions about who should and who should not receive a visa.
In addition, we are currently looking at ways that the visa
function can be strengthened as a screen against potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and we expect to make recommendations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this fiscal</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. These recommendations will apply regardless of decisions
about the respective roles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> and the proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX> regarding visa functions.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Safety and Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fundamental Changes Needed to</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ensure Safe Food</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> 
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10, 2001</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47T</NUMEX>).
14 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-822.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-957T


<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security Implementation</ENAMEX> and
Transition Issues
The ultimate effectiveness of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> will be
dependent on successfully addressing implementation and transition
issues. Picking the right leadership for these critical positions
in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> will be crucial to its success. If you don't
have the right leadership <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in key policy, operational and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management positions</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> will be at risk. In addition
providing the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> with some reasoned and reasonable
human capital, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and budget flexibilities combined with
appropriate safeguards to protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' constitutional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and to prevent abuse can also help contribute to a
successful transition. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Branch</ENAMEX>
have critical roles to play in achieving desired outcomes for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.


Key <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success Factors, Leadership</ENAMEX> and
Accountability
Among the most important elements for effectively implementing
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet department</ENAMEX> will be close adherence to the key
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> factors. Strategic planning, building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX>, human
capital strategies, financial management and other critical factors
will make the difference between a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> that can quickly rise
to the challenge of its mission and one that might otherwise become
mired in major problems and obstacles that hamper efforts to
protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> from terrorism.
The quality and continuity of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> is
critical to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and sustaining the long-term effectiveness of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security goals and objectives. The experiences of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> that have undertaken transformational change efforts
along the lines that will be necessary for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to be
fully effective suggest that this process can take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 5 to 10</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to provide meaningful and sustainable results. Given the
scope and nature of challenges facing the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, the
critical question is how can we ensure that the essential
transformation and management issues receive the sustained,
top-level attention that they require. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> can ill-afford to
have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> or deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> being side-tracked by
administrative and operational details -- the mission of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> requires their undivided attention.
As a result, it is important for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to give serious
consideration to creating a deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>/chief
operating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> (COO) position within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to provide
the sustained management attention essential for addressing key
infrastructure and stewardship issues while helping to facilitate
the transition and transformation process. Recent legislative
language adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Committee on Government Reform</ENAMEX>
suggests elevating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">undersecretary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> to a deputy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, equivalent to the deputy position provided for in the
Administration's proposal. We believe that is an important first
step to ensuring that transformation and management issues receive
the top-level attention they require. Raising the organizational
profile of transformation and management issues is important to
ensure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> has the authority needed to successfully
lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>-wide initiatives. We are not convinced that an
under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, on par with the other under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">secretaries</ENAMEX>, would necessarily have sufficient authority.
To provide further leadership and accountability for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may wish to consider several points:


•
First, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should consider making the deputy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>/COO a term appointment of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 7 years</TIMEX>,
subject to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> confirmation. A term appointment would provide
continuity that spans the tenure of the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and
thereby help to ensure that long-term stewardship issues are
addressed and change management initiatives are successfully
completed.


•
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, to further clarify accountability, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COO</ENAMEX> should
be subject to a clearly defined, results-oriented performance
contract with appropriate incentive, reward and accountability
mechanisms. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COO</ENAMEX> would be selected without regard to political
affiliation based on (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) demonstrated leadership skills in managing
large and complex <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) experience achieving
results in connection with "good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>" responsibilities and
initiatives. Requiring that both the performance contract and the
subsequent performance evaluation be made available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
would provide additional accountability and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transparency</ENAMEX>.


In addition to providing top-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and
accountability, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> will need to develop employee
performance management systems that can serve as a key tool for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">aligning</ENAMEX> institutional, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, and employee performance; achieving
results; accelerating change; managing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> on a
day-to-day basis; and facilitating communication throughout the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> so that discussions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and organizational
performance are integrated and ongoing<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.15</NUMEX> A cascading set of
resultsoriented performance agreements is one mechanism in a
performance management system that creates a "line of sight"
showing how individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> can contribute to overall
organizational goals<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.16</NUMEX>
Further accountability can be achieved by ensuring that all
relevant management laws are applied to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> (e.g,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Performance</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Results Act</ENAMEX> (GPRA), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Financial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officers</ENAMEX> Act, <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clinger-Cohen Act</ENAMEX>, etc.). These laws provide a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> for the management structure of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and a
basis for ensuring appropriate transparency and accountability.
15U.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S. General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Capital</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Principles</ENAMEX>
From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nine Private Sector Organizations</ENAMEX> 
, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/GGD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-28</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31, 2000</TIMEX>).
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing</ENAMEX> for Results:
Emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Benefits From Selected Agencies' Use of Performance</ENAMEX>
Agreements, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-115 (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 30, 2000</TIMEX>).
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-957T


Request for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Increased Human Capital</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Management Flexibilities</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s proposal includes a set of human capital and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management flexibilities</ENAMEX> for the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> believes that
its reasonable for certain flexibilities to be granted to the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> in such areas as human capital, provided that they are
accompanied by adequate transparency and accountability safeguards
designed to prevent abuse. Human capital and management flexibility
will help the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to reorganize, realign and transform
itself to achieve its important missions. Appropriate safeguards
can help to prevent abuse of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and provide adequate
monitoring mechanisms to gauge performance. For instance, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may wish to provide the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> with "early out"
and "buy out" authority in order to help quickly realign the
component <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX> and provide for future flexibility. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> might
consider new scientific and technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> tracks to encourage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recruitment</ENAMEX>, retention and rewarding of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with critical
knowledge, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may wish to provide the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> with
some limited term appointment authority. These and other suggested
flexibilities for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> should be viewed in the context of how
similar flexibilities have been exercised by other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> with
similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation Security</ENAMEX>
Administration (TSA), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
should also note that, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> has indicated in the past, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
are already accorded in law significant flexibilities, especially
with respect to human capital issues, but for a variety of reasons
they do not always take advantage of them<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> should use the
these existing flexibilities and be given others in areas where
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has done so with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal</ENAMEX>
Revenue Service, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX>).
In requesting human capital flexibilities, questions have been
raised about whether they would result in eroding merit principles,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">veterans</ENAMEX>' preferences, whistleblower protections, collective
bargaining and other basic civil service provisions. Recent
testimony to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governor Ridge</ENAMEX> has clarified the
Administration's commitment to these provisions.18 The final
legislation should clearly reflect the applicability of these
tenets to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Managing For Results: Using</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategic Human Capital Management</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drive</ENAMEX> Transformational
Change, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-940T(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 2002</TIMEX> ).
18 Statement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Ridge</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Homeland</ENAMEX>
Security to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Select Committee on Homeland Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15, 2002</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-957T


Request for Increased Budget
Flexibility
Other flexibilities, such as ones for acquisitions and
contracting, are included in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s proposal. Careful
analysis is needed to determine the need for additional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flexibilities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may want to consider not expressly
providing certain flexibilities in the initial legislation, but
rather providing a mechanism for expedited consideration of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flexibilities</ENAMEX> should the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> request them in the future.
For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> might wish to agree on rules specifying
procedures for consideration of proposed changes, time limits on
debate, or requirements that any amendments to future legislation
be strictly related to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX>. This would not be the blanket grant of
authority envisioned in the original <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Freedom to Manage</ENAMEX> proposal,
but it would permit both the executive branch and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to
feel confident that proposed changes would receive timely
consideration.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> has suggested that it needs a special grant
believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should be careful to distinguish between
those flexibilities that will solely enhance the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> of DHS
and those that might simultaneously raise other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, including
concerns about the constitutional responsibilities and prerogatives
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislative branch</ENAMEX>. For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s proposal
permits the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> to allocate funds as he sees fit, without
regard to the original purpose of the appropriations. Moreover,
there must be a system to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funds</ENAMEX> across
the wide range of existing budget accounts and program activities.
This is necessary not only for the budget resolution and
appropriations process, but also for tracking budget execution and
for accountability to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, through its appropriations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittees</ENAMEX>, has
proven quite adept at creating and granting the kind of flexibility
it sees as appropriate to any given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
flexibility over the timing of spending by varying the period of
fund availability: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> may receive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-year</TIMEX>, multi-year and
no-year [permanent] funds. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has granted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> varying
degrees of transfer or reprogramming authority. These flexibilities
are generally provided as part of the appropriations process and
consider the balance between accountability and flexibility to
ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in the spending of taxpayer
funds.
Over the longer term the creation of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> may also
be an opportune time to review the account structure of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component entities</ENAMEX>. Should the orientation of budget
accounts be shifted


DHS Transition Issues
toward the strategic goals defined in plans? Such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reorientation</ENAMEX> might facilitate the process of linking resource
allocation to results consistent with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPRA</ENAMEX>. Efforts designed to
rationalize the number of budget accounts within the new department
can serve to provide flexibility while ensuring accountability.
of the largest reorganizations ever undertaken and the difficulty
of this task should not be underestimated. Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s
proposal, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX> existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and programs and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170,000</NUMEX> people
would be integrated into the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> in order to strengthen
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s defense against terrorism. With an estimated budget
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> of the component parts of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37.45</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, successfully transitioning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in an endeavor
of this scale will take considerable time and
19
money. Careful and thorough planning will be critical to the
successful creation of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. While national needs
suggest a rapid reorganization of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> security functions, the
transition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and programs into the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> is
likely to take time to achieve. At the same time, the need for
speed to get the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> up and running must be balanced
with the need to maintain readiness for new and existing threats
during the transition period. Moreover, the organizational
transition of the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">components</ENAMEX> will simply be the starting
point - as implementation challenges beyond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> should
be expected in building a fully integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. As I stated
earlier, it could take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 to 10 years</TIMEX> to fully implement this
reorganization in an effective and sustainable manner.
A comprehensive transition plan needs to be developed. The
transition plan should establish a time table for the orderly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migration</ENAMEX> of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">component agency</ENAMEX> or program to the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, identify key objectives to be achieved during the first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> following the transfer, and describe the strategy for
achieving an orderly transition and sustaining mission performance.
More detailed implementation plans also will be necessary to
address business system, processes, and resource issues. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> has taken an important <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step by establishing a
transition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s proposal entitled The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Homeland</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2002</TIMEX>.
Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-957T
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has an important oversight role to play in helping to
ensure the effective implementation of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. In
addition to the transition plans, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should consider
requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> to submit regular progress reports on implementation
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and should also conduct periodic oversight
hearings to assess progress and performance. In this regard, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
stands ready to assist the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in conducting its oversight
role.
Increased cost must also be considered with regard to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s proposal. It is likely that over time consolidation of
functions within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHS</ENAMEX> may reduce costs below what otherwise would
have been the case if these functions continued to operate
separately. This, however, is unlikely to happen quickly. Moreover,
we should expect that any reorganization would incur start up costs
as well as require some funding for redundant activities to
maintain continuity of effort during the transition period. The
Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget Office</ENAMEX> (CBO) has estimated that the costs of
implementing the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $3 billion</NUMEX> over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next five years</TIMEX> with an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> estimate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 million</NUMEX> in FY2003
and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$225 million</NUMEX> thereafter. However, there are other transition
costs that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> acknowledges are not included in their estimates
beyond the cost to hire, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, and equip key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. The CBO
estimate assumes continuation of the existing multi-pay and
retirement systems--however unlikely-- and does not address the
potential need to cross-train existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>. Although the
purchase of new computer equipment, supplies and compatible
information management systems are included, no estimates are
provided for the cost to correct existing computer system
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">deficiencies</ENAMEX> nor the resources to support some system redundancy
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a period of time</TIMEX>. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> did not attempt to price the
relocation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to a central location.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> has argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX>'s estimates are inflated.
In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of the total <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> spending
will be for administrative costs, but that a proportionate share of
the costs to currently administer these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> will be
transferred. Depending on the decision to co-locate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and
the flexibilities ultimately provided to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> in
legislation--in particular a broad grant of transfer authority and
the ability to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> through non-reimbursable agreements with other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>-- these estimates may well change. More important than a
precise cost estimate of the transition, however, is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> that there will be short-term transition costs and that
these costs need to be made transparent. To fully recognize the
transition costs, in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should consider appropriating
for them separately.
In summary, I have discussed the reorganization of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX>
security functions and some critical factors for success. However,
the single most important element of a successful reorganization is
the sustained commitment of top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to modern, effective and
credible human capital strategies and to setting clear goals and
appropriate accountability mechanisms. Top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> involvement
and clear lines of accountability for making management
improvements are critical to overcoming an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s natural
resistance to change, marshalling the resources needed to improve
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, and building and maintaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>-wide
commitment to new ways of doing business. Organizational cultures
will not be transformed, and new visions and ways of doing business
will not take root without strong and sustained leadership. Strong
and visionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> will be vital to creating a unified,
focused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, as opposed to a group of separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> under
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">single</NUMEX> roof. Modern human capital strategies, including
implementing a credible, effective and equitable performance
management system that links institutional, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and
individual performance measurement and reward systems to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s strategic plan, core values and desired outcomes will
be critical to success.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, this concludes my written testimony. I would be
pleased to respond to any questions that you or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Select Committee</ENAMEX> may have at this time.


Related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Products</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">New</ENAMEX>
Department Could <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Improve Coordination</ENAMEX> but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transforming Control of Public Health Programs Raises Concerns</ENAMEX> (

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-

<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-954T</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 16, 2002</TIMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Department</ENAMEX> Could <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Improve Biomedical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">R&D Coordination</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">May Disrupt Dual-Purpose</ENAMEX> Efforts 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">924T</NUMEX>,<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Title III</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Homeland Security Act</ENAMEX> of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-927T</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9, 2002</TIMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intergovernmental Coordination</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partnerships Will Be Critical</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">899T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Department</ENAMEX> Could <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Improve Coordination</ENAMEX> but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May Complicate</ENAMEX> Priority Setting 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">893T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 28, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Department</ENAMEX> Could <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Improve Coordination But</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May Complicate Public Health</ENAMEX> Priority Setting ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">883T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25,2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: Proposal for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet Agency</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Has Merit</ENAMEX>, But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Implementation Will be Pivotal</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">886T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Key Elements to Unify Efforts Are Underway</ENAMEX>
but Uncertainty Remains ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02-610</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7, 2002</TIMEX>).
National <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Preparedness: Integrating New and Existing Technology</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Information Sharing</ENAMEX> into an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Effective Homeland Security</ENAMEX>
Strategy

(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">811T</NUMEX>,<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Responsibility And Accountability For</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Achieving National Goals</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-627T,April 11, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Preparedness</ENAMEX>: Integration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Local</ENAMEX>, and
Private <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sector Efforts Is Critical to an Effective National</ENAMEX>
Strategy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-621T, April 11, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Progress Made; More Direction</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership</ENAMEX>
Sought ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">490T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 12, 2002</TIMEX>).
Related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Products</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Challenges and Strategies in Addressing</ENAMEX>
Short- and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Long-Term National Needs</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">160T</NUMEX>,<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 7, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risk Management Approach Can Guide</ENAMEX>
Preparedness Efforts ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-208T, October 31, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: Need to Consider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>'s Role in Strengthening
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Preparedness</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-145T,October 15, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Key Elements</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risk Management</ENAMEX>
Approach

(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-150T,October 12, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeland Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Framework for Addressing the Nation</ENAMEX>'s
Issues

(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1158T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 21, 2001</TIMEX>).

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>:
Development of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Strategy</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Enhance State and</ENAMEX>
Local
Preparedness ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-550T, April 2, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Combating Terrorism: Enhancing Partnerships Through a National</ENAMEX>
Preparedness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strategy</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">549T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 28, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Critical Components</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Strategy</ENAMEX>
to Enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State and Local Preparedness</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">548T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intergovernmental Partnership</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
Strategy to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enhance State and Local Preparedness</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">547T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March22, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Key Aspects</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Strategy</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enhance State and Local Preparedness</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">473T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1, 2002</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Considerations For Investing Resources</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Biological Preparedness</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">01-162T,October 17, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Combating Terrorism: Selected Challenges and Related</ENAMEX>
Recommendations ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01-822</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 20, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Combating Terrorism: Actions Needed to Improve DOD</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antiterrorism Program Implementation and Management</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01-909</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 19, 2001</TIMEX>).
Related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Products</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Combating Terrorism: Comments on H.R. 525</ENAMEX> to Create a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council on Domestic Preparedness</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">555T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 9, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Combating Terrorism: Observations on Options to Improve the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Response</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">01-660T,April 24, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Combating Terrorism: Comments on Counterterrorism Leadership and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Strategy</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">556T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 27, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEMA Continues</ENAMEX> to Make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coordinating Preparedness and Response</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01-15</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Response Teams Provide Varied</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capabilities: Opportunities Remain to Improve Coordination</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14, November 30, 2000</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: Issues in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Counterterrorist</ENAMEX>
Programs

(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-NSIAD-00-145</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6, 2000</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: Need to <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Eliminate Duplicate Federal Weapons</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mass Destruction Training</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/NSIAD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">00-64</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21, 2000</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Combating Terrorism: Observations on the Threat</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical</ENAMEX> and
Biological Terrorism ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-NSIAD-00-50</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 20, 1999</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: Need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Comprehensive Threat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Risk</ENAMEX>
Assessments of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Biological Attack</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/NSIAD-99-163</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 7, 1999</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Observations</ENAMEX> on Growth in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
Programs

(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-NSIAD-99-181</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9, 1999</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Analysis of Potential Emergency Response</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equipment</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sustainment Costs</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/NSIAD-99-151</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9, 1999</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: Use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard Response Teams</ENAMEX> Is
Unclear

(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/NSIAD-99-110</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21, 1999</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: Issues to Be Resolved to Improve
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Counterterrorism Operations</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/NSIAD-99-135</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 13, 1999</TIMEX>).
Related <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO Products</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observations on Federal</ENAMEX> Spending to Combat
Terrorism 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-NSIAD/GGD-99-107</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11, 1999</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: Opportunities to Improve Domestic
Preparedness Program Focus and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Efficiency</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/NSIAD-99-3</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 12, 1998</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Observations on the Nunn-Lugar-Domenici</ENAMEX>
Domestic Preparedness Program 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">/T-NSIAD-99-16</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2, 1998</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Combating Terrorism: Threat and Risk Assessments Can Help</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prioritize</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target Program Investments</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/NSIAD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-74</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 9, 1998</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combating Terrorism</ENAMEX>: Spending on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governmentwide Programs</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Requires Better Management and Coordination</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO/NSIAD</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98-39</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,1997</NUMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health Bioterrorism</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disease Control</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevention</ENAMEX>'s Role in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health Protection</ENAMEX> (

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">02</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">235T</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 15, 2001</TIMEX>).
Bioterrorism: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health and Medical Preparedness</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-141T,October 10, 2001</TIMEX>).
Bioterrorism: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review of Public Health and Medical Preparedness</ENAMEX> (

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-149T, October 10, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Safety and Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fundamental Changes Needed to Ensure</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe Food</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-47T, October 10, 2001</TIMEX>).
Bioterrorism: <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Coordination and Preparedness</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02-129T, October</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,2001</NUMEX>).
Bioterrorism: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Research and Preparedness Activities</ENAMEX> 
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01</NUMEX>-
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">915</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 28, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Biological Defense: Improved Risk Assessments and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inventory Management Are Needed</ENAMEX> ( 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">01-667</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 28, 2001</TIMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">West Nile Virus Outbreak</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lessons for Public Health</ENAMEX>
Preparedness
