
 
     		
 	
 		so do you have any hobbies
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well right at the present time nothing real special i kind of like gardening and i'm kind of into camping and you know vacationing that sort of thing i don't have any real serious
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		i'm an avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		oh okay i think you're
 	
 	
 		um i consider that a hobby i don't know they were like suggesting like handcraft things which i guess that's a really true true hobby
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i i think anything that you enjoy
 		um it doesn't really have to matter i mean it could be working on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> could be your hobby really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well yeah i kind of enjoy doing that a little bit too
 	
 	
 		well did i
 	
 	
 		no i i guess if you make money at it it becomes a vocation then
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't know i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> i said you go out some to work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> it's not worth getting all mad and fighting and hollering at each other when it goes wrong i says you go pay to have someone do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because it always seems it goes wrong when you try to do something
 	
 	
 		i guess <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far</NUMEX> north as you are if you like gardening you've still got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple months</TIMEX> to go haven't you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah um well right now we um start our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> inside
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh yeah that's right you would yeah
 	
 	
 		we'll start them inside and uh
 	
 	
 		in cold frames or whatever the
 	
 	
 		yeah well we usually start them right in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> tries to set up a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">greenhouse</ENAMEX> on her back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">deck</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the wind a wind storm come and knock it down but she's had really good luck i mean it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> well actually it if you if you start it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and you can get your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> outside pretty much <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of May</TIMEX> you can leave them outside you might put them in the ground just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week of June</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but we can put <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> in the ground in the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		i've i've lived in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> most of my life but i did once i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one winter</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i i remember that it was on into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> before it really started warming up
 	
 	
 		yeah well well we live we live really close to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Champlain</ENAMEX> which is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Champlain Valley</ENAMEX> so we're a little we're about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ahead</TIMEX> of everyone else out on the outskirts so
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		oh yeah
 		okay because that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> the weather a little bit yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah we are a little lucky well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> lives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles from here and he gets <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">frost</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">crop</ENAMEX> gets killed
 	
 	
 		you're at
 		yeah
 		you're right across the uh lake from what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plattsburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Plattsburgh Air Force Base</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i had i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> that was stationed there
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		Plattsburgh for a while he he remembers lots of snow
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plattsburgh</ENAMEX>'s kind of a it's uh it's uh depressed economically
 	
 	
 		oh really oh
 	
 	
 		when you go across the lake um i don't know why we have so much going for us
 		i really don't i'm just wrote my resume up because told we might be facing layoff over at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital</ENAMEX> and they've never had well they've had layoffs recently but when we got hired here no no never any layoffs never never
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and now we're looking at serious i i mean i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> when they start getting rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i'm i'm working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> down here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i interviewed with them but i didn't want to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		even though my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i guess we have to get back to hobbies since
 	
 	
 		yeah we're getting to where straying i guess yeah
 	
 	
 		stick on the subject
 		well interesting thing that i do is with gardening uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> grows <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> that you can dry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you can make flower uh dried flower arrangements and you can get real handy with the hot glue <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and we made some really nice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">wreaths</ENAMEX> with uh dried red <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and dried white <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and uh eucalyptus
 	
 	
 		hum yeah
 	
 	
 		you you know what eucalyptus is it's
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah the they sell uh it's sold in the
 		hobby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nurseries</ENAMEX> it's got a kind of a peculiar smell to it but
 	
 	
 		yeah it's got a smell yeah at first i'm like oh how why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like this but it it is kind of a nice smell after a while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> put them in
 	
 	
 		yeah i didn't realize what it was for a while i'd walk into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> where some of that and i'd wonder what is that you know and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> i i realized that it was eucalyptus
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it's it's it's like a fad thing i i don't know it's i've never heard of it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX> i've used so much of it that
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i hate to
 	
 	
 		that's the stuff that koala <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bears</ENAMEX> eat in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		maybe that's why they're
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so slow i guess they're stoned on the stuff or something
 	
 	
 		yeah it it looks really potent potent stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh it's yeah i think it's the greatest stuff in the world though it's jeez they i make all kinds of things with it we make all kinds of things just with dried <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>
 		i i almost want to start a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> doing it but i don't i i'm so uh timid when it comes to starting a business
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's that's a big step yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it is especially with the being in on the creative aspect aspect on the crafty end
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		you know after a while you make some stuff then you start looking at it go boy this this is kind of ugly
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i know someone who does a lot of woodworking for a hobby um he does it believe it or not i wouldn't imagine why but to get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> away from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		hum
 	
 	
 		because he's a seasonal worker he works in the construction and up here it's almost a pattern i mean you see your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> do it then their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> do it what they do is they work construction then they get laid off for like twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> in the winter
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was going nuts and his uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> built him a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and got him some uh oh i don't know what the equipment's called but <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and thi ngs
 	
 	
 		um-hum shapes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		and set set him up and he he makes all kinds of furniture for um his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and he makes uh uh like little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' furniture
 	
 	
 		routers
 	
 	
 		he gets right into it and uh

 	
 	
 		there was a program on TV down here on the educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> here a while back about a lot of little
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you know up there especially this particular one i think was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 		where out in the just kind of out in these little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> they'd be i n they may be the same kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you're talking about you know they've they've got twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> to do something
 		and they they're making furniture and just you know things like that during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> and then they go off and do other things during the summer
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a it's a really good thing
 	
 	
 		so yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah because it's keeping him sane and plus it's keeping his marriage so and and plus he's getting on in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> now he's he's not that old but he's getting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to the point where he needed an extra boost to to do something like that and uh it's really it's it's uh hard work i couldn't imagine taking lumber raw lumber and trying to make something out of it he dowels
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that would be really tough you know like say the
 	
 	
 		he dowels everything and it's all got to line up  and uh i don't think he goofs too much i don't to see too much scrap around
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah yeah that's that's something now our temperatures down here we're starting to get pretty consistently in the seventies and eighties
 		and uh so and uh so as far as you know planting outdoor stuff matter of fact tonight i just got through i was planting some some trees out back <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		God i'm envious
 	
 	
 		this is uh it's really nice out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> almost hated to come in
 	
 	
 		is it going to be
 		is it going to be really dry it are you <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> are no i always plant <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in the fall i don't know why so the the cold weather can kill them
 	
 	
 		yeah these were uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that that wintered
 	
 	
 		but i guess
 	
 	
 		i don't don't know where they came from they come out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nurseries</ENAMEX> mostly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> and places like that
 		and they come down here and they'll sit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nurseries</ENAMEX> here and they'll go ahead and and uh leaf out
 		so what i'm planting or actually transplanting is a tree that's or <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that are already leafed out
 	
 	
 		oh that's good i guess they they say you can plant them in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> or the fall um
 	
 	
 		yeah mostly i think in a place where it's really cold they do it in the fall let them winter
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> but uh down here well it's done both ways it it just kind of depends on what you're
 		what you're planting but uh all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shrubs</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh when you have time to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> does uh flower gardens she gets right into it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she spends lots of money on them and i guess a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do do do that they landscape their whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with flower gardens she's got like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just a small patch of lawn and just <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and bulch <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">bark uh tree</ENAMEX> bark all over her lawn
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> down here the the normal kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> there's very few of them that'll really do well
 		everything does real well here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> until about oh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and then the real the heat sets in
 	
 	
 		it gets it
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June July August</TIMEX> are you know most of the those kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> just are just barely staying alive let alone make flowers
 	
 	
 		do you have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shade trees</ENAMEX> around your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or is it
 	
 	
 		uh we're in a relatively new area we're kind of out of uh the natural tree area we're kind of up on a on a higher on a slope
 	
 	
 		so you don't have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> coverage
 	
 	
 		so we don't have where we are right now there are very few trees this was this was this was pasture land but down the down the hill here a little ways there are <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> that are look like jungles you know they're really
 	
 	
 		because going going to make
 		yeah see um where uh where my uh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> passed away but where aunts are they have these huge pecan <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and they just shade everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		now where is this
 	
 	
 		uh it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> it's yeah it's right outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macon</ENAMEX> and and it's just a i like the way that i like the way that idea of the south is
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but when i think of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i think of nothing but no <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and just grass
 	
 	
 		well i tell you what now see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX> there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas East Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Texas Atlanta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> are almost identical in every way weather and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are very very identical so if you were familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's that dry heat
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh well no it's it's uh not dry at all it it's humid
 	
 	
 		well where is it is it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> wasn't it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s humid
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston Houston</ENAMEX> is awful
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Houston</ENAMEX> is really humid now
 	
 	
 		it's humid
 		
 		
 	