
 
     		
 	
 		okay do have  yep
 	
 	
 		are you there okay  okay
 	
 	
 		there okay had to mess with my phone here um do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i have one
 	
 	
 		oh okay i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> yeah yeah uh do you work
 	
 	
 		how about you
 		
 
 		oh my goodness
 		yeah i do i do i work and and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>'s in a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> he's uh he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> so he's not quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half</TIMEX> yet he uh i put him i'm
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		kind of had different different ideas from what probably the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have i put him in a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> from the very beginning he started in day care when he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight weeks</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh no kidding
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and i just i don't know i have kind of the opposite opinion of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i have had this real problem with a a private individual i mean i i kind of looked at it like
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you take him to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with a with private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> when the door shuts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has total control and i always figured at least in a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> there are other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around and if you get one bad apple there's are at least other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can see it they can watch and i just kind of always felt that the chances of something happening were less
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 		um-hum because there's
 	
 	
 		you know how can you help depending on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> care center you know you got to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when you hear about all the horrible things that happen in day care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> have you ever noticed they're always like a family owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> run it you know kind of thing i mean it's it's a
 	
 	
 		it's like a family thing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you never hear about it really in the big ones so that's what i did and i have had just excellent luck i have been just so happy he's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh good oh good i was just going to ask you how it you know if you liked the the but obviously you do or you wouldn't have him there  i know but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right right well he was in he was in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first two years</TIMEX> and uh it was wonderful and i loved it and i was so happy there and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who owned it sold it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		but i thought okay i'm going to keep an open mind here and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who came in it just wasn't it just wasn't the same and their their attitude and philosophy was just completely opposite from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		right
 		wasn't the same uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		left him there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX> and just decided i can't do this anymore and i moved him which was an extremely traumatic experience but but he's done well he's been there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of months</TIMEX> now and i just feel so lucky yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		was it yeah
 		good
 		oh good that's great that's good well i got to stay home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first ten years</TIMEX> my oldest one is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten and a half</NUMEX> now
 	
 	
 		how about you do you work or do you get to stay home with them
 		wonderful
 	
 	
 		or she's i guess yeah it's was about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> so i yeah i i was really happy that i was able to do that but i that's what i wanted to because i uh
 		you know i just couldn't wait to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and so if i was i was so anxious to have them and i couldn't wait to have them it would be kind of silly you know to go back to work as soon as i had them so so it it it it was really great by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the ten years</TIMEX> i was really ready
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah i bet
 	
 	
 		to go back to work and my youngest was only uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half</TIMEX> i mean she was already <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half</TIMEX> so it wasn't you know she wasn't an infant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		he didn't leave the baby yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so i felt real good about that but uh boy i tell you with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> coming up i'm just pulling my hair out in terms of what i'm going to do i i guess i went back to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh i worked full time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all last year</TIMEX> and now i'm going to school part time and uh graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and i'm working part time and so i'm still yeah i'm still going full time but i only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> time salary
 	
 	
 		i know how it goes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> lets out i just don't i haven't i have no idea what i'm going to do because i certainly can't afford what we did last year
 	
 	
 		right right did you have them in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> or something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		which was
 		well we did we tried we had all different things we sent them to camp <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one first month in June</TIMEX> they went to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> school then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second month</TIMEX> they
 		uh one my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> went home to visit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> for a while and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> uh went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and there we had uh i don't know some
 		forget what else we did but it was all uh really expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah that stuff is expensive it really is
 	
 	
 		so now they're a year older and i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> going to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> will be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine and a half</TIMEX>
 		and so i'm not i think i can leave them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for a if i can work part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> you know i'm going to leave them home right
 	
 	
 		are these yeah yeah i was going to say they're getting to the age where you should be able to trust that a little bit yeah
 	
 	
 		right yes in fact i'm doing that right now with their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> when they get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> before i do
 		you know that's okay but the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> now i have i have had her since i went back to work or before i went back to work really in a home day care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		situation and uh we've just been really thrilled with it too we were what actually we it took us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to find
 	
 	
 		to find the right one that's what we have to do though
 	
 	
 		yeah right but i wasn't embarrassed to shop around you know so the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> we found it through the there's an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> here in town of professional home care providers or something like that in Plano
 	
 	
 		no no
 		where do where do you live
 		Plano okay
 	
 	
 		yeah and they have a number you can call and all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are registered with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> and you know go like our our uh
 		i don't want to call her a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX> she's doesn't like to be called that
 	
 	
 		care provider
 	
 	
 		care provider
 		right she goes to seminars and uh she gets home visitations by this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> uh uh i don't know the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> i guess some of them and then some by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> and they
 	
 	
 		oh that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> meetings and everything and so it's just really really well regulated
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		and she's just great in fact uh she's all upset because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galen</ENAMEX> is going to go to
 		kindergarten <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next fall</TIMEX> and she says this is it you know i'm not going to have her anymore and i said oh no don't count on that  after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> classes she's going to be here because she's going to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> kindergarten so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but we we've tried we've tried everything and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when i went back to work i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> at the time just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">barely eight</NUMEX> and uh we put him in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amrein's Day Care</ENAMEX> after
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i've heard that they were very good
 	
 	
 		after
 		well that's why we picked it because they were were supposed to be real great and you know i think they were fine but the thing is he was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school all day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> it's open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> situation where they don't have walls so there is like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty second graders</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		in the same area with no walls and uh
 		and then he'd get on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amrein's Bus</ENAMEX> to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amrein</ENAMEX>'s
 		and then there would be a whole ton of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all in the same room you know you know what fun they had with these computer games and then they'd go outside for awhile they had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX> and story time and everything but it was just like going to school until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thirty</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">school all day</TIMEX> yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		instead of being able to get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two thirty</TIMEX> yeah because he was always around with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and he just really missed being able to be by himself and having some  peace and quiet or you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh even at that age they need that time we all need that time
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just some quiet time to wind down from the day
 	
 	
 		right that's exactly it so another thing that we tried to do i i know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s too young <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> but we're trying we tried to sign him up for after school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scouts</ENAMEX> and stuff like that and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think that's really important and we've already started about you know i mean how young can they start T ball and soccer  you know i mean i just you know we both think of that that as just so important to get him involved in stuff like that and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right right yeah
 		it is
 		it is and
 	
 	
 		you could hardly wait i mean he's he's so much fun now he's really he's really starting to get lots of fun and i can't wait until stuff like that starts happening you know and you know we did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> egg hunts which was really <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> he was really able to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i bet yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and to know what we want know what he was doing you know and enjoy it and it was so much fun and gosh he went a couple of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends ago</TIMEX> and rode an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> and God he got up on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> all by himself and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord i</ENAMEX> couldn't believe it they had so much fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		right
 		oh my gosh you are kidding
 		you're kidding oh that's great
 	
 	
 		i bought us tickets and stood there in line and i thought i'm going to end up on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> with him  you know he did it by himself so stuff like that is starting to come along where it's really getting fun you know but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well good for him
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		day care has just done just incredible stuff with him and he like comes home with something new everyday you know and so I know i know they're working with him and he's
 	
 	
 		well that's great that's so good
 	
 	
 		excited to get there in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and just doesn't even want to kiss me good-bye it's just like bye and he goes running you know and he's always having fun when i pick him up so you know yeah this this day care is is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		he's out of there
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bright</ENAMEX> Steps in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> and whenever you say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bright</ENAMEX> Steps everybody goes oh i've heard that's the best day care in town you know and it's it's one of those that's very hard to get into and they have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> day cares <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lewisville</ENAMEX> and one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irving</ENAMEX> and she had to open the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lewisville</ENAMEX> because her waiting list was just like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year old</TIMEX> it was ridiculous and she's got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two day</TIMEX> cares within like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> blocks of each other yes so its i mean she's
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 		no kidding
 		she knows something right that she needs if
 	
 	
 		she knows what she's doing all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are degreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and oh it makes a huge difference
 	
 	
 		yeah that makes such a difference
 		that's the way it is at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s nursery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> too and i think that really makes a difference they're in it because it's a profession not because it's a job they could get because they didn't qualify for anything else you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's right that's right

 		that's right and his old day care as much as i loved it you know and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> i really liked her and she worked really hard to get good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that she got
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		were there because they weren't qualified to do anything else you know and and i got lucky and all of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> were very good
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 		because because right some sometimes that's fine that's great you know sometimes it isn't you just have to well is it real expensive then
 	
 	
 		yeah but then sometimes you know
 		yeah
 		um it just went up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first of this month</TIMEX> i'm paying uh seventy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine dollars</NUMEX> a week for now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wow yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's a little high but but it's you know it's like where he was before i was only paying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty three so</TIMEX> there's quite a little jump there but i looked all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		i looked in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> care there was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> and you know and there were places that were cheaper but is it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no yeah
 	
 	
 		you know your peace of mind is worth a little bit of money you know and i have peace of mind where he is and some of those other places i wouldn't have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's exactly it see we do the same thing since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galen</ENAMEX> goes to nursery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> we pay our our home care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> for our day care provider
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full time</TIMEX> for a whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> but she she's gone <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three mornings</TIMEX> Galen just doesn't go there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> a week but i said to her i said you know it doesn't matter if
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for whatever reason when school holidays come around i used to have such a problem with that they wouldn't have anything to do i'd either have to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		
 		
 	