
 
     		
 	
 		well i wondered if i was going to get to talk to a male or a female on this topic
 	
 	
 		have you been talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> yeah yeah this is this is probably more interesting if it had been a male and a female
 	
 	
 		i was afraid we might get into an argument  well uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		i guess uh there have been certainly a lot of changes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of generations</TIMEX> for uh the roles of women
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i guess the most significant probably is that so many are working now and trying to juggle
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		job and home and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and all sorts of other possibilities you know they may be going to school or may have elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or you know all sorts of other things
 	
 	
 		yeah it it seems too me like though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s roles are changing faster than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and therefore the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are spreading themselves thinner
 	
 	
 		oh i think so
 	
 	
 		than before
 	
 	
 		absolutely i i i think it's extremely difficult to keep up with all that
 		uh we have to these days
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes i think i am going crazy trying to do it but
 	
 	
 		do you work outside the home
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yes they are getting older now so they are not quite as much of a responsibility but they are still there you know they still take time and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		and i you know i still provide most of the the things that go on around the house
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so uh yeah and for a while i was going to school to and that it was tough
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh i think that while it's a good change for i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to be able to fulfill their potential in whatever they feel you know their
 		expertise may be uh i think sometimes other things suffer and that i think it's hard to find a balance there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		but in some ways i think we are expected to do it all you're almost looked down upon if you don't try to do all of these things and that's where the problem is really
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah i have little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four and one</NUMEX> and i decided that it was very important to me to stay home um and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when i i i happen to you know be i'm very active with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> my age and most of us do tend to stay home but
 		when i run into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know just have recently had had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> or have very young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and are working full time i there's almost a uh friction between us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are you know necessarily good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> even though that has happened too uh it it's almost as though it puts you on different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of a fence you know when if you decide to go back to work then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you feel like you are always having to defend yourself and and if you don't then sometimes you feel like you're looked down upon by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that go back to work and so you're just wasting your time at home
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah yeah it's a tough one i mean i've done some of both i when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were real little i was at home for a couple of different periods of time oh i think the longest was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than a year</TIMEX> but still
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at least i was able to to spend you know those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first months</TIMEX> with them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh i mostly went back to work because i was tired of doing without things  you know the money was the issue
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh even now i would i would like to not have to work in some ways it it's a kind of pull and tug on the other hand
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i can't imagine just being at home uh although i have a lot of interests and a lot of things i would like to pursue
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh still uh there's there's sort of a feeling of accomplishment with having you know a job and
 		all that goes with that
 	
 	
 		no that that's definitely true in fact i i work out of my home um i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> and i do taxes and bookkeeping and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i uh it it was it's a way for me to stay home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i mean i still unfortunately have to be very disciplined in in doing my work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five in the morning and ten o'clock at night</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but but it it's worked out for for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> uh to have my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> and eat it too kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's a good deal where do you think this is going in the future i mean do you think things are going to change or are we going to keep
 		having to try to juggle all of this
 	
 	
 		well i i i hope that they will change uh but but i'm i just i know it's going to be a slow change uh i
 		i feel as though
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going back to just having a
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> wage earner i mean i'm just thinking of my circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i know i know quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have decided to
 		not have both both uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> you know both uh of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> work and yet um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i well i hope to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> based you know helping out you know child uh care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> at the place of employment and and things like that that will help out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do you think do you think we're setting a trend here or
 	
 	
 		i don't yeah i well i see i think some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wanting to stay home more and take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh and even those who may not do it seem to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		spending more time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and really trying harder at making all of the the family things work
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh but i don't know if they're going to ever give up their careers you know It's sort of like they went to school and they worked so hard to get where they are i don't know if they want to completely give that up
 	
 	
 		right it is a very personal thing
 	
 	
 		but it would be nice if there could be an in-between a middle ground somewhere
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think it's hard though when you talk about
 		about
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and and raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have a hard time understanding a middle ground i think they uh they need security
 		and yet they
 		i don't know i from speaking from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they they aren't real flexible when it comes to things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they uh they they want to know things are going to be a certain way
 	
 	
 		well yeah i think they they like a routine of sorts
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 		well we'll see i i'm hoping to see more female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in in our society
 	
 	
 		well yes i i like the fact that you know gradually you're beginning to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> but it's still a long way from
 		being what it ought to be
 	
 	
 		oh yes and the the numbers are still very skewed
 		to say the least
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay well i enjoyed talking to you all right good-bye
 	
 	
 		okay you too <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	