
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> about another block over and i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's funny i didn't expect to have any more calls
 	
 	
 		so i'm not very far away
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i thought i was uh through i had done <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know is there a limit on it
 	
 	
 		well i thought <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> was the maximum
 	
 	
 		okay i didn't know that because i got to be pushing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> some where i lost count around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or seven</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i've been writing mine down just in case anything you know just
 	
 	
 		yeah i should have been and i just i just forgot to uh so uh we're going you work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		i did i don't any more my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does
 	
 	
 		oh i i i do but i'm not going to be at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this month</TIMEX>  so
 	
 	
 		oh well where you going
 	
 	
 		i'm an ex <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI'er</ENAMEX> i'm uh i'm officially retiring unofficially i'm going to go to work for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> of ours
 	
 	
 		oh how neat
 		well that's a good choice
 	
 	
 		uh i
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called Onum
 		uh it it yeah it's located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh Onum
 		yeah i know them i used to work with them
 	
 	
 		oh you you you you did
 	
 	
 		i was a mechanical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> i did uh package design and i uh when we first contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Onum</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i was part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Rickey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay well you worked with a whole bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine then
 	
 	
 		was part of that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> probably
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah he's been there for since i left
 	
 	
 		oh okay and i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three or four years</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX> used to come out and visit us uh when i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		well i worked up there for a year
 		oh yeah
 		he made a lot of trips
 	
 	
 		yeah well the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> for operations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Onum</ENAMEX> stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bryant</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i don't know him
 	
 	
 		the he used to be a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX> in fact he started <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> plants
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and he left <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight or nine years ago</TIMEX> and went elsewhere and he's he came through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and visited with me and bottom line is i'm going to retire and go to work for him
 	
 	
 		that's sound like a good deal
 	
 	
 		so uh we're going to talk about about advice giving uh giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh selecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> you about ready to talk
 	
 	
 		yeah go ahead
 	
 	
 		okay  you said you're <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Judy</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		okay i'm i feel i'm like i'm almost an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on this subject i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in college and if one doesn't graduate i'm going to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> there by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well how did they decide which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> to go to and what did what'd you tell them
 	
 	
 		well it's it's interesting because it sort of fits their it sort of fits their personality uh my oldest who's a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTD</ENAMEX> now
 		she uh uh always our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> borders <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland College</ENAMEX> i mean you walk out our back door and you're on the campus
 		and she uh has always uh never really wanted to leave home and uh it turns out that when she came time to go to college well we're in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> in fact she stayed out there with us for a year
 		then uh uh we brought her back and set her up in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> she went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland</ENAMEX> and then moved back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> when we got back
 		but she just kind of went to from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTD</ENAMEX> and it's too bad she's never lived on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> and she has a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Edwards</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> who is living on a campus
 	
 	
 		hum because
 	
 	
 		and she sees what what she's missed out of college now wishes that she'd done something like that
 	
 	
 		well now
 	
 	
 		but at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at eighteen</TIMEX> you know uh uh i i wanted i wanted her to go away but she was just too much of a home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's uh that's kind of the way i was when i started school i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midland</ENAMEX> and when i was looking for things and and and what i would probably recommend to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> was something that i was comfortable with and i wasn't quite ready to be a long ways off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		and maybe and i knew i wanted to be in engineering so i was looking for a good engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so i ended up going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so i was there i was you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> away from home so any weekend i wanted to come home i got in the car hopped you know i was home in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> and so that worked out real well and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah that that yeah yeah that's not a bad deal well my my middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who's a freshman
 		she has always wanted to live on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> and she'd been kind of a home body i mean this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who who uh when she was little and went to stay over at somebody's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> i'd always know i'd get a call at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock</TIMEX> to come get her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i mean because it when it came bedtime she wanted to be in her own bed but uh she uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> and went to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> and she always thought she wanted to go to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> she and i took an interview trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and she was accepted by several of the of the good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> there but when it came down time to make a decision she said dad
 		i don't think i want to go that far away i've never been away before
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh uh she wanted to go to a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> like a place like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> was out of the question because she needed to be in a more of a small smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> environment so uh we went down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> uh uh i took a day off from work and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we went down uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Edwards</ENAMEX> and interviewed and it it just kind of met her her criteria it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty five hundred</NUMEX> undergraduates on a gigantic big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> and it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>'s a nice city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it's and she's pretty happy i mean she's here she's finishing up her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">freshman year</TIMEX> and she's pretty happy and likes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> and i got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> though who is a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkner</ENAMEX>
 		he is not academically inclined at all he's very uh kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unacademically</ENAMEX> inclined he wants badly to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> because that's where all all his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood are going
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and he uh i don't think he didn't apply i don't think he'd get admitted there but he's starting to get enough motivated he wants to go there that i think he'll go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland</ENAMEX> and take what he needs to have to take to qualify in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> and then try to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> the next year
 	
 	
 		oh well that'd be good i think he'd enjoy a lot it's a it's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it's a good place to grow up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh sure
 		yeah right and and he went out there and spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> here back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month or two and</TIMEX> and what i like is that when he saw it i think he's now motivated to to to go to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh so those the academic standards will improve yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah and the uh uh in in you know one thing you know in in terms of how how i i would advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is of course you got to look at what you can afford too and the state school system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh is probably one of the least expensive in the world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		uh again i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it's expensive but you my goodn ess state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> cost more than private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> do here
 	
 	
 		and he
 		yeah
 		yes and and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i knew had would go to school in some really you you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> and some of these really nice
 		these uh name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and and of course they would get out but they got they ended up getting more or less the same job i did and then they but they're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty thousand</TIMEX> in debt from student loans
 	
 	
 		yeah they end up yeah
 		yeah you end up getting the same degree and it's it's uh uh
 		now i i think that that what happens is the prestige you you can't you you can't sell that too much
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> beca use after all the degree just gets you in the door
 	
 	
 		yes and it's what you do afterwards
 	
 	
 		it's it's what you do after that that that that that uh it that really <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> how far you're going to go with a degree
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think that uh it's getting so darned expensive now i went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowden College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunswick Maine</ENAMEX>
 		and uh it's a a small at that time all male school there are more uh uh males uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> they're all all the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are now coed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh and you know i'm i'm talking about the early nineteen fifties and you know tuition was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six hundred dollars</NUMEX> a year my goodness it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen thousand</NUMEX> now
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah it's incredible now
 	
 	
 		and i don't know how and uh i mean they always have a waiting list <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> long for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and the only thing i did notice is about seventy percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are on some kind of financial aid
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and they're all going to have to pay it back they're going to be in debt for the rest of their lives
 	
 	
 		and
 		and they're going to be in they're going to be in debt for the rest of their lives yeah uh
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i guess the the main thing if i was recommending to someone like you said you've you've got you've got do something you can afford but then to go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that also is is somewhat well known at least in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> for what you want to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> is known to be a good engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and A and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> maybe is known more for computers
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that kind of thing i would i would if if you know what you're going to do i think that would be important to deal with too because
 		when you then when you do try and get your foot in the door at the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that you would possibly want to work for tend to interview more heavily at those locations because they know that that particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> had a good department
 		you know in in computer science or in engineering or in business or or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i i think that's exactly right and you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> that go into engineering know what they want to do
 		uh you know i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> that started off going well well well my oldest thought she wanted to major in psychology and she's carried through on that uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX> is what in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> of her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">freshman year</TIMEX> and she's gone from political science to international studies
 		to bilingual education to elementary education and fortunately as a as a freshman everything she's taken has has been uh is applicable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		will transfer so that's good yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's it's applicable to those degrees and and and those are strong degrees all of them in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that she's going
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and i i think you made a very good point though that somebody that is really has some direction and knows what they want to do uh then they need to go go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that's got a good reputation in that field
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh uh but i would guess a very very small percent of college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX> know what they want to do
 	
 	
 		i i think to some extent you're right most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a general idea
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		and then there's there's probably that probably fifty percent have a general idea and the other fifty percent are waiting to see what hits them when they get there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i i went i went off to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> wanting to either be a high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">algebra teacher</ENAMEX> or high school <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> because my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the in high school were my algebra <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and uh
 		and i was going to do that until the end of our sophomore <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> when we wanted uh we came time to sign up for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> and i had taken chemistry for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time that year</TIMEX> and surprised myself i did well in it
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and and sort of made a decision as we were walking me and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine were walking over to campus uh to to sign up for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> it was just sort of an off the wall decision
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh uh but i had no earthly i didn't do well in chemistry in high school and had no earthly idea that i'd get my degree in chemistry
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		on on the way in so it's uh but i i think uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who has some idea like you did is is is well uh you you know that that helps a lot were you uh well prepared for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> in in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> did you go to public school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i had yeah i was in public school i was in all honors classes i was also a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Merit Scholar</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay well you you you had a lot of things going
 	
 	
 		and i had the i think the other thing that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would benefit from in high school is taking an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">aptitude</ENAMEX> test
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because there are some good ones out there and i know in in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> at least they offered several different ones where you went through and you know you answer all these questions back and forth and things it it ended up being things that you liked versus things that you had an aptitude
 		
 		
 	