
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 		we built our home in what was a brand new subdivision in nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five</TIMEX> and we were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> in this subdivision to be built on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> finally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just last year</TIMEX> the last home
 		of the last lot was sold and the home a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> was built on it so the subdivision is now full but we're in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		oh that's pretty nice i did mine i built my own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty one</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that's pretty much about the same time and i i built on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two acres</NUMEX> of land in a town called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cumberland Rhode Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was it's uh it's just a private uh piece of property i mean there's no you know there's no other
 		well there's other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in the area but at that time there were just individual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> scattered throughout
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the town
 		and i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cumberland</ENAMEX>'s probably got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in it or so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is right on on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts Rhode Island</ENAMEX> state line that's that's why i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> it's only it's only a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minute</TIMEX> ride
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i did the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> myself as a matter of fact i had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> poured the concrete poured and the rest of all the building i did entirely on my own which was quite a project uh i don't
 	
 	
 		um-hum would you do it again  oh i see well we wouldn't have done it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time so
 	
 	
 		no  no i i i don't think so
 		uh i i would i would probably i would act as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> and subcontract everything out i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i but i would not physically do the work because i worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> after after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">working all day</TIMEX> in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> all your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> were tied up and it took me about oh a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> to finish it which i thought was pretty good
 	
 	
 		did you finish it
 	
 	
 		yes i i completely finished the house
 	
 	
 		so you do not have any place that has a mop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> off or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a piece uh we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who uh rents rents <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes redoes homes</ENAMEX> and rents them
 	
 	
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he never quite has finished any one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that he's done i mean there's always just one little detail that
 	
 	
 		well i
 		i had uh when i moved in i did not have my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> built and my breezeway and the concrete stairs upstairs the stairs the stairs were
 		were made out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> and the reason i did that it was getting
 		late in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> was coming
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i just i ran out of time really and i i waited until the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was completely finished in the interior and the exterior exterior of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> short of the breezeway and the and the attached garage
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i did that and the driveway <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following spring</TIMEX> which uh i needed a break from the work and i i needed a break to get a little more money ahead stuff like that so i waited
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		oh probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November December</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> i guess around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> and then i went ahead and built the breezeway and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> because i thought it was too cold to be pouring concrete outside in the winter time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		did do you find that uh the area has changed since you built your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or has or has the area mainly it are the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in keeping with the decor or in the style of yours
 	
 	
 		uh
 		sure yeah they they that area has managed to maintain itself very well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		real proud of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and they've managed to take care of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i noticed
 		now
 		that
 		several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> where the elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> that live there
 		have either gone on or or moved or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are now living there okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they just don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> seem to tend as much to them as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> did does that make sense
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well it's a little bit surprising because uh the older we get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> retired a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we still of course are maintaining our home and he keeps up the painting and and all of this and we did remodel we have a large uh
 		den i suppose it is kitchen den combination and we did remodel that after
 	
 	
 		oh i yeah yeah i've done the i
 	
 	
 		after uh he retired but as far as doing anything uh major to it we at this point would rather travel and i uh
 	
 	
 		i've done the same i did the same thing but what i'm saying is that some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i know they have moved on to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> or retired you know similar to your you know your situation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> have passed on to their uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or or to younger younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and they don't seem to maintain it as well as the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did i or or like you would or i would and perhaps its just it's
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know some of them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> were given to them and some of them the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had to buy and perhaps they don't have the money to spend on them
 	
 	
 		yes
 		somehow we don't think of a gift as being quite as dear to us as something that we've had to work for i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think you're right i think you're right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		we i i look at our home though and i think well gosh you know if we don't do this then the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who owns this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for instance is going to probably remodel the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> put in new cabinets
 		that kind of thing you know after oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty six years</TIMEX> uh things get a little scuffed up and it's not something that i'm not interested in the mess anymore
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh the style of our neighborhood uh
 		we're certainly not the smallest home and we're not the largest home but it has maintained itself in that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that were built afterwards
 		uh have come up
 		some of them are a little smaller because at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point they wanted to put some <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two thirty five</TIMEX> housing in
 	
 	
 		what is what is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two thirty five</TIMEX> housing i'm not familiar with that term here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		it it it's a law it was quite some time ago when the neighborhood was very new and we had some very very restrictive covenants uh in the subdivision
 		and they were attempting to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in an area that was originally set aside for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and i think the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two thirty five</TIMEX> came because they could <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could get into them for a down payment of something like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> dollars
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and of course we were involved with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and were able to stop that before it got off the ground and so the some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> on that side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> are a little bit smaller but they were
 	
 	
 		um-hum i built a i built a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom Colonial home</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and a half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX> up and down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a and an attached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and a breezeway and it was a it's a pretty substantial home i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i i like the roominess of it uh
 		and and i actually the only thing i've done other than you know wallpaper and painting paint over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> in the in the interior is i did refinish all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen cabinets</ENAMEX> and i put a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> in the basement
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which was probably the best move i ever did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		we have a rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">base</ENAMEX> here and it's very difficult
 	
 	
 		excuse me <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verna</ENAMEX> for just a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> can you hang on just a second okay
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		okay there's your report okay and
 		that's everything would would you give this to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Rashad</ENAMEX> for me please would you carry that over okay if you want to hang on a minute you got a minute okay hang on a minute and i'll i'll uh finish up with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>  yes ma'am
 	
 	
 		we have a rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">base</ENAMEX> here and it's very difficult to put in a basement our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is all brick and with the two
 	
 	
 		yeah are you are you on a flat on a slab like
 	
 	
 		no no we're build
 	
 	
 		you do you have a basement
 	
 	
 		no we do not have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> because we would had to have built up instead of down because uh there's the rock is so close to the surface here that it's difficult to to do <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basements</ENAMEX> so we didn't do that but um
 	
 	
 		i see
 		okay
 	
 	
 		we have an attached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and
 		etcetera typical family the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> home
 	
 	
 		well it sounds it sounds it sounds like you have  it sounds like yeah sounds like you have a real nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and it's uh it sounds like what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> or is is
 	
 	
 		we're uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two miles</NUMEX> we're between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Interstate I</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five</TIMEX> and we're just now being found by the north end of the state and getting a lot of
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you know there were <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> on the market for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> that sold in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX> because there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming down from
 	
 	
 		is your real estate market uh slowed down there like it is here in the northeast
 	
 	
 		it just it just went crazy this last year
 		everything sold absolutely everything i mean we had someone come knock on our door <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and offer us a price which i thought was absolutely ridiculous for our home the problem is there's nothing else to buy
 	
 	
 		it did
 		is that right
 		you know well if you sell it for that
 		sure if you sell it for that price whatever you have to buy is going to be inflated by that same amount so there's really not an advantage to it
 	
 	
 		that yeah
 		well and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are all here and we want to stay here so
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		we have no reason to sell so nice talking with you sounds like you're busy
 	
 	
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Verna</ENAMEX> yeah well i'm in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and i have someone here with me and uh it's really been a pleasure i enjoyed it and uh if you ever get to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> look me up
 	
 	
 		thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		thank you ma'am
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	