
 
     		
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as i understand it is
 		
 
 		less than half of all eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> participate in national elections
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and less than that in local elections and do you think that's a problem and do you have any or do we can we can come come up with any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> for that so if you're ready we'll start
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i participate in all of the national you know elections and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> elections that you know that affect me
 		i'm sometimes not too good in local elections i do i do vote you know in bond matters and uh things like that but i don't i no longer have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> elections you know doesn't really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i don't really get terribly interested in that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i do try to i don't just vote for to be voting you know i try to have you know educate myself a little bit you know on the on the issues rather than just voting blindly you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		um-hum but that's what i do i always i vote in the national elections
 		and i vote pretty much i i've been pretty good about voting in um most of um for like the for for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and and things like that and try to try to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know go through and figure out because most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you don't a lot of them you don't have any knowledge of and just go in and just arbitrarily voting all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> or all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> i try to i try to find out a little bit about them
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah i do too
 	
 	
 		but i understand why i i know one problem is uh
 		why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't don't register to vote i i know some personally because in the past and i think that's been changed that
 		that's how they get the jury uh rolls from from voter registration but i think that's going to be changed
 	
 	
 		yeah right uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i don't know if with that changing if uh you know if the voting will pick up but i think it's just like you say when you're if you're if you don't have an interest in something and you don't really care you may not go and vote
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		but uh what what is it what was the percentage for national elections
 	
 	
 		less than half
 	
 	
 		less than half
 	
 	
 		less than half i was kind of surprised to hear that
 	
 	
 		that that surprises me too
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought it would have been higher than that
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		do you ever or have you ever do you ever actively work for a candidate
 	
 	
 		um no i haven't
 	
 	
 		well i've only done it one time way back when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Connally</ENAMEX> was running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor State</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i were  pretty heavily involved
 		in working in his campaign it's really interesting to do it's hard work but it it's interesting to do
 		but i haven't done any of it done any of it lately
 	
 	
 		so uh the campaign that you worked when he was running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and that and he was elected that time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right uh-huh yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's i i would imagine it would be pretty i have uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine whose her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and i've gone to a a few things with her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's it's just like a different different world getting involved with those kinds with those with those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in politics so it is interesting very interesting
 	
 	
 		it really is yeah
 		yeah it
 		yeah it's interesting to do
 		yeah
 		we did mailings put up signs you know and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		went to a few dinners things like it was interesting it really was of course it was all volunteer we weren't paid members
 		it was interesting to do
 	
 	
 		so
 		what so do you think there's any what what could be done to improve the
 		percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know maybe it's  you know better education i don't know i do believe that you know if you don't educate yourself
 		vote in this these elections whether it's you know local or national you pretty well you know deserve whatever you get you know if you don't  if you don't participate in it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i really don't know what the solution would be everybody  or a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought when they ended the poll tax you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> that that would bring out you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know maybe it maybe it should be stressed through you know public education in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you know or something i don't know
 	
 	
 		i don't know well i know for for you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who is of voting age and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um he didn't want to he did he said he couldn't afford to be off from work because they did not pay pay them for being off from work and that's why he didn't register but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i wonder if that was really you know the real reason and then i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> uh well she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty now</TIMEX> but i got her a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voter Registration</ENAMEX> and gave it to her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i really don't think she ever turned it in but you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i just don't think it's important to to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and maybe thing you know circumstances may change and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but to get them interested in doing it i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know really know what a solution would be i really don't you know like you say if you  if you do everything but fill out the card for them that's really about all you can do uh-huh
 	
 	
 		maybe maybe a real campaign and you know just go vote instead of uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that maybe it you know just just to really really encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to to do it so maybe that's maybe that would help i'm sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah some sort of educational process i'm not quite sure what
 	
 	
 		unless a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who who are eligible to vote have no transportation and and and
 	
 	
 		that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		you know not able to get there or or for whatever reason so uh i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i don't know either it's kind of a tough question
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		don't really know what a what a real solution would be for it except like you say some sort sort of an educational process
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		something to generate interest i don't know quite what
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i really don't know
 		well maybe some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> can figure this out
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		well maybe maybe we'll get this question again and can
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		get some thoughts in the meantime if i had some you know think about it ahead of time
 	
 	
 		maybe so
 		yeah right
 		yeah  well it's nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX> bye
 	
 	
 		take care bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	