
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		family reunions
 		no you just just talk
 	
 	
 		does this give us the signal i guess not okay um
 		we have family reunions about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and generally it's held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and we have it in the state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> which has worked out pretty well uh over by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifton Forge</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		which state park
 		huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Delford</ENAMEX> have you ever heard of that
 	
 	
 		no but it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> oh well it's bound to be beautiful
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 		well it's pretty good yeah  uh there quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so we have to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		try to find a time when everybody can be there and we've
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		been pretty lucky so far
 	
 	
 		yes that that sounds wonderful i we uh we have family reunions not on a regular basis and there's mostly in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s family uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s very small
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um it's essentially the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of us makes up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		when we do get together and and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> do get together it's usually a wedding or or uh or a uh anniversary uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> are still living and on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side both both are living and on the other side the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> is still living so um we do uh occasional get together usually in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		at my uh my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Hampton</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Hampton</ENAMEX> uh-huh i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> originally
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		i said i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> originally i'm not i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maniac</ENAMEX> in other words
 	
 	
 		oh really  yeah oh we lived in uh we lived in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dover</ENAMEX> uh until we moved out here
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so uh yeah and i don't know do you do anything special to make it interesting
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		well uh we're we're some of the older ones in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> so the ones with small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> usually have ball games and kick ball things like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh one of them has made big banners to put on the
 		oh we have one of those isn't that awful
 		shelter a covered shelter and they've had big banners to display across the front of that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it's always a potluck everybody brings food
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah seems to me well the the the uh main event of course is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>  at the end uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		everybody has a specialty and so uh it's sort of it's it's sort of a high class potluck i guess you could say and uh it's wonderful it's uh uh i mean
 	
 	
 		ah
 		get all those good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> favorites
 	
 	
 		right i mean and and if somebody didn't make
 		the usually thing they'd be you know everybody else would get all upset you know so if you try something new right and try something new it's not it's not acceptable
 	
 	
 		drum them out of the family
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and then afterwards uh usually uh there's a gathering in the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> to watch a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		so uh and uh and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are usually uh playing out in the back she's got uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> acres of
 		property that go with uh with her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so there's plenty of room for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to go crazy and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> can
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 		oh yeah that's great what time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> do you
 		you have it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> like after yeah at football games it is it's wonderful uh my next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> will be
 	
 	
 		it tends to be in the fall yeah that's that's a beautiful time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		a wedding in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> so we're looking forward to that
 	
 	
 		yeah oh that will be nice
 		yeah do you have a feel for how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are when you get together
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it will be quite a few because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they're all going to be there with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whoa  oh gee
 		well let's see i i don't think i could put a number on it uh i know that uh we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and um my
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and one of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> has
 		um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and then her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> going on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> so there's there's plenty of plenty of that and then her stepfather has uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golly</ENAMEX> so that's pretty that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids kids</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> really get along with each other they're all young they're all i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh do they do you organize things or get or do they just
 	
 	
 		no i they're pretty good at it my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> i guess is the oldest she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 		and uh she is really good at that you know that kind of thing getting everybody together to play games and stuff so they i mean they don't need much uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		they just have a good time probably
 	
 	
 		you know much direction in that area  and and then of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandma</ENAMEX> always seems to
 		provide a a lot of things to a lot of toys and things yeah there's a lot of stuff just there to to let your imagination go wild with you know of course the new thing is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a lot of things to do huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> seem to enjoy that we we will have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> somebody have will bring an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> right i well my my i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> who uh is uh engaged to be married
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		always bring one huh yeah
 	
 	
 		her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> uh are her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> i guess her fiance hard to keep track these days um is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> freak so he'll he'll have a he'll he'll usually bring a few games
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um oh then we always video tape
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so we always have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> on tape and we see how they grow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> yeah yeah that's a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah that's interesting because that's a good idea
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's a lot lot there will be times when we'll turn that on instead of instead of watching something on TV
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> is her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no her family is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and in uh in uh oh in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh and one of them is living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> now they're all in the northeast part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and then we're living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		yeah right well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and one is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> right now and uh the other one is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">new Mexico</ENAMEX> wow that's we've seen just a little bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> we haven't really traveled that much since we've been here uh but we've seen a little bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and that was very nice and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> seemed very nice
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh-huh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> is beautiful
 	
 	
 		but everything in between was wasn't very interesting
 	
 	
 		that's kind of what we found she's uh in the northern part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> it's pretty it's up in the mountains yeah it's beautiful
 	
 	
 		oh yeah up in the mountains yeah that's that's what we miss we miss mountains and trees
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course you have plenty of uh plenty of uh mountains in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and then in northern and you know up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> too we had uh one of the um
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		times that we had sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion was when uh was this i think it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last last winter</TIMEX> we uh we went up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> to go skiing
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		and uh a bunch of us got together it wasn't the whole family it wasn't all the all the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> usually when when we make a trip
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		out there somebody else flies in or something because uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> all have well they have a lot of connections with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> my
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> who is a pilot my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX> is a pilot um and so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that makes it great doesn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah a lot of mobile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so the so the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> can usually get up and uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh and then so we're when we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> everybody else is in that area anyway and usually somebody will drive in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> so uh it's usually some kind of uh semi reunion
 	
 	
 		right well we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every fall</TIMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> who lives there still and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> and nieces and nephews so we always have a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Farmington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's usually out on a farm one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh gee  homesick um
 		have you heard about these uh these businesses these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that uh i mean their business is planning family reunions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> oh yeah that's i i thought about this and uh it seems like a pretty neat
 	
 	
 		no i haven't huh-uh
 	
 	
 		thing they do uh family reunions and they do um oh what do you call it um
 		oh class reunions
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and they make all the plans they contact everybody and they make sure everybody's got travel arrangements and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and uh i guess it's in fact i think it was started by somebody who was a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> and they got this brainstorm that you know they could make a living
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		by arranging for different family reunions and class reunions all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> yeah i always thought that would be kind of might be kind of fun you know especially with a class reunion where
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's pretty interesting
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you have to do a little research try to find everybody  i guess it's a little easier with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion and they you know and they they're really organized you know they setup they they get the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> and they and they uh
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh arrange for the catering and they have name tags
 		
 		
 	