
 
     		
 	
 		exercise tends to be a a topic that i guess i've never developed any will power to maintain any regular program i uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh i guess all the factors that drive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to do that are appearance or general health or some some need for reduction of weight or whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i haven't uh been cursed or blessed with either depending on the way you look at it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um i've always been a physique that can stay skinny no matter what i eat or how much i eat or if i
 		uh exercise or not and they tell me that's going to catch up with me someday uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh well they say your metabolism slows with uh <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">six percent</NUMEX> with every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> of your life or something like that
 	
 	
 		well maybe that'll allow me to outweigh some of the things i have to pick up on occasion
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		when uh i got married i was working a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> in college in construction and lost lot of what little weight i had
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i got married at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> pounds and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years old</TIMEX> and i was just this little toothpick up there had to buy a new suit for it just to fit in there
 	
 	
 		whoa
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it took me a good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> to put on some weight and any exercise even when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> would come and i'd mow the lawn i'd lose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven pounds</NUMEX> just just as soon as the heat kicked in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and finally at around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age thirty</TIMEX> i i managed to keep some weight and not lose so much during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and i hover at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> fifty and i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six one</NUMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		wow
 	
 	
 		it's not too bad it it it's unfortunate though i guess because i probably should uh do a little less of the hardening of the arteries with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> and a little less of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> here and there but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well to give it give you some perspective my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six two</NUMEX> and weighs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two hundred and fifty pounds</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah a lot a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> in laws are all everybody is bigger than me for the most part
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh it's kind of nice i've noticed a little bit of love handles here and there and my face has filled out a little bit from the pictures but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		all that is is ever so slowly so
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		but then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five years old</TIMEX> and he's he doesn't show any signs of having to cut back either so there's hope for me maybe i'll maintain that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's great
 		well i know in in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has always been an exercise fanatic in fact uh he's from um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and he came to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and one of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> jobs was to teach gymnastics
 		and uh he use to make a living for a while doing gymnastics and swimming and in fact in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> that was what he did for a living too but
 		uh of course he came over here uh i don't know fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he um it it of course it was much more prevalent in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> exercise was much more taken much more seriously than it was here in fact
 		it it hasn't it's just now getting to the level where it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> you know now with everybody is going to the health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um he he keeps saying that he was too early  he came too early
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		but um
 		he and but the irony irony is that i've been overweight all my life and he uh he almost discouraged my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and i from getting involved in athletics
 		um
 		because he felt that we needed to concentrate on on other things more important things in life uh but now and and he's still into athletics in fact he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX>
 		and he is in the senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">olympics</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and he always brings home <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> and gold medals and he competes against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as much as thirty years</TIMEX> younger than he is
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and he still wins these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> and gold medals
 	
 	
 		good
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but i'm at the point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> where i have some concern my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has history of heart problems for herself and her family my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had phlebitis
 		and um i'm i'm realizing that i need to do something uh or you know i'm going to suffer for it if i don't especially where i'm i'm about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> pounds overweight
 		and so i've started an exercise program i'm i'm sometimes i'm a lot more
 		diligent than others but uh i work a fellow i work with is a weight lifter and he's he's uh
 		he's competed and he's uh helped me develop a pretty simple program that involves some weights and and and some aerobics
 		and really with the design not towards being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body builder</ENAMEX> not towards being you know <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mister America</ENAMEX> but but purely uh uh geared towards being being healthy
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh and i'm i'm at the point where i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i really don't want to have to have
 		problems with uh you know my heart or anything like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah well i've i've managed to
 		i guess the work i do gives me a little bit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">well</NUMEX> a lot of walking and a little bit of lifting on occasion
 	
 	
 		that's good
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's not all sitting behind a desk so that's kind of nice it uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i could sure tell the difference though after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year or so</TIMEX> of being there uh prior to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to uh working a steady <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hour</TIMEX> job as it were i had been working for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and had relatively real <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years old</TIMEX> and could handle getting up at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and not getting to bed until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		virtually working or playing myself to death <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> of sitting down and then going to that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> as a camper this time i couldn't even do what i used to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it was really an eye opener for me to see that even sitting down for a little while sure changes the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>'s capacity
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah well i i i've i have a desk job i don't you know i don't have an opportunity to walk around all that much uh unless i take it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it's but it's gotten better i mean uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> i lived in the uh i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and i'd commute to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so i'd end up sitting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> and then i you know a lot of it in car fumes you know inhaling car fumes
 	
 	
 		goodness
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then i'd sit at a desk for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> and then sit in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another hour and a half</TIMEX>
 		now that i've moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> away um
 		i have a lot more free time to take walks with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or go bicycling bicycling or play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball or baseball</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and uh
 		uh it just uh it from that standpoint uh leaving that area was a was was turn turn around was good for my health i guess you could say
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i like to bicycle i tend to be rather sore <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> or two
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		those uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> speeds and their unforgiving seat that i sit on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but they tend to like the parking lot up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Springcreek Plant</ENAMEX> the upper limit of it's terraced and its usually unoccupied
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		boy you can just you go down hill down hill down hill then turn around and work your way back up and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's fun for them we take the long route go up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alma</ENAMEX> and across the back way come in the parking lot
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> off the day
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh after all that and i usually end up having to by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> they're usually tired enough where one of them or the other needs a little push along the way and i'm sitting here trying to go my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> and push them too and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh it gets to the old leg muscles but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		can't do too much of that or i'll waste away
 	
 	
 		well i i envy you
 	
 	
 		i sat down to uh one of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> did the oh they do that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um blood</ENAMEX> deal oh
 	
 	
 		life track
 	
 	
 		no it was just one of the what is that pulse no not the pulse
 	
 	
 		oh blood pressure
 	
 	
 		blood pressure yeah they sit there in the cafeteria sometimes and take that on your way out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and after having sat for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty or thirty minutes</TIMEX> and i get up and walk over to that and sat down and they took it it was pretty low like it usually is it it stays real low
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess all the arteries are open and doesn't have any trouble pumping it all through but uh
 	
 	
 		wow
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> looked up at me and said oh you must be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jogger</ENAMEX> and i said oh if you only knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch potato</ENAMEX> with remote control
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh so fortunately i don't know what the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> level is but at least it hasn't clogged up yet
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well they had that whole life track thing that i participated in at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and at the time i was a real mess i mean uh i was eating poorly i you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> was everything was borderline my blood pressure was borderline my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> was borderline but since then
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it had nothing to do with the life track thing but but just just i think well maybe it did you know it makes you think
 		you know we've changed our eating habits dramatically i mean when uh when the phone rang we were making granola um
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh uh we're we're trying to cut down on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and you know we're doing all the all the stuff that the you know all the mags are talking about these days uh um
 		but you know i feel a lot better about it i don't it it comes a real worry but these things are like time bombs and all of a sudden they go off and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um i guess looking at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and seeing all the problems they've had you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s had bypass surgery and uh and she's she's got
 		
 		
 	