
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Diana</ENAMEX> uh on capital punishment in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> they give the death penalty for shooting of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i believe also in shooting of uh rape i mean
 		killing a rape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> or i mean someone in the process of rape
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't know what else i don't really remember what else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		how do you feel what what do you think about it
 	
 	
 		i think it's justified
 	
 	
 		uh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		very much so
 	
 	
 		i agree i i agree you know i
 	
 	
 		i think it should be in other cases other than just shooting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah oh i do too i do too
 	
 	
 		i mean i think they're doing their duty but i think if they're going to come out and kill somebody else then they deserve it
 	
 	
 		they ought to get it for killing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> just as easily as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> yeah i agree i don't know i heard something on the news <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> they were talking about
 	
 	
 		that's right i agree
 	
 	
 		uh oh i know what it was it was in our in our little local paper our little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lewisville</ENAMEX> paper that comes out twice a week on the front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX>
 		uh there's a little thing at the bottom that it's like a call in survey that says you know do you think so and so and then you call this number and you press like one for yes and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> for no
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things the questions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> uh this last paper and i haven't seen the results of it i'm anxious to was do you think that um capital punishment ought to apply to drug dealers
 	
 	
 		oh i think
 	
 	
 		which i thought was a real interesting question
 	
 	
 		right right  did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> tonight by any chance
 	
 	
 		no i didn't huh-uh
 	
 	
 		well they were showing a segment on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> that's going after the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> he's just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> he's a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and he just got fed up with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he said he's had his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> broken into and windows smashed and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> stolen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times and everything trying to keep keep him quiet but he's organizing people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're going out and marching on the corners and taking taking back their territory
 	
 	
 		you know i think that's what it's going to take though
 	
 	
 		i think so i think
 	
 	
 		i really do i yeah it's going to take uh you know the the police i i think i don't think can do it uh can do it alone you know
 	
 	
 		that's right i think you're right
 	
 	
 		it's going to take uh it's going to take all of us getting together i'm sorry i'm trying to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> is asking for a kiss and a hug so he can go to bed  it's going to take all of us you know getting together and just saying we are not going to take it any more
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		we won't allow this in our neighborhood and it said they're going to other neighborhoods from there
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then quite often they'll get shot because
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		they're horning in on somebody else's territory
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right uh
 	
 	
 		i think they said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty one</NUMEX> had been shot out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in the last year
 	
 	
 		my gosh the only thing about the death penalty and and i know that that they try to be careful and they try to be sure but these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are on death row for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> you know and you know if if
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right i know it
 	
 	
 		you know i i think to be you know convicted being convicted is one thing you know and that's and that's great if they're convicted if they're sentenced to death
 		to me you could not sentence them to death unless the case was for sure i mean it had
 	
 	
 		well it goes all through the state it goes all through the state supreme court system before they're
 	
 	
 		right right and and by the time it gets there and they've been convicted and then they've been sentenced to death
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		then it should happen yeah
 	
 	
 		they're sure i mean there's no doubt i mean i there can be no shadow of a doubt in my mind there has to be no shadow of a doubt to get that penalty so once they've gotten the penalty and there is no doubt do it
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you know just
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't i guess i mean that's may sound that sounds cold but gosh you know we're keeping you know we're we're keeping these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for fifteen or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> on death row
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's right
 	
 	
 		and not doing anything with them and it's costing us a heck of a lot of money and that's terrible to look at it that way but
 	
 	
 		yeah it is i know but that that's the way it is
 	
 	
 		yeah if the crime was bad enough that they were sentenced to death then do it you know uh
 	
 	
 		we had one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> that was sentenced to death and the execution was to have taken place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX> i don't know if there was anything in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> about it
 	
 	
 		i didn't notice it huh-uh
 	
 	
 		and there was a lot of protest even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redford</ENAMEX> you know was protesting this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s execution so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> backed down and i was so mad the crime was horrible his crime was just horrible
 	
 	
 		gosh yeah
 		oh man
 		yeah
 		and those kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'm sorry you don't reform them
 		you know i really believe you don't
 	
 	
 		no i don't think
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they're the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that commit these  excuse me grotesque crimes and have done it over and over and over again you don't reform those kind of people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX> and being under the influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is no excuse to me
 	
 	
 		no no and i don't know the same thing goes with some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">insanity</ENAMEX> pleas you know well if you're insane enough that you can go
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		cut twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up into little bitty pieces and bury them in your back yard then are you can can you be helped you know i have i have my doubts you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right yeah yeah i do too
 	
 	
 		i you know i don't know i think there's a point some of these plea bargains and all this kind of stuff that they do it's just it just gets out of hand and i understand that you know that you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		right
 		wasn't it Lewisburg that had a lot of uh bad things happening just in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of weeks</TIMEX> or was it not
 	
 	
 		no no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		no
 		maybe it was i think it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South East</ENAMEX> area from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> lives down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rowlett</ENAMEX> and she was telling me about it yeah i can't remember what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> was some little area
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah
 		oh really
 		yeah
 		we've had several here lately and it there were several of them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> and then it started kind of happening a couple of places in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dallas</ENAMEX> and that's maybe what you were talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> breaking in uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and taking or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they they think it's the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> taking uh
 		little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> right straight out of their beds at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> an d  you know breaking in obviously watching them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> because they're breaking into the right window
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 		and that's the last they saw
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know the little girls <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> and taking them out putting them in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and driving them out and taking them out and molesting them and then bringing them back and throwing them back in their own front yards
 	
 	
 		oh gee
 		is that right i hadn't heard about that
 	
 	
 		yes that is happened i think there's been  i think there's been like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or seven</NUMEX> of them over the last like probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight eight or nine months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		gosh
 		they don't kill them they just molest
 	
 	
 		they don't kill them no they've taken and they're all like um like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine anywhere from nine</NUMEX> to twelve years old i think is what they've been
 	
 	
 		gosh
 		gosh
 	
 	
 		and he's taken them and and raped them and then brought them right back and just kind of thrown them out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in their front yard and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's scary isn't it
 	
 	
 		oh can you imagine because it it happens in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> so the parent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't know this the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> was gone until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> is knocking on the door screaming let me in you know can you imagine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh boy
 		yeah you wouldn't even dare put these signs in the window little emblems in the window saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in case of fire you know have you seen those
 	
 	
 		shoot i you know i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> i never even thought about that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		God maybe i'll take it out i hadn't even thought about it
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		that's terrible
 		well it's really bad that you have to be you know we we were over at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> tonight and
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is only is just a little over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and their little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> you know so there's a big difference and they were playing in the back yard and we were getting ready to leave and i went out in the back yard to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> were gone and the back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX> was open  you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh gosh oh gosh yeah
 	
 	
 		and she didn't act like it bothered her at all oh this happens all the time and we walked through the fence out the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">alleys</ENAMEX> or come to the back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you know and walked and i looked down both directions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> and i saw neither one of them and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and oh and she was like oh God he does this all the time you know where are you you know screaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J D</ENAMEX> and you know my heart was in my throat you know and uh he <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> down
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>  and he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 		shoot
 		i guess so
 		gee
 	
 	
 		you know and he you know i don't know
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> around here just let their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> run everywhere and i just can't do that
 	
 	
 		yeah there was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> picked up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rowlett</ENAMEX> from uh from her front yard and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was working in the back yard and had just left her <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">few minutes</TIMEX> in the front yard and somebody apparently drove up and took her and they never saw her again
 	
 	
 		oh God
 		oh man
 		this is too scary that is just too scary you know i let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> play here in the back yard and we've got
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> gates that go into the back yard and we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> foot privacy fences and one of the gates has a padlock on it and then the other gate just has one of those slide bar things but it's on the inside it's
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you'd have to climb like come over they'd have to come over the fence they could not open a gate you know and i still feel a little uneasy about him playing back there you know i mean if i don't hear him playing i mean i i get up and come out and look out the window real often you know so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 		watch yeah yeah i don't blame you
 	
 	
 		it's really scary that you have to be that scared about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but i mean you do better safe than sorry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and if they find who's doing that to those little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> as far as i'm concerned he could
 	
 	
 		he could fry yes to put it very bluntly he could fry yes yes because sometimes there are crimes worse than murder
 	
 	
 		fry  yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i and i believe that and this is one of them because these little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> will never be the same
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		huh-uh that's terrible
 	
 	
 		never be the same so  i don't know it's  it's really scary and i don't know what to
 		and i don't know what needs to be done you know it seems like there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> to put them in jail and when they do put them in there you know were i'm taking a business law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that teaches it is a practicing criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		so he comes in and tell us all these bizarre cases you know  and he said you can pretty much you know if you ever get on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> you know you're not told this but if you ever get on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> you can pretty much guess whatever you sentence them to they're going to serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a quarter</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's going to be reduced right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		they they'll serve they'll serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> of it so if you want them to stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen years</TIMEX> don't sentence them to fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> sentence them to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> you know because then they'll serve fifteen or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> so which is really i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		it's just not it just doesn't seem right
 	
 	
 		no it doesn't it doesn't they just get out you know there was a thing on
 	
 	
 		well what are we going to do about it  How i mean how can it be changed
 	
 	
 		well
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> will do something and
 		they don't seem to
 	
 	
 		that's the thing and you know we're just going to have to adopt a  a completely different attitude
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we're going to have to say if you commit this crime and if we're sure you commit this crime you are going to be sentenced to death period
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		period and do it you know and if you commit this crime you will be in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for the rest of your life we're not going to say we're going to put you there for the rest of your life and let you out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen years</TIMEX> we're really going to do it you know it's just the system has just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and and i understand they're doing it because the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> are full but somewhere we've got to come up with some money to build to build more you know and keep these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in them you know
 	
 	
 		right i think so yeah
 		yeah i think it would be worth it everybody would
 	
 	
 		they were i was watching a show <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about this the other night</TIMEX> and you know they were like in i think it was on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Forty Eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hours or Morning</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	