
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 		movies i've i haven't seen too many lately
 		i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and we went and saw
 		The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rescuers</ENAMEX> Down Under over the the break do do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you take to movies or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Walt Disney</ENAMEX> movie
 		
 
 		and it didn't get as you know as good a reviews
 		as like the Little Mermaid the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and got all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> and things
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
 		but this one was i thought was excellent the i can't both
 	
 	
 		was that the animated version
 	
 	
 		yeah it's animated and i can't believe how good they're getting with their animation now
 		it's just just the special effects you know and in this movie this there's this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and he rescues this uh bald eagle
 		and uh and it's a huge eagle you know wing span of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twenty feet</NUMEX> or something like that and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> actually rides on his back
 		and he rides through the clouds you know and you see him coming out of the clouds his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> coming out and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> coming out and it you know they're flying all over with it
 		and i mean i know there they there must have used been computers or something for animation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> but it was just
 		so real realistic and lifelike and good animation
 		what a good show
 	
 	
 		even better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Rabbit</ENAMEX> insofar as animation
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX> was a composite one there's one there's a movie i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Rabbit</ENAMEX> that's not a recent movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i enjoyed that show
 	
 	
 		yeah that was made in a few i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years back</TIMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		latest latest one i've saw which was a
 		mistake to go see was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lionheart had Claude Van Damme</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he was he's of course uh i guess he's trained in this uh martial arts of some sort but
 		the plot was bland the acting was bland It was just mostly centered upon his abilities to
 	
 	
 		chop them up huh
 	
 	
 		yeah chop them up exactly and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		this is supposed to be the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that's uh replaces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lee</ENAMEX> or whatever or
 		or the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Norris</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		type guy
 	
 	
 		or he's singular i guess you know you know how they can make any of any single one of them in a movie to be a super
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">superstar</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> of any sort you know but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Norris</ENAMEX> of course could be just about equal if not more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and all of them i guess could be in that fashion
 		or category
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was about uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Foreign Legion</ENAMEX> fellow
 	
 	
 		keeps trying
 	
 	
 		who deserts to go help his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 		who got who became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> because he was selling drugs
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he got killed
 	
 	
 		really uplifting huh
 	
 	
 		so he deserts and goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and he starts out by fighting to make money
 		and then he moves on to L A to where that where she is
 		to just help him out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was really i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> really must think there's some real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dummies</ENAMEX> out there or something i don't know
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't heard i hadn't heard much about that movie i other than it was a chop them up movie
 		but uh
 		well i guess that's one i won't go see
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well it was worth the buck i guess
 	
 	
 		oh you went to the dollar movie yeah
 		yeah they show up at the dollar movie right after they get come out you know they're usually not
 		not that great or didn't do that great anyway
 		let me see let me see another movie i watched uh i want to see is uh that new one uh
 	
 	
 		a lot of
 	
 	
 		that won all those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Dances With Wolves i</ENAMEX> haven't seen that have you seen that one yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what what what
 	
 	
 		i i absorbed all of that movie in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sitting uh
 		i guess what made it so good was the cinematography cinematography
 	
 	
 		the the wide open you know spaces
 	
 	
 		yeah and the music and uh well it had an excellent story line Everything about it was good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i thought an excellent one too was misery
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Bates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Caan</ENAMEX> i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Caan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> but
 		that was a well directed and acted movie
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		i'd recommend it It's a little on the violent side
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then what movie isn't anymore
 	
 	
 		right right yeah our movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it used to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX> and
 		you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">PGs</ENAMEX> used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rs</ENAMEX> and
 		seems like the rating system you know is kind of switching that way a little bit
 	
 	
 		well i have no objections to it It's just uh and it's a matter of your taste uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah oh yeah it's just that yeah it's just that the rating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> seems you know instead of having <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> now they have what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> seventeen
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they just changed it because <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> had a connotation with it you know
 		so
 	
 	
 		and even on those type they don't show what you expect
 	
 	
 		right a lot of those are really violent type movies
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		really gory
 		um
 	
 	
 		yeah that seems to be the norm of most movies but
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		what the hey this is America
 	
 	
 		let me see
 		let me see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> movie i saw i guess it was a while back Red <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> have you seen that one
 	
 	
 		yeah yes i have that was pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah i read the book before so i knew the story line going in but
 		they changed some things in the movie wasn't the same i thought the book was better
 		than the movie but i thought the movie was really good as well
 	
 	
 		i always wait for the movie i don't have time to read the book
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two</NUMEX> thick novels like that a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know that's about all the time i can
 		i can spare but that was a good show i thought you know
 		i read about how they did uh an article on how they did all the special effects with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX> you know that wasn't a real submarine you saw in the water it was it was all done in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">smoke</ENAMEX> and mirrors and
 		all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> magic it all those underwater scenes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i thought you know it looked to me like it was a real submarine
 	
 	
 		they did me to
 	
 	
 		that was in the water you know
 	
 	
 		that's the magic of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> special effects i hear this movie F <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> part <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> coming out is uh pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		did you ever see the original one
 	
 	
 		i didn't
 	
 	
 		it was uh you ought to rent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh F X</ENAMEX> part one It doesn't say part one but it it's F slash X
 	
 	
 		huh what's that about
 	
 	
 		a uh special effects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who somehow gets involved in this um
 		oh
 		i'm not sure i can't remember It's been a while since i've seen it But he he gets involved in some sort of bad dealings
 		with somebody and he has to go underground and he uses all of his special effects knowledge in doing what needs to be done
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		to to fool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and and things huh
 	
 	
 		right and using makeup and using the
 	
 	
 		all the tricks
 	
 	
 		all the props and whatever to get to where he needs to go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that sounds like an interesting concept
 	
 	
 		but you need to rent the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one first
 	
 	
 		to understand what's going on the second
 	
 	
 		uh if if that is that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one follows the first i don't know if they have the uh
 		original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> on that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to that one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they're supposed to be coming out with all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> movies
 	
 	
 		oh i expected those i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> i mean they were doing their dealings with that before they even got over there i think
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> too
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah well they had some in some of those you know they i guess they retitled some movies that were going to be about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lebanese</ENAMEX> and and you know and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and they decide oh make it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> you know and they just change the title and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and reshot a few parts you know where they yeah you know where they could i guess they figured we wouldn't can't tell the difference between an
 	
 	
 		actual names will not be used
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		eventually i'm sure they will come out with the the the proper names
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right it was such a it i guess they they'll probably come out with a lot of
 		movies you know it was it was such a rout though you know i don't know
 		you know they probably do the story of someone who was shot down early in the war or something and how he survived or
 	
 	
 		latest story
 	
 	
 		or about or about those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> newsmen or whatever that got captured
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> i understand is supposed to be play <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Schwartzkopf</ENAMEX> supposedly
 	
 	
 		
 
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		i don't know that's just one of the many rumors that floats around
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or what you read
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think we've probably
 	
 	
 		pretty much used up the tape i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's been about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>
 		it's been nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		same and uh we'll
 	
 	
 		keep on watching those movies huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		talk to you on the next go around
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	

 	
 		adios
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	