
 
     		
 	
 		well what would you have at a dinner party
 	
 	
 		well uh lately since i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i've cut down on having dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> but  when i do i try to keep it pretty simple on things that i can prepare ahead of time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i have one recipe for uh a really good um type of a meatball it's called burgundy <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">meatballs</ENAMEX> and it's made with red
 		red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and um it's it's really good and you can make it ahead of time and then um make the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> when you're ready to um to serve it that's one of my favorite things to to serve
 	
 	
 		oh gosh that sounds great
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well um i think it would probably depend on whether this was a formal or informal dinner party but if it was informal my first choice would be crawfish
 	
 	
 		sure
 		oh really well i guess being from that part of the country
 	
 	
 		because i mean crawfish everybody over here likes crawfish but you know i i wouldn't have to worry about satisfying my
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		guest but if it was a formal uh dinner party i would probably think of something else like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um shrip</ENAMEX> shrimp fettucini is real easy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to um make and everything and it's usually well liked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i guess i'm just a seafood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> so i think on the lines
 	
 	
 		well how do you make how do you you cook crawfish i in fact i just came back from the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we don't have too many you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that eat
 		crawfish but they had live crawfish on sale
 	
 	
 		oh yeah um you're not supposed to i mean you're not supposed to eat them
 		dead i mean well you eat them dead but  right because if if they're dead for too long you can always tell whenever they're cooked if they've been dead for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> because their tail straightens out and you're not supposed to eat those because they're the bad for you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		don't buy them that way
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay well i'll remember that
 	
 	
 		yeah so if you ever go in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and order crawfish i mean every once in a while you'll see one i mean it doesn't happen very often because it's just an accident but if the tail is straight on it then yeah don't eat it but um you just put some cajun well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		lots of pepper and you just boil them and they're absolutely wonderful but there's uh they're a pain to peel for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> once you get used to it they're real easy but um you know if you have nails or anything you can
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		plan on those being shot
 	
 	
 		when you were um when when you  serve it do you shell them and then serve them to
 	
 	
 		i think for a dinner party i i don't know it depends like if like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my age if there was a bunch of college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> coming over for a dinner party no i they would shell their own you know we'd just have crawfish and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> or something but um if it was more formal like if i was you know working environment then i would probably um shell
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shell</ENAMEX> them or at least disconnect them from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> but there's a there's a big thing over here that everybody sucks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> so um
 	
 	
 		so they don't have see that
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		it it would just depend that's the best part of the crawfish sucking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> but um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know it just it it just depended on what type it was i guess but you can buy uh the crawfish tails already peeled and everything and
 		usually you use those like for frying or to put in salads or to um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know make a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> with or something like that but you can go ahead and buy them cooked and shelled and they're more expensive of course but
 	
 	
 		does it taste a lot like shrimp
 	
 	
 		um  yeah it really does i like shrimp better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just um but crawfish i mean it just has a taste of its own it also depends on who's cooking it and how much seasoning they use and stuff like that but um
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i think that and also to get totally off crawfish the subject of crawfish lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and hors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">d'oeuvres</ENAMEX> and stuff like that for a dinner party i think that that really helps
 	
 	
 		yeah we have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is the one who cooks
 	
 	
 		that's what i need
 	
 	
 		all the time and  yeah that's what i wish i had  but in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> i'm the one who who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX> and i i really enjoy it it's gotten a little more difficult with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but i really do enjoy cooking
 		and we um we have them over for dinner back and forth quite a lot and before i had my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> we sort of had a contest going where you know he would
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cook</ENAMEX> and then the next time it would be my turn and i'd try to outdo him and then he'd try to outdo me and  we we was really a lot of fun and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i bet that that got pretty competitive you know as far as who could come up with the best recipe
 	
 	
 		yeah it did and we we tried to be
 		fancier or more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> than the other or uh it was a lot of fun you know it something unique you know and then we got into different um themes you know um whether it would be
 	
 	
 		that would be fun
 	
 	
 		ethnic food or um sometimes it would be um oh oh i don't know maybe an outdoor theme or uh uh elegant theme or you know  it was a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		uh huh
 		sometimes it might be the candlelight and sometimes it might be the picnic out back or something  well that's you know that's fun
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		it was fun and and we threatened to make the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> uh
 		make us dinner <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time uh just to even it out since we seemed to be unfairly doing all the cooking and they were doing all the enjoying i'm
 	
 	
 		uh huh
 		
 
 		that sounds right i would i'd take him up on that
 	
 	
 		it does except that knowing them they would probably do something ridiculous and terrible just just to uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		make sure that they didn't have to do it again  make hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> or some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato chips</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		um-hum maybe  i that's about how much i can cook you know i'm i'm doing a lot more cooking now
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		then i used to but that's only because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> just started working so she's tired when she comes <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the afternoon so i try to have things cooked for her but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		uh um i usually try to stay out of kitchen i don't know  not one of my favorite hobbies but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it can it can be fun i if you have the time but you know a lot of times it's too it's too much of a rush really be able to enjoy it
 	
 	
 		well um my grandma speaking of those meatballs again she um every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> whenever we have at the big get-together over at her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> she makes this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat ball sauce</ENAMEX>
 		and it has i don't know they are just kind of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">like quarter</TIMEX> size meatballs and they are absolutely delicious i don't know what she calls them and i don't i'm sure she puts <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> in it because um she cooks everything with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't know i would i would be interested in getting that recipe for you if you have it around
 	
 	
 		yeah it's um it's in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> i don't know if we have enough time for it it's real easy one of the unique things in this  like a pound of ground beef some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> crumbs um an egg um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um what ever seasoning usually just light <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seasonings</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt</ENAMEX> and pepper <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um</ENAMEX> and chopped up water chestnuts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that would be wonderful
 	
 	
 		which is something different um makes them a little bit crunchy you need to chop them up real fine but um it makes them crunchy and that adds something new to it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> is just made with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um bouillon cubes water burgundy wine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um cornstarch</ENAMEX> instead of flour
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so it's not a it's not a thick rich type of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> it's more of a when you use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> starch in in gravy like you know when you have um <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gravy</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> that comes with a lot of that they use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn starch</ENAMEX> instead of flour in all of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauces</ENAMEX> and gravies and it gives it a bit of a different consistency
 	
 	
 		well um how long do you cook the meatballs
 	
 	
 		the meatballs you just um after you form them fry them in a pan until they're
 	
 	
 		uh huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> browned on all all sides and then drain off all the grease uh then what i usually do is i freeze them and then when you're ready to serve them
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		then you cook the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> and then put the meatballs into the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> and heat it probably you have to heat it up for a good
 		oh if they're frozen you know it may take a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> for them to thaw out but then heat them thoroughly in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> itself let them simmer in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> itself
 	
 	
 		hum that sounds great especially i mean the fact that you can prepare the meatballs so so far in advance i mean like if if you are having a dinner party on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> you could do it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> that would be great
 	
 	
 		that's real good
 		right and then freeze them
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i going to have to keep that in mind for my future because i hope to have lots of dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>  because i like to i mean i'm
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm sure that i'll be involved in a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and i know that my future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> will be you know he's going to be working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevron</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> so he's going to be um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i'm sure that dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> will come in handy
 	
 	
 		yeah you'll meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> invite invite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> over and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at work
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i have to impress the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>  and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> because um i'm in i'm in public relations in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so i'm going to have you know my whole job's going to be based on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> and stuff like that so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i'm gonna have lots of dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and have to take them out to eat and
 		right now i am taking a class on etiquettcy and all the little bitty things that i didn't even know i mean i thought for sure i'd been raised properly but i'd been doing a lot of things wrong i didn't know about
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but um  so
 		is there anything else
 	
 	
 		well
 		i i think we've we've covered the subject i've got some interesting information about crawfish i was in fact i was it's good cause i was curious about that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> when i saw those for sale
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yes you need to try them oh they're wonderful
 	
 	
 		oh i will i'm sure my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> will be
 		surprised because we were talking about them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> even before
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	