
 
     		
 	
 		okay what do you usually wear to work
 	
 	
 		well uh i am basically retired now i was a member i was in education and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> so basically i wore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dresses</ENAMEX> and uh heels and i was never one uh because my work often took me into court uh never was one that got uh accustomed to wearing pants suits and pants to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that was just me i know many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are comfortable very comfortable in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> and what have you wearing pants uh it i guess i was just old enough not to uh be very comfortable in it how about you
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and they don't really have uh dress code so to speak there it's pretty lax about um you know we you can pretty much wear whatever you want to
 		and i wear anything from jeans when i'm feeling really casual to uh suits and dresses when i'm meeting with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> or i i teach training classes
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so when i'm teaching a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> obviously i wear a suit or dress so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it uh definitely fluctuates mainly with what i'm going to be doing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> and kind of what my mood is and when it's raining i'm more likely to wear jeans and and when it's really cold i'm more likely to wear jeans or pants or sweaters or that type of thing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but it just really depends on the weather and my mood and then you know obviously when i'm doing anything that i'm in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or or making presentations teaching whatever i'm going to dress up more
 	
 	
 		yes
 		and i think that does make a difference because when you do have to be in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh i think you the the tendency there is to wear dresses and suits and and uh more classical style of clothing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what about the miniskirt
 	
 	
 		there are a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now and then</TIMEX> that wear those to work there pretty strict about that though um i've never worn i just wouldn't i mean even to well jeans aren't exactly professional but for some reason a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini skirt</ENAMEX> is
 		to me a little more unprofessional to wear to work than jeans just because it's maybe it's just because of the sexist views and everything but you just feel like you're you're being
 		showing too much leg i don't know i wouldn't want to wear a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini skirt</ENAMEX> to work i have seen a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do it though but they they weren't overly short and they weren't overly revealing they were pretty much in good taste but um for me i just
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for me i just i just couldn't wouldn't want to do that
 	
 	
 		well there are miniskirts and there are miniskirts there are some that are really short and then there are some that may be will come like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four inches or five inches</NUMEX> above the knee and again it depends upon the size the shape of the person
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's what i've seen
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as well as the shape of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s legs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now i also uh even though i retired from education i uh i do modeling and i teach at a modeling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so when we are doing wardrobing and we have uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two two hour</TIMEX> classes in wardrobe we do discuss a great deal the miniskirt and the types of clothes to wear on the job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh even though i may have them from <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade on up through uh grandmothers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and uh when i always try to emphasize the clothes that you wear should not necessarily be the greatest fad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because maybe they those are not the clothes that are the most uh appealing to you or the most uh complimentary to you
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh the miniskirt many times will evoke comments you don't really want
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and then uh then you're in the situation where you're very unhappy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i feel like too on the job when you know there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> around and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> you just
 		you know you don't want them looking at your legs  necessarily and uh to me i just wouldn't feel comfortable in that at work
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		well i i uh i have to agree with that even when they was very very popular in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early sixties</TIMEX> uh i uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh again maybe because i was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> there were still many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> who wore miniskirts uh we had no regulation against it and a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> did of course and it could be very embarrassing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men teachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because they were not that careful in how they handled themselves in those miniskirts
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so i think uh uh of course now i go the other extreme i do not like to see in the corporate areas uh all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> dressed like men
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with the suits and uh white shirts and ties and what have you so that they all look exactly the same
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i don't like that i don't i think there should be individuality in dressing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		even with the very tailored look of a suit sometimes i like to have something a little just a little something that's feminine
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		not you know you don't want to over do it but just a little a touch of it just to say yes i am a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> but i can be professional too
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i and i don't think that you have to be manish and extremely tailored to to look professional
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i think that you you make of that what you wish and you can go the opposite direction and uh overdo all the frills and laces and flounces and what have you which don't belong in the uh at least in my opinion
 		in the workplace uh but that that you can have a classical look without a lot of a great deal of adornment and what have you and still be very feminine because that was one thing i always fought against i started out as a physical education teacher
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i was always fighting against the idea of looking tailored or mannish uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would never ever guess that i was phys ed and um and that pleased me
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and uh so then i of course just continued what i considered the best style of clothing for me at work
 		and uh and i find even even at home here now i i will wear blue jeans or i'll wear shorts
 		and what have you uh and be very comfortable but when i go out somewhere then uh unless i have a pair of dress slacks i don't usually wear a lot of blue jeans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have difficulty getting them to fit me comfortably any how and so uh uh i just feel that uh you know each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has to dress to their own liking and for their own comfort
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh there are certain norms that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> should be able to uh put out as guidelines for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right that's what i one thing i like about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is that they aren't overly strict about what you wear and they don't
 		you know your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> doesn't come up to you and say now remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> you have a meeting so you'd better wear a suit i mean they they leave it up to you and your judgment to to use good judgment and dress tastefully and dress for whatever occasion you may have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		yes
 	
 	
 		the only real restrictions they have are uh no halter tops and no shorts even the long walking short of the squirts the the split skirts anything that that could be considered shorts they don't allow and they don't allow um
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		and they don't allow uh any sweat any sweat shirts or t shirts that might have vulgar or you know anything like that on it but
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		other than that it's pretty pretty lax and i think that's good because it does allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> and it allows you to kind of dress the way you feel <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> or you know if you want to be comfortable and casual you can and sometimes i think you
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		may be more productive if you're comfortable with what your wearing and can be be feel more relaxed whereas uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		sometimes when your in the suit and feel kind of almost stiff and you're not you know maybe you don't uh can't get as comfortable to sit down and you know like when i'm writing training material i prefer to be more comfortable unless i know i have to meet with a customer later during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		so that's i think that is good that they're like that i do know there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that are very
 		strict about what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> wear and they must wear blue or gray or black and a white shirt and you know no variation and i don't i don't quite agree with that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i don't either unfortunately i don't have to work in those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>  but uh i i uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		did have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> come over from one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> where i was volunteering and uh they were doing a presentation and every one of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> coming up
 		were dressed exactly alike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and women
 		they all had on the gray jackets and the gray trousers or slacks or skirts and the white blouses and the same color tie i mean you could hardly tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> except for the lengths of the pants
 	
 	
 		uh right
 	
 	
 		and one was a skirt and one was a pant and uh and i think that's sad because that doesn't allow for any individuality
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's uh can stifle creativity
 	
 	
 		right i agree
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well it i guess we've talked probably long enough nice talking to you too i enjoyed it bye-bye
 	
 	
 		i guess so well it's been nice talking with you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh bye-bye</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		
 		
 	