
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		so do you have a computer at home
 	
 	
 		i sure do i have an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> it's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one thousand</NUMEX> model but it's still compatible to the uh late model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> personal computers the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three thousand</NUMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> even the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundreds</NUMEX> out now and i love it
 	
 	
 		do you i got my i got my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one i've been at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> forever and i found an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> selling his really old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> PC
 	
 	
 		how about you you got one
 		
 
 		oh a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think so no not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety nine</NUMEX> it's one of the full <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> PCs
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety nine</NUMEX> i mean or something
 		i got you right
 	
 	
 		and he's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> so he even came over and set it up for me and had it running for like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred dollars</NUMEX> so i thought that
 	
 	
 		my goodness gracious
 		well you sure made a savings there i have never heard anything to beat that that's just terrific does does is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> compatible type
 	
 	
 		well now it does
 		no no no no it's just the old PC and it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> floppies it doesn't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Winchester</ENAMEX> it doesn't have anything but for what i need just keeping records it does just fine
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well if you ever decide to get a newer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> model think about an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> because it's the slickest machine you've ever seen
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		it's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four thousand ninety six</NUMEX> color graphics it's got real-time animation capability there's a world of games for it if you're into that but it can do word processing you can import pictures into your documents and uh it just does everything a PC can do but it does it better
 	
 	
 		i'll be darn when i uh i'm in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> right now but when i was up at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">McKinney i</ENAMEX> had uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM PS</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i loved that thing i loved it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you did well i i venture to say your you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> if you have any would enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> better
 	
 	
 		well i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> fortunately that have left grown gone thank heaven
 	
 	
 		oh really  well you're not supposed to admit that
 	
 	
 		to them i admit it  it was fun leave
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i are gonna be glad to get ours out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> too i know exactly how you feel
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">emptiness syndrome</ENAMEX> is a myth there's no such thing i mean
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		i'll tell her  we're sure not staying with the PC subject subject too well are we  well how how how much memory you got have you got on your machine
 	
 	
 		it's nice it really is
 		yeah we're talking though uh on my
 		you know i don't really know i knew when i bought it but i don't know right now i've got a little program uh genealogy program called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Family Ties</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and i can research and go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and and discover who married who what year and all this sort of thing and come back and load it all into my computer and then when i want to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		say this is going to be a present for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> tell them all okay here you are and then i can sort it all that they can trace it back to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and on you know do an explosion
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it all prints out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and you know you can select the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and get the whole thing i think it's just as neat as it can
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's neat
 		yeah i'd like to have a piece of software like that for my machine now on my machine i've got a microphone hooked up to it and i can digitize me and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all talking and all that but i can hook a VCR up to it and take our picture
 	
 	
 		oh how fantastic
 		how fantastic
 	
 	
 		and then then then if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had the same kind of computer which they don't they don't have a computer but if they did then they i could send them all that on a floppy disk and it would play out for them right there on the computer and they could click it to see each next scene
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but that's all possible to do on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> and frankly my VCR camera cost more than my computer did
 	
 	
 		get out of here
 		for heaven's sake i've never heard of one
 	
 	
 		but you can do all those sorts of things on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i didn't know anything about this that's fantastic
 	
 	
 		yeah there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't know about it it's put out by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodore</ENAMEX> they made the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty four</TIMEX> but this is a machine that they bought from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that got started up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well they make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> and uh not only that but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> is Unix compatible so if anybody around there is using Unix and they want a cheap Unix's work station that cost under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> runs Unix
 		and uh besides uh being able to do all the other things i was telling you about
 	
 	
 		well i'll be darn
 	
 	
 		it's a fantastic machine if you've got to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> compatibility they've got a card you can plug in and you can run <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> software but the machine is so powerful i don't need it
 	
 	
 		what
 		what do you have at work
 	
 	
 		uh i use a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> work station at work but i'm i'm in the process of purchasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> to use it as my desktop computer but research work though i use a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun Sparc</ENAMEX> station
 	
 	
 		so you're into computers
 		oh we have some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suns</ENAMEX> in this building uh i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> and and i help them with their maintenance contracts and repair and things like that just it's it's not much of my job but it you know i do come in contact with them
 	
 	
 		are you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		those are expensive machines
 	
 	
 		i know well see uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sparc</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> run about twelve <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> in color and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> runs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only forty seven hundred</NUMEX> in color
 	
 	
 		good grief
 	
 	
 		so it makes a real nice cheap Unix compatible desktop work station and see i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at home and everything i run at work i can run at home by you know same sort of stuff and uh
 		uh it really makes it quite nice it definitely does i have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four and a half megabytes</NUMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine</ENAMEX> here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh sixty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five megabyte</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagate</ENAMEX> hard disk and it rips
 	
 	
 		why do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has not used the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omega</ENAMEX> because uh-huh
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX>
 		well because it's made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodore</ENAMEX> and uh most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all they know about is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> compatible because most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that know anything about computers don't know much but they do know about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so when the PC came on the market and then it being <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the market earlier than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> was but when it came market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just naturally assumed that well if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> makes it should be the computer of my choice
 		and they intend to look around very much so as a result <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macintoshes</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amigas</ENAMEX> didn't get a fair break
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		where but honestly an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> is far and away a much better PC than the PC will ever be it has a full multitasking operating system during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas holidays</TIMEX> while my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> played games with my machines i backed up my hard disk because i used my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commodore</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty four</TIMEX> as a terminal to it like a main frame
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i was copying files off my hard disk to floppies and they were playing a game using the uh joy sticks and they never even knew i was there except i was sitting there and i was pushing another floppy into this little slot uh while they were doing their thing to keep copying files out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you can't do it on any machine a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> or anything made
 	
 	
 		well that's wonderful i'd never even heard of it
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of neat not to mention the fact that it's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four thousand ninety six</NUMEX> colors and you can't get more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> out of a PC or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> either one
 	
 	
 		so your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were having a good time and you were working
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right i can do that exactly  you sure can you can network them together and everything it's a fantastic machine needless to say so i'm very uh high on it but you said you have computers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suns</ENAMEX> at work right what other machines do you all have at work
 	
 	
 		that's marvelous just marvelous
 		well i work in I A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith</ENAMEX> so we're forever looking at something else uh i you know i work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i see well tell them to look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think it's a toy and a game machine but it is a most powerful work station all the way around multitasking and i mean a real-time multitasking operating system and computer made
 	
 	
 		well you know you'd be surprised how many of the various ones are coming in and giving us demos at all times and i sit in on all this stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		not only that but this machine can be hooked up to a regular TV set and you can do video presentations with it
 		it has all kinds of software you can use that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commodore</ENAMEX> makes called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga Vision</ENAMEX> so that you can take pictures in and then you can make up your own video presentation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packard</ENAMEX> uses it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett Packards</ENAMEX> makes PC's and they use the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> to do video presentations and um uh campaigns educational type uh presentations for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> incidentally incidentally <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bausch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lomb</ENAMEX> uses it too
 	
 	
 		let me ask you something uh if you were if you needed to go to another
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> somewhere you know fly to a to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX> and do a review there could you put your presentation on a television and just kind of send him the disk instead of going yourself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well what you would do in the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> is you'd use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NTSC</ENAMEX> output that you can get on the machine put it right out to a uh video video tape and just cut you a video tape by uh by running it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to the video tape because all the sound and graphics that it produces can be put right out of the back of the machine to a common VCR and recorded on a VHS tape
 	
 	
 		so you could just say okay fellows we've got a problem get everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and let them see this tape rather than buying an airline ticket
 	
 	
 		yeah if you wanted to you could uh but you could do the whole presentation and slick it up and edit it and make all kinds of changes and modification till you had it down pat
 		on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> once you had done that i mean including hooking up a camera to take pictures of things like maybe you want to do a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a a</NUMEX> a presentation on how to run some piece of gear well you want to take pictures of it you might want to take pictures of it running
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because you can put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> frame into the machine
 		and then you can describe what's going on you can record microphoning machine then there's a way to link all that together and once you got it satisfied satisfactory done you can then take it and play it back out of the machine right out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">port</ENAMEX> in the back to a VCR and record it
 		after that you can put it all on floppy disk it might take several and between on how big a space you're talking about and uh carry it to another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> if they happen to own an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX> well you slap it on there put it on their hard disk and away you go
 	
 	
 		how much will
 		how much would this cost
 	
 	
 		for what to do it well the parts or the machines depending on what well you can get a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two thousand</NUMEX> which is uh a bare essential machine to do this with for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about twenty three</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah for that whole operation
 	
 	
 		and uh then you would uh with some add on options and things you'd have to have probably the outside price at the max would be about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 		if unless you want to use a video tape to to do all kind of weird things like wipes and <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">and</ENAMEX> fades and things like that which the uh TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use
 	
 	
 		we don't need that type we don't need that type of graphics that's just not necessary
 	
 	
 		okay well if you don't need that which is really fancy and that has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty four</NUMEX> bit or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixteen million</NUMEX> colors
 		if you don't need that that's another fifteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> and that's made by a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> just for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amiga IBM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mac</ENAMEX> both tried to get them to make it for their machines but they can't because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amiga</ENAMEX>'s the only PC on the market that has special graphics and sound
 		and peripheral handling chips inside and that's why it can be a multitask operating system and not and handle numerous multiple jobs at once because it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> co-processor chips in there that help out the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CPU</ENAMEX> and off load from doing the graphics
 		see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CPU</ENAMEX> in my machine is a little old <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty eight thousand</TIMEX> and it loafs because there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> co-processors chips in my machine to handle the graphics the
 		the color graphics one co-processor chips handles all the sounds and it can make it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> channels of sound <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them come right out the back as stereo ports i have mine hooked up to my stereo down stairs has excellent stereo
 		dynamic range and it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> chip in it that has all your peripherals so that if i were to copy a file from my hard disk to the floppy
 		then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CPU</ENAMEX> just goes out and tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula</ENAMEX> that's the chip that does peripheral handling copy this file from the hard disk to the floppy and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CPU</ENAMEX> goes off and does something else because
 		
 		
 	