
 
     		
 	
 		are are you a uh a TIer
 	
 	
 		uh no no i work there as a temporary
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but are you at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so you have to do the random drug testing
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah in in in fact with me uh this is uh it's not much to talk about i i'm so
 		much for it i don't really have much to comment about it uh there's been some interesting subjects that they've called how many times have you called or have you been participating in this uh
 	
 	
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten ten</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> calls
 	
 	
 		oh you got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> well you you've passed me up this is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh um as contract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> we have to do random drug testing too so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it doesn't bother me i don't feel like it's really a violation of privacy or anything
 	
 	
 		no i think it's good in fact uh i don't know what the statistics were but i think that they were very surprised to find it
 		so low i think they were expecting it to find uh like the national average at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and i think it was tremendously down
 		i think
 	
 	
 		as far as the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> you mean or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		yeah as as far as the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they actually found that were <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> but i think that uh i was well you had when i was at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> of course we had all the information before they started
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they said that a certain number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that the heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> would either quit or go in rela rehabilitation programs and i think that's what helps you know that that you know warning when you have a drug program
 		uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are worried about it or are taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> actually go and then uh usually a lot of them uh partake in uh some of the benefits of of rehabilitation and everything so
 	
 	
 		right yeah so that's real beneficial for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and the employee
 	
 	
 		yeah our our numbers have been way down i don't know what they were
 	
 	
 		oh when i worked for the temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> as a permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and so we had when we sent temporaries to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> we had to have them drug tested and we did have a couple of cases where we really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> said that they hadn't used anything and their test came back positive and normally we didn't retest them but there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we really thought that they were telling the truth and we retested them like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> and they came back negative
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time so that that's the only thing i think that might be a little bit of a problem
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you're that's a good point but at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> they before they had the testing i've forgotten it seems seems like it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago September</TIMEX> something like that
 		they told us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that did it was the one that did it for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and and that of course that's critical just as the point that you're brought up that
 		whoever does your testing has got to be you know have a lot of quality control that they keep track of everything they don't make mistakes that would be terribly embarrassing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		for someone to really come back positive and they were not and i haven't heard of any now i'm not in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh they say that there it's almost down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come back and say they are positive and and they're not you know in other words there's very few mistakes and that of course has got to be critical it's got to be
 		if you have a drug testing program it's got to be with a very very good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> you don't just have you know some local uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> do it it's got to be a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a highly qualified agency
 	
 	
 		right yeah not just some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s office somewhere
 	
 	
 		no you don't want to do that it's got to be you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> that do quality control and and double check and i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has has latched themselves up with an established group
 		and and that would be true for any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that does it and and not to have a just a very casual thing it's got to be with a
 		you know <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class totally independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> not local of course ours i think well i think it was in in the south somewhere but it wasn't even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> you know the one that did us yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		huh do you do they um have a policy where they counsel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if they come back positive or do they fire them right away or
 	
 	
 		oh no no they're not fired they there are they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chance to then go in a program if you come back positive you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chance to go in and go into they have a lot of uh rehabilitation both for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use uh
 		and they have uh a lot of uh they they have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> where you can go for personal problems financial or whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so they they they they don't no it's not firing first it's uh definitely try to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to rehabilitate in fact they
 		again before you go you know that's that's why i said when they first started it they had a rehabilitation program in effect that said if you worried about this and if you may have taken drugs
 		go ahead and and get rehabilitated <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and and and they won't even say anything about it you know oh sure
 	
 	
 		right i think that's really good i know some places just fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the spot if they come back positive or something
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 		oh yeah no that that's not right it's really uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> or whatever you want to say that it is you know it's a weakness and all and who who all of us have weaknesses of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind or another and i think that uh
 		those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have that and and however they got into it i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i always worry about the the classical thing that you see on TV where the drug uh pushers
 		give it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> for free you know and get them sucked in and then they sell it to them you know the classical thing is to give it away or i always worry about my teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> going to some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and they slip it to them i i don't know i don't even have that much knowledge to know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		whether that would uh get them addicted or not you know that that's a real worry
 	
 	
 		yeah some of the stories you read about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> that's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> try it one time and they're addicted my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> and he works with mostly with adolescents
 	
 	
 		oh you know a lot about it then yeah
 	
 	
 		so yeah i hear a lot of horror stories about things like that but most of the time it's
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		they get into a wrong crowd <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and then they start a drug problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's usually not a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time accidental thing i don't think
 	
 	
 		yeah i know i i'm glad of that and i have uh knock <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> had uh pretty good luck with or very good luck with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> so far i know that they're not on it that's my  phone i i i have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> still at home one's at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> and one's at home gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of calls a night
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh no no no no no i i i don't care about that that that she she'll be on the phone <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		well i'll let you go if you want to go ahead and take that
 		um yeah uh it seems just if you watch what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> that start running around with and kind of keep up with who their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are that's best way to avoid trouble from what i can gather
 	
 	
 		right
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no not yet we're expecting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> so we're starting  from yeah
 	
 	
 		oh great oh fantastic fantastic experience i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> as i said i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at home and uh i always say that i've learned so much more from them than i than ever taught them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's a uh fantastic experience you can't
 	
 	
 		oh we're really excited about it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you
 	
 	
 		you know one thing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> believes is if you suspect your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are having any kind of problems he believes you should take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in for a random testing like on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> if they've been out at a party <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you're not too sure what's going on he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> all the time haul them into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and get them checked
 	
 	
 		the the key thing that i think uh we try to do is that bring all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> over here have our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> as a place where they can come at any time
 		so that you always see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> rather than make them not welcome and they're always over in someone else's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so our we've been lucky that uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is usually the place where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> could come you know and
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh-huh yeah i think that's a really good thing to encourage
 	
 	
 		and then you can kind of keep an eye and you can make judgments and make comments or whatever you want but at least you see what's going on and uh you always have your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> welcome then then your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'ll think that uh you know you're cool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and all that you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well well good luck with your your expected uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> there uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was yelling in my ear was talking in my ear she said uh reminded me to say that uh they're very cheap until they get get to start dri ving
 	
 	
 		oh well thanks
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we have one of course i say in college driving and and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> going to drive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> so uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are cost you practically nothing because you always get so many things from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> and everything but
 		you wait until they go and get a car insurance and you and that's when they get expensive as they get older you know uh it it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		they they cost you practically nothing from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one to five</NUMEX> and then slowly but surely starts to creep up when they start to take lessons but uh it's well worth it and everything
 	
 	
 		gets worse
 		
 
 		yeah uh yeah i think it'll be neat
 	
 	
 		be great it's a great experience really you still there okay i thought that was cut off there but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yep i'm still here
 	
 	
 		well good you know i don't have much to say about drug testing uh
 	
 	
 		well i can't think of no i can't think of anything else to say about that either
 	
 	
 		so you you've done this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> did you get did you get the booklet on as to get the gifts and all that
 	
 	
 		uh no i i don't work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> so i get cash
 	
 	
 		oh okay well i i didn't know what they're they were going to do they sent us a little booklet i just got it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or so ago</TIMEX> saying you know
 		so many calls will be something a prize and everything
 	
 	
 		right yeah there's yeah
 	
 	
 		well that's great well what kind of cash i've forgotten what were they going to do
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		was it <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a call or something well hope i hope they follow through and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a call
 		yeah well technically we're not supposed to talk about the phone calls while we're on them so i guess we better get off
 	
 	
 		right yeah well right
 	
 	
 		it was good talking to you bye
 	
 	
 		right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bye-bye</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	