
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay my views it asked for my views so my views on that are yes i do still consider them a threat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really
 	
 	
 		and yes i do and the reason i do is because
 		um i've
 		with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> was raised and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX> was i because it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikita Khrushchev i</ENAMEX> believe
 		i know it was one of the old old school <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> and uh he he is a definite he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist Leninist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> through and through
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist Leninist</ENAMEX> communism is a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> because um the whole nature of it is to control the world the the whole goal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> Leninist
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theology</ENAMEX> is world domination
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i do not believe that it has not they've never stated that their goal is not to
 		you know take over the world and they've never repented of all the massacres all the just the you know the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of uh massacres they've killed more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and all this and so no i don't trust them a bit i think it's a big scam
 	
 	
 		think so
 	
 	
 		yes i do i yes i would all but say i know it's a scam you can't trust him he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> for years
 	
 	
 		was he
 	
 	
 		yes he was for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many many years</TIMEX> he was trained in the old school of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX> theology and he he's never changed any of his
 		any of the he he deals in that kind of theology he's you know he might say one thing but what he does is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leninist</ENAMEX> in nature and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so that's why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> are so angry with him right now is because they've they know it's a scam and so you know i that's what i feel i don't know what do you feel do you agree with me or disagree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		um you know it's it's hard to say uh if if things change uh change there so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		rapidly but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev Gorbachev Gorbachev</ENAMEX> is i don't know i think i think you you're right he's a chameleon he's just a
 		he's
 		he he's just he seems to have flip flopped
 		on you know uh uh you know when they first came into power when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was in he was this real nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and he was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		trying to uh win everybody in the West over about what oh what a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX> he was and all this other stuff but then you know now he's uh
 		know now he's uh you know crushing the  uh demonstrations and and and trying to close close it off again so i i i can't figure i can't figure him out i don't know if he's being pressured from
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh above or around or uh from other places in in
 	
 	
 		well if he got out of line too much from the old school they'd just knock him off i mean they're not going they're not going to permit anyone in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Parliament</ENAMEX> to get in power that's going to change anything too much so
 	
 	
 		yeah that
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are starving i mean they cannot
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they've got to know that something's got to give because they're in their society you're not at
 		you know it's supposed to be all for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and one for all but that ain't how it works baby i mean that's you know they're not going to do something unless they've got incentives and they don't have any incentives to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no because they've taken them from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> Leninist theology is to i mean it really is its own religion it it could be classified in theological terms as a religion because it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they deny God self is everything self you know everything is um for me for me for me and therefore
 	
 	
 		or for the for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> which means everybody else except you
 	
 	
 		right but that's not what they really do they say that but that's not the reality of it even the Bolshevik revolution the whole thing was uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		an attempt to uh gain authority without
 		you know having to be risen up in authority the best way to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godly</ENAMEX> authority is to you know work and and work your way to the you know work your way up not being promoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> because promotion comes from God
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but when you anytime you see a nation go in and just overtake it and it's take it take authority take control it's a i believe it's a spiritual
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		thing that happens and it's like a spirit of witchcraft it's like a a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> goes over that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> because you have these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that want they're power hungry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they want all this power and they want to control all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and it's not for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it's for themselves and the way you know that is because they didn't work their way up from the bottom up they went in and they took power and they took authority and they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		took authority and they cut and they stab and and our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> does that a lot too i know it's not necessarily i don't think this is the greatest system either but i just feel like there's just a lot of oppression
 		over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> because of that the authority is there to exalt self that's the whole Leninist theology they deny God they deny any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> they've
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		forbade religion for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and God's the one that opened the doors for their religion for for Christianity to go in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> it's not it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> he will not receive the credit for that because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> man
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		saying that could not have done anything God had to open those doors and i believe that the the pressure just got so great from the people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because that they you know they God just honored their prayers and did a miracle because i don't know we our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastor</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and we work with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minsk</ENAMEX> and in
 		Belev <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and some other places and so i don't know i have a real heart for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> that's why i think it's funny we got this call because
 		i have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> my one of my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> is going into into the underground church cause it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		basically it's still underground it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and so they're going in a mission trip into Latvia
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months</TIMEX> and so they're preparing for the trip you know and and it was i sat behind her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and they had their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> folder
 		so i thought oh that's cool so anyway so this is kind of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my little pet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anyway i don't know i just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think they want a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> world order that's what i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> would like to see a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> world order a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> world economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with him in charge of it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is going around talking about it too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's like all these pawns on this chess big all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> on this big chess game you know and it's a world championship and who is ultimately going to get the power who's going to get put in checkmate and who's going to be ruled out of the game
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and who's going to have the power over what they want to establish in this one world you know community they're always talking about it all the time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you hear a lot about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it it's all that it's it's all that uh the new age philosophy and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> you must be to know new age
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh yes oh yes i know all about the new age philosophy yeah and uh it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 		right
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but they are in such disarray over there they're not in any position to exalt exert themselves over anybody right now like they were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> falling apart and their whole economic system falling apart they can that that we need to take real advantage of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to to pull their satellites away from them
 	
 	
 		but yeah i think that they still are a threat but yet maybe a different ki nd of a threat than a military threat but i do believe that they're a military threat i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just look what we did to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it was with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> were they fought us with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and they've they found out the hard way how bad badly put together the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's true yeah that's true they did didn't they
 		i know it's it's interesting i still wouldn't want to take them on though
 		i still wouldn't want to take them i still think we need to be very careful but i believe that their economic
 		or an economic threat more than anything at this point
 		because they want control over the i know they want control over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and that you know that's why i see them diversifying their their power and their control that they have
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and like for you know instead of just being oh big tough <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> but i still believe they've uh they've probably got weapons we can i mean they they never would sell to anybody else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh of course
 	
 	
 		you know so i guess i feel like yeah they probably i wouldn't want to mess with them but i don't trust them i'm not all like oh yeah they're just like us i i have a heart for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> no
 	
 	
 		no no no
 		not not not for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> definitely not for the leaders
 	
 	
 		no i wouldn't be surprised if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> wasn't a satanist wasn't a satanist i'm not kidding
 	
 	
 		well they're they're they're a secret they're a secret society they're a secretive society
 	
 	
 		right
 		even yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and they're not going to let you see what they don't want you to see
 	
 	
 		exactly even you know in our own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was in the scull and bones the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trilateral Commission</ENAMEX> and all these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> with ulterior motives and so it's like what on earth is you know are these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ever here and involved in
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		in the high ranking things i mean when you look at their history and what they've done to their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> what they've done it's like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can we trust them have they repented for what they did have they made a world apology
 	
 	
 		no they haven't
 	
 	
 		we we repented this was wrong we're going to start seeking God and we're going to start seeing God to do for our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> what needs to be done
 		and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> will call a national day of prayer is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> saved i don't know God knows he says he is and i'm going to trust that with him but i mean it's just no i don't trust them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no
 	
 	
 		you'd be crazy if you trust them but anyway call it what is it McCarthyism no  i'm not like that i just got enough common sense that nope
 		to you come repent make a world apology for all the wrongs that you've done and yeah we've done wrongs but we've not done near the atrocities they've done and we need to maybe do that also you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i'm saying i'm not saying like oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> we're so we're perfect over here i'm not saying that either but that's not what the question asked so  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i could preach
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		
 		
 	