
 
     		
 	
 		hi
 	
 	
 		i don't know much about this topic let me ask you does she spell her name with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ns</ENAMEX> and an E
 	
 	
 		uh no she doesn't  okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh okay well then we're all right okay that would have been totally weird
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i have no idea who listens to this
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's right well we'll find out later  they've got this all reported i guess
 	
 	
 		there you go yeah
 		
 
 		oh right i didn't know there was a proposal to serve young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to have a year of public service
 	
 	
 		actually i didn't either um uh i really wasn't familiar with that and um i didn't even realize i had put that as you know this must be something
 		fairly new because i don't remember this as even being one of the topics you know  had to put have be discussed
 	
 	
 		yeah i didn't
 		i didn't either are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh God close <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johnstown</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ha</ENAMEX> we're not suppose to do this  i i can i'm from originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beaver County</ENAMEX> oh my God
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh your kidding
 	
 	
 		no i could smell an accent <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a mile</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		oh isn't that fun only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from there can tell everyone else is where did you get that weird accent
 	
 	
 		are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		uh no right now i'm in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s a TIer
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh okay well my yeah actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he's with the uh he's with the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and uh i'm a civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> but i'm taking a year off
 	
 	
 		
 
 		are you my
 		oh how nice
 	
 	
 		um what uh how do you feel about uh the the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are they are are they talking uh do you think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen years of age</TIMEX> like right or during high school
 	
 	
 		i don't know i'd <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all is there a proposal in this i mean is there a legitimate proposal i didn't see that on the list but i guess it's unless yeah
 	
 	
 		i've never heard of such of thing this is this is really a surprise to me i wasn't total i'm glad it was you because i was afraid i'd get some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on here that knows all about this
 	
 	
 		yeah really i guess i would say that if there is one i would think that they are talking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen years or twenty one years</TIMEX> of age
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i personally don't think it's a good idea for a year i would look at it more as a uh internship kind of thing maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> through you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days to six months</TIMEX> or something um but more than that i would have a problem with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		and and how do how do you think that they would propose to do is far as if uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is coming out of high school and going to college how could you know i wonder how they could possibly
 	
 	
 		enforcement
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh if this would be a voluntary thing or a mandatory
 	
 	
 		yeah the way the the way the voice might have worded it it sounded almost mandatory as opposed to elected and i would obviously i mean not obviously but i would be against anything like that being mandatory
 	
 	
 		yes it did yeah
 		well i think i would also and i think it it really uh would be very difficult in terms of uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'm thinking mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> going to college i don't see how
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		how with uh the work load <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have nowadays and what often most college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> i'm like maybe when we went to school i don't know how long ago you went but
 	
 	
 		thirty something
 	
 	
 		yeah  me too and and uh you know i think it it's it's most of them now carry part-time jobs on top of having fifteen or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> credits
 	
 	
 		there you go yeah
 		
 
 		that and thus think i mean i don't know i went to uh even though i'm from that part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i did go to high school in uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and i we had it was mandatory that we took civics every year
 	
 	
 		yeah oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah it was a mandatory and then you had to take a test that showed you had a certain knowledge of state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> and they did offer actually certain types of public service internships that i think is a very good idea that that's mandatory
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i see
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't know how any i mean the whole thing sounds a little bit ludicrous but that's my word
 	
 	
 		yeah the other thing i think that they could do possibly is with um
 		i don't know when i went to school we had um in our social studies we had it divided into for every report card period like there were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six six week</TIMEX> sessions and we could pick what we wanted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to take you know whether you wanted to study <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Indians</ENAMEX> or this or that maybe as one of those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six week</TIMEX> sessions instead of having a class um or have the class but as part of that or part of the credit would be to do something like that on a voluntary basis
 	
 	
 		and when they're younger not when they're getting into undergraduate and college age
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i i uh i really i'm bewildered as far as how they could even work something like this in if they try to make it mandatory
 	
 	
 		i don't yeah and i maybe that's not what they meant maybe that's just the way both of us took the wording but i
 		i think it's a good i get idea to get younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in some way or the public you know happenings it's just they they're not aware of why things cost what they do why things operate the way they do but i just
 	
 	
 		right
 		right and in this area there's so much going on volunteer wise like for home life uh i you know i know it's for
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you mean in the in the area of geographic region you're in uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah there there are many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> uh feed the hungry all these there's a lot of drives in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for this type of thing already you know not neccessarily sometimes um
 	
 	
 		grass roots effort
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they might even have i know uh with a niece and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> of mine they're <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was uh like uh church <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and they even had things where they would have them go to shelters downtown and help for a day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		or um what a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do here is um they have things to school where they have actual they have a holiday game <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> but every your uh your uh fee if you want to call it or the way you get admitted to going to this show is to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		bring a can or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> for the hungry
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they do that i mean in in in north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they do that quite a bit where you know if you want to go to this particular movie or concert or a discounted thing the big thing down here is rodeos uh if you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah  that's quite different from up here i guess yes
 	
 	
 		yeah really i'm i'm bite my lip i'm not going to talk <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>  it's just listening to you i just talked to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's like really weird  coincidence yeah uh um i really don't think they can do it though i mean i i you know i think that things that your talking about like anything that emphasizes the social services
 	
 	
 		yeah that is this yeah that is pretty wild that is pretty wild yeah
 	
 	
 		with the public service  i
 	
 	
 		right right or yeah i think they can integrate maybe a short period of time
 		in with high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and get them to be aware that you know they're not uh especially <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> they're not the only ones around and what maybe their
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are going through especially i know in an area like this it's uh fairly affluent and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> here are really out of touch with reality i always call it <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		are they
 		even are you are you in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> or are you in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we're in no we're in uh where they call it now north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Potomac</ENAMEX> it's it's a  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> but it's close to Potomac
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and um you know you see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen year olds</TIMEX> driving around in brand new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMWs</ENAMEX> and it's just unbelievable you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that's we're in a yeah that's we're in a near next to a town called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Plano Texas</ENAMEX> and it's very um it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falls Church</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery County</ENAMEX> i'm familiar with where you're at um and they really that's a good way to put it i know
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i went to high school in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> at an inner city school although i lived in a different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> near a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Evanston Illinois</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the reason that i stayed at the school i did was because at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Evanston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">township</ENAMEX> which back then was like one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the country
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		everybody was already doing the um driving the beamers and you know with nothing to think that um they didn't have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> dollar wardrobes you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i i just i just think the one thing they do so strongly about is what your saying that i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have a sense of civic responsibility
 	
 	
 		no they don't
 	
 	
 		i think then that's a step away from even duty i don't think they even have a sense of the responsibility
 	
 	
 		right and i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other area here is that um this is typically what we call in this area yuppie area and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know other than you know occasionally they're not even aware that there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over fifty that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		exist  you know and and i think it might be another good public service might be to have them help out in geriatric <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> or you know this type of thing they are around uh
 	
 	
 		this is true yeah
 		yeah i think the one thing the the there's a program called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh Habitat For Humanity</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> started the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and i think i think programs like that with what you just talked about going on in your area local area at and something like that would be good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but not that specifically but things along that  of of activity
 	
 	
 		right and i i in general i feel that um i don't know what this still proposes far as what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age or</TIMEX> or how they would do this but i feel that reaching
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> when they're younger is better though i think once they're out of high school they're so into their own thing that i think it would be very difficult maybe by that
 		time they're too uh calloused to what is even going on you know where as younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> it's the it's the grade school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> when there say no to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and that type of thing in school
 	
 	
 		formed yeah they're already
 		right
 	
 	
 		they're the ones that'll come home and tell you you know you shouldn't smoke it's bad for you shouldn't drink it's bad for you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think it's the younger it's the younger uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that it reaches more and so if they want to start this type of thing it should be integrated maybe from a young age and and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i agree with you like pre junior high and and um see and make it you know a curriculum oriented type of proposal as opposed to anything mandated like the old selective service or anything so it sounds like we're in agreement with that
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right right
 		yeah i think so uh
 	
 	
 		anything any else we can  we can talk about
 	
 	
 		i don't know i guess that's it say hi to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> if you're
 	
 	
 		talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> yeah your right it's like i mean this is very strange because i'm not in that part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i don't care if they listen i'm not in that part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>  i don't want to offend you i and i'm not in their part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so what i hear all my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and it's like oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah you miss yeah i don't know if you miss it or not but
 	
 	
 		yeah i i do i mean i didn't grow up totally there because of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> parental divorce in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but um you know it was always shuttle back and forth so uh it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> but yeah i miss it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well this is a good area because you're far enough away and yet you're close you know so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> and things or whatever you wanted to you can be there but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know i enjoy being here i don't know if i'd ever you know i might go back there eventually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> it's a depressed area uh right now you know
 	
 	
 		yeah really is they've cleaned it up a lot though i mean i don't think we'll get in trouble doing that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> i lived there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> i i liked when i was a teenager and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early twenties</TIMEX> and i liked it there a lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't but i really enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		yeah i lived there in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early twenties</TIMEX> too before i moved
 	
 	
 		oh  that's the
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's weird i hope we never met
 		
 		
 	