
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh okay go ahead yeah i understand the topic <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> is uh our policy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> and you know what we've been doing down there so i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no no go ahead
 	
 	
 		as you indicated you don't have too much input into the area it it just so happens that uh our daughter-in-law is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panamanian</ENAMEX>
 		and uh we have been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> and i have worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX> and
 		we visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> occasionally so  yeah we we do have a little information on it here but uh
 	
 	
 		oh very good because actually um when i was in college i visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> several times i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> and um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX> but but recently i have been following the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> rather than
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it does seem to have quieted down there just a little bit that's that's for sure
 		no i the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> policy uh towards <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> as far as uh well i kind of go back to to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Salvador</ENAMEX> thing because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> had a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> down there for a while and i worked in there for a little while and at that particular time let's let's see that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy three seventy four</TIMEX> kind of before the the uh the
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> really picked up down there and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> policy at that particular time there was of course military assistance to uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> itself you know anything that's
 		that's anticommunist you know we kind of had a tendency to be pro  it don't matter what their excesses were and i believe at the time that i was down there that uh the
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Salvadorian</ENAMEX> government you know really gotten out of hand yet the uh right wing death <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> type situation i believe that that was beginning to form but i don't
 		i i wasn't really aware of it's being you know terribly uh you know rapid at the time that that i was down there i think that really kind of developed a little bit later on
 		but uh our policies seem to be pretty much one of uh you know trying to setup businesses
 		down there and use the one resource anyway that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salvador</ENAMEX> had  plenty of and that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we didn't seem to be going in and taking anything out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> other than just it's it's labor
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because everything that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> did anyway we we shipped in and it was worked on down there assembled and then sent back here so i didn't feel that we really exploiting exploiting them any
 	
 	
 		did that have
 		um so you don't you don't feel that that we were um
 		exploiting in the sense of we were benefiting and they weren't
 	
 	
 		no uh in the particular incidence that i was aware of now <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> wasn't the only ones in there <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playtex</ENAMEX> was in there was uh several other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course we kind of concentrate on there wasn't much to take out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i felt like we're going in and taken all their um their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> or anything like that because uh it just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the only thing that they had a great abundance of was uh you know human beings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> did did we tend to um change their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attitudes attitudes</ENAMEX> like
 		some times when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> go into foreign countries they tend to flaunt <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> things Americanism um consumer products TV the whole works
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i understand what you say there was a uh
 		the time that i was down there i stayed quite a a bit at the uh uh one of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Salvador</ENAMEX> and at the time i thought there ought to be a law against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>
 		because they for the most part tend to be the most obnoxious
 		as a as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and i saw this in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> so uh oh you know it's it's the uh the almost stereotype
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know flowery shirt shorts camera hanging around their neck you know demanding this that and the other thing you know we're we're here and we want this and we want that and that sort of thing that's
 		that's the stereotype that's very strong down there you know that uh
 		the you know that sort of thing
 		i i i believe those of us who were working down there got a little bit more appreciation for
 		you know the local
 		uh culture i really don't believe that we were
 		quite that bad but yet they were having to deal directly with uh you know with the uh the local people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> there is a there is a bad uh uh you know the old brash ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> type
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		situation and i saw incidences in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> where i just wanted to go over and crawl in the corner and say oh my God those are those are not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>  they can't be but they are
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh of course now i i do have to i remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case where we had some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX> in there who were every bit as bad but i mean it i think it's just kind of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North American</ENAMEX>
 		situation uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> they've been used to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> down there for so darn long
 		but i didn't see quite as much of that sort of thing as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Panamanians</ENAMEX> are just about as  as uh as as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> as far as uh creature comforts you know they're uh they're they're every bit uh
 		i i know when my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and he was stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> and he married a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Panamanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and when she came up here uh you know she's
 		you know except for the language situation some of the cultures she's just about an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> you know is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far as</NUMEX> TV and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know the the moneymaking part of it and all that matter of fact if anything she's worse  but uh uh it it just there's little enclaves down there where you know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have a lot of influence
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> kind of
 		um you know sort of accepts that but i've also seen the other side of it too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX> but um
 		i there weren't as i recall or at least i wasn't aware of that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> there except for a very heavy concentration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> this was when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first</ENAMEX> are started and it was one of the big targets
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i don't i don't think at that time at least <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> was
 		uh
 		an obnoxious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in the sense that that we were very controlled regarding number of days off and and you couldn't just take up take off and leave your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and go explore and and things like that
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but and i was working actually in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> program so that was quite specialized although i was living in the slums i was really working with the middle class
 	
 	
 		uh-huh What uh what area did you live in
 	
 	
 		i was up in Arequipa
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		i've heard of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so
 	
 	
 		well
 		well is are they is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> still active down in there
 	
 	
 		i don't have any idea um probably not i mean there were thirteen i was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru Peru</ENAMEX> thirteen which meant there were twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> before mine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that had gone in and and some of them were quite big in the sense they were community development and they were building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and doing coops and things like that health um inoculation and and things
 	
 	
 		oh has those influences lasted do you know whether the the things that that you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> before you
 		did did those
 		did those live on or were they reabsorbed or how
 	
 	
 		no no i believe they did because um some of some of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> uh that i knew of did marry <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvians</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and have been back and every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then some news filters in that they went to see some of the old things and of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> program um
 		that was that you know that that just continued to grow in fact after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> i mean we were just a very small specialized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> too to get that going and spread and then of course <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> bowed out of that because that's uh uh
 		something that nationalized very quickly and the same with the coops
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's that was kind of the the aim wasn't it to get it started and then have it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		taken up by the oh okay oh so you know well that's
 		i had wondered sometimes i knew that there was a lot of a lot of effort and a lot of work went into a lot of that and i just wondered if if it lasted and if it took you know like yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i've you know some of the programs i would have concern about like um the language teaching you know i mean
 		why should we push <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were down there teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and when they talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX> or someplace one of the eastern law <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> requesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> to teach
 		language you know to me that's a little bit marginal i did teach economics at the university <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and the textbook was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> but basically i taught it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spanish</TIMEX> because i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i really didn't see the point in their knowing stuff rotely and writing it on a test
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah my brother-in-law teaches at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Illinois University</ENAMEX> and they were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and he was over there
 		at uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Shah</ENAMEX> and and teaching
 		
 		
 	