
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh right up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> out there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh right
 	
 	
 		did you hit one
 	
 	
 		yeah i just hit one then
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> scandal
 	
 	
 		it i got to uh this is going to be fun are you <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		kind of neither
 	
 	
 		okay well i'm a i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> so i was going to say if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> we would really have a good time
 	
 	
 		i do have some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> leanings because i am division one you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i uh to answer that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before we get to our subject you know i always get a kick out of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who take credit for all the military hardware that
 		was bought for the war and how successful it was though when it comes to the budget they say well the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> control all the money and they're the ones wasting all the money and i always wondered how they can play the money either way they want you know i get a kick out of that but anyway the subject go ahead you first
 	
 	
 		uh i think it's a stinking shame that
 		that there isn't capital punishment for those assholes that stole our money
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh i don't think it's over i think that uh so many other things have taken over uh in the media
 		but i think it was just plain greed and i think it was deregulation really when they said do anything you want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> go ahead loan your money out you know
 	
 	
 		i agree with you i think it had something to do with deregulation but i believe uh
 		more of it was just greed
 	
 	
 		yeah i was talking to someone i can't remember who it was but he was a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> and he said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> were calling he borrowed some money and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> were calling and just looking for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to give their money away
 		they just got totally carried away with buying property and reselling the same property and uh yeah there there should be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in jail as far as i'm concerned
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		not just a couple
 	
 	
 		you know we've watched and watched TV and seen that a lot of these people
 		were doing things not just playing in the gray and not just reselling property at a profit but financing the same property <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and four</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and the list goes on and on
 	
 	
 		well i i agree <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		you know of of just the crimes committed
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		much less for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> that should be indicted
 	
 	
 		it may have started with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> too i noticed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HUD</ENAMEX> was in terrible shape and that was property and uh they lost a lot of money there and then some of these big these rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> started to even uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murchison</ENAMEX> here who owned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> had a lot of property down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> this was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> and he lost you know all all of his money before he died
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not all of it i don't know how much he lost but uh they were just buying property and buying all kinds of real estate and thinking that there was a bottomless pit and it always would it always would increase you know it always would uh
 		uh be more than what you paid for it and they just never even got conservative with our money at all
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 		everyone forgets whose money it was
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and everyone forgets that there are several of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are
 		wanted
 		by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> currently and are overseas where extradition is merely a funny <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> word
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i
 		i as far as being a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> i think no American
 		could stand
 		for criminal action
 	
 	
 		well now the reason that i said that is because i was going to blame all uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganomics</ENAMEX> for you know you spend your way to prosperity and when you opened up the bank deregulation without any controls i thought well
 		that was the philosophy you know just keep spending until taxes are lower and i thought that's not going to work you know and i knew that it wasn't going to work originally
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		and it hasn't worked now you know
 	
 	
 		in theory in theory a healthy economy
 		has a lot of spending going on
 	
 	
 		right no doubt no doubt
 	
 	
 		and
 		and if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are making money
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can spend money
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it'll generate taxes
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i i agree with that but there's got to be some control and apparently there was you know
 	
 	
 		well the problem is and the problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reaganomics</ENAMEX> is
 		that
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the top are the ones getting rich
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		for what they would cost and we weren't producing anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> weren't producing anything it was all inflation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i'm sorry we don't get into a real argument over it we agree too closely but
 	
 	
 		yeah i know uh
 	
 	
 		but you
 		you can't say that that was right
 	
 	
 		oh no i
 	
 	
 		no intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can say
 		that
 		we could spend our way rich
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		remember all we're doing
 		is delivering pizzas to each other
 	
 	
 		and and not high quality ones at that you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		well i do have a lot of confidence in the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the economy and everything else i i feel bad when i see the inefficiency even here at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> you know and i think that the
 		it it still a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> don't understand that uh they need to put out the best that they can because it comes right back to them you know
 	
 	
 		it is a life and death struggle with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		i know and i when i of course i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and i work with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> and i just cannot understand why they're just happy to
 		spend their time here rather than produce you know and they think that well i'm paid anyway so it doesn't matter you know
 	
 	
 		i i'm very tired of it all pays by the hour
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and i'm nonexempt
 	
 	
 		yeah oh really
 		you don't sound like a nonexempt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is so
 		what
 	
 	
 		you don't sound like a nonexempt
 	
 	
 		what what does a nonexempt sound like
 	
 	
 		uh you're too informed they're they're very they're very uh not interested they wouldn't even talk probably about some of the things we're talking about now
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i guess i'm dealing with too many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> here i don't know really i'm being a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> i guess i'm i'm letting my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> come out you know
 	
 	
 		uh that's
 		well i
 		now maybe i'm not the uh typical nonexempt that you deal with
 		the badge is silver
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i am degreed though nonexempt
 	
 	
 		uh well that's good
 	
 	
 		no  that's not good but
 	
 	
 		no right i mean that's good that you're degreed
 		uh uh your time will come we uh i know a few people
 	
 	
 		no i i do not wish my time to come
 	
 	
 		oh really what are you in a tech like do you do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> work or something
 	
 	
 		oh no no no i
 		government tool control is my specialty now i did PC protection control work for uh
 	
 	
 		oh quality okay
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or twelve years uh right now i'm just trying to tool crib and hauling chips
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		times are bad
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well now is is uh really terrible i'm uh management level uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and when the cuts came <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us got uh bounced back and so we're just uh i'm calling you from work i'm i'm covering uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weekends</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> now i'm i'm one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager reps</ENAMEX> there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us to cover in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and just we're essentially standby and problems uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all all nights</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> that's my i only get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one weekend</TIMEX> off a month right now
 		i call it my recession job
 	
 	
 		it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> being basically an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and liking uh doing installation work well there's not any i mean there literally is no installation work going on
 	
 	
 		they turned all installation up here off
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they told <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> they could not work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't care what the jobs are
 		you will not work
 	
 	
 		yeah it it
 	
 	
 		and and as far as our you know
 		our conversation goes
 		i would really be interested to know
 		how much
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s problems now are related to
 	
 	
 		banking
 	
 	
 		the banking structure
 	
 	
 		i think that not not only <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> but a lot of it when they talk about uh there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point i was going to make i think the last i heard and i i have to admit i'm not as informed uh that much but there's something like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about eighty six billion</NUMEX> that they admit well i always double that i figure well
 		if they claim that it's going to cost us eighty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six billion</NUMEX> it's got to be twice as much because no one admits their mistakes and so if that's true it may mean that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred billion</NUMEX> dollar category that was that went down the tube somewhere
 	
 	
 		i
 		it really hurts me
 	
 	
 		yeah it's amazing really it's amazing that
 	
 	
 		to realize that
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there are trying to retire on their home values
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i know what you mean
 	
 	
 		uh one of our
 		senior
 	
 	
 		course your value of homes up there are pretty good i mean here they're not really that high but are they pretty good up there
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		our economy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> fell completely apart
 	
 	
 		well we're in the metroplex here you know and uh it it i die every time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Dynamics</ENAMEX> they they lost several contracts and and i don't know if you noticed yesterday
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you probably don't pay attention to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Helicopter</ENAMEX> you know they were going to have big uh award and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secorski</ENAMEX> got it which was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing Secorski</ENAMEX> this which is up in the north somewhere you know
 	
 	
 		yeah it's northwest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle Seattle</ENAMEX> and also uh they do some of that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wichita Kansas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i don't know how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> didn't get it
 		well i i don't they were advertising here that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI TI</ENAMEX> was getting the uh electronics with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> and so it was a double one that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metroplex</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> was doing the electronics for them
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and they they advertised that that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI Bell TI Bell</ENAMEX> and then all of a sudden <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secorski</ENAMEX> got it yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secorski Boeing Boeing</ENAMEX> doesn't need the money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secorski Boeing</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		something i almost think there's some politics around here because the metroplex here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Fort Worth</ENAMEX> area the uh
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i don't know if <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has lost as much as everybody else but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Dynamics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LTV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> have lost project after project you know
 	
 	
 		well you realize
 		
 		
 	