
 
     		
 	
 		well ironically enough i'm sitting here with a cast on my leg because i resumed an aerobics class <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night before last</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		i ripped the ligaments in my right ankle
 	
 	
 		awe
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		exercise is not supposed to do that to you
 	
 	
 		that's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> kept saying as they laughed all the way you know down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hallway</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you do anything on a regular basis
 	
 	
 		well i i off and on off and on right now i've been off off
 		but um i've been going over to the fitness center
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a good yeah i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house unit</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> uh-huh well i try to go over there <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and i try to walk um at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times a week
 	
 	
 		do you when you go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> i have to ask you and if this is getting to  we're not supposed to get too particular but i'm just curious
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when you go over there does it bother you in terms of how things are arranged either at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> location or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> in terms of there's so much it's so much of a weight orientation weight lifting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera
 	
 	
 		yeah uh well i've been going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> i haven't been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> one now in oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> yeah well at least since they've redone it supposedly redone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's well it's not that great and i go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> one on and off but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s working over there and he just goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> one but i just don't i mean it's just so much weight lifting even the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> one has a lot of weights in it
 	
 	
 		so i don't really know what
 		yeah
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		or is that what your into or
 	
 	
 		no no well i've i've used the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nautilus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">equipment</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> and stair climbers and stuff like that mostly i don't use the free weights but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tread mill</ENAMEX> and the stair master myself over there
 	
 	
 		yeah i like those too and the pool yeah that's great
 	
 	
 		and the pool when it gets warmer
 		yeah  i know well what i did was i went to a jazzercise class
 		in a new location in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> near where we live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> and
 		long story short i hadn't this is really a stupid thing that happened but they have like the gymnasium flooring and then like they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> feet of linoleum around the perimeter in the back where i usually stand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> like that i go to instead of having that level you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they had a chrome strip that wasn't level and it was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about four inches</NUMEX> deep and then about oh a seventy degree angle
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and as we were jumping around or doing something i just jumped up and came right down on it
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		the orthopedist called it a uh basketball injury where the ankle just rolls under you and it snapped
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		woo
 	
 	
 		i know we went to uh HDA well whatever in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> and the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> was like a bad comedy show
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> said you didn't do anything there's only a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> chance that the radiologist will call you that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> the radiologist called me at work and uh i was on crutches and he said i think you better call an orthopedist
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		so we went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and he just put a big old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		put a big cast on it
 	
 	
 		yeah for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		so i mean i like aerobics but i'm not so sure
 	
 	
 		well not that much though
 	
 	
 		no i've never i was off for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months</TIMEX> too just for some other surgery i'd had but i've never i'd you know i was pretty much in shape walking and
 		and you know this is one of those things like this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orthopedist</ENAMEX> said he said you'd be surprised how many basketball how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in here with things like that because they are active
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i was real embarrassed but i felt kind of stupid
 	
 	
 		well those things happen though
 	
 	
 		yeah they do i mean i guess i'm glad you know that um nobody really noticed i guess you could say
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i got up and started jumping on it again
 	
 	
 		well that did a lot of good i'm sure
 	
 	
 		yeah really so i enjoy aerobics and i do it because i like it i mean i like the music and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		i like the music but i've been unable to do that because i hurt my foot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years ago</TIMEX> i broke my heel
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh so
 	
 	
 		that makes my foot how'd you do that in aerobics
 	
 	
 		no no actually i was up on a ladder and uh fell off  leaned the wrong way
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when i came down i hit with my full weight on my foot but on concrete
 	
 	
 		what'd they do for that did they have to cast it and
 	
 	
 		yeah they had well they had to go in and do surgery they put a pin in it
 	
 	
 		oh so the aerobics the impact would not be good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that  cause i permanently damaged the the uh cushion under my heel you know the normal cushion that you have there so
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't do any jumping up and down because it makes it hurt
 	
 	
 		oh that makes sense so i mean are you in terms of other things like like like not running but playing a little bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> or can you not do stuff like that at all
 	
 	
 		uh well i haven't tried that i don't know it's been i bet it's it's been  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> since i played tennis
 	
 	
 		yeah it's been
 	
 	
 		but um mostly into just walking and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		that's probably the safer way because i notice in aerobics um lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that that don't look like they shouldn't be doing certain things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm always afraid they're going to fall over and have a coronary coronary
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there was my ego when i went ahead and i went oh i can do that and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		half the time though i don't um jump <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as much as i mean i'm like i'm real tall and you know i'm i'm not heavy but when you go easy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred seventy</TIMEX> at my height um i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-hum uh-hum
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know you just take it easy um but when i see some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i mean some and i just don't think it's healthy all that pounding all the time
 	
 	
 		sure
 		it isn't really it's not really good for your knees
 	
 	
 		so yeah that's the other reason and
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		i don't know this was just i guess something freak that happened to me because i wasn't familiar with the um
 	
 	
 		well the floor was uneven you know
 	
 	
 		oh it was completely i mean it literally the two dissimilar floor level floor coverings were not level and at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> after it happened i thought maybe that's a handicap access and then i said no that's just the way it's constructed
 	
 	
 		sure
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> i said i said a few things to him when i got home i said who has engineered that
 	
 	
 		real ly
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i uh sounds like you like one thing that i like like swimming you like that a lot
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i like swimming uh-huh
 	
 	
 		do you like that what'd that voice say do you like to exercise because you want to or because you have to
 	
 	
 		uh no i like i like it because i i want to it makes me feel better
 	
 	
 		that's how i am yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if i don't do it i just feel like i don't have as much energy
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i mean it's real funny because if you you know it seems like when you exercise and expend the energy that you'd be tired but it's the other way around
 	
 	
 		right it curbs the appetite and helps with the calories and all that stuff
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah really
 		yeah and i need all the help i can get
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 		that gravity factor i know
 	
 	
 		uh-hum uh-huh it does get you
 	
 	
 		like that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">orthopedist</ENAMEX> said to me he said don't worry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX> he says he said uh you're at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> something but you're on the upper side he said that uh don't worry he says even if you weren't doing anything your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> would start that would start to happen to you
 	
 	
 		but thanks a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah because i was saying to him i said i'm not that heavy i'm not heavy you know maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> pounds like any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i said uh why do i feel like i need to start pushing myself more and he goes human nature
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		and then you know you see these little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in these little bitty things and they're all like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one years</TIMEX> of age
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		but luckily at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> there's a little more diverse diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's true they do
 	
 	
 		except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that lift the weights they do intimidate
 	
 	
 		they do
 		yeah i try try to go real late or real early before they get there
 	
 	
 		there's
 		yeah there some things i'd like to try but you know sometime when i ask i just feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> am i stupid or what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's one thing i like about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> place at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> that's there one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> that's there at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> is real helpful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and his name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B J</ENAMEX>
 		and
 	
 	
 		i don't think i've ever i think i've that there was some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> there i've been there like maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> times but i actually like that site better than the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> just because of the type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that go to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's terrible it's i don't know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> location it just seems that um sometimes i feel like i'm in a singles bar
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's true yeah i and i haven't haven't noticed that up at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't either and i just uh it's not that far of a drive and i'm glad they did that um you're not missing anything at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> renovated site it's not
 		at all anything worth talking about
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought maybe one of these days i'll drive over there and check it out but
 	
 	
 		yeah but if you don't live near there that's not worth
 	
 	
 		yeah i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> but it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> way between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek</ENAMEX> and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> site so
 	
 	
 		we
 		yeah that's that's actually where this happened to me out in i say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> but it's all the same to me <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> over on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park Hill</ENAMEX> there's a uh new recreation center
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh as we were doing it too everybody noticed that there were all these big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> of assorted nationalities  to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> waiting around for us and as we walked out i was limping and i'm like oh great i have purple <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tights</ENAMEX> on you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're going yes but in general i like to exercise i i like dance a lot so i mean i aerobics is something i'd hate to give up but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he he kind of said something to me about probably not as bad as your foot but he just said to me maybe you ought to try bicycling or
 	
 	
 		yeah  probably will for a while because it
 		it's going to be real tender when they
 	
 	
 		he told me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> to twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> not anything you know i said but you're only going to put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> he said yeah but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's just  they tried to put me in some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um immobilized walker</ENAMEX> because he doesn't like to put casts on when it's warm but i just the more they tried to get my foot in the more i screamed i couldn't you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i know what you mean
 	
 	
 		adjust that well you you know more about this stuff than i do obviously then
 	
 	
 		not fun
 	
 	
 		no well you're walking okay now obviously and you can
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i have a slight limp from it but it matches one if i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the other side
 		yeah  yeah you know
 	
 	
 		so you're still able to walk yeah
 		well is there anything else about exercise we can talk about
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well other than i need to go you know more
 	
 	
 		yeah me too me too i need to go actually get something to eat here
 	
 	
 		i need go more but it's great though i really do enjoy it
 	
 	
 		okay thank you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure thanks then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh bye-bye</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	