
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all right  um
 	
 	
 		so let me guess it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		no not originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		uh either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> i think's almost everybody's favorite
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know
 	
 	
 		not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i used to be a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> when they back in the seventies when they were real good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Csonka</ENAMEX> and all them yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah they were my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		well i didn't get uh
 		into <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> until about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Dan Marino</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> year
 	
 	
 		okay are you you used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville Kentucky</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		no just uh i liked them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		my biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> ever my favorite was uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> Rams
 	
 	
 		they're pretty good i like their
 	
 	
 		yeah i never lived anywhere near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Dickerson Dickerson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		but i think they're on the down slide
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> coming up is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX> huh um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		he's getting some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> together some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> together there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think the the team i like rooting for the best which i don't i don't know if they really are the
 		
 
 		a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but they're an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> that's why i like them is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Eagles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Cunningham</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you don't like him
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i like him
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i like him because he's reckless
 	
 	
 		i think that's why i don't like him
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog team</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> oh yuck i hate them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> put me in labor back when they was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and i i kind of rooted against them and everyone else couldn't understand why
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there are really serious about them
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i know
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> for a little while and uh
 	
 	
 		so i
 	
 	
 		i don't know she said they go crazy
 	
 	
 		yeah i had fun rooting against them it was
 	
 	
 		yeah you'd have the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on you didn't you
 	
 	
 		i know
 		it was kind of funny because i wasn't from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i don't know
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		i've never been to any  a game or anything like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i just uh
 	
 	
 		i've gone to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few</NUMEX> games i not in a while
 		went to uh actually went to a play off game once
 	
 	
 		that would've been great
 	
 	
 		when we lived i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and we saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX> play the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colts</ENAMEX> in the play off
 	
 	
 		when was this
 	
 	
 		it was like uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least ten years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it went into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">double overtime</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i bet that was a good one
 	
 	
 		yeah it was a great game
 	
 	
 		i like those close games
 	
 	
 		so who do you think's going to win this year
 	
 	
 		right down
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
 		that's a toss up between uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> with them trying to repeat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and oh i hate to hazard a guess uh
 		i'm trying to go through and see who's got who uh
 		i'd say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX> but i doubt it i think they're going to be next year
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> might try to make a run back but i doubt it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they've lost too many people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>'s got a pretty good shot
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i uh
 	
 	
 		if they hold together
 	
 	
 		forget who their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> is i can see his face
 	
 	
 		yeah i can't remember his name either
 	
 	
 		what is his uh let's see
 	
 	
 		they have the defense to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh if i could think of some of their names i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Smith</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Smith</ENAMEX> uh he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> isn't he
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no he's a defensive end
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he's a big mean guy
 	
 	
 		i shoot i can't even think who's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> uh the uh darn uh coach name for the Bills
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um isn't it Marv Levy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's it
 		i had fun watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> because the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> looks like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm like what is he doing what's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX> doing out there  called her up and said hey what's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> doing out in TV
 	
 	
 		the what
 		now who who was this
 	
 	
 		uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>' coach um what's his name i can't think of his name
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Parcells</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Parcells</ENAMEX> yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> looks like him
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so i had fun laughing at it
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right i i didn't catch that for a minute
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		looks like him a lot younger but
 	
 	
 		oh there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that i out and out hate and that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you hate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX> i don't really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Mike Ditka</ENAMEX> i don't like the way he treats people
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i didn't like him from uh
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMahon</ENAMEX> was real big f or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh he had put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Flutie</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Flutie</ENAMEX> had called a time out
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you know he was in trouble the time was running out on the clock and he goes walking up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ditka</ENAMEX> to talk to him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ditka</ENAMEX> just turns his back on him and walks away
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and i didn't think that's
 		you don't do that
 	
 	
 		no i mean that's not what a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s about
 	
 	
 		uh but he you know
 	
 	
 		i mean if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> screws up you got to say okay you screwed up what do we do now and move on
 	
 	
 		it's you know
 		i played softball and i screwed up coming around <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> base one time and the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> actually called time out and came and tapped my tail with her foot and said you know pointed that finger and went ah yeah yeah yeah yeah you know and i thought okay
 	
 	
 		so that's better than ignoring you i think
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah well it didn't hurt and she was more you know we was in a uh it was a play off of a sort i guess yeah we was down in there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		huh
 	
 	
 		uh for the uh nationals
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		i'm trying to think where we were
 		i don't remember where we were
 	
 	
 		huh well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX> just got a uh one of the new football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> whatever it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Football League</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World League</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh Sky Raleigh Durham</ENAMEX> Skyhawks
 	
 	
 		have you watched any of those games
 	
 	
 		i watched a little bit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> of the one game
 	
 	
 		oh i've watched the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> you know i they're combined
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's who was playing
 	
 	
 		i've watched them twice and they look like bumbling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idiots</ENAMEX> out there at times
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh they don't look like they know what they're doing
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and i know they do
 		they've got to know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i watched them when they was playing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> over there in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> i think is where it was and uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> i watched them play
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and they just they looked terrible
 		but they got the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> backing them so they might make it
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah that would be interesting to see i'm uh every attempt so far i think has failed  at a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> football league
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah well well uh that's how i got to liking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Flutie</ENAMEX> he was playing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Generals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		on uh the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USFL</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> they had a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> called the Showboats
 	
 	
 		yeah i remember that
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i didn't care for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Showboats</ENAMEX> much but i did like a couple of their players
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and a couple of them even went to the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> i just don't remember their names
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Doug Flutie</ENAMEX>'s the only one that sticks out in my head for some reason
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		uh i think that's because of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditka</ENAMEX> done to him that just put it in my head and kept it there but uh i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know
 	
 	
 		well
 		it will be interesting seeing these games across the you know from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> or wherever
 	
 	
 		yeah well i that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Knights</ENAMEX> i think is who it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spain</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they were a fairly decent looking team
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		they take the football serious
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh shoot i don't remember remember what the score
 	
 	
 		well they have a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> behind them you got to remember that instead of just you know one section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> like we have
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		i never thought of it like that
 	
 	
 		they don't they don't have another football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to root for no competition yeah so
 	
 	
 		no competition
 	
 	
 		they're going to have a lot more support over there
 	
 	
 		yeah i know they take their softball serious or their soccer serious i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		definitely
 	
 	
 		and so i guess they would take it serious i i never thought of it like that
 		i guess the next time somebody starts harping down i'll just bring that up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's a good come back thank you
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right sounds good
 	
 	
 		what about your kickers
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		kickers on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">softball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">kickers huh</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know i hadn't thought too much about that i always liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Bahr</ENAMEX> because he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX>
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX>
 		so
 	
 	
 		i i've i've barely made it out of high school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but i like uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reggie Roby</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reggie Roby</ENAMEX> who does he play for
 	
 	
 		he <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh at times i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Butler</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX> you know there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i like on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's he's all right
 		but they got uh
 		uh what's his name
 		i was going to mention Majkowski but he's a quarterback
 		oh well i can't think of his name
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		can't even think of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> he plays for either
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		that's real bright
 	
 	
 		huh
 		all right well listen i've got to go
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		it was good talking to you
 	
 	
 		all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	