
 
     		
 	
 		all right well i have a lot of different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that i like to to keep in touch with of course <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX> being one of them i mean uh you know you can't live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> without you know
 	
 	
 		well what are the others
 	
 	
 		well uh i originally came from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> so uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis Cardinals</ENAMEX> are one
 		um i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> see i have i have a tendency to adopt adopt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> when i went go to a team uh go to a town yeah so uh i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> and i adopted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royals i</ENAMEX> lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half years</TIMEX> so i adopted the uh
 	
 	
 		well it's helpful
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Astros</ENAMEX> so i mean you know i've got quite a few
 	
 	
 		well do you keep up with the statistical stuff
 	
 	
 		no i don't i don't get into that too much every every once in a while i will keep in in touch with maybe like who's in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of hitting or something like that but i don't get into you know how many errors somebody has or things like that
 	
 	
 		well there's there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on that was on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norm Hisken</ENAMEX>'s show that i listen to going to work in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> who does uh uh it's essentially trivial statistics but they've got a statistic it's a statistic that has to do with winning
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and losing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one</NUMEX> run games
 	
 	
 		i've heard of that one
 	
 	
 		and apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> won a lot of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> run games
 	
 	
 		well i didn't know that that's supposed to be a real good statistic uh
 	
 	
 		well it it it is but it's the it's it's a reverse indicator
 	
 	
 		well that's true they don't have the offense to uh to get out or to have the the more runs so
 	
 	
 		well what the what the argument is and it it it it's one of these statistical gee how can you draw a conclusion from it but they find that that that there's a connection between that and how they do in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spring</TIMEX> training <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's strangely enough it's almost like the law of averages catches you on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		which means that if you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good year</TIMEX> winning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> run one run games that the following year
 		you'll have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad year</TIMEX> and they they've got um they've looked at i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and the uh the statistics are something like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty one</NUMEX> out of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX> it was which means that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> are going to have a terrible year i think
 	
 	
 		which i was kind of leaning toward anyway to tell you the truth
 	
 	
 		well i mean and it's uh i don't know what do you what do you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incaviglia</ENAMEX>'s uh loss
 	
 	
 		i kind of think it was necessary i mean i i i i don't i'm not a a big um
 		pure power <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hitter</ENAMEX> anyway i mean i don't like these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that get up there and swing for the downs every time i mean uh i think that uh that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> ought to hit a home run if he's got the pitch to do it
 		but when you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> strikes on you you have a tendency you know you should you know shorten your swing a little bit you know if it's a perfect shot go for it but i mean you know the strike outs were a big problem for him and uh plus supposedly what i heard he was not much of a team <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> anyway so
 	
 	
 		well it it's an interesting concept though when you look at uh of of how baseball how apparently i was reading in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit Tigers</ENAMEX> are going to sign him
 		and uh and the point of of i i guess i don't understand the the strategy of how baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">works</ENAMEX> but it seems that
 		you know they can sign him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> and he could go in the team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> and and and they put him in the lineup and he hits a home run and all of a sudden he becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and and all he has to do is hit the ball i mean it's not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well that's true
 	
 	
 		and and all he has to do is one you know hit it once it doesn't he can he can strike he can swing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times if he if he fouls it up he can swing as much as he can it's an interesting uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		an interesting concept of of how they do that but i agree with you i think that i think that's part of what
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">uh baseball</ENAMEX> needs more of i uh i i guess what bothers me is is that when you go um you wait and wait and wait and finally a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> gets up there and blast a home run
 		and that's all the game is i'd rather see the ball hit around and
 		have the people
 	
 	
 		yeah well there's there's another point to that too they said that um that he was horrible at uh at batting with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> on base now
 		having somebody get up and hit a solo home run does you you know gives you one run obviously but i mean if you can't do it with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> on base there's something definitely wrong um you know you you've got to be able to get the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> run home runs you know to to be able to
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh score enough runs to be able win in these uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and age so
 	
 	
 		yeah well how do you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royals</ENAMEX> are going to do
 	
 	
 		i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royals</ENAMEX> will
 		do okay they have they have several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> that had badly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years last year</TIMEX> and they are they're these
 		uh cycle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> they they pitch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year bad one year</TIMEX> good one beer bad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year good</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saberhagen</ENAMEX> has won uh supposedly the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cy i</ENAMEX> think he won <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cy year</ENAMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and uh you know so he's very much due for a good year
 	
 	
 		well are they going to beat are they going to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well now see that's a good question i that's i don't know how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>'s going to react to being uh swept in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> they could very easily
 		uh take that as a challenge which is the way most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> naturally you know naturally do uh and and just go out and and not give anybody a chance to beat them so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> from time to time and i watch i i watch their sports up there and they're uh they're they're certainly intense about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinals</ENAMEX> they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> is there is there life up there like <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> is down here i think
 	
 	
 		you did you actually live in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i lived in the suburbs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah everybody does right
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true too  i think that's all that they have
 	
 	
 		i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that lives in uh yeah it's well i should say on the west side i mean everything's on the west side <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manchester</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh out that way and uh went and visited him but anyway it is interesting well how are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinals</ENAMEX> do you still keep up with them or something
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah oh yeah i i definitely do in fact i've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that still lives up there um from what i hear from everybody up there they're not going to have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good year</TIMEX> because they let too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go but i've been following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spring</TIMEX> training and they're like one of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in spring training so far so
 	
 	
 		well is that a good indicator
 	
 	
 		that well it can be it it really kind of depends on on um
 		what they were you know what they were looking for in other words if if in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring</ENAMEX> crain training they were looking at all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like a lot of them do
 		um then it really doesn't give you any indication but if they were uh playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they're going to play then that might be pretty good indication so you know it's it's it's not a great indication because there have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that have just
 		you know come out and just won all kinds of games in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring</ENAMEX> craning training and then gone on a you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> game losing streak in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of the season so
 	
 	
 		you know what i think's remarkable is uh it seems that what you really need to do to win though is to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that has reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and has some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have have have really breakthrough years
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah
 	
 	
 		and and the question is how do you forecast that if you had to you know if you had to bet on who would be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> i mean it'd be really tough
 	
 	
 		you can't
 		right the i think the best thing that you can do is go with um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> that are
 		that have the talent to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the best years</TIMEX> and um that they hadn't had these
 		uh gigantic uh career <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> yet and and just kind of assume that you know someone one of them is going to break through eventually so and i i think they said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> um this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i'm not sure that they said that they had that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> having career years
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and and so they may be even better better this year
 	
 	
 		well well when are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> going to come through with it
 	
 	
 		uh that's a good question i the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> have a have a pitching problem
 		and whether or not they can fix that or not is going to be an interesting question they're doing the right thing though uh they are going with their farm system they're letting their farm system uh build up and stuff like that and
 	
 	
 		well is there enough money that's part of it i oh oh that was part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skip Bayless</ENAMEX> argument i don't know if you read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skip Bayless</ENAMEX> but a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a local commentary and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		his argument is that uh the ownership is not inclined to lose big money long enough to to bring in the big dollars
 	
 	
 		um that's probably true well conside ring what i've seen in the last uh you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two seasons</TIMEX> i'm beginning to agree with that yeah but i mean you don't have to spend the big money as far as i'm concerned to uh
 	
 	
 		would you would you agree with that
 	
 	
 		to win you just have to spend it if it's necessary in other words if you've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> who's helping your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> then keep him there don't let him go away you know and i think that's really what's been hurting uh uh the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 		well didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> put up quite a bit of money for their pitching staff
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they they spent more money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> and they were you know toward the bottom of the league uh so it's like i said spending money doesn't guarantee you uh winning a pennant
 		it really doesn't so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well and that i think that's maybe part of it that that the um and it you know if i owned the team i think you'd like them to do well but the question of losing big big money that what didn't didn't did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinbrenner</ENAMEX> actually make money on the
 	
 	
 		uh you got me i you know i think that there's coming to a point real soon when ticket prices are going to be to the point where the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> can't go and once you do that you lose everything i mean
 	
 	
 		well it it it yeah it's it's a little bit like any other sport you know when it starts costing you fifty to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> to go to a game
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i mean i i guess as we get older if you're probably going if if you if you compare to go to a a sport a a say you go to a rock concert or or even a performance uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		an opera or the symphony or something uh if you know it but how how often do you do that and i i would i would think baseball probably feeds on a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can go out there you know several times a
 	
 	
 		right
 		that that's the whole point there're so many games in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">in a year</TIMEX> that they've got to have repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> they can't afford not to and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know that's one of the things that i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> has done um i mean their you know their ticket prices are you know kind i guess as high as anybody else's but what somehow or another they attract
 		uh so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from some i mean they're a some it's a small market and yet they attract as many if not more than most uh uh most other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah but don't you think there's a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX> there're older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> there i don't i don't mean older um you know the fact that that it's it's a better established and that the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is is is more of a of a
 		
 		
 	