
 
     		
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		um yes
 	
 	
 		let me see
 		let me see uh interesting subject i was i was a law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half</TIMEX> so i've got uh slight bit of expertise in that area
 		not much
 	
 	
 		well explain this to me
 	
 	
 		i
 		okay
 	
 	
 		why do we have sometimes a petit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> isn't it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a grand jury
 	
 	
 		uh okay it depends on the kind of action it is and also depends on the state um you don't have to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of twelve and that's true in just about all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> um
 		it just depends on which ever state statue governs on the uh selection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> now the the term petit usually applies applies to grand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> you have a uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> and a petit grand jury
 		um sometimes in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> they also call a uh less than twelve member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> a petit jury uh did that sufficiently confuse you
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all right now</TIMEX> when do we have them just in criminal big criminal cases
 	
 	
 		um
 		uh when when do you have what a jury
 	
 	
 		when you have both like i was called
 		for a murder trial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they had had already had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> trial and determined that there was enough evidence to go on and have the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one
 	
 	
 		um okay
 	
 	
 		so is it just murder or what
 		where you have both
 	
 	
 		uh okay i i still i still don't get it both what
 	
 	
 		both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh at the same time
 	
 	
 		no they didn't have they had had one
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah
 	
 	
 		and decided that there was enough evidence and then
 	
 	
 		okay uh well well what they do is on a criminal indictment <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> they go to the grand jury okay the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> will either indite or not once a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is indicted then they generally have an evidentiary hearing
 		um
 		and it's strange strange that there would have been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> there because evidentiary hearings are usually are just before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> now it's possible they had another trial
 		in which
 		now i i i don't know enough about it to to really to really say uh uh
 	
 	
 		say
 	
 	
 		how long did the other trial go do you know
 	
 	
 		huh-uh i don't know and like you said maybe it was just with the judge i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah uh the thing is
 		in almost almost every case when there's a question about uh the evidence against the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> there's there's what's called an evidentiary hearing
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">both sides</ENAMEX> get up there and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> decides whether or not the evidence is good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and if the evidence is good then they go ahead and go to trial so you were probably probably being tapped for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> for the trial
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i'll tell you something i think ought to be changed
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		well they sent out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> summons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> showed up right all the others had gotten out of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> went on for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> explaining to us how the law goes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and some of the particulars of the case and then all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got to stand up if they wanted to get out of it well that was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of us right stood up and tried to get out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i mean that took like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> at least for him to listen to everybody
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then he he didn't let hardly let anybody off you know it was just like we wasted a prayer i didn't go up there because i knew i didn't have a leg to stand on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well it's it's hard to get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty i mean it's uh it's an obligation on on each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> and short of uh any of the special circumstances then they generally won't let you out
 	
 	
 		yeah i've been getting out of it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> because i was going to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you can plead that and i had small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but then i found out that you're not supposed to plead that unless you're the care taker you know and i'm not because i have to go to work and then they were going to day care so i shouldn't have been doing that
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but anyway
 	
 	
 		well as long as they didn't question you too closely i mean the thing is uh the easiest way to get out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these things is uh
 		uh uh they'll ask you questions like do you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> have you heard anything about the case do you have any uh specially if it's a murder case they may be asking for uh for a capital uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>'s capital punishment
 	
 	
 		punishment
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you can always say that you object to that and they'll let you off there
 	
 	
 		well i certainly i believed in it in some situations you know cases but i would feel that it would be very hard for me to impose it on somebody
 	
 	
 		yeah uh that
 	
 	
 		i think
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that won't get you off
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that you you have to be you have to be dead set against it
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um
 	
 	
 		the fact that you're willing the fact that you believe in it doesn't uh doesn't matter of course they're going to ask you can do you think you could impose it in this case
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know i that that to me that's always been a stupid question i i mean i don't know i haven't heard the evidence yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean if if if he did something really really gross then yeah
 	
 	
 		well this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that was sitting in in front of me said that he was a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> and he had been tailing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that was murdered
 		and as far as he was concerned that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was guiltier than hell now listen to what he supposedly did he supposedly stuffed paper toweling up this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s nostrils and down her throat and strangled her
 	
 	
 		ugh
 	
 	
 		now how this happened was this rich little socialite in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> decided that she was going to bump off her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> because he didn't want to divorce her
 	
 	
 		oh God
 	
 	
 		and she wanted to get a stab at more money right by knocking him off
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		so she hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> to do it and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> actually did it
 	
 	
 		oh God
 	
 	
 		now she uh in the mean time took off with one of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who was also under indictment for attempting <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> among them
 	
 	
 		
  
 		they ought to make this into a TV show
 	
 	
 		yeah among them <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> right so they split anyway they got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and he's now going to side with the cate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> so that he'll get a lesser sentence
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah he's going to turn states evidence
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		God
 	
 	
 		pretty interesting huh
 	
 	
 		now that that would have been fun to sit in on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well now they're going to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up after they've gone through this <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> page thing that we had to fill out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and decide to call in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to three</TIMEX> at a time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're going to do this let's see all through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> and the trials not supposed to start until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> well that's the beginning of my vacation
 	
 	
 		um that
 	
 	
 		i don't want to be picked
 	
 	
 		nothing like taking your vacation what you ought to do is reschedule your vacation real quick
 	
 	
 		i can't i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>  it's then or never
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah um gosh
 	
 	
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		what a way to spend your your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not going to be summoned i mean out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> i'm not going to be one of the twelve especially see i put that down that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had told me that
 		but then i've heard that won't make a difference either
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's
 		well it may because it it's something that could have influenced your your your uh
 		uh your uh your bias
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so well there's a good chance if they if they ask you about it you know i would i wouldn't just come out and say i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> guilty
 		but i i would say that i've heard enough about this that i i really have a preconceived notion
 		of of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that you know
 		in in other words if you if you can just show that you're not going to be
 		that you can't be uh unbiased that's going to be enough
 	
 	
 		well
 		what do you think can we change the system
 	
 	
 		well there's been all kinds of talk about it but quite honestly i don't think there's anything else that we could put in place that would work as well i mean i i realize it's cumbersome and uh
 		uh it's time consuming and at times even ridiculous but it the that nobody's come up with any better solution
 	
 	
 		but something ought to be done because if you have money you get a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and you get off
 	
 	
 		well that that is that's a
 		that's one of those things i think's sort sort of a preconceived notion on the part of the public they you can have a whole bunch of money and you can have the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> but
 		you you know if you've got if you've got a reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> who will look at the evidence i mean you see that's what it all comes down to it's the jury
 		uh if they are
 		i mean there's no doubt that you you can pick a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> okay in some in some respects you can get the kind of jury you want
 		but short of that i mean if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are reasonable and they'll look at the evidence and decide on that basis then then you know supposedly money doesn't count
 		but on the other hand what can you do about it i mean what what solution is there
 	
 	
 		but if you've got a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> he's going to be able to get more
 		persuasive evidence than a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> would to present
 		and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> that's you know chosen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that really doesn't even want to do it
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh you mean a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> appointed lawyer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah there's there's little doubt that i mean obviously a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> doesn't have the time or the resources to do as much
 		but on the other hand i mean again what what can be done about it you know
 		it's it's one of those i i think unsolvable sort of things i mean we we make the motions of
 		
 		
 	