
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well have you ever had uh had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion oh
 	
 	
 		yes and uh let me tell you this is really neat thing to do too that they did i didn't do it some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> organized it and what they did was they had uh a book made up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it was like when our ancestors first came over
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 	
 	
 		and then what they did was they asked every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to write something about their family
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and like how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you had and who you had married and
 		you know it went through like and it showed who my uh well who my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were you know and who he married and then how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we had and then like his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and it went through the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's so neat
 	
 	
 		and it was so good
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		yeah but it it really did you know and plus plus it got a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> interested in it because you got to participate sort of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah so so did everybody send in their information then they made a book up about it and then you could get it at the reunion
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 		right and everybody got a book that came to the reunion and it told like uh you know where the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Connally's</ENAMEX> came over and um
 	
 	
 		oh nice
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it told what happened when they got there and how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they had and it just kept coming on up through the generations
 		so it was really that was really neat and
 	
 	
 		wow that is neat so do you have a big family
 	
 	
 		well he does  he does i don't but uh he has enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> to make up for me not having any
 	
 	
 		oh he does yeah
 		that's kind of how my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are i have a kind of a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and he just has himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and that's it so he had to kind of get used to us when we first started going together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's what that's what happened when i when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> uh met my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> i said this can't be you know nobody can have this many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> because a lot of them lived in like a group you know down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> highway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there was a lake and they all lived down there by it
 	
 	
 		oh how nice
 	
 	
 		and so we were going down the highway you know and he kept saying this is where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> and this is where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> lives and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> you know and we and i kept thinking
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is putting me on nobody has this many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> you know  so but they really were all there and another thing that's real good about um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		how funny
 	
 	
 		family reunion is having everybody just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> whatever is their specialty and bring it at because nobody it seemed like liked the same thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but you had a choice and then you got to taste a lot of new dishes and stuff too and got get a lot of good recipes where if you set a certain thing and say okay we're going all going to have fried <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> or we're all going to have fried chicken
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		everybody might not like that
 	
 	
 		not be able to do it so did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come like from out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to the reunion or they did did you put them up in other peoples <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> or did you have hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> or how'd you do it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah they came from all over
 		um they just stayed with different ones of them they just came down and like say okay this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kip</ENAMEX> uh all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and their grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and everything and then they had it it it gotten so big that they had it at the church
 	
 	
 		they did um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church service</ENAMEX> ahead of it you know and then they had uh
 	
 	
 		how nice
 	
 	
 		then they ate out on the ground
 	
 	
 		and they just brought food with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum  um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		did they just have like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a weekend</TIMEX> is that how they did it uh-huh well i'm real curious because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> i didn't sound i don't think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is as big as  your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s i don't think we'd need a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> but um
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		the problem is we are all really scattered around there isn't any one place where most of us live so if we ever had a reunion we'd kind of all have to stay in a hotel i mean
 		you know there'd be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who lived there that would have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but they couldn't put everybody up so it i think it would get kind of expensive
 	
 	
 		but you know what you can do at a lot of these lakes and things if you could find a centrally located like uh say it's about the same distance for all of y'all to come they have these places where you can rent them
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it you know like on a lake and it's like uh it's a big place i mean you know it got and it got little rooms that separate off of it and stuff and it's not very expensive that a way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh you mean so oh i see so everybody could stay together yeah a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		right it's like a they have like a a convention type thing and then it has little rooms off of it where you know you'd go and sleep at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> time but then it has like a kitchenette and things like that but you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		see that would be great because then you could spend so much more time together than if you all were in your own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> or something and then every time you wanted to go eat
 	
 	
 		right
 		and another
 	
 	
 		with somebody you'd probably have to go to out eat or something it would run into a lot of money so
 	
 	
 		yeah but they had that was you know that
 	
 	
 		that sounds like fun
 	
 	
 		what you can do is you can uh write different places the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> and tell them what you're interested in and ask them what they have you know at area lakes and all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if they have something like that because now every time we plan anything just about we write to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> of where we're going because you can find out so much easier that a way than try to locate it you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you get a
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		calling different places can really really run you up a bill but uh if you can find a centrally located place where everybody would have to come about the same distance i mean you can't get it exact you know usually
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh and then everybody goes that place and me it's not bad at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they have lot of times they'll have like uh little cabins and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four or five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> can stay in those cabins because they have you know just the single bunk beds and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they can all stay in those cabins and then you know you can have cookouts and stuff like that that doesn't cost you as much
 	
 	
 		that'd be great that'd be really nice
 	
 	
 		yeah but that's uh you know that's the best way i found because whenever you have something where you go and now we had one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">soun</ENAMEX> d good
 	
 	
 		this was before i lost a lot more of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but it wasn't any of my immediate family anyway because i didn't have any of them left but um they had uh uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		thing where you could everybody could come and meet and go out to eat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i didn't think that was as good because it was like you know you couldn't really talk and stuff like you could when you was at the lake or somewhere you know where you were out this was like ev erybody came into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and went to this restaurant
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah yeah
 		right
 		and you have to sit at a table and just yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and it just i didn't like that one as well
 	
 	
 		well um did you was it hard to decide what who to invite and who not to invite i mean did you have to draw a line or did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that had that reunion have to draw a line like they just whoever  wanted to come
 	
 	
 		no
 		what they did was well see what they did was okay they uh wrote they wrote to all the initial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know the the oldest ones
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		okay then those in turn got a hold of these other ones and they had like i think there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that would call
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know some of them if they didn't have their addresses and all on and you know they told them that what we had to do was when we sent back in our information we had to tell them how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were going to be coming
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and then when they when they talked to us or when they sent us the letter it uh  you know to get the information and all it asked you know will you be willing to bring and you had to check off what all you would be willing to bring
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and so really there wasn't any problem with that's the reason it ended up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> because i mean there was just so many of them
 	
 	
 		there yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but it turned out so much better like that because everybody knew they knew ahead of time how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to expect
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		now if there was a sickness or something like that i mean you know you're not going to lose that many
 	
 	
 		sure sure no that would just be a few but how about like because of divorce and stuff like that like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are divorced and they're both remarried and you know there i mean there's i don't know
 	
 	
 		right
 		okay well
 		well see then okay if you wanted them both to come then you would put you would have put that down on the list and you would have sent you would have been the one that sent their invitation to them and ask for their information
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah so then i i'm kind of like in control over who comes of just from my family
 	
 	
 		to send back to those other people
 		right because once it went to the the oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and then they knew who they wanted to invite then they sent their little things to us okay it was up to me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who i was going to you know whether i wanted my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and you know my any of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to come
 	
 	
 		right
 		right i see i see that's a pretty good idea to do it that way
 	
 	
 		so
 		and then you know it never did like if i didn't want somebody to come then i just wouldn't send them one of the questionnaires
 	
 	
 		um-hum right right right well that's a real good idea huh
 	
 	
 		so there really wasn't a problem that a way
 		well but i tell you what that's the neatest book we've got course we've got well you know we've still got it and they charged us i think it was like
 	
 	
 		i bet
 	
 	
 		it was like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six dollars</NUMEX> i can't remember exactly you know that we paid for the book to be printed and it's not uh it's not a hard back book it's just a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh like a you know folder type thing but it has the entire you know it has everybody that you could ever imagine and some you couldn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		how neat
 		yeah i know that's really neat that's really neat
 	
 	
 		and it'll be something my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will have you know just like
 	
 	
 		i was just thinking of that what you could tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah because if you stop and think i don't know if you're like me but i know very little about before my grandparents i mean very very little about it
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum i just the thing is i know a lot of stories but i can't remember who it was about
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> told us when i was growing up and even when i was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> they still tell all kinds of stories about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> because they all grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
 		but i can't you know so i remember these stories but i have no idea who it was that was in those stories
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i i mean i couldn't give an accurate i couldn't tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> what you know those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were like i just remember they have some funny stories but i don't know who it was
 	
 	
 		maybe what you could do if you couldn't get into a full family reunion and you wanted to go back some but then usually when you find out some information from like your parents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then you can find out from you know you can find somebody else that can tell you something else about these
 	
 	
 		the rest yeah
 		
 		
 	