
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all i'm gonna to tell you i i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but they're not in public school yet i i get i get that experience starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next fall</TIMEX> with kindergarten
 	
 	
 		ah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you haven't really uh dealt with that in a sense
 	
 	
 		no but uh being one of these late in life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> i've listened to everybody else's you know complaints as to what's what what's the matter with either their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or the school system so i've been surprised do are do you have school age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> are both out of school and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know i i've
 		in hindsight seen some things that i wished that you know i had done something about that was you know within my power or uh
 		you know wish that in some ways we as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had more control over
 	
 	
 		such as
 	
 	
 		what's happening up there you know type thing um well
 		just over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> there were situations that um uh came up that i didn't think were fair or handled correctly or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> didn't seem to be
 		teaching anything of course it's a little hard to tell from
 		the the information that you get from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> you know they they bring things home and i was never one to believe everything my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> said you know about something
 	
 	
 		um-hum they
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh still i i question the ability of some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to uh really do a bang-up job and yet others i know are just wonderful
 	
 	
 		well i heard a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a frightening</TIMEX> thing actually actually i didn't hear it it was told to me or suggested to me uh that to work as a teacher
 		in the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i think it's similar in in many other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> if you have a degree in a technical field you do not need a teaching certificate because there is such a shortage
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to teach math and sciences and somebody said well you know you could go in and and substitute teach
 		at seventy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a day and there's always going to be you know uh somebody having a need for a math or science teacher i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> they're letting me in to you know this would be this would be frightening i don't know anything about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's pretty interesting because just
 		just because you know a subject matter doesn't mean you can teach it
 	
 	
 		right
 		right and even if i knew how to teach the subject matter i don't know if i'd know how to handle that kind of a a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah in fact i think that's that's one of the big problems <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is
 		the the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> behave or act and and the way they are sometimes disinterested in what's going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and disruptive
 	
 	
 		i tell you what i'm finding frightening and this comes from you know the the aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie near forty mother</ENAMEX> so i went through this period of supposedly you know cosmic social enlightenment
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm on i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> school system and living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> and there is a real dichotomy in terms of educational and economic background of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are going to be attending this school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i used to think well that's wonderful you know they can get a real life experience
 		what i'm seeing now uh in terms of kindergarten preparedness just from in in in different preschools it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and night and i wonder how do they handle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who is obviously very ready and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who doesn't even speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> let alone know her colors
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they're in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> and i guess also you're going to see the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of the uh crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		starting kindergarten my God i think it'd be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> is what i'd read
 		i thought how well how do you how do you weed those out
 	
 	
 		yes some of those certainly have a lot of disabilities difficulties you know with uh
 		all sorts of things and i would imagine their learning disabilities are quite large in some cases
 	
 	
 		and i was listening to NPR the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX> and they've quoted statistics that i just about my throat just about fell into my toes
 		they said at the bottom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores of graduating college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> are usually those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that go into education
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		that's encouraging
 	
 	
 		yes and i and i i got to thinking back when i was teaching college chemistry
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that took took you know the lower level courses i sometimes wondered you know are they really even educatable or trainable and it my God you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> are the rest of us who went for the big bucks you know staying out of you know where where maybe we should be kind of socially obligated to spend some time teaching or something with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's you know that's an idea maybe there need to be some radical changes made do some things that are
 		totally different and unheard of
 	
 	
 		well you you know you you sit here and you think about that at the same time you think
 		God i just hope i don't sound like a stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> because if right now if you ask my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty put twenty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and ask them how many have gifted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you're going to have twenty hands you know up there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh you're kidding
 	
 	
 		oh no nobody has nobody has a non gifted child
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i keep thinking you know uh gifted is is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Einstein</ENAMEX> or you know uh musical prodigies it's it's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who's you know precocious
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know what has you know has has the educational system been watered down to that anybody who's above average is now gifted
 	
 	
 		hum that's interesting i don't know mine didn't did not fall into the gifted category
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh don't say that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nope</ENAMEX> and i would never have said so either uh
 		but uh they managed to get through although not always
 		with flying colors uh
 		in fact one of the incidents i was thinking of that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> had um he was struggling with senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> and i had a meeting with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice principal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> and
 		uh she showed me a paper that he had just handed in and she told me what she had requested
 		and i read it and while it had you know a few little grammatical problems it wasn't very long and so forth i thought it had some nice well thought out
 		uh parts to it she gave him an F on that paper and i thought well now here you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who is trying to pass who is struggling with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX> and you give them an F
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on something that doesn't seem that bad to me what are you telling that student
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're telling them that well hey you might as well forget it you know
 	
 	
 		well you see i think that that just harks right back to the elementary and junior high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> because i have a stepson now who's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> and uh i was just absolutely shocked
 		uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that i saw his schoolwork uh i remember being you know taught and i think you know it you have to teach how to write an answer and you know how to construct a thought process
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		you know they can get a they they can grasp the points can they convey the data verbally or in writing and that's what's you know really scary to me um
 		i would really you know there's such a a push push among among young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> to make sure their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is computer literate
 		i would really think that they should be stressing more can the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> write a thought
 		and at an early age and if they can't i mean if they have missed that training then somebody you know before you're you you start penalizing them with bad grades for not being able to communicate what they're thinking
 		teach them these basic skills
 	
 	
 		yeah uh it's pretty sad to think uh about those who even even even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are graduating from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and they are telling tha t they don't know how to read you know
 	
 	
 		well  my stepson you know i
 		he went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> i just really get my military i married into a military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i don't know i really address them all as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> so i don't offend anybody
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh you know fortunately for him he wasn't dumb but boy he sure had trouble you know putting things on on paper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that that they did for him they tested him and they said that he's you know great in electronics but he yo u know he's really does need the basic skills and they put him through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>
 		of composition writing in addition to all his electronic training and at that point he has now graduated from warfare electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with honors
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who who really you you know barely made it through high school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i keep thinking you know it's not it's really not too late at any point to do you know some
 	
 	
 		that's interesting that the military saw that and did something about it you would have expected them to be the last ones to
 	
 	
 		yes
 		but yes and i kind of have always pooh-poohed military educations
 		but i think that for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> it's going to be you know his lifesaver otherwise he might have been driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> or framing houses you know from here to eternity
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know you know it does make me nervous
 	
 	
 		well i can see why if you've got little ones just coming along there's a a whole lot of stuff going on out there
 	
 	
 		there is a whole lot of stuff going on out there and and part of me says i just would like to you know shut my eyes and pretend it doesn't you know go on
 		or send them to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and then the you know the old social conscience says you know i'm not working i don't need to work maybe i should volunteer to you know teach what i know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		maybe adult literacy maybe you know composition writing maybe you know uh volunteering you know on a tutor line or though the even through the elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for help with homework or
 		the other part of me says is God i've had enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  do i really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	