
 
     		
 	
 		okay we're gonna talk about the public school system what's wrong with it and or if anything is wrong with it and what we can do about it what should be done about it
 	
 	
 		okay
 		fantastic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> thing that pops into my mind real quick is uh about the uh funding of the the school system right now evidently uh that's that's a big problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's amazing um  i always thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> never got paid nearly enough i mean to be doing what they're doing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh when i was in college i like i enjoyed teaching because i did some teaching part-time and i really enjoyed that but i wouldn't wanna go teach high school or junior high it just you know too many problems
 	
 	
 		oh Lord i mean yeah and you talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> and pressure i tell you what it's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah they're putting in fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty hours a week</TIMEX> i'm sure because they got to grade papers and get class stuff ready and you know and they're being paid probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> what most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being paid
 	
 	
 		do right
 		exactly and uh
 	
 	
 		hey we're paying basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> a year for for what you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right and then they uh poof it off you know just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarpley</ENAMEX>  but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know it what gets me is i can't believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> um
 		or our state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> can't come up with uh some kind of workable means to have funds for the school you know it's uh i just don't understand that
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh i don't do you have little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or what
 	
 	
 		no uh sure don't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i have just been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX> but i have a sister that's a uh school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a three year old almost four and a and a two year old</TIMEX> so we're looking at uh the older <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> going to school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> not not  well not this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">coming fall</TIMEX> but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> after that and the year
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay so it's getting close
 	
 	
 		yeah he's gonna be going to kindergarten so so you know we're we're thinking about that what that what that gonna be like are they gonna be taught nothing are they gonna be taught something we're gonna we're gonna be involved in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s education we're gonna be teaching him what we can at home of course
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		because uh i guess we don't trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> which is really sad
 		um but but it if it doesn't start at home it's not gonna go anywhere
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		right that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and we're gonna try to teach him good values because
 		you know when when when they get to upper level school and they start teaching well hey if you can play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> or basketball that's what's important not if you can read or write or do or understand understand some science you know i mean give me a break that's that's that's bogus
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		right right well and uh you know one thing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i've talked about it are uh private schools
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know whether uh uh we would want to invest in in private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> as they're growing growing up because you know just in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area um we're not real comfortable with the with the public schools
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh school district just recently got an advised status because of their low quality schooling i couldn't believe that
 	
 	
 		right
 		right you know the one that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason we bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> we were hoping you know well the school district's gonna be good you know for resale value and so on and so forth but
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um i can definitely uh see on down the road you know when we do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and are getting to that age that's gonna be a definite concern
 	
 	
 		yeah we talked you talked about before about uh the school funding i think there's only gonna be one solution to school funding which i i don't think will be necessarily
 		the best way but i think what's what's gonna have to happen is there's gonna have to be tuition for grade school and junior high and high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that's the only way they're gonna fund it because they start raising taxes for property and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are gonna throw a fit
 	
 	
 		that's yeah and you know that's taxes is right now are political suicide you know and i don't think any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>'s gonna do that so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah and the only thing they they would would think of would be tuition
 		you know if it works at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> it'll work down below and you know that's gonna that's gonna affect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of course which is probably the only fair thing to do
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it'll be hard for those that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have have in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because they have to pay out even more
 	
 	
 		exactly and you know it's gonna really hurt the the middle class uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think because uh they're the ones that'll probably have to uh uh carry the brunt of the load
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		and most the problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and and knives and everything i mean good grief what's with
 	
 	
 		yeah now that's that's just unbelievable to me you know
 	
 	
 		i can't believe that i mean when i was in junior high and high school that never happened you never heard about that
 	
 	
 		well yeah we didn't we didn't even think about it you know
 	
 	
 		no and now you know what we have now you know got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rusty</ENAMEX> because he like you know a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magnum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> like good grief
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean i would i'd be afraid to be in school i mean be teaching or even a being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and think what's what's it gonna be like for my my youngest and my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> when he goes to school
 		what what's gonna happen i mean i i'm afraid for him to go but on the other hand you can't hold them back
 	
 	
 		exactly right
 		well no and you and you wanna encourage them you know to to be active and everything in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but uh you know with all the peer pressure that's going on with all the negative things it is uh it's a tough environment to be growing up in
 	
 	
 		yeah a lot tougher from it was when i was going to school and that was when i was i graduated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nineteen seventy nine so</TIMEX> that was what twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		okay
 		right
 	
 	
 		so you know it's a lot different now and what's it gonna be like in another twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> when my uh oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s in high school
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		i'm afraid to i'm afraid to even think about it
 	
 	
 		no yeah that is a scary thought
 		but uh  i don't know i i guess what you have to do is just uh keep encouraging uh you know encouraging them and and uh uh try to be open with them so that you can deal with the problems as they come up yeah and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's all you can do you got to you got to be your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> i guess even when they're a teenager and they you know are kind of standoffish still you got to be their best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> because when they got problems who they gonna go to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that are dealing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or or there parents
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		you know and and if they go to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> dealing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they're gonna be in even worse shape
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> don't don't really encourage
 		to stay away from that you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are there teach history and that we fought the civil war etcetera etcetera they don't teach them good values like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are bad i don't maybe i'm wrong maybe because i haven't you know been in that kind of environment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> but it just is amazing you know need to teach them good values
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's true that's true and uh
 	
 	
 		of course what what if if i say this is a good value someone else is gonna stand up and say oh no and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX>'s gonna get after them and have a lawsuit which is gonna take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> to resolve you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		well and i think uh you touched on it you know you've got to start them at the home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know that's where they that's where they get the the deep-rooted values and and uh and that's about right then you just have to hope and pray that that everything uh works out works out okay
 	
 	
 		that that's all you can do
 		that's right well i got to be going so uh
 	
 	
 		well okay well hey i appreciate the call you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> hm have a good life uh
 		
 
 		
 		
 	