
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so which uh what basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are you interested in
 	
 	
 		well i guess i'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Laker LA Laker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> when it comes to pros
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh uh the college ranks
 		um
 		i guess i really of course i try to follow my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX> that's uh BYU
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> but they don't have much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> usually
 	
 	
 		no they're more of a football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> than they are basketball team
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they you see them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> on TV once in awhile but you but you never see them on a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		on nationally basketball
 	
 	
 		you know that's true i don't think i've ever seen them nationally on basketball
 	
 	
 		they uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> they
 		had a really good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Aines</ENAMEX> was there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years ago</TIMEX> by now
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so they made it to the
 		sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sixteen</ENAMEX> once or twice in their history and that's
 	
 	
 		um yeah that's not too bad
 	
 	
 		and they usually lose in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> round what they get
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		well i'm uh originally from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> area so the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> pro anyway in that part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> so i i do pull for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i mean of course <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good year</TIMEX> to be a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> i guess because they're doing pretty good
 	
 	
 		isn't the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> you're talking about yeah the pro
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> as far as college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> uh i know it's really easy to say but i've been pulling for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years</TIMEX> now so uh
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		so i finally am feeling better about myself as far as college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> although i've i've really you know again being from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> i pull for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> uh but they're on uh probation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> so you can't do much about that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no no
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		so did you watch the uh final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i watched every uh i watched <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> games of that and uh i was very pleased with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> games because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> uh you know i was pulling for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX> on the other side so it was it was real nice to have the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that were there
 	
 	
 		every game
 		right right
 	
 	
 		of course i wasn't really i mean i i
 		UNLV kind of gave me the impression of being a uh um oh i don't know a macho <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> you know they just didn't seem they seemed to think they were better than everybody else and and maybe they were but um i was real happy to see them get knocked off so
 	
 	
 		yeah that i i watched that game
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it was a good game it was a very close game and hard fought game
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and it just i don't know it looked like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNLV</ENAMEX> may have had more uh talent but as far as playing together as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> it didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> seemed to have them off balance
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that uh
 		they didn't just couldn't aren't aren't they more of a running gun team
 	
 	
 		UNLV yeah their their they play the pro style is the way i've always called it and uh you know the fast breaks and and
 	
 	
 		right fast breaks and things and
 		they shut all that down and made them pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> court it seemed and
 	
 	
 		right and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNLV</ENAMEX> wasn't used to that of course i've i knew whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">UNLV</ENAMEX> went in at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> time  see i don't know if they were necessarily behind but they weren't ahead as much as they normally are
 	
 	
 		and
 		what
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and you know that meant that they had to play <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a second half</TIMEX> and they've not they've not had to do that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		right right they didn't have they didn't have to go through some tough games during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and that and that
 		and so that's the you know it's a terrible time to have to deal with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right in it when when it counts so much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>'s schedule was was so much harder than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNLV</ENAMEX>'s that it uh it just made them a much tougher <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> overall and uh that had to help them a lot
 	
 	
 		right
 		i think i think that that probably was the difference in that game because it really could have gone any either way down to the end you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so do i take it you think though that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> will uh will win or
 	
 	
 		well
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>'s pretty good um
 	
 	
 		probably not
 		since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kareem</ENAMEX>'s retired
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they haven't had a center
 		and uh they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't think he's really been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super star</ENAMEX> for them
 	
 	
 		no well he's uh i don't i he to me is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> he's more of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a real</NUMEX> tall forward uh
 	
 	
 		and
 		yes it's
 		right right
 		so
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX> does a
 	
 	
 		i uh they'll make it you know i it's it's it's going to be a war between uh between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and uh and uh and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Celtics</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that's going to be a war it's going to be a great series
 	
 	
 		that sure is if
 		i think that's going to be one of those that's uh that's won by the home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> you know whoever has home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> advantage is going to win that one i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> will probably be um in there
 		um
 		let me see where does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> fit in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>'s in that same uh that that same uh division
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so
 		i don't know those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> hasn't been having that great a year this year
 	
 	
 		no but as i heard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Isaiah</ENAMEX> came back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> so uh that might help them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah they have the they have the play-off experience well so does so does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> i mean so does <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so do they all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX> back uh you can never count the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics</ENAMEX> out when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		uh starting to click on all cylinders they say he's starting to do starting to play
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		he's yeah but he's been kind of up and down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> uh  you know one game and he'll be playing to where everything he throws up goes in and then the next time he'll you know he can't seem to hit the side of a barn so i don't know i'm i'm kind of i'm not sure about him this year
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		right
 		last i've heard is that he's starting to peak right now
 	
 	
 		um-hum well that's when you do it
 	
 	
 		and he's starting to be more consistent you know right at the right time of the year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		oh any any dark horses i you know
 	
 	
 		well the dark horse yeah that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio San Antonio</ENAMEX> the dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> that could could
 		really flip in there i think somewhere
 	
 	
 		yeah anybody who has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davi d Robinson</ENAMEX> got to have a chance anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		he's got to be pretty much you know i use to say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akeem Olajuwon</ENAMEX> was the dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> you know when  against any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> he would dominate but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>'s getting up there where
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		every game he's just i mean it looks like he's going in for a dunk and they kind of just scoot out of his way or take a step back you know nobody's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		got enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> i guess to challenge him when he's when he's driving hard to the hoop
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		he's uh he
 		too bad the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX> couldn't get him
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Tarpley</ENAMEX> they're in big trouble
 	
 	
 		yeah well then he's gone now so they're going to have to do something about that well i thought he was gone period i i didn't read the story but i i read that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah for awhile anyways
 		i heard he was suspended
 	
 	
 		well that might have been what it was but i i guess the headlines said something about him you know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mavericks</ENAMEX> you know released him or something i'm maybe i misunderstood what they meant
 	
 	
 		because of his
 		um if they did they'd still have to pay his contract
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 	
 	
 		they may have done it
 	
 	
 		you never know yeah but
 	
 	
 		it was a lot of money he was making like i heard on the radio it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty three thousand</TIMEX> and change a month
 		that's what he was being paid
 		you know he wasn't even playing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> what a good job he had
 	
 	
 		that's what i think
 	
 	
 		he ruined ruined his sweet position
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i'm looking forward to the the pro play-off uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's coming up isn't it yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 		who's the other one that's doing so well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland Portland</ENAMEX> i haven't seen them on much TV at all much at all but all i you do is hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> they have the scene the you know what do they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Davis</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		Portland yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		they've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> or they're not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> but i mean there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that are really good doing good or something i forget exactly how that worked but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they're like i said they're doing extremely good right now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX> isn't doing too bad so it's it ought to be a real interesting play-off yeah
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah yeah i don't i don't think there's any clear pick that you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess i guess the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that i just you know think you can't count out are the are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics</ENAMEX> and the well because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> and and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Johnson</ENAMEX> they they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that seem to find a way when there's when there's when it's on the line they seem to find a way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		when it's on the line
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know uh so
 		those are what makes makes a champion i guess
 	
 	
 		yep that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well it's been nice talking to you all right well take care bye
 	
 	
 		well
 		nice talking to you take care bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	