
 
     		
 	
 		well we haven't really heard that much in the news lately about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> involvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> since uh all this <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> crisis began so i haven't really paid that much attention like since
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> when all of the news and all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> began to focus
 		in on um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and the so the last thing that i remember hearing that much about is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>
 		scandal that happened in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> presidency can you think of anything else that's happened recently
 	
 	
 		no i would agree with you we haven't had too much but uh historically we've always uh
 		almost been like a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> to in and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> area and uh almost used them i i i feel um i think something will have to be done down there very soon about uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and and uh some of the other areas but with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> as you said it's just uh been very quiet i i keep pretty close tabs on the paper and you don't hardly see a
 		unless it's there and we're just not seeing it
 	
 	
 		well the only uh references that i have seen lately has been uh  in part of the
 		overmilitarization of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> was due to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> selling them <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and things and and they made references to in the past
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how we have given <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX> and to other places in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> and that those might turn around and haunt us someday i mean not not to this large scale as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> but that whenever we give <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to people
 	
 	
 		well it's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as as we did and as we sold <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to  pardon me to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> when we wanted them to fight <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and then uh and then it turned around and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i i agree we're the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">munitions</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> in the world and so um there's a lot of money to be made there and it's uh be very difficult to to cut it back to a level where it should be
 		and and then it will come back to haunt us it seems to come in cycles
 	
 	
 		um-hum  and i know when i spent the time that i've studied in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> uh since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spanish</TIMEX> was one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> in college  that uh there was a kind of a lot of resentment there towards America
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		about uh like you say using them you our interest there is
 		you know what profit we could make off of any kind of relationship with them and that we weren't normally very interested in them and they have in other in most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> they
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		there are a lot of the kind of problems that we've
 		fought for in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you know that they have corruption and and they don't have um
 		i mean there's just very few really modern cities
 	
 	
 		right and the probably the biggest biggest problem down there is that's where the that's the drug entry points in their economies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of several several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> is so built on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">on the</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that uh our our little war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> has really been laughable it's just a
 		you know such a small amount and it does it just it um cuts off just a trickle and uh if if we can't get a handle on that through some
 		through some uh method i don't know where where that'll be another big problem
 	
 	
 		well that's right because that's just so much of the way that they make their money and so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> have uh have to have that for farming  and they don't look at it so much as you know
 	
 	
 		right right
 		and as long as we're the largest uh consumer then uh this is the market
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's right
 	
 	
 		if we can cut back the usage then uh maybe it'll have to go someplace else
 	
 	
 		and i think it's really very sad that north of the border
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> is so different from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> there's really a disparity between the um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		what you i would call civilization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		right yeah we're just so much wealthier and uh and uh there has to be resentment built up and that's where uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> can use uh use that whenever the opportune moment arises
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes it's really kind of sad and that we would go all the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and that we would be very concerned with the situation between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle East Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and and when we have when we have a lot of problems right right in our own back door
 	
 	
 		that's right our own hemisphere but we've that's been uh that's been the way it's always been
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX>  so i guess we've kind of neglected <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		very much so except when we need them you know when they found <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> then we got very friendly with them again
 	
 	
 		right recently yeah fairly recently well that's really sad i hadn't thought about that in a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hm
 	
 	
 		well i guess then i will go but i made me stop and think a minute about
 	
 	
 		okay
 		sure did
 	
 	
 		not worrying so much about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> crisis i know that it's not settled but  there are other areas that we could focus our attention on well thank you you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		always yes ma'am
 		you too dear bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	