
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 		yes i do believe that there is too much immigration now
 	
 	
 		well yeah  a well yeah living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> especially i see it  and and
 	
 	
 		did you
 		well it's not just that are there enough jobs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here now
 	
 	
 		no no it's terrible
 	
 	
 		and yet they're letting more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah from everywhere too not just from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> you know just everywhere
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i wasn't talking about just <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> i was talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Block</ENAMEX> uh
 		it's terrible
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i
 	
 	
 		there's and there's nothing we can do about it
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> seems to do as they wish when they wish
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't ask us do they  no you know and it's really hard i think on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> because they come over here
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all they you know thinking that they're going to have money and jobs and success and everything and then they then there is no jobs and they end up homeless and not knowing anybody and no money and it's terrible
 	
 	
 		yes living under a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> so to speak now it's true though that the bulk of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yes
 	
 	
 		are successful
 	
 	
 		really and true how how how how do you figure
 	
 	
 		uh i saw it on the news uh i saw it on the news yes the bulk of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are successful you know they pay to end up as tax paying citizens
 	
 	
 		did you really
 	
 	
 		making uh
 		above middle class income whatever that is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the united</ENAMEX> states now
 	
 	
 		probably more than what i'm making  maybe i should become an immigrant and go somewhere else
 	
 	
 		well yeah you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 		uh they say that's due to their work ethic
 		now i don't know if that's true or not it just might be a matter of luck
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		but then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> always has been
 		for the immigrant
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh you know if it hadn't been for that i guess i wouldn't be here because  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		huh none of us would
 		yeah
 		there you know there's only a very few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native Americans</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		and then they're treated rotten the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> well they've got they they've got the worst deal around
 	
 	
 		yes they are
 		well most of them you're right but then i drive through Riodosa
 		and i think well not all of them have it
 		desperately bad
 	
 	
 		i've never
 	
 	
 		you know you've you've driven by
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mountain Gods</ENAMEX> outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riodosa</ENAMEX> haven't you
 	
 	
 		i've never been been out there
 	
 	
 		oh it's beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> up there in the mountains of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh just just gorgeous and that inn is huge and
 		but now uh like i say
 		that one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> is the exception not the rule
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> were treated dreadfully
 	
 	
 		yeah oh and still are
 	
 	
 		and still are yes
 	
 	
 		you know don't have good jobs and living on reservations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX> and oh it's terrible it makes me really ill but i've never even been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian</ENAMEX>  but a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> i've been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well i'm i'm i'm a native born <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> but uh you know how it is
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		we go where the work is
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true well did you start with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> out here and then go to
 	
 	
 		uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and oh okay and then went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seventy four</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		so yes i am i am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> TIer
 	
 	
 		so do you see a lot of uh well let's see what's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> do you see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> of any kind like like we do here
 	
 	
 		uh
 		the ones we see are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> by marriage a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> there's an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> base
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that marry GIs <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean Americans German Americans</ENAMEX> uh a few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah
 	
 	
 		few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> you understand
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but then you know too on a it's uh of course what i think about when we talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> i know they're coming from everywhere but i think a lot about
 		coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> because i guess i'm so close to that and if they close the well the borders are closed basically i mean they're but we get all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that come in illegally and stay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's not really immigration
 	
 	
 		well no that's true it's not but it is i mean they're coming i mean we've we've got
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah you can't stop them and once they're here to some extent we support them
 	
 	
 		they're supposed to have all these laws passed where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't supposed to hire illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> and all this and whether that's working or not i don't know because i don't hear anymore about it
 	
 	
 		i don't either but uh what i suspect is that illegals were hired
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred</TIMEX> and fifty years of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> history i don't think they can stop it by a federal edict
 		i don't think the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can stop it by making by waving their magic wand and saying it will happen no more it's just too inbred in the culture you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dumas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> and uh every roofing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> was illegal
 	
 	
 		i know  well all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> here too at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time now it's see how i'm not in the restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> anymore so i really don't know but at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 		the whole kitchen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> and the busboys and everything were all illegals in in most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> i worked in as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> you know it whether that came to a halt i don't know
 	
 	
 		sure
 		see uh
 		still some migrant labor is legal
 		you know
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i know it is
 	
 	
 		it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		is it too in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> also i i didn't know
 	
 	
 		yes yeah during <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX> harvest and whenever the the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX> and all are
 	
 	
 		but see they'll come in and do work that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won't do now i don't know about this day and time when there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of work i know if i was out of work i'd do anything to make money
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		because it's pretty scary when you own a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and you know
 	
 	
 		well the truth of the matter is i don't know what your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> payments are but you couldn't make a living on what they earn
 	
 	
 		you could
 	
 	
 		you could not
 	
 	
 		you could not
 	
 	
 		have you seen how those poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		migrant labor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> oh my God they live in cardboard boxes
 	
 	
 		oh it's horrible isn't it
 	
 	
 		and these fine <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> take care of them
 	
 	
 		um-hum see and they put their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to work and everything don't they
 	
 	
 		and i
 		yes
 		and i don't hold it against the people
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		they're hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> trying to make it
 	
 	
 		and no one and see <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> wouldn't do it wouldn't they wouldn't live like that
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		they wouldn't do it
 	
 	
 		no they'll they'll ask for a handout first
 	
 	
 		you couldn't get the street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i was just going to say you couldn't get these homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> probably to do that
 		i see them on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corners</ENAMEX> with signs saying i'll work for a meal but i'll bet you if you stopped and you offered them a meal if they'd come and do your yard they'd get out of it some way they just really would
 	
 	
 		no no what they're doing is they're asking for handouts
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		because if you took them into your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to to work in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> or whatever they'd know where your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is and how to break in then
 	
 	
 		i know it
 	
 	
 		or
 		now that's not true of all of them there are
 	
 	
 		but how do you know  the good from the bad
 	
 	
 		i i don't i don't know but i'm sure that times being as hard as they are
 		and times are hard
 		not everyone's that way
 		you know good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are being put out of jobs now
 	
 	
 		oh yes how well i know i was laid off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> but i was i was lucky because i was one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to go
 	
 	
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well in in division <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i got uh went right to you know they have the job <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> for us and everything and i just
 	
 	
 		oh so you don't
 		oh and you got transferred to a different
 		right
 	
 	
 		oh boy i worked hard through i went through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J O B's</ENAMEX> and found this and was versatile enough had a little bit of office experience and they hired me and i was just real thankful and now there's nothing
 		for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are getting laid off now there's just nothing
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've i've noticed
 	
 	
 		you know i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> has been hit also
 	
 	
 		uh rumors still persist i try not to believe them and listen to them but they still persist that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> will close
 	
 	
 		i don't know i haven't heard anything i don't hear much about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> it's kind of like they're kind of trying to be invisible  forget about us forget about us
 	
 	
 		yeah so you're in division what now corporate corporate okay yeah that that must feel somewhat safer
 	
 	
 		i'm in in i'm in payroll division <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> yeah corporate payroll so
 		it didn't for a while there were a lot of rumors flying and uh i still hold a red badge and it's still uh i'm still under <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> so if they had a layoff in division <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bumping</ENAMEX> and
 		
 		
 	