
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		well credit cards
 	
 	
 		i have some do you
 	
 	
 		well yeah i i i've used them a bit too much sometimes
 	
 	
 		yes me too
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		do you have uh like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> and and those that are those the ones that you use the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the most</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		well i have uh
 		we've got an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> which we got that on purpose so we could pay that off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> that way we we know our limit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but then i also have department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know we keep <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple hundred</NUMEX> dollars um if that much charged on those which isn't too bad it's just your normal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah just a pretty pretty pretty much uh what you can pay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		you know getting clothes and stuff every once in awhile
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah well we have uh have department store cards for nearly all the department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> i guess uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but but we don't you know don't use them a lot uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but we do have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> cards uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has uh has an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> through her through the company
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't even have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> to use for business so
 		or i use a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		just your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		right and uh i i find that they you know they work all right i haven't found anybody that will will turn one down
 	
 	
 		yeah i you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> always complain about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> saying not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take it but i've i've rarely found a place that wouldn't that wouldn't take it so that doesn't bother me luckily
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		the uh yeah it's it's uh it is convenient to have that you know and it and if you can do a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the</NUMEX> a lot more with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> when we do when we go traveling
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> works a lot better for some things because you can charge you know airline tickets
 	
 	
 		oh does it
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and and get some benefits from that i think too
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true that's that's real nice to
 	
 	
 		you know
 		but it's i tell you it's it's really uh it's tough to uh to deal with when you let your your balances build up
 		you know so that it it's
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		you've we did it uh intentionally i did it intentionally i was running some business expenses
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> card
 		so i knew that i was running a balance up but it sure is hard to get it
 	
 	
 		paid back i know
 	
 	
 		paid back down
 		it uh
 	
 	
 		when we <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got married we you know went and got all the credit cards and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course charged those <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppies</ENAMEX> up and it's oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> when those bills start coming in
 		they want a lot of money when you start getting them up there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but uh you know you find it's uh that the uh the interest rates vary so much on those that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that we've been paying real close attention to that so we're using the ones that uh have the lower rate as a matter of fact the uh the uh credit union
 	
 	
 		that's good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX> card i think has the lowest about the lowest interest rate of any of the ones that we use
 	
 	
 		that's good
 		i've noticed on the like the department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> they sure do hate it when you pay double payments
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it's like whoa
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		wait a minute
 		don't pay us too much you know and they drop it your balance uh they drop your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> payment down low because they want that interest to build up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		so that's what i normally try to do if it's pretty low i try to make a couple payments at a time
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and get it down quicker
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but they're easy to use
 	
 	
 		so you haven't been tempted uh to to call any of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine hundred</NUMEX> numbers trying to get a credit card then
 	
 	
 		no have you
 	
 	
 		i have been tempted i just i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those ads on TV last night that
 		you know somebody
 		call in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> you know and you can get your gold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> card or gold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i don't understand how they do that
 	
 	
 		and uh of course it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine hundred</NUMEX> number which that means they're going to charge you you know fifteen or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> dollars just to make the phone call
 	
 	
 		right
 		but they say you can't be turned down and i don't understand how they can
 	
 	
 		well the thing is the that a lot of those are like they're set up through a bank or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> type thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you have to have a deposit in that you know that deal of you know if you want a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollar</NUMEX> credit line then you have to keep a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> dollar balance in there
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i see
 	
 	
 		well then they sure they won't turn you down because they've got your money
 	
 	
 		sure they've got your money already
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well gosh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but that's yeah i know that's the way some of them work anyway
 	
 	
 		well that's darn easy then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't turn you down either i'll give you one
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		huh no i haven't attempted that i'm satisfied with what we have right now and we do have a gas credit card and we use that
 	
 	
 		yes uh
 		yeah that's one that we don't use uh i've had uh you know had different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or you know gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> cards before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i didn't use them we we usually spend cash you know pay cash for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and then uh most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> will take uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> card anyway so
 	
 	
 		right
 		right that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		so i i can use that and uh
 	
 	
 		well we uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> always usually always pays with cash but i never seem to have cash
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		or at least not enough you know to fill a tank up so i always almost always use my credit card on that on that and then it's nice you do tend to pay more for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> but other than that it's it's a good deal i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah but they're of course now they're beginning to to get the picture i think uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevron</ENAMEX> has just recently dropped theirs back
 	
 	
 		yeah i saw that
 	
 	
 		so they quit charging the extra i don't whether they they drop the ir price back to the cash price or raised all their prices up to the charge price
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 		but they won't they won't charge i saw that advertised too that's a good deal
 		but it's real convenient it's real convenient for me i really i just like being able to go in and do that
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> you have to pay it off at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the month</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		huh yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 		it's not going to go up too high
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's good for emergencies
 	
 	
 		right yeah that's it's always handy to have that that credit card for whatever it is that you might need it for
 	
 	
 		that's what we do on
 		that's true we always use especially on trips you know we just charge all our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> that saves us spending it or shelling out the cash right then
 	
 	
 		yeah that's it when when we travel it's we used to use our the gas card just for that you know
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		and now we don't have of course we don't drive on our trips very much anymore either we used to drive like we'd drive to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> twice a year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we don't go we don't we don't drive anymore when we go down there we usually fly so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know you can fly just about as cheap as you can drive so
 	
 	
 		i know and isn't that terrible
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		and save all that money
 	
 	
 		yeah so anyway
 	
 	
 		hum
 		well do you think we've
 	
 	
 		well
 		i think they've got enough uh enough information from us anyway
 	
 	
 		okay well thanks for talking
 	
 	
 		okay it's nice talking to you okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you too bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	