
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		views huh political views huh
 	
 	
 		well just any any political event or view or anything
 	
 	
 		well i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> done screwed up
 	
 	
 		well uh in what way
 	
 	
 		well as far as like the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over there he told them to uprising have a uprising you know
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overtake</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> so now that they're listening he's not helping them
 	
 	
 		i don't think he ever told them to to rise up against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what he said when it first started that they should think about what they're doing and and you know what he's doing
 		that they should you know make him understand it it's just like them saying that we should understand what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is doing
 		but they don't have no say so in it i guess
 	
 	
 		well unfortunately the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the United States</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can't get involved in a civil war in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> because it's not
 		it it's
 	
 	
 		well that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> was was a civil war
 		that's what get you know it's like a double double
 		standard
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i'm i uh
 		the uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> in the northern part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> unfortunately when the the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> were
 		when the boundaries were adjusted and changed and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> were basically forgotten because there's a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Iraq</ENAMEX> there's some in uh Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and there's some in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		well that's where he bombed before with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX>
 		that's where he put the chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and killed all them people
 		what's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> did
 	
 	
 		yeah it it's just unfortunate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't get their own uh
 	
 	
 		land or something
 	
 	
 		well their their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or their own
 		something originally
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		now they have to deal with whatever they get dished out more or less taken on from each side
 		because they're getting it from like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> closed their borders
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so i think they're screwed up there
 	
 	
 		yeah they've they've got plenty of problems without the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> i don't know if they can go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> or not that wasn't
 	
 	
 		the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> borders are still open uh from what i understand understand um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> are going into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> i know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> the uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> has some pretty strict
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		now they have yeah they're pretty strict anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i doubt that they're letting too many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqis</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have proof that they're leaving that they're not going to stay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't even think that will help right now
 		because you never know who's on whose side and they're worried about that and
 		they could get over there and change their mind or something you know
 		who knows
 	
 	
 		then the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi Arabians</ENAMEX> will just shoot them
 	
 	
 		yeah now that's something i like about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> there's not a whole lot of crime over there as far as petty crime
 		you know they
 	
 	
 		well they it's a it's all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> over there are very wealthy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are wealthy and and they don't have some most of their basic needs for for food and shelter and clothing are met so they don't have any
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh any need that's going to drive them to to petty theft or or to that type of crime
 	
 	
 		i wish it was as good over here as it is over there but
 		if you're the
 	
 	
 		yeah but those uh those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are so extremely wealthy but from what i understand though that it's private
 		it's the same type of wealth distribution where you have a the very few are very wealthy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but since there's so much more to go around that that leaves the the lower classes with more
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's better than none at all i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they don't have no crime
 	
 	
 		so you think that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s foreign policy is poor because of because of what's happening to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they
 		no i just think i don't know if he should have made that statement other than that you know he's all right you know but
 		i don't know i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> fan i'm not really none of them's fan
 		i just wish something else could be done in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i don't know what
 	
 	
 		something else done here that would would solve the problems in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid East</ENAMEX> or or
 	
 	
 		no that would solve our own problems
 		i don't know i think the war was good to a point but then it really didn't help us any you know
 	
 	
 		no other than than reestablishing the dominance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in the in the world economy
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah that's it that's all that's that the to let the world know that we could do what we say we was going to that's about it
 	
 	
 		another thing that was good if you're looking at the balance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super</ENAMEX> powers between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> went in and led the battle and and solved the problem and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> is is a whimpering
 		is a whimpering country right now because they they've got so many problems that they can't even
 	
 	
 		now they now they have an internal problem themselves right now and i think that has to do with them having problems with food and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and</ENAMEX> and prices and all of that stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		a lot of their their civil problems where they've got their uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baltic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>
 		rising against the the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is the same type of deal as what occurred with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it's the same type of situation where
 	
 	
 		they they want their own their
 	
 	
 		where where ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were split up and and our and don't necessarily have the same uh social structure or value systems as the government
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		it's i it's it's kind of fortunate that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was founded in the way that it did because it's such a mixture of people
 	
 	
 		oh goodness yes
 	
 	
 		with with for the most part with the same ideals
 	
 	
 		yeah more or less just whatever it it's really that choice
 	
 	
 		yeah and and
 	
 	
 		that's the biggest that's the bottom line is it's your choice it's not told to you or pushed on you it's whatever choice you want to make you can make it yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and and when the when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was founded the people
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> all had the same value systems and beliefs and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> coming in understood that and and it wasn't as if it was forced upon them they chose to come to this country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it wasn't as if a a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was established when they were already here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		well i think we've taken up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've enjoyed talking t o you
 	
 	
 		all righty bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	