
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		i'm not sure i even know where to begin on this mess
 	
 	
 		oh it it is a mess
 	
 	
 		i do believe though a lot of speculative speculative buying and investment on speculation uh too many large deals with too much risk uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh definitely
 		um-hum bad deals with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and on it goes over a long period of time and i think
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it i think it's a a type of situation where okay the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> investment didn't work but if we throw a little bit more money in on it maybe this one may you know and try to get our money back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		throw good money after bad you mean
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		those you said it's just not doesn't work
 	
 	
 		that's that is that is some of what some of what i had read is that's part of cause of it now as to the question of what to do about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh heavens  i would
 	
 	
 		uh it has to be government regulation
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it but
 		you know it it's it's i don't know  it's not something i know a whole lot about but uh it's such it's such a big huge complicated mess
 	
 	
 		i don't either
 		but the other thing this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickson</ENAMEX> that they convicted he only got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i know i couldn't believe it
 	
 	
 		so that's going to leave a message to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that yeah
 	
 	
 		he can be out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty months</TIMEX> they said
 	
 	
 		well yes but he's in very poor health so you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty months</TIMEX> may mean a lot longer for him but still
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 		yeah but still i i health and health and everything i mean if yeah
 	
 	
 		it's our money it's our taxes that have to pay for this mess
 	
 	
 		oh that well there are too i think there's too many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> period there's you know you you drive down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on every corner
 	
 	
 		this is true this is very true
 	
 	
 		and and it it i think it's too easy to to uh form one
 		that you know because i mean look look in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they're everywhere they were everywhere and then then they started being taken over by bigger bigger ones and then they just the bigger ones took on the little one's debt and then it it just snowballed
 	
 	
 		and that's probably another cause of the problem we are looking at right now
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it it there's just it just seemed like everybody and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this is a very true thing i didn't think about that part of it
 	
 	
 		you know because you know i have never i'm uh we're originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>
 		and there are you know mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and maybe a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> in the area i mean i have never seen so many as there are down here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really that's interesting
 	
 	
 		they're they're they're just everywhere and and you know set up in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX>  i seen one on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preston Road</ENAMEX> that was set up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> for a while before they built the little building
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes this is true
 		oh how funny
 	
 	
 		and then uh and then uh it went out uh i mean i just wonder
 	
 	
 		how much that cost us
 	
 	
 		yeah and how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lost money on that lost money in that thing but who but uh who knows it's
 	
 	
 		that is scary i didn't think about that
 	
 	
 		well they need to prosecute the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are taking the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> a lot a lot better than they are have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickson</ENAMEX> is the only one i even heard of i mean there may be more that they are prosecuting but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickson</ENAMEX> is the only one i even heard of
 	
 	
 		they must be getting some on the national level i think i've read various things but i just no names come to mind
 	
 	
 		because if he only stole <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> stole <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> that's just a drop in the bucket compared to some of them that were were skimming millions
 	
 	
 		yeah because that's a drop in the bucket to the taxes we're going to have to pay to to make up for this
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah because
 		there are bigger fish i know i mean otherwise it wouldn't be in such a mess
 		that the the stealing because uh stealing and leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> probably they can't they probably can't find them what the deal is  oh
 	
 	
 		you know you've got a good point there
 	
 	
 		but uh eventually you know the the tax money is getting extremely low on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FSLIC</ENAMEX>
 		i mean they're in they're getting they're getting so low it it's almost in trouble and and where's where's that going to come from
 	
 	
 		and the
 		and the other thing is they said the insurance the uh insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> the insurance industry is beginning to resemble the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> industry so they they say the next big crisis could well be our insurance
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah  that's and that's frightening that is frightening because
 	
 	
 		as another uh
 		my car insurance is frightening right now i cannot believe how much money i pay
 	
 	
 		oh oh our car insurance
 		i can't either for for uh for nothing for almost nothing
 	
 	
 		well and i just carry the absolute minimum required by law
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i'm paying i mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every quarter</TIMEX> i'm paying like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and that
 	
 	
 		oh well you don't pay we we keep full coverage down here on everything because well it's not it's not that bad but that's getting off the subject  uh
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		but uh but the you think that they that they could come up with a better system of regulating these these little bitty uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> that uh
 	
 	
 		well i you know the problem is who is they and you get they is the government
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> yeah that's what i meant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you get you get into when you start getting them to do things you get into a lot of special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		yes exactly exactly and lobbying oh you know there's a big
 	
 	
 		and you know
 		and and would that make it worse or would that make it better or would that offer new opportunities for other people
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		that's what scares me when you get into that type of situation you know if you are going to change it watch out for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that's changing it they may put another loophole in that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		makes it even worse
 	
 	
 		wasn't even there to begin with
 	
 	
 		yeah and and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like us never hear about about what's really going on and what they what they're really doing
 	
 	
 		and i think reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> for that type of thing is a waste of time because they're there to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> that's the problem with the news both the on television and the paper
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		television is worse television is worse
 	
 	
 		well all they're there to sell you know or to entertain even worse and uh not to transmit information
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh yeah that's
 		yeah oh exactly what makes
 	
 	
 		so what we get is so garbled that who knows if we even have the ability to decide anything
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah  we got these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> deciding all this stuff for us and we don't even know what they're deciding
 		so it it's
 	
 	
 		and whose best interests they represent us or someone else
 	
 	
 		and how many of them were invested in just how many of them have invested in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX>  or own a or has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> that owns yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		it's really a scary scary thing
 	
 	
 		yeah but i'm it's one of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those things that i just don't know where the answer lies
 		it's just it's just it's going to uh it it doesn't seem like it's going as badly as it did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> it's kind of slow because the closings has kind of slowed a little bit
 	
 	
 		well now there was an article in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> in the business section how tough it was to get a loan approved anymore
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah when when you know when you're trying to buy a house how incredibly hard it is to get get a loan approved simply because they're they are tightening down so much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh well i can see why i can see why
 		i can see why because they were loan they were loaning money to everybody and anybody that i mean they didn't check up on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they were loaning
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ungodly amounts of money that were that that that couldn't pay for it
 		and you wonder how in the world these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got their loans why look at look at the i <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">thirty condos</ENAMEX> i know somebody at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> that bought one of them things uh back when they first  opened
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh yes
 	
 	
 		you know that big scam and they just they just left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> they just they just packed up and left town
 	
 	
 		smart move
 	
 	
 		and i mean i mean they left well yes but no because they uh they left their loan hanging yes they they just
 	
 	
 		oh did they
 		oh
 		that's not
 	
 	
 		and that happened that happened a lot in this area <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just packing up and leaving their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and leaving the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> out to dry on the loans on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> on house loans
 	
 	
 		well
 		but they are hurting their own credit that way
 	
 	
 		hey i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that it does they don't care it wouldn't i am extremely touchy picky picky picky about my credit rating but but i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that just don't care what they done
 		bankruptcy means nothing to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and it hurts all of us it when they declare bankruptcy it's you and me that have to pay for it and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't care
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 		yeah because they can you know they write all that and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that write things off as bad debt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that lowers their threshold of income of what they have to pay taxes on which automatically automatically makes our taxes go up because there is so much that has to be paid
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh of course
 	
 	
 		and if this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is exempt from paying it we have to pay more that's exactly right so it's just
 	
 	
 		we got to take up slack
 		and so it's it's it's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just run running out on loans that they couldn't pay for in this area i mean you just can't imagine how many houses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just run have run out on
 	
 	
 		yeah that is really sad
 	
 	
 		i i know it i know it i don't think it's it's as bad now as it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> when everything just kind of fell apart you know
 		everything just kind of fizzled what because when we moved down here in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty three</NUMEX> i mean there was <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> going up on every corner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yes
 		and and the unoccupied
 		
 		
 	