
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well i haven't uh you know when the war was on i watched um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Nightline</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pretty regularly and read the paper and all but when uh lately like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> or two i guess with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>  and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> break with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i um
 		i hadn't been thinking much about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> and what's going on over there have you been keeping up
 	
 	
 		uh well  uh just really the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of days</TIMEX> since this uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>
 		debate or whatever you want to call it that uh
 		voted on whether there was going to be a cease fire i guess
 		you know the thing really isn't over they uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they had uh kind of uh i don't know if you call it stand down or whatever but anyway they stopped
 		and wait to see if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> would accept a permanent cease fire situation though
 		as i understand it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> point of view this current cease fire thing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> uh
 		had set up you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> are probably not going to go for at all unless they're just absolutely forced to
 	
 	
 		uh
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so i guess from what i understand the thing could just
 		they could take off at any moment without uh
 	
 	
 		start it
 	
 	
 		you know any
 		uh-huh you know any local um
 		you know congressional effort or anything else because you know it's not really settled yet
 	
 	
 		there's no official document signed or anything
 	
 	
 		not yet not yet at all
 	
 	
 		well i um when the when the crisis began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX> i began to think well i i um couldn't remember things that i had studied in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and all so i got out like my encyclopedias and
 		tried to read about the history and it was really what i felt was kind of cynical because it there just hasn't been any peace over there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ever in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of history
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah i don't know why they expect it's going to start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's right and it just it's just not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they
 		and it's not uh you know there isn't any real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> because they do fight among themselves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they fight with each other and they have such hatred for
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah the uh the thing that's kind of interesting uh about this my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and uh he came within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a quarter of an inch</NUMEX> of going uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> he ended up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> instead and because of the way they split a transportation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so he ended up going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> ended up going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi</ENAMEX>
 		well he's still in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> are home now  he he almost wishes that that he could have gone home
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		he
 		and got it over with  well i just  there's just no way for us to be involved over there and hope that there will be much peace
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um with and that i'm afraid that we would have to stay
 	
 	
 		yeah the thing uh the other thing too when this all started if you you know if you did much reading on the thing you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> was just you know somebody's
 		uh you go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War i</ENAMEX> when the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> broke up
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> mostly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		decided to carve up that part of the world and call part of it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Persia</ENAMEX> and part of it uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and part of it something else you know and they they split things along um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		geographical lines but they didn't take any kind of consideration into uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> or cultural
 		things at all so the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> of uh of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> really doesn't make just a whole lot of sense
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		except that it is an accepted
 		place you know it's like any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you know for whatever reason it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's actually there well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has had uh designs on that place since nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty two</TIMEX>
 		so you know it wasn't like something that just suddenly popped up
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and it's just that this was an excuse
 		you know to make some noise now something that i read in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that i thought was kind of interesting was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		uh their version or vision or whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> now is somewhat changed in that we won you know now now we are a uh a legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the game over there you know the
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		we i don't think we can really understand their attitude because their culture's just so much different
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh we are now a legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the
 		in the in the game because we came in with a certain amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and we
 		you know we defeated
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> couldn't do it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and we went in and did in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> couldn't do in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> you know so
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		that kind of ups our stock in there just a little bit it makes us more legitimate
 		so now what they're saying is that well since we won whatever we say goes because it's a kind of a might makes right attitude about it and you know we've got the power
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		which is why for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> had so much influence in there because they'd go in and they'd win something
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then and then they could call the shots for the next
 		you know period of time until the next strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> came up and you know and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and caused problems so
 	
 	
 		well i just uh i'm not interested in keeping big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> over there and having to go in and call the shots like you say and and i just would prefer that i mean sometimes we've said let's keep we
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		we're not interested in what other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> do and then other times we jump in and do things and while i'm really glad that they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i it was important demilitarize demilitarize that area because of all the build up armaments
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't hope i'd i hope we don't try to keep uh
 		in there and try to
 		keep our fingers in the pot and try to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		stay over there because we just don't want to send our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there and make them stay
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's the uh
 		that's that's the big thing you know we still got a little bit of the old
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> um
 		problem in you know in the back of our minds we we got this we're we're used to wars where you can get in do the job and get out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> we never did get out you know never did get the job done because they were too <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> strung
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh this thing they they gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> uh the power and the material and the
 		told them to go do it and they did it you know got in and got out i'm not sure the the big fuss that we're going to see now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX> i would think
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 	
 	
 		is uh you know the uh the business with the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiites</ENAMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know in the southern part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and also the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> because these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> evidently are you know being killed off by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and whether the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> will do it on their own but whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> comes around and says hey wait a minute we know this thing isn't
 		uh all that much over we've got to go back in there and and be sure tha t this large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> isn't just wiped out
 		which is seems to be exactly what's happening right at the moment
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i noticed that
 	
 	
 		but uh you know
 	
 	
 		well i don't think there's much hope for a lasting peace over there like they
 	
 	
 		oh well no no there there never will be i mean uh uh the only way that you're going to have peace over there if if we determine that we want to go in and wipe out every last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		history
 	
 	
 		you know until we make a decision to do that there won't be peace but i don't think we want to make that decision either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no
 	
 	
 		so that's that's a little rough you know we're not we're not quite up to that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well i guess i better go i have a repairman just came for my refrigerator
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh well that's fun
 	
 	
 		but yes well i enjoyed the topic i hope you have have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you too bye bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	