
 
     		
 	
 		hell air pollution tends to be a a topic that uh
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a lot to say on and some don't care much for it at all but uh i found that there's there seems to be quite a bit that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> can do as far as air pollution and one thing
 		it kind of hits the old pocketbook a little bit but if you can just keep the automotives <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> going properly instead of uh letting them rundown and use a quart a oil a mile like some of these smoke <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> do
 		that would uh make quite a difference we all seem to have one or more of those things and then we have a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at least in this part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that uh love their fireplaces
 		and we burn off an awful lot of uh acreage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> and put it up in smoke and on a
 		proper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> as far as the temperature goes you can have a cloud of smoke hovering other a neighborhood that's just sickening really i mean it may be pleasant inside but it stinks outside
 		so uh little things like that uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> can do what what else do you think they can do
 	
 	
 		well you know i i think fireplaces are great but you know you really don't have to have wood
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		you know i mean fireplaces their great but you can get you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent clean burning natural gas in your fireplaces and i mean you know most of the fireplaces are for ambience anyway they're not that efficient
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		they they really are but but uh i live in a place where <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 		are are i mean you know you you you see a picture of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX> here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay area</ENAMEX> and you know at anyone given time you'll see you know
 		maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the car
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so i'm i'm a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX> for mass transit there's there's just uh uh you know there's just no reason on a regular basis for someone having
 		you know to uh if if if we just did our mass transit better and longer and more complete you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay area</ENAMEX> here we got uh uh system here called i don't know if you've ever been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay area</ENAMEX> uh it's called uh
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BART Bay Area Rapid Transit</ENAMEX> and they uh um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh connect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> and and
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> but if it were to go to complete completely around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX> and when you ever you get on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">BART BART</ENAMEX>'s just absolutely wonderful because it's fast it's clean it's really efficient and it's it's actually fun to ride
 		but uh it's just you you know it's its its been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> assed and uh they need to completely uh you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		make the system so it goes completely throughout the the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay area</ENAMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would ride BART but a lot more would
 	
 	
 		make it
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if uh and i think that alone that alone would just cut down so immensely on that we've we've also i mean the fact of the matter is is that you know they've just got to find other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		and and and and go other routes our our our i think basically our air pollution is one of the one of the uh oh
 		uh
 		oh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of main side effects uh or or or or you know one of those visible symptoms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> energy policy period and our energy policy is just nil just is nonexistent
 		and uh if we had one
 		you know striving to meet certain standards and certain goals and really to push it and uh let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and the yeah you know the the automobile manufactures and stuff it it it just keeps sliding
 		i i think it would make a big big difference it's just it you know it just hasn't hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> yet that we may have crossed the line
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that line being of of uh you know a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a a</NUMEX> a planet that's going to be able to continue to live or it's gradually already dying and it will not be renewable i mean we may have crossed that line
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it will be up to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and maybe their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to you know
 		to find out
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and things will live on this planet but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> may not be able to anymore
 	
 	
 		right it may not be us yeah we have a um they happen to use about the same abbreviation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area they use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Area Rapid Transit</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DART</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DART</ENAMEX>'s problem here the you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metroplex</ENAMEX> itself suburbs and all it it's a pretty hefty uh distance from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> to the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> so they they run uh
 		they gather the monies from the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> and the other suburbs and and run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DART</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> throughout the suburbs to downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> as it were and it's a good
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> or so miles in each direction just about and they also try to run <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with you know around locally the only problem is for me to go to work i live um
 		less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles from the front door of my my uh place of work and for me to get there
 		it would take me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> transfers and that's just ridiculous can't get there from here  and it's a large place i mean we're talking about
 	
 	
 		oh that that that's terrible i mean that really is you know
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> thirty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the whole area right and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> inside it's fairly large and there's no reason for me to have to go from point A to point B in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when i can roll that old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX> of mine down there for a lot less than that
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		plus it would cost me oh i think the last time i looked at it was about had a dollar fifty one way
 		and i said no i'm not going to do that fast isn't that bad yet
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		so that part's one problem i i wonder about the whole CFC issue i've i've read some papers from some
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> that don't get published that well because of their opposition to that saying that they're really not sure that the CFC's are the main problem yes we have a ozone problem but is it
 	
 	
 		well i mean it it it is a fact uh the the CFC's do act like i mean it it it's it's like a billiard ball you get a CFC up there high enough you know it's a it's in the ozone layer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it doesn't just breakdown one it's not a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to one reaction it's it's a catalytic thing and it it actually just rumbles around and around and and breaks up every <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C O</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O O O three</ENAMEX> molecule it hits
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i mean
 	
 	
 		well they weren't negating
 	
 	
 		whether whether it is the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX> or not it's uh you know i i think no one can doubt the fact that it is
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		you know i mean it's it's a bad thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a real bad thing and it's just you know i think it's so many of these bad things some little really don't contribute that much and some just insignificantly but uh you know i i heard something <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> that absolutely floored me
 		i'm a i'm a i'm a space <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX> and just absolutely uh am absolutely crazy about the solar you know and think that we ought to put as much money as we can possibly get into the to the space program and i found out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX>
 		from an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> one of the most respected uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>
 		that every time
 		i the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle</ENAMEX> goes up
 		it dumps more than what is it a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred tons</NUMEX> of these fluorocarbons into the ozone layer it is probably responsible our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> shuttle
 	
 	
 		um
 		that's interesting
 	
 	
 		breaking down the ozone layer each flight could bring it down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as much as one tenth</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's interesting
 	
 	
 		and it's the solid rocket propellants
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		parts of the system
 		if if it were to be jettisoned lower you know before it got up that high
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it it it it it really wouldn't have that great of effect but what happens is it goes all the way up through into the ozone layer and then it keeps firing and dumping and i just blew me away
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's an awful lot
 	
 	
 		yeah uh and it's frightening and and and a couple of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> down there have been screaming about this for some time now and of course uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> is the one that's going to
 		you know suffer the most because uh that main whole that's over
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Antarctica</ENAMEX> continent continent you know uh it it expands out over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> and at certain times of the year
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know there's absolutely no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> protection whatsoever in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> in the last in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of the shuttle the uh uh the skin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and and other you know uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> have gone up you know so mething like like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six thousand</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems like i heard that just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> on either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> or somewhere that they they were talking about that
 	
 	
 		yeah they're they're they're so they're they're a little bit cross with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and we could remodel that system you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we don't have to use those as a matter of fact it wasn't designed that way initially at all the solid uh propellant <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> were a uh you know were time saving money saving afterthought
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and uh i just you know i think it's just been uh uh uh
 		terrible anyway anyway but that that that that that that as an aside but there's another one of those things you know it's like so many of these little things
 		that that that add to it that i i just think this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> not only this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but the world has kind of started thinking
 		that uh if we don't get it together here
 		
 		
 	