
 
     		
 	
 		okay the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> if i buy a car it'd probably be an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made car
 		that's what's with me wrong because i feel of the economy i would probably buy an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> even though sometimes the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are better but we're losing a lot of money
 		buying foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting out of jobs as it is
 		so i'd probably buy i've always own <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> car
 		uh the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is probably something i couldn't afford
 		like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> i would love to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mark</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh what do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> sevens usually run
 	
 	
 		oh about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 		to forty
 	
 	
 		thirty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well there's a tremendous amount of money alright
 	
 	
 		it's a luxury car it's a it's a sports luxury car
 		it's right below the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Continental</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		you know it's it's along that line
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i agree about that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> should be
 		the ones to be bought  um i just wish their quality would to still improve further
 	
 	
 		yeah they're getting even better i think
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yes it's a matter of time it's probably going to be another
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to five years</TIMEX> before they're really up to par where they should be and then i believe the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		already have foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they will already have in fact i have one myself i'm
 		reluctant to admit
 	
 	
 		i don't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has one
 	
 	
 		she does
 	
 	
 		yes she finally she wanted she had a she's got a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> um not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> that what is it Accord no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX> yes that's one
 	
 	
 		and she hasn't had any problems out of it see
 	
 	
 		what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> model is it
 	
 	
 		oh think it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's fairly new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine mine</ENAMEX> is an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sentra</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the only problem i've ever experienced major type problem i've experienced is a
 		a fuel pump  had to be replaced and it's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four thousand</NUMEX> no it's got <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eighty nine thousand miles</NUMEX> on it now
 	
 	
 		see i have a i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Continental</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		you do
 	
 	
 		it's a yeah it's a seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> it's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred thousand</NUMEX> miles
 		and there is no problem with the car see the i think
 	
 	
 		no major malfunctions then
 	
 	
 		huh-uh huh-uh my air conditioner went out but i mean  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 		but uh i mean as far as major there's nothing major with the car
 	
 	
 		i see well that's good to hear
 	
 	
 		but
 		it i think what it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> had made good <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and then they started more or less trying to hurry stuff
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> car i think now that they have that's uh that's  made it on the what do you call it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX>'s list or the the why they check the how they judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> what is it list where they come out with the consumer list
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Digest</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Reports</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah is a is a is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taurus</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taurus</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one that's made it
 		and uh its a you know it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door it's a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> now for me to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> i would have to buy top of the line <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> and that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> Show
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's it's it has a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX> speed i like that stick shift
 		but see that's top of the line that costs twenty whereas a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> would cost about
 		a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Taurus</ENAMEX> i think is twelve or thirteen
 	
 	
 		well that's not too bad in price listing
 	
 	
 		huh-uh the the yeah see the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Taurus Show</ENAMEX> has the spoiler kit and the and the big engine and the and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		it has an eight
 		cylinder
 	
 	
 		it has the well yeah i think it has the it has that engine like the Mustang
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> it's i think it's you know the speed uh uh manual transmission
 	
 	
 		correct
 	
 	
 		so
 		but yes i would definitely buy one of those before if i had to between that and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> i'd probably buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Show</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Iacocca</ENAMEX> stressed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini van</ENAMEX> uh i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini van</ENAMEX> has been one of the best top of the line <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		their durability is a lot better i understand than most other vans
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think it would it's not so much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vans</ENAMEX> any more or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> some of them are ugly
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry  they look like space mobiles
 	
 	
 		there's a lot of uh duplicity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> the way the build them too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		insofar as their design um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> even foreign
 		but i'm sure it's all for streamlining or for air streamlining
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		why you can't still go fast so what's the difference that's what i don't understand
 		you know they're making it so that they're talking about the wind current and how how efficient it is but if you can't go fast you can't go fast i don't care how sleek they make it
 		it just makes sense to me It's like they're making a
 		a model of a speed car when you can't go fast
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">in</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> it would probably be alright if you put it on that autobahn
 		
 
 		but over here nobody should be going that fast to be worried about wind
 		
 
 		no
 	
 	
 		uh yeah  just a second
 		going to pick them up
 		excuse me for a moment
 		right i'm fixing to get them right now
 		excuse me i had to uh
 		talk to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know how that go
 		but
 		i guess that's about it
 		and i better let you go
 	
 	
 		okay so i guess we have nothing to do on the other end there's no uh interruptions here to tell us that we're done or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's it just hang up all righty bye
 	
 	
 		okay later
 		
 
 	
 	
 		come here
 		
 
 		
 		
 	