
 
     		
 	
 		you can go ahead and start if you want uh
 	
 	
 		well um the budget's an interesting issue uh particularly since i'm pretty much a libertarian and an anachro libertarian at that
 		uh so i would basically say the way to fix the budget is to uh cut and eliminate taxes charge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> fees for things that uh are absolutely necessary and to be allocated fairly that way
 		and um i'd say <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> of the budget has no business being there
 	
 	
 		i can agree with that and uh i know one thing we we need to do a lot of spending cuts instead a lot of raising taxes because that's what's really  hurting everybody's goat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fail to realize but you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doesn't generate money
 		you know they may print it but that's not really the way money is made it's it's made from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working and doing things that are productive and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s the net cost
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doesn't produce anything
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		so uh a dollar tax isn't isn't a dollar that can be
 		you know that that makes more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> or anything else it's uh it's lost
 	
 	
 		correct that uh i guess the uh the big thing about that is the fact that they're spending someone else's money it's not like it's they're out of their own savings account
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's another quagmire that really hurts us
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it's it's real easy when you go home and and you think gee you know i'd like to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX> isn't it nice i can make my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> pay for it
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but but uh you know i mean the real world doesn't work like that or at least it shouldn't but it seems to in government
 	
 	
 		
 
 		isn't the basic needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place is to protect
 		and what is the other one
 		basic services is to protect
 		and i don't know about providing all the other services that they do i mean even
 		i i guess the uh the latest uh fire they came under was whenever they were providing a
 		uh a tribute to um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Welk</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum oh that's right
 	
 	
 		contributing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred thousand</NUMEX> to
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		restoration to his home i think that was called back because of all the flack they received but but that's the another one of the big examples of
 		why we're in such dilemma
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well even just the general funding for the arts uh in humanities and then you know they get into these censorship issues and everything else i mean
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the art's in humanity should be privately funded
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		um a lot of these social welfare programs i mean that's why they're things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> is when you and i think that those are important but we give our dollars to them and it shouldn't be a government responsibility
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> i think is supposed to be doing is is defending our rights
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		no more and no less
 	
 	
 		and the power given to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> is just astronomical and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's awful
 	
 	
 		when you sign your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten forty</NUMEX> form you're signing a away you're rights i mean your your rights to uh uh protect yourself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that shouldn't be that way either uh
 		the power given to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is just well beyond it should be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the really what given it was given to them by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> never really had the right to give it to them is the is the real argument
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um yeah it's it's so i don't know i mean so it i mean getting back to the budget it's
 		i guess the the fundamental thing is to
 		give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a concrete get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to agree on a concrete idea of just exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is supposed to be doing for them no more no less and cut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> back down to that size
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		it's it's it's an enormous  enormous bureaucracy though it's going to take probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to really get that in to order too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		because everybody will want that pet project
 	
 	
 		oh sure and and there's going to be a lot of you know cover your ass and
 		you know well you can cut his program but not mine and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and entrenched <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> that don't want to loose their jobs
 	
 	
 		correct
 		and all the uh unnecessary military installations
 	
 	
 		yep yep
 	
 	
 		will have to be probably scrapped
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that's going to be difficult
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		we may we may need a constitutional convention
 	
 	
 		really the biggest way
 		yeah
 		uh probably will it's the only way it's going to change is for us to have a better budget for running this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is for everybody to get involved and right now i don't see that happening
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		not at the moment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or not at this
 		short time period
 	
 	
 		right i agree
 	
 	
 		so my you have some pretty good ideas there
 		um
 	
 	
 		well it's been nice talking to somebody with who uh  basically agrees with me
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'm um
 		
 
 		i voted libertarian this last election i mean in most uh
 	
 	
 		did you
 	
 	
 		some of the boxes you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm really am interested in getting most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbents</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		yeah absolutely i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> rats have uh
 		driven this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> downhill for too long
 	
 	
 		yeah well all parties too are responsible it's not just one particular one
 	
 	
 		right that's why i said republic rat
 	
 	
 		oh i see i see
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well now that we have aired our views in such an open way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well it was good talking to you
 	
 	
 		you too have fun up there
 	
 	
 		you too
 	
 	
 		hope to talk to you again maybe
 	
 	
 		okeydoke bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	