
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay what is your feeling on drug testing
 	
 	
 		well uh i'm i'm for it to be honest with you i think uh that um uh honestly if you feel you have something to hide that would tend to make you be against it but if you don't really have anything to hide even though i know it is sorted of an invasion in one's privacy
 		uh i think as a protection for me and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do know that we're drug clean if you will that uh it's one way to uh try to uh
 		catch those who might not be and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kinds</ENAMEX> and the kinds of problems that they can cause in the work environment or even outside the work environment i hate to think about
 		uh the fact that uh i might have someone on the job who takes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and could maybe on the way home harm somebody uh if you know um running over them or something like that
 	
 	
 		not even
 		yeah not even on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> while on the job
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well that that's right i i i i haven't quite thought of that uh uh that's a very good point now limitations i i do i do think there needs to be some sort of limitations to the way you test because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>
 		tells me that there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> prescription drugs like that the uh medical profession can put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on and which could cause a test to show positive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in fact uh that was not necessarily the case
 		so it seems to me that uh even though i i personally think it's a good idea that there does need to be some some uh thought given to it some serious thought about how you can do it how you can exempt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at least the serious periods of time short or long periods of time uh
 		um
 		who are on prescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or maybe come up with some other way of being able to test them
 		i i don't know i i'm not in the medical profession so i wouldn't have any idea but what do you think about that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i personally think that uh it should be done also uh my feelings are the same as yours from that standpoint i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty four years</TIMEX> in education
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> right and uh so i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> from uh the early very early fifties uh because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you saw it begin to come into the schooling system
 	
 	
 		absolutely coming into the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> more and more and
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh that's terrible
 	
 	
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> being introduced to it and giving it you know to get them started on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they give them for nothing and uh you know and then i see um um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		it's horrible
 	
 	
 		the uh the problem with testing uh now they test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> they test horses uh  they test uh uh
 	
 	
 		right now they test <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> for uh
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> right yeah and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> that's always that became a common practice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right and
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and so it seems to me the idea of having random and i agree with the idea of random because that way nobody ever knows for sure when it might be their time i i uh agree that uh random checks uh
 		of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> be it in schooling systems or on the job uh i think the text the uh the topic was suppose to be on the job
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh uh but i i think that uh that is uh well in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and age if the problem ever got under control where it became no longer a problem then maybe you know you could let the rules relax somewhat but
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well now just stop and think of of um um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> for example all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> are uh of course here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX> we have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wright Patterson Air Force</ENAMEX> uh uh base right here where there's so much research going on uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		base uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh are on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> uh it doesn't the test results uh the results which they are
 		uh striving for could definitely be an error or misconstrued or misread or any number of things which could mean peoples lives
 	
 	
 		oh sure absolutely absolutely absolutely and and and just as any work place like you say yourself you have come from the  education environment you you know yourself you don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> or principles or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> on the job
 	
 	
 		yes um-hum
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		who are uh just as guilty of something that we want prevent prevent the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> from taking part in it doesn't doesn't set a good example there's also the matter of the same kinds of problems you get into in terms of handling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh kids
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		uh uh teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh it can cause erratic behavior it can cause all kinds of major problems
 	
 	
 		it can and it does
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i see well
 	
 	
 		it does most most definitely does
 	
 	
 		do they have any kind of random testing in the schooling system over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no we we do not have uh we um no i spent uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first eighteen years</TIMEX> on in school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> on the west side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton</ENAMEX> which was primarily black and the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen years</TIMEX> i spent um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		doing nothing but resolving problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that were assigned to me that couldn't be resolved on a local level which could be a complaint on a principal or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a riot a bus action stabbing taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to court and what have you and i was on the east end of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton</ENAMEX> which is primarily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um um</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i could by see a tremendous difference between it but we would see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um taking uh a product called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toil</ENAMEX>
 		which is Toluene which is used to clean automobiles motors and what have you
 	
 	
 		i never heard of it
 		oh Lord
 	
 	
 		and they would put this in they have they'd steal a whole gallon of it and we finally found the chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> from where they were stealing it tapping through the bottom of a a semi <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> because it's so volatile
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> could not keep it inside a  a uh building
 		and they would tap it from underneath drain off a gallon put a gallon in an abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would go to the abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> wet a cloth with it put the cloth in a plastic bag and then inhale the fumes
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they they they do this like on lunchtime they come back to school and they'd have red marks all around the nose and mouth and we knew immediately
 		what they had been doing and uh then would have to try to take appropriate action but uh you know there are a lot of things we think in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> we think of crack we think of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> we think of marijuana we forget that there are other types of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of uh uh habituating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that are used  that are just as dangerous  as as the others
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh it's i you know  it's it's it's  terrible um of
 	
 	
 		well don't you agree though that if you do test in a in in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or a business or in a government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that random testing is the right way to do it
 	
 	
 		i think so uh i i see nothing wrong with that i think that that it should be uh better accepted than um uh forced testing of everyone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it uh perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would accept it better and then they know perhaps of a of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">future years</TIMEX> down the road uh that uh uh mandatory testing if everyone everyone could
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh would come about just as small pox vaccinations were for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and some of the other types of vaccinations for syphilis and uh gonorrhea what have you
 	
 	
 		right right
 		
  
 		oh yeah yeah well don't you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> really in this case should set a good example by maybe doing it first
 	
 	
 		yes absolutely and i think it should start right with our legislatures
 	
 	
 		well i agree i i concur <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent i really do
 	
 	
 		and uh you know
 	
 	
 		and uh it's not the sort of issue the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go and petition the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> to do uh uh unfortunately it seems to be the sort of thing that somehow or another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> do to pressure from the private sector who maybe having trouble
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		have to eventually bring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislatures</ENAMEX> to get them to enact and then it final comes to government and i've always been a little disappointed that we the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> sometimes don't initiate certain things like that i mean we we did back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> time try to initiate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Rights</ENAMEX> issue
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but on on on just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds hundreds</NUMEX> of other issues it seems like we sort of sit back and react rather than act
 	
 	
 		that's right but we but uh we we do uh legislate uh things now like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the seats in
 		car safety seats seat belts we can legislate them we can legislate say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> cannot get into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> without having certain immunizations to protect them you would think that we would uh you know take it another step further than the
 	
 	
 		oh you mean uh yeah right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we'd have uh some other kind of protection for them uh uh in for the staff the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you you know and and i understand they they fear as i'm sure your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> will tell you of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah right well testing has several things that that uh come along with it it it it enables you to
 		uh uh if you do find someone then it enables you do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things one it enables you to help them not necessarily to fire them
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely it helps
 	
 	
 		but but it should be given in a positive light so that you can try to help them and at the same time you can find out where they're getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> from it puts pressure on those who would try to push things illegal like that
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		because they know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they're pushing it to if they're in a work place where they can be randomly checked when it happens then they stand a chance of being turned in and you got ways <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> of cutting the whole drug traffic trade
 		because of the fact that you've got that kind of pressure
 	
 	
 		right right
 		well that that's very true and it is an immense problem and i think that that perhaps the uh money is spent in the wrong spots uh i think i i
 		uh am very much in favor of the types of programs we're having in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> with uh teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we have a program called uh DARE um
 		i wish i could remember what all it stood for but it was against uh ways to uh say no to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> and drugs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> uh in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> around in and around the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX> area have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> which go into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grades
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they they talking with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on that level and that's to me the level where you need to have it you can't wait till their already in high school because they've already tried it long before then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh but you implant the idea that this is not what not what they need to be doing for themselves and here's how to avoid
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	