
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 		what kind of TV shows do you like
 	
 	
 		well uh i don't have a lot of time to watch TV unfortunately this is not a good subject um i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when the little bit of time i do  get to spend because i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in the evenings um uh i like to watch movies and comedies and uh i watch the news
 	
 	
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the news
 	
 	
 		and the only  game type shows that i ever watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">are Wheel Of Fortune</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		um i don't i don't care for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wheel Of Fortune</ENAMEX> very much
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't care for game shows in general i guess uh they're not usually there's usually not that many on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the evening</TIMEX> anyway so about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wheel Of Fortune</ENAMEX> is about the only one that's on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in the evening</TIMEX> times
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah i know oh i haven't watched it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages</TIMEX> but uh you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		um i do like uh
 		uh well they had a good TV movie on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> called
 		Separate But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes i didn't get a chance to see that
 	
 	
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of fame type presentation uh it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-parter the other part's on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> but it was about the uh
 		the uh the well it's supposed to be a true story you know a dramatization the true story of the legal struggle that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ended up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> versus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Education</ENAMEX> which ended up um
 		oh saying that separate and equal is not constitutional as far as you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> it was talking about and it was interesting it was a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's it's really a high <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these high drama type you know uh shows that's also true any of those things i like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall Mark Hall Of Fame</ENAMEX> and those kind of shows are always so good i like i like to watch those
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		yes they are they i love those but they unfortunately they don't have nearly enough of those those and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic</ENAMEX> ones specials those those are great too
 	
 	
 		right right oh yeah i can watch those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic</ENAMEX> ones over and over again
 	
 	
 		yeah i know what you mean
 	
 	
 		and they're they're good they're they're i like news shows too like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh when i have a chance i watch those on uh i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> is usually on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> and uh i just like to see you know who they are raking over the coals
 	
 	
 		yes well you know it interesting they have a new one out have you ever watched <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Expose Expose</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i haven't caught that one yet
 	
 	
 		uh that's kind of
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> along the line of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sixty Sixty</ENAMEX> i mean that excuse me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX> and uh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i've only watched it once uh like i said i've been in
 		class and uh so during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> uh i don't have much time and i spend a lot of time with uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> and she lives
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a way away so uh i'm you we're not usually watching TV  but uh but it is interesting uh they this time of year unfortunately it gets
 	
 	
 		right right
 		right
 	
 	
 		kind of most of them are reruns and you know stuff like that that's why i kind of stick to the movies if they're good uh that one sounds good though that was on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> i didn't get a chance to i didn't get home till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX> so  yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah it's like right well that makes it hard
 		yeah that was a good show um what else do i enjoy
 		oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i have been
 		into this uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX> have you ever heard of that show yeah
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i've heard of it i haven't watched it uh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		it's getting pretty you know it's kind of like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> type thing you know but it's more of it it takes place in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> and it's this law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and all the cases they take and the and the uh interoffice uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh politics and so forth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to maneuver and get power and back stabbing and
 		also helping each other and you know if you know all the love interoffice love affairs and uh all that all that kind of stuff and you know power struggles to see who's going to be the next uh uh oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> or whatever and that kind of thing and uh and then of course they always have a lot of court cases and they show where they actually have courtroom drama
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		type thing where they're trying to
 		you know you're always sitting there trying to guess at the end of the show you know and they always have the verdicts you know and you're always trying to out guess is he going to be guilty or innocent or whatever and they always put you know twists and turns twists
 	
 	
 		i was just going to say yeah usually  twist it you know it's hard oh
 	
 	
 		yeah they throw a lot of twists and turns in like like one of the recent shows there was this really uh
 		a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who uh was accused of killing her
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire husband</ENAMEX> who was you know much older than she was like you know in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early twenties</TIMEX> and he was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his sixties</TIMEX> and he was she was accused of killing him for his money and she said no she wasn't and the and this law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> took on the case and got her off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and uh and you know you think she's innocent all along you know and just you know because because of her circumstances
 		that you know that's why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> thought she had done it you know because it just looked so obvious that she had done it and that's why everybody assumed she had
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so they get her off and at the very end of the case after it's over he's talking with her and he figures out that she really did do it after all a uh after after he got after he got her off
 	
 	
 		oh my gracious so what did he do then ooh
 		yeah well then they couldn't retry her oh
 	
 	
 		well that's how the show that's how the show ended it just left you hanging there like you know like you set me up you fed me all this information information you know that made it look like this other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was guilty you know and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's how he basically got her off by by casting a shadow of doubt saying well this other his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> did it you know and because this other will was had her name on it you know and all this kind of stuff but actually
 		she had done it after all and he figured it out after he made her innocent and then that was right before he was going out to the big news conference you know to
 	
 	
 		oh my good
 	
 	
 		to talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and stuff you know and how does it feel be you know to get her off the hook and this and that and they he went out there knowing that she was really guilty  so that kind of thing so it's a fun show then i like comedies also like uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there's a show call i watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> once in a while uh you you've heard of her probably yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yes i don't watch her anymore not after that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Star Spangled Banned</ENAMEX> thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i don't watch her that often i watch sometimes i watch The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> that's that cartoon show
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i've never watched that either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bart Simpson</ENAMEX>'s or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> is another one it's a sports comedy where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> of a a football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> a team <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> where they're never have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> you know but he's always trying to
 	
 	
 		i have watched that yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		always try ing to
 		pull it off and he has his a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> a a broadcasts anchor at the local news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and she's always trying to get him out of jams and she
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so you know whatever whenever i have time i just turn it on basically and see what's on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's a nice way to relax i mean in a way i mean i find it anyway although sometimes watching the news isn't very relaxing  i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from from
 	
 	
 		it is
 		no no
 	
 	
 		class and everything and turn on the TV and watch the news early news and it's like uh i i didn't really need to watch that before i go to bed you know
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		so
 		but i enjoy taking in a movie when i can i'm going to try to watch the second half of this one tonight
 	
 	
 		yeah well see that was that's another if i would have been home probably wouldn't have watched it because i have class <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> and i would have missed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> and that's the most frustrating because that's you know you can if you missed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you can kind of catch up they catch you up you know with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one but if you miss <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> you've missed the whole you know outcome and oh it's frustrating
 	
 	
 		they catch you up and the
 		right do you have like a a VCR where you could
 		tape it or something on the record mode or on the time yeah
 	
 	
 		no i don't unfortunately we have cable but that's one thing i need to we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but it broke down so uh i haven't gotten another one because i haven't you know i haven't even
 	
 	
 		hm
 		it broke down yeah
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		rented movies to watch because yeah yeah but uh but perhaps perhaps when it's over i will you you know i of course
 	
 	
 		so little so little time to do that
 		yeah have a chance more chance to relax
 	
 	
 		right well that's it i but i have gotten we have cable and so um that's
 	
 	
 		right there's always a movie on
 	
 	
 		yeah sometimes i spend a lot of time on that some movies that i would never have gone and seen uh you know have turned out to be really good movies uh you know you hate to spend the money on them especially as expensive as movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> are today
 	
 	
 		you
 		right
 		right how much are they out there
 	
 	
 		uh movies oh uh it costs you <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> fifty to go to a movie each a piece to go to uh a movie unless you catch a good matinee
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> fifty yeah
 		hm
 		out here i it's
 		i think out here they are still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> fifty about a dollar less
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well uh everything's high priced out here  but uh uh
 	
 	
 		things are going up all over too yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah uh but i'd rather you know watch it on of course the only problem with cable though is it's it's is that they show the same <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five hundred</NUMEX> times before  you know you don't get that many new ones in but uh uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they have a lot of good uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> likes to watch uh the sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">station</ENAMEX> you know and uh
 	
 	
 		specials
 		uh-huh yeah the all sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		right uh you know things like that so uh that's what makes it worth it uh because he's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped</ENAMEX> and he's at home all the time so so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		i see
 	
 	
 		uh you know he enjoys that but uh um i  i like i said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX> isn't my best subject because but i i do enjoy a good comedy a good movie is a comedy if i can you know sit down and and watch or if they have a good uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know show on that's a good comedy i'm not real much for the sitcoms because of their they need to have a new twist or something in some of those you know they're getting all kind of the same but um uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the same yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just
 	
 	
 		well i think we've probably talked long enough  about this subject
 	
 	
 		uh yes uh okay well it was nice talking to you and uh
 	
 	
 		well it was nice talking to you and you have a nice day
 	
 	
 		okay you too bye-bye now
 	
 	
 		okay bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	