
 
     		
 	
 		okay do you have you noticed any new um trends in politics
 	
 	
 		well the one i think is interesting is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California Los Angeles</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> who says he wants to resign and did you hear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> said that uh he should
 	
 	
 		oh really no i didn't hear that
 	
 	
 		think it i think what's interesting is that uh uh the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> and a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> went out there and are demonstrating
 		i find it interesting that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> would bother to go in how do how do you feel about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> getting involved
 	
 	
 		um i think sometimes it's good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> outside they get a different perspective uh perspective on an issue and stuff so
 		yeah i don't see any problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX> going in and getting a little bit involved i think though that it should still be uh sort of up to the majority in the area i don't know on something like that they wouldn't really vote on it or anything though
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> should resign
 	
 	
 		
 
 		probably so just because they were under his authority and he obviously failed somewhere along the line
 	
 	
 		well well speaking of that kind of issue have you kept up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Wiley Price</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what do you think of him
 	
 	
 		oh um
 		i think he's got good intentions but i'm not sure if the way he goes about what he does is really right
 	
 	
 		he's an interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i was talking to someone who said that uh for all his
 		obvious uh attention to efforts to get media attention that he actually is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> on the uh i guess he's on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">County</ENAMEX> uh
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Supervisors</ENAMEX> or i think  and that that that uh at those meetings he really comes quite well prepared and is well informed and is a hard worker
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and is really quite agreeable uh uh and that the stuff we see in the
 		you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> is uh well he's really just trying to make a political statement i
 		i find that an interesting element of politics that we don't that that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would not know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wiley Price</ENAMEX> apparently is a is a
 		you know course he's got in this this deal over racism and uh you know name calling and all this but apparently he's a a worker
 		uh you may disagree with him but i i i find this whole what do you think of this uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen one and ten four one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i think that they should go ahead and go to the uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen one</NUMEX> i to me it's just fair you know and equal it seem like every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> should have an equal voice
 	
 	
 		i agree with you but did you see the map they drew up on uh on how they were gonna divide up the districts
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		it was it was the strangest i'm i'm not sure it was gerrymandered but the way they drew these little patterns and stuff i i i guess i'm a little cynical of the of the power base
 		i i i and i don't quite understand why the power base uh doesn't uh
 		why they don't go with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen one</NUMEX> i
 		you know i
 		and you know the it seems to me that what happened in the in the election that a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they said particularly the the uh i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> don't vote because they don't think
 		that they have any affect and it's i i guess i am disappointed with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> in that uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen one</NUMEX> it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know you can you can disagree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Lipscomb</ENAMEX> and uh what's what's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>'s name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Ragsdale</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah you can disagree with uh what they're doing and what they're saying but in reality i think they're
 		they're trying to represent their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is doing itself a disservice i think they ought to get on with something important
 	
 	
 		yeah they really make themselves look bad and i don't know why certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are fighting so hard to keep the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten four one</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah and i but i think even i even those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauken</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box</ENAMEX> and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think it's i find it interesting that everybody's so busy politicking that
 		the question is did we get anything good done it's like this whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> issue are are you involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> at all public school
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		this whole thing down there where they're they're trying to um
 		uh you know devote all our money and raise our taxes and better <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and and it all seems you know everybody's trying to one-upmanship on everybody else so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it
 	
 	
 		i i have got to run to a meeting it's good talking to you i don't think we've gone our <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our ten minutes</TIMEX> but i think we've we've talked long enough so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> was
 		okay good talking to you bye
 	
 	
 		okay good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 		
 		
 	