
 
     		
 	
 		so uh describe your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> budget
 	
 	
 		well i've uh
 		for a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i i've pretty much flied without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and uh just recently uh we we set up a budget and and we're trying to stick to it we just bought a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so we've got everything you know pretty much we know what our uh
 		our fixed expenses are per month and then we've got some ones that are variable that that pretty much stay within a certain range and then uh then there's the ones that you never know anything about and that's the the food budget but that
 	
 	
 		well yeah and to some extent uh utilities i imagine
 	
 	
 		yeah well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> they're pretty much uh
 		uh you can pretty much uh figure what they're going to be and one of the nice things here is the electric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has a plan where they'll average them out for you
 	
 	
 		uh they have that to some extent here but it's not quite as good and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh transportation expenses i guess you own a car
 	
 	
 		yes sir
 	
 	
 		and you know how much you're going to drive every week
 	
 	
 		well i used to um i used to know uh fairly close to exactly how many miles i drove because i i was very convenient i lived uh uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nine tenths of a mile</NUMEX> from work
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so so was uh you know <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two miles</NUMEX> a day  to and from work  so it kind of cut my transportation costs a lot but now i've just bought a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and so my uh transportation costs have gone up by uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		yeah i understand that we we have a real similar situation ours uh
 		quintupled at least uh
 		so there is a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> budget
 	
 	
 		yeah pretty much um the problem is there never seems to be enough money
 		uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and uh it seems like the more money you make the more money you have the more things that they seem to need
 		and uh of course nothing ever goes down i mean uh i remember you know i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> total i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> left in the house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i can remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> would start and i'd go buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know shoes and i could get out of the out of the uh
 		shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> without spending more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> dollars nowadays <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> dollars buys <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> of shoes
 	
 	
 		if you're lucky
 	
 	
 		yeah so i mean things have just really gone out of sight in the last uh i guess about the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		exempt or nonexempt
 	
 	
 		i'm exempt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wow</ENAMEX> must be nice
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		part of the high price spread uh
 		no uh
 		well we don't
 		we do but we don't have a family budget
 		we have the fixed things that we have to pay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		we have the things that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX> but it seems that by and large the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX> just don't exist
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		well you know the auto budget
 		car payment sucks a hell of a lot of it dry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and insurance is insurance bad there
 	
 	
 		um
 		i've got uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> there both one's a seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and one's a seventy eight
 	
 	
 		well we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one eighty nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh my insurance is about uh
 		it was running <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about four hundred dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> but when i moved to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> i live in because it's a different county
 		which has less crime and uh less you know less <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> and so it's a cheaper place to live as far as the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s concerned so my my i think my insurance dropped about uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> dollars a year
 	
 	
 		wow that's that's not bad <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four hundred</NUMEX> and something a year that's that's
 	
 	
 		well it's actually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> for each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		that's cheaper than we pay
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i was down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and i was paying unbelievable rates for both car insurance and for home insurance um they
 	
 	
 		well here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> it's even worse because we have uh no fault
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you have that there
 	
 	
 		uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> they uh they have no fault in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		well no fault's rather funny in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> because uh it seems that
 		everyone pays all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		instead of just the guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> pays
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		it's kind of it's kind of strange here the way things go uh here if you have an accident and no one's injured the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> won't even show up
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 	
 	
 		nope
 		they tell you if nobody's injured you all exchange names and take it up with your insurance company
 	
 	
 		God
 	
 	
 		well if you i don't know how familiar you are with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> but uh especially the the center part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> where i <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety five</NUMEX> runs through it is really heavily populated
 	
 	
 		not at all
 	
 	
 		and there's just so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and so many accidents <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single day</TIMEX>
 		that it take another police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> just to answer the traffic
 	
 	
 		they don't even try to keep up with it
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		God so you lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		not a bit
 		yes sir
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i spent uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple years</TIMEX> down there moved down there in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> and moved out in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nine</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		are where you from originally
 	
 	
 		uh right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh so you just basically went home when you had a chance
 	
 	
 		and my family
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> uh didn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i had a chance to uh transfer up <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> after i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hunt Valley</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that's nice
 	
 	
 		so i got an opportunity to transfer back and i took it
 	
 	
 		God that's great uh no i'm a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">west Texan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there is a difference
 	
 	
 		yeah believe me i know there is i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> and i don't know if you're familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> but Plano maybe <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> actually were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		everybody else was an import
 	
 	
 		well i'm i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">west Texan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock Midland</ENAMEX> Odessa
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amarillo Dumas Panhandle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a different world from down there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>'s been fun
 		but they have a real problem
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		next to every window the state
 		seems to have put up a turnstile
 		and every time you
 		look at a look at the mountains
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or think about looking at the mountains
 		you got to throw in a dollar
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		or or so it seems i i may just be paranoid but that state income tax is just eating me alive
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they have a state income tax in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> but i noticed when i was in the in the
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they didn't have a state income tax but they sure nailed you on those darn county taxes and school taxes and property taxes
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah property taxes and yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my God ate you alive
 	
 	
 		inspection
 		you know they have the state income tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then they also have property taxes
 		and they also have sales taxes and they just
 		and they just get you every direction they can
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i just don't know sir but they it seems like they trying to get you every which way
 	
 	
 		yeah it sure does um there's uh some good books that i've read um that you might be interested in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Charles D Gibbons</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who runs some ads on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">light</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> TV and he's got seminars you can go to and they try to hook you into his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> which costs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four hundred</NUMEX> bucks
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but he's got a couple of books out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them is called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um  Wealth Without Risk</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've heard of the book
 	
 	
 		yes it's a very good book it's tells you how to cut money on your taxes and on your insurance and then what to do
 	
 	
 		legally
 	
 	
 		what to do with the money that you save
 	
 	
 		legally cut money on your taxes huh
 	
 	
 		yes  yes sir
 		legally legally cut money on your taxes and on your uh insurance and then he tells you how to invest that money in order to uh uh
 		you know be wealthier uh he also has a new book out that i purchased right before i moved and haven't had a chance to uh crack it open yet um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Self Defense</ENAMEX> i believe is the name of it
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> uh has a lot of good ideas some of them i already knew about some of them i had already practiced but i suggest it to anyone who wants to be better off financially to read it because uh
 	
 	
 		and that includes everyone at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes yes i'm one of the ones that had my salary frozen for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety one</NUMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		well even the you know the non exempts
 		technically yet we haven't had our salary frozen
 		yet
 	
 	
 		yet
 	
 	
 		but when you're only at living wage it doesn't matter
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know survival is a funny state
 	
 	
 		yeah i know what you mean i uh when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> and i had uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> non exempts
 		um under me
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh i i was appalled at what the hell they were paying them i just couldn't believe it
 	
 	
 		did well i've been with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years</TIMEX> now i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WF</ENAMEX> for several years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it just never never seems to improve
 		it it and it doesn't seem to get much better for the exempts either unless you're <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty eight</TIMEX> or above
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's really a shame
 	
 	
 		well i i've
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that they bought they ended up buying a very high payroll
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh the you know uh i thought i was making a good wage you know high wage till i came
 		
 		
 	