
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well what what do you think is the uh the main change in uh what what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> are you i'm i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty nine</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty nine</TIMEX> okay so we're we're we're both uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the very early sixties
 	
 	
 		right and i have i mean i've seen some change like i know um
 		when i was young most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> pretty much were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewives</ENAMEX> and stayed at home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and to me it seems like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's almost the opposite now where the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is working and and they you know take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to child care or maybe they work part-time or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that seems to be a pretty big change
 	
 	
 		yeah the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> in general is being really restructured from one income to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incomes which means from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> if you're lucky  um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		i uh it's it's funny because both of us both of us then were really just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adolescents</ENAMEX> when when i think most of the major changes for adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were going on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> i don't think changes are are still progressing but it seems to me that the uh
 		really the seventies the early seventies was a period of the most change and if i had to be somewhat abstract about it it seems to be the major change has been that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> have acquired more choice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum oh that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i mean that's sort of the overall the meta the meta change as it were uh where that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> really have more of a choice now about what they do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		of course they find that the choice creates its own hardships in a way because life is not quite as simple even if it is for your you know you can choose something you really want which is a wonderful thing but it does seem like an awful lot of my uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult women friends</ENAMEX> are anguishing over over some of these choices um
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i know the choice to either work or to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is probably pretty difficult because i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> just naturally tend to have those instincts that you you know you protected the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you want to be with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> yet there's so many material things to be had out there that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think oh but if we both work we can get a really big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and we can get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> we can take a vacation we can do this and
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		and it's kind of almost expected of you anyway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kind of look down on on a you know the role of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> it's kind of like oh well you know she didn't go to college and she's just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> and that's all she does right
 	
 	
 		right
 		she just settled for that yeah
 	
 	
 		right even though there's probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with MBA's maybe even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PhD</ENAMEX>'s that are staying at home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		well i only know i have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh i only know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who's decided to go the quote unquote traditional route and i have a lot of respect for her because she made it as a real choice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she really knew that she didn't have to do that but she decided that was what she wanted to do in her life and she wanted that role she's a she's a marvelous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i you know i say all power to her because she's an example to me of someone who really does have the choice i feel that a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> don't well i i said they have the choice but they don't necessarily feel that they do because they no longer  feel like if they were to just be a parent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		rather than uh you know the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super woman</ENAMEX> success in the business world as well they would somehow be perceived as a failure in their own eyes or in others and and then you see then it's not a choice anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		and and frankly it's the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> don't have this choice you know they don't feel this choice um uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in most subcultures in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that that i've been exposed to if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> were to say uh no i've decided not to work i want to stay home and do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> rearing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has a good job and i want her to keep that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm going to i'm going to be the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caretaker</ENAMEX> and you know and then then take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because we don't want to put them in day care and this and that i think most
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would feel funny about that and maybe sort of feel like he isn't that success that he could have been
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		so it's um
 	
 	
 		there's some TV show on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and i i i think i've seen it once i don't get to watch much TV but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's a TV show where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is the one raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is and i maybe they based it on that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Mom</ENAMEX> movie but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i didn't i didn't see that
 	
 	
 		but uh there there is a TV show out there i guess they're trying to gain you know more public acceptance of things like that because i know there are cases where that happens and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i've i knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who did it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> but they they were very apologetic about it because you could tell they were used to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kind of going what are you doing that for you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right it's probably getting more and more accepted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in fact it seems like
 		it's kind of almost like anything goes now you you're not too surprised on much of anything when you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at home raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> works that's not real surprising and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i've seen more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that have um parental leave not just maternity leave they can grant paternity leave as well as maternity leave
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah in fact i'm pretty sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has something like that because uh one of the area <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> uh in my area as a matter of fact took off um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> had their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> now it might have been just to take care of her and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> instead of having you know a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> or someone come in or whatever midwife or whatever you call it that they have for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first couple of weeks</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't know if he took that out of his vacation or if they really do have a paternity he put paternity leave up there but it might have just been him describing the fact that he was taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation days</TIMEX> to go be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> for a little while i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		i'm not real sure how that goes
 	
 	
 		yeah the other big change i see in in in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s lives is um
 		
 
 		to remain biological they uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are because they have choice are having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> much later in life
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who are having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are having them at age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh if i'd been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of generations ago</TIMEX> they would have
 		had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> running around by then
 	
 	
 		right well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they in general are just getting married a lot later i'm still single so i'm sure i'll be one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that's you know one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> when when i get around to to ever getting married and then having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		that's uh i think i think that's getting a little more common too
 	
 	
 		yeah i actually think i i'm i'm somewhat encouraged by that trend because after all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live long er lives now so it's not like you can you know it's not like you're going to uh you know pass away before your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is an adult i mean barring unforseen you know unforeseen circumstances
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> make better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> when they're a little bit more mature i really do
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree
 		i agree i think it also gives a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> a chance to if she does have a job a nd a career it gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> both a chance to both be working and maybe save up some money and then it gives her a little more option if she wants to stay home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> while they're young
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> for awhile and then once they've gotten to school age maybe she could go back to work so she's kind of got that option if if they wait till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> they've saved up some money that it's not as difficult for her to stay at home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and live off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> income or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah that's true
 		so i guess i oh i'm pretty encouraged  i really am but then i'm a product of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> i don't know i if i'd been born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years ago</TIMEX> and were looking at this time i might not like it but it sure seems nice to me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i mean i have other things to complain about but in terms of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s roles um things really seem a lot more flexible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i seem to see more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in uh
 		in leadership type roles and management positions in politics and
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it's still still admittedly a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> but but it's an improvement it really is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and i'm sure that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> that never would have happened but yeah she's i think she's in her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term now so
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she's she's yeah this is her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term i think she's going to going to uh not going to run again after this but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh we do and we have several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> but you just start hearing more and more in fact oh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> too  can't forget that one so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Richards</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		what what's her name
 		no it we don't get much <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> politics out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to be honest
 	
 	
 		she used
 		yeah she was inaugurated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you're starting to see more of that and i know when i was younger it was all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and still all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> but i'm sure one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> we will well look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX> ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> and i guess one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> we'll we'll eventually have
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		although during during during the uh Presidential debates there was some really nasty patronizing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		stuff toward i mean i don't know if if you saw those but i thought she was treated badly at for being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> frankly i really did by by uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the then vice presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> uh who really sort of i thought had a very demeaning attitude towards her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and  it was sort of it was acceptable to say certain types of things to her that she couldn't say back that kind of thing which i i i i found myself getting really quite enraged about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but really that's a previous generation i don't like it's harder to imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of our age doing that and not feeling really stupid
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 		i agree well i think we've we've gotten our <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five five minutes</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or seven</NUMEX> or whatever so
 	
 	
 		well they've gotten their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> worth of us i've enjoyed talking with you
 	
 	
 		it was nice talking to you too
 	
 	
 		okay take care bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	