
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		that was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i thought they gave up after a little while but i'm sure glad you were home i think we're going to discuss why we think uh uh so few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> vote in national elections and even fewer in local elections
 	
 	
 		that's it yep
 	
 	
 		and that's what we're going to talk about okay and uh uh okay where do you work <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't work my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works nope i'm just one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewives</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay how did you get how how yeah how did you get in the program
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> both work at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> so yeah
 	
 	
 		oh that's neat they both work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> yeah i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> here how many calls have you been in on this year
 	
 	
 		oh goodness um
 		i i can't really say i haven't i haven't listed them or anything
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know i haven't been i i hope the computer keeping track of them because i'm not well
 	
 	
 		yeah i've enjoyed them so it doesn't really matter
 	
 	
 		oh i do too i i just really i i try to get in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one a night</TIMEX> if somebody doesn't call me i call somebody okay you you about ready
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay by the way you don't sound like you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that's why i didn't think you don't sound you sound like you're from the north that's why i didn't think you were from
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		huh
 		oh well it's funny you should say something like that because uh i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX> i was from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> originally
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		well that's why i picked it up yes you have you have a northern accent
 	
 	
 		but i don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> accent
 		oh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> accent but i don't
 	
 	
 		well not i didn't say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> but i could definitely tell your from the north
 	
 	
 		oh it's northern well i've been i've been everywhere i've lived overseas for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four four years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> rather <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>
 		and i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> before i came here i was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> so it's but i've been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX> so i sort of consider myself a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> i got a
 	
 	
 		yeah well you never i don't think you ever lose that that that which you which you begin with that accent
 	
 	
 		no
 		i've got a i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're still are i myself am a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> so you can never as a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> you can never become a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> unless you were born here and have
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		where where you native <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where was i i was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so i've been i've been in this area for most all my life
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah where what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		oh okay
 		now i i i ask that because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX> area in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX> and you can tell she's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> too yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they have much more of a twang down in that area okay okay
 	
 	
 		right right well i'm going to push <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and let them start recording okay
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Karen</ENAMEX> uh you know it always has amazed me and in fact i think i wrote a paper on this in college uh that the national elections uh just have
 		so few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> voting in them you know uh maybe uh fifty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> or less of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> have you ever thought much about it
 	
 	
 		well yes i have um i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> for a while and it really bothered me to think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are affected so you know so closely by
 		you know that it comes so close to home as far as the government you know that because they are so directly connected with it and yet so few of them were registered to vote
 	
 	
 		did
 	
 	
 		and and it really it really used to bother me and then and then i'd hear complaints about this and that that was you know was happening
 		to those of us in the military the cuts and things like that and i would be like well are you registered to vote have you you know made any uh
 		changes you know as far as your voting habits on you know who who you're voting for and what you're looking for and and uh no they'd say no and i'd be well then
 		shut up you know you don't really have much you don't have much that you can say so
 	
 	
 		how do you vote how do you vote in the military do you vote absentee in your own registered state um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah you vote absentee yeah you vote you you still connected to your state legally you still
 		you can you still are responsible for paying those taxes they withdraw taxes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for for that state if like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we don't have it so yeah but but if you are they withdraw that from your pay and uh you can be you can
 	
 	
 		we don't have a state income tax right
 	
 	
 		you can uh be have suits brought against you as if you were from that state yeah so you are attached to that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> from which you came from
 	
 	
 		from that state um-hum um-hum yeah
 		right i'm going to inject a little side anecdote for you back to the to the uh uh the main topic here because it it you might be interested in this uh you know i i've
 	
 	
 		to voting uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as i mentioned i've had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> of expatriate expatriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and uh you vote in the embassy
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh uh</ENAMEX> from whatever country you're in you go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Embassy</ENAMEX> and vote there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillipines</ENAMEX> uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> not stationed there but i was i was there on business and visiting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that i knew very well in fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had been my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> when we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>
 		and uh it was with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and i went to his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for dinner and they had a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who was probably about in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade and was attending a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in uh uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> and this was in
 		uh this was just nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> just uh prior maybe in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> prior to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> election and i went home for dinner to dinner with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> and they were they were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> and uh they lived there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX>
 		and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> said gee the darndest thing happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> she said i'm so embarrassed she said i was over at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>'s school and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> came and spoke to the
 		to the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so she was there visiting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portugal</ENAMEX> and she visited this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and spoke to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and after it was over she said i went up to her and i said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mrs Thatcher</ENAMEX> i'm a great admirer of yours
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she said what i wanted to uh uh i've always wanted to meet you and i've enjoyed this opportunity to meet you
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> said oh you're you're an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> yes she said well something i want to ask you about she said when you're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election year</TIMEX> like this how do you vote
 		and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> said oh if nothing changes i'll vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and she said oh my goodness no i didn't mean that and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX> realized immediately she didn't mean that she meant what was the process of voting
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> was embarrassed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX> would think that she was going to ask her how she was going to vote and it was so funny and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> kept looking at her and said i can't believe you could be so dumb
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh i it's it's interesting though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do we've had noticed we had been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one election year</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> in another
 		that there seems to be a higher percent of the expatriate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> i mean well over fifty percent that do bother to register with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> and go vote you'd almost think that you think you're more important when you're out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and you're exposed to some things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think i think sometimes that you um you pick you become more aware of what you have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and how important it is to you you become more loyal so to speak to to the things that you don't have at that time and you realize hey my you know we really have a good thing there so i think you hold more dear the things like democracy and your rights
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		true
 	
 	
 		you know as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> but i think uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i've talked to as far as voting because i've worked you know in in
 		trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to vote when i was in the military i was a uh represented you know i represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as far as voting and um from what i spoke speaking with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it was
 		mainly that um they felt frustrated that their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote wasn't going to do any good you know that um
 		and and it was really hard to get across to them that it didn't matter you know it's a matter of that's your right you should go and do it you know and that your <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote can count when you get a whole lot of people
 		if everybody says oh well my vote doesn't count you know then then what do you have you know
 	
 	
 		that's exactly right and they don't realize that that it's it's all onesies and the onesies all add up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know the thing that that i surprised me even more you know if we got a good contest going we do manage to get fifty percent out in national elections and uh but what's even worse is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">off year</TIMEX> congressional elections
 		uh when there's not a presidential election uh and the local election and it bothers me and i i think that's even more important to vote in those because uh oh sure and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you can make a big difference in those and it's more more to home a lot of the time
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's it's like a school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> election you know those of us with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> are very concerned about what goes on uh in the school system yet school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> are elected with sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to fifteen percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> turning out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		isn't that ridiculous
 	
 	
 		and yeah and and you know the one of the things that i can still remember a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> standing up pointing his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipe</ENAMEX> at a class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> while he was lecturing and he said the problem of the vote is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 		uh public is sometimes asked to go to the polls too often and to make too many and too difficult decisions and i think of that every time i go find one of these ballots
 		and you not only get it in the presidential year uh where where you go down through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or nine judgeships</TIMEX>  and uh uh
 	
 	
 		yeah but don't you think in a way that's kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> out i mean it still is your responsibility and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and</ENAMEX> and nowadays they do have more information that you can become aware of and there are things like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Women Voters</ENAMEX> or some of the other groups
 	
 	
 		what
 		oh yeah it it still is your responsibility
 	
 	
 		that you know put give out uh nonbiased information just general information on how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> stand on certain issues that you know you can make a decision on how you feel about certain issues and who you want
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		to represent you and so i really don't i don't agree that you have too many choices that you know it's it's too hard and i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just lazy i think they don't want to get out
 	
 	
 		yeah i yeah i i i think you're right there and i'm glad you mentioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Women Voters</ENAMEX> i've
 		i don't know how long they've been around maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> but it's only in my more mature <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that i have become aware of them
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and and i make a real effort to go out and read all and particularly read their things about
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for lesser <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> that you don't you can't read their view in the paper uh and i i think that is tremendously important and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		
 		
 	