
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay so uh what do you think about it
 	
 	
 		well um i guess i i'm more concerned about public safety than i am about the um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> for
 		the private uh the idea of preserving privacy for the individual um because i can't really see why anyone
 	
 	
 		privacy right
 	
 	
 		um who has nothing to hide would object
 	
 	
 		well there is always the uh the possibility even remote as it is of uh of mistaken uh of
 	
 	
 		that's of course that is certainly true yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and see that bothers me i'm i'm a i mean i'm i'm very much for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i really am i mean i'm going i'm going to take the negative side just for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a second</TIMEX> just to do it
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		um see i have to take uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> for a uh for for kidney transplant and i'm going to be taking that the rest of my life now you i don't know how that's going to affect uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 		if you had to have a drug test yeah
 	
 	
 		right i mean i haven't had one yet um <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> and and uh we you know we do have the random drug testing but i've missed it so far but i mean it in the back of my mind it always bothers me and what happens if it you know if it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they catch it they think that i'm you know i'm on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and they send me and and have me uh you know go through this this thing you know yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		checked out or whatever i but it seems to me that there are ways to accommodate that um i agree that that some innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> might be victimized by a false test
 		but i would think that um that some guidelines could be set up to avoid that for example that one uh positive
 		would not be uh accepted as an automatic um
 		reason for whatever they might be going to do if they found a positive uh dismissal or treatment or whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but that that what it would do is it would trigger perhaps uh one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more stages where further tests could be taken uh done
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because um there are there must be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you or in other circumstances that could come up with with uh false positives for certain kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> on the other hand um
 		i think there's certainly some professions that ought to be tested
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		because of the of their responsibility for the public welfare and certainly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in uh industries well the transportation industry for specifically uh you know specifically but um in many many cases
 	
 	
 		um-hum no
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		whether or not an individual has a problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> it's not even going to effect anybody but his uh you know himself and his own family perhaps um
 		depending on the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> he might be on but um and eventually that's going to show up anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		in the way he works and so on but there's so many things that it would make a difference i guess i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i uh i would not want to have anyone in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> uh victimized by someone who you know a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> or a train <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> or something like that who um  you know hadn't been tested
 	
 	
 		right well i you know i'm like i said i'm i'm very much pro testing um and and this is why
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh</ENAMEX> number one is i i'm i'm kind of i know this sounds like a slogan for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> but i you know we are in a war against  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah sure
 	
 	
 		it's it's horrible i mean
 		you don't know whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> sitting next to you anywhere is on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it takes some drastic steps at this point and i think personally the drastic step has to be
 		that um that you can't work if you continue taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i mean it's as simple as that i mean make it so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		make it difficult enough
 	
 	
 		well make it uh make not necessarily difficult but make it so that it's not glamorous
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it's glamorous taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or at least it seems that way
 	
 	
 		yeah according to what you you hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who um have serious problems i mean we have um really i guess we're kind of lucky we really only know of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who uh who's a family they go to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and so on and he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and he's really the only one that i know of personally who got himself really messed up um having having been involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but
 		i know of a number of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have you know gotten all messed up most of these are young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i work in the education system and so i have a little more contact with that but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the effect that it's had on this young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s life is so dramatic that it's heartbreaking and he may never really be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a productive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of society But sadder than that he may never be able to have a normal happy life
 		because it has strung him out so that he has anxieties now that are are almost uncontrollable i mean he he puts himself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 		fairly regularly thinking that you know he he's not sure if he's going try to commit suicide or not
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		i mean he's you know he's so messed up
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um this was a nice sweet young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who teenager you know and he's now a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> i guess who um just got
 		really down the wrong path and uh you know i don't know that that his problem would ever have been detected by drug testing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but seeing what <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> did to him makes me see makes me realize what it could do to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know in the work force as well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um it's horrible
 	
 	
 		well then let's let's answer the second half of the question what limits ought to be put on it do you think
 	
 	
 		well the limits uh uh would i think have to do with what i'd alluded to before that there needs to be a further um
 		that that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> positive on a drug test would not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		constitute uh dismissal or grounds for whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> might
 		uh have set up for those who genuinely have a problem in other words there needs to be um more than
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		treatment before for dismissal type thing
 	
 	
 		pardon yes right there needs to be more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> test and there needs to be some
 		some measure of uh certainty before anything drastic happens there are lots of things that are involved there um such as perhaps insurance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know denial of insurance for someone um and undoubtedly there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would be victimized by this um
 		that would that you know it would be unfair and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> for example or um
 		even even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might be of the gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and i'm not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for that particular  segment of society but um i think that
 		there doesn't need to be fuel to the fire for discrimination because it makes a bigger problem
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um so it seems to me that that um there needs to be some ground you know some rules that protect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure though when we talk about what rules if any that we should say well certain segments should not have to be tested i really don't see why
 	
 	
 		personally i think that's what i was about to say is that everyone needs to be tested
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah
 		yeah i don't i don't know why it would be you know um
 		bad to test just everyone and it may be you know it's not feasible to do everyone but certainly random testing the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know that that they
 	
 	
 		that it could happen um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah would be some measure of protection but the bottom line is that that if if you're going to stay clean and straight then um
 		you're you're going to do that because you want to really
 	
 	
 		right
 		well there's yeah there there's going to be some measure of incentive
 		uh reward or whatever but the reward ultimately ultimately comes down to what you want
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i i've got to agree with that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so um hum
 	
 	
 		no that's very true
 		well it sounds like we agree anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so i think we i think we did pretty good
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well  all right well uh i guess that's about it
 	
 	
 		i guess if that's all we've done and i guess we've talked long enough
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		it was it was talk nice talking to you too
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	