
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well how do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s roles have changed
 	
 	
 		well that kind of caught me by surprise it's kind i think i think that they have changed drastically i mean i think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who
 		you know gave up their careers and stayed home to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and um
 		you know played a really subservient role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i just don't see that anymore at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who do stay home to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> i think that they are still thought of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as</NUMEX> equals in in the role you know as far as the role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and society goes
 	
 	
 		well i i uh just in my lifetime i know that the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> has changed drastically also my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> when she began having her family she quit her job and stayed home until
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm the youngest in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> until i was uh in junior high school old enough to care for myself when i got home from school
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but i think that uh the changes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next twenty years</TIMEX> will probably be just as drastic you you'll see more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women CEOs</ENAMEX> and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> holding public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		definitely
 		i think the biggest problem uh the biggest change that needs to be made is the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are paid
 	
 	
 		oh i agree
 	
 	
 		i mean you know it's just the statistics are just staggering that when they make like you know sixty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX> on the dollar for what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> make for the same jobs and that i mean i can get really angry about that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it it's probably all it it's
 		the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is is in an evolutionary stage so we i'm sure it will eventually evolve to where it is equal it just hasn't reached that point yet because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> uh haven't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		been in positions similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> relative to how long <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have had those types of positions
 	
 	
 		well
 		that's true
 		but you know i'm a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> trying to raise a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and it really upsets me not to be paid you know the same for my job now i don't see that so much in my job but i know in other professions
 		um i know that it's true i know you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine that are affected by that
 		and uh just you know it's just not fair
 	
 	
 		no it's not fair
 	
 	
 		i don't know what to do about it
 	
 	
 		well there's not much you can do except for yourself individually and and stand up for
 		your salary i mean for what you want in your own job and if if it's not going to work out go find some place that will do what you want to do
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		and then too i think that
 		you know i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have been forced into the workplace unwittingly just because it you know to raise a family nowadays it takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incomes
 		they have to work and then i think the majority of the time they get still get stuck with most of the you know running the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> type chores
 		you know taking care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and you know arranging their schedules and
 		being responsible for those types of of things i know that i do know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that that participate quite actively um you know in in things but i know a lot that don't so
 		it's just a real shame you know i think when you look at the changing role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> you have to look at the changing role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> too because they're directly related
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i think it during this in this evolutionary theory that i have here that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> will eventually
 		evolve around to where they participate more in the home because when it gets to the point to where that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is dirty and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are dirty and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s not home she's at work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are going to gradually learn how to do those kinds of things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		well they may yeah i think eventually but some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> don't see some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> just don't care
 	
 	
 		well at i the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> that are being raised now by working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> i i are are a little more in touch with
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the household chores and duties and what has to be done so i think over a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> time it will all change because it's really been uh my generation
 	

 	
 		yeah i i agree with that
 	
 	
 		grew up for the most part with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> but again my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> plan of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> plans on working and not being at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it will be my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who really make big changes i think because that they will probably the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		now are at home without their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> well or in some type of a day care or something because so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> work now
 	
 	
 		right in day care
 		yeah i agree i uh you know it's fun being single it's like i almost have to work right now i'm at home because i am recovering from surgery but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i really resent that in that i don't have that choice to be able to stay home with my child
 		but uh i guess as long as you are single you have to support yourself nobody else is going to do it for you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well how do you feel about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> do you think that that's going to grow and how far do you think that's going to go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next ten years</TIMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		well i think that that there's more you know there is definitely more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> uh i think it's going to be a long time before we see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> president uh i don't think that's going to happen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next ten years</TIMEX> i don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		think that's going to happen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next twenty years</TIMEX> but uh you know i think that there's progress
 		and i'm not very political so i don't really know you know any i don't know any statistics on you know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> run for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and how often they're defeated
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't know any statistics either but it's it's probably going to be the same type of situation that that uh the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have gone through it took them
 		well black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> long time to to get up to the pay scales of the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and now i think it it's feasible for a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to be president
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think we will see a black a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> before we see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> president
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and since since this evolution or this this progression of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> salaries and all that was all before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were heavy in the work place i <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will probably go through the same type of deal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		same type of battle yeah
 	
 	
 		type of deal it's just further down the road
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i don't know i think a lot of um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are uh do you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> you know because we now we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman governor</ENAMEX> and of course <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i do you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		no i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> well
 	
 	
 		we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman mayor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do yeah yeah you do now  and uh we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman mayor</ENAMEX> now too in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> has had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman mayor</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> because i used to live there too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman governor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years ago</TIMEX> or whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh did they
 		oh i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX> i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> governor
 	
 	
 		huh
 		was she elected or was it something that
 	
 	
 		i think she was i'm not sure it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred or so years ago</TIMEX> so i i don't know i'm not real up on past history or anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's interesting i didn't i i i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i i'm thinking it might have been the kind of deal where her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was governor and he died or something
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right why i asked if she was elected or if it if it was something that was passed passed down to her through through the ways that the laws work
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		but
 		uh i'm surprised i really am surprised you know that major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> you know especially in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> would elect a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> governor
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh like i said i really have no interest in politics it's just not my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> but uh
 		you know being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> i don't know even that i would vote
 		for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the high offic e
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't now because i don't know of one that's that's equipped to handle
 	
 	
 		i certainly i wouldn't have voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ann Richards</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> and uh i can't say that i would vote for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman president</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		no i why i didn't
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		we might see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman vice president</ENAMEX> that wouldn't surprise me and then of course if something happened to be uh i'm sorry yeah if something happened she would be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> but it would not be something that she were elected to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the
 		the problem i'm sorry go ahead
 		i uh i just i don't think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman president</ENAMEX> is anywhere in the near future if not just for the just for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> prejudice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the world several major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the world that we deal with all the time don't respect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman president</ENAMEX> would be
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		laughed at by other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> because they wouldn't respect her as a business person
 	
 	
 		nope
 		what about  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> wasn't she fairly she was i thought she was real well  real well respected
 	
 	
 		
 
 		she was but i don't think that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> deals as heavily with with
 		like for instance the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i don't know all the details of it but i i know that for instance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> women are just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and in uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> has done business in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and it was very difficult for her going over there because they just don't have very many business women
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> basically see a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and ask them to go get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> or something it's just it's very difficult to be well respected and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> had been in office it was probably very difficult for her at first but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well she comes from a a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where the model
 		
 		
 	