
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay well our involvement in our involvement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 		well
 		i don't know how you feel about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> but i think but i think we did the right thing there
 		i think they stopped too soon though
 	
 	
 		yeah i kind of feel that way too
 	
 	
 		i think they should have just kept right on going into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>
 		uh probably could have struck a deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi's</ENAMEX> and just let them have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well and now the way they're uh treating those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> is that what they its terrible and we've just kind of backed off i don't understand that why we
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 		well i don't either and it's certainly foreseeable the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> have always been
 		that way and every time they try something they they get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> they get the crap kicked out of them
 		and
 	
 	
 		are they just kind of a nomad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> type of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they're scattered all over really you got them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> and
 		they sort of just meander around but they they hold true that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Iraq</ENAMEX> is theirs
 		and uh i don't know it it was certainly foreseeable right after the war i mean it should have been obvious if it it was obvious to me it should have been obvious to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> there should have been some plans to
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		try to give them some aid i mean we helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Afghanistanis</ENAMEX> there's know reason why we shouldn't have helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>
 		it didn't have to involve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> could have just given them uh you know supplies
 	
 	
 		yeah but he's just shooting them and they just killing them off
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i mean Lord there's things that we probably never will hear about that he's doing of course he's been doing it all along anyway
 	
 	
 		horrible things
 		yeah well yeah i guess he has i think they should have gotten rid of him that's that's the thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i can't say i mean it's it's easy to understand why he's still there i mean those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over there have nothing i mean you can't you can't drag this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> down with nothing
 		and the only thing that surprised me i really i really expect the army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> to get him out
 		i really expected to have the
 	
 	
 		his own people
 	
 	
 		yeah i expected some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> and stuff to
 		quietly do away with him
 	
 	
 		assassinate him
 	
 	
 		but uh it's amazing that they could stand around and watch their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> get decimated that way and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		not
 		do anything about it
 	
 	
 		yeah it's like he has some sort of a power over them i i can't figure it out
 	
 	
 		yeah it's either that or he's well entrenched and they couldn't get to him or something
 	
 	
 		but he's still running things
 	
 	
 		he's still running things
 	
 	
 		and they're still doing things for him
 	
 	
 		and apparently still has a great deal of control
 	
 	
 		see that's what i don't understand
 	
 	
 		i don't either it's it's tough to understand those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> anyway
 		they they think completely differently the way we from the way we do
 		i've got several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Middle Middle Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> uh my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> and i was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i have a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and i've got a couple <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kuwaiti</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you really know about them
 	
 	
 		no no i don't i
 	
 	
 		you don't
 	
 	
 		no i know i know a little bit more than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but no where near enough to
 		even talk intelligently about them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> aren't you glad you're not over there or you weren't over there when all this erupted
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yes i am
 	
 	
 		had have you ever gone back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nope</ENAMEX> never have
 		never wanted to
 	
 	
 		how long were you over there
 	
 	
 		uh we were there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's along time out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s life anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah it was it was nice i enjoyed it uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tehran</ENAMEX> was a beautiful place i still remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we lived in great big old it was almost something out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Baba</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forty thieves</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		you oh how neat
 	
 	
 		yeah it was it was really nice
 		we've got some nice uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">uh Persian</ENAMEX> carpets that we still have
 	
 	
 		ugh
 	
 	
 		those are very nice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and you couldn't get them over hear for
 	
 	
 		well you can you can but they're expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah you'd have to be
 	
 	
 		i went matter of fact i went to a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> carpet auction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three weeks ago</TIMEX> and i'm just amazed at some of the prices they're getting
 	
 	
 		and especially now you know because you probably couldn't get anything out of there any more
 	
 	
 		no not out of there but of course these things are made in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>
 		and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> ones are you you know we we don't them anymore but there was loads and loads of them sent over before the embargoes
 		and so they're still floating around
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah there's a lot there's a lot of them
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Afghanistan the Afghani</ENAMEX> uh carpets are nice too i mean you can't tell the difference if you're not an expert
 		they are all nice i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they make nice carpet
 	
 	
 		and they probably they do it all by hand probably
 	
 	
 		yeah they do
 		the goods are you can tell the machine made ones
 		but the handmade ones are very easy to spot because you have the same
 		um you have a uh oh i forgot what they call it it's the the
 		um  what am i trying to say not the picture it's the uh way it's woved you know weived woven yeah woven how it's woven into the fabric and you know they have pattern pattern that's the word good grief it's been along day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		woven
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh um</ENAMEX> and when you turn it over you'll see that very same pattern uh it will be fainter of course but it will be that same way and the machine made ones they don't they don't look like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it looks like our carpet where you just have a flat backing and then the thing is knitted into this backing
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		uh they're nice though i i like them i'm
 		still negotiating i'm trying to get a couple of them for myself
 	
 	
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have them  oh i don't know she
 	
 	
 		yeah they
 		they they keep they keep coming with this well when we die they're yours i i don't want to wait until your dead i mean you'll probably have it in your will that you're going to be buried with them i don't know
 	
 	
 		they're yours
 		wrapped up in their c arpet
 	
 	
 		yeah just to spite us you know
 	
 	
 		well uh my my my ex
 	
 	
 		go go  i said go ahead
 	
 	
 		oh oh go ahead i was going to say my ex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was i was talking for him last night and he was talking about going over to uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Iran</ENAMEX> or wherever their asking he's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electrician</ENAMEX> he's certified and he's gone to school and all that for it and they're asking for these specialized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go over there for is a year and he was talking about going over there and i said you really want to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean i think it's probably still very dangerous over there
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i think it is too there's too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> running around uh when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> uh a lot of uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit</ENAMEX>'s work over in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		lots and lots of them and it it it's a it's a real financial boom for them because the the wages are tremendously high
 		i mean they got all that money and they don't have anybody to pay it to um and it's tax free
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they get free trips home twice a year things like that so they the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brit</ENAMEX>'s loved it but i i'm not so sure i would want to go over there that's a little being an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> you're still
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean you're still is a target over there
 	
 	
 		yeah until they really and and it's not over see that's the thing it's not over and they're sending all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> back and i think well they're probably going to end up going back over there again
 	
 	
 		no not by a long shot well
 		well you know we're not sending back as many i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think we're sending back a lot we're not sending back that many yet there's still a lot of them over there
 		a lot of them a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> a lot of ground forces
 	
 	
 		well they're still shooting down <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now</TIMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		honey i uh you what we did i mean you know telling uh telling uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> that well if you use your if you use your uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter aircraft</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> we're going to shoot them down okay well wow wee you know why don't we go in there and just wipe out all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> then we don't have to worry about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you know they don't need the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> to wipe out those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> evidently they just
 		going through and blasting them but you know from what i you know we don't hear just hear hear bits and pieces but it's pretty gruesome
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and probably a lot worse like you said than even know
 	
 	
 		well over there in that part of world anything like this always is i mean their
 	
 	
 		and it will never end they've been fighting
 	
 	
 		no
 		no they've been fighting for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and it will be they'll fight for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more years</TIMEX> it it it's going to go on forever
 	
 	
 		for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of years
 	
 	
 		um the thing that surprises me really is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s sitting there in the middle of all this
 		uh i mean
 		i i have some bones to pick with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>'s but you've got to admire their tenacity
 		to be sitting there surrounded by hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> and to maintain this is our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">homeland</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah and and they
 	
 	
 		they're pretty brave
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still coming in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and stuff jews coming in to uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> i saw that on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty uh 20/20</NUMEX> or something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> you know the about the migration and it's just and and jeez i don't know what their doing with all the people
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they have
 		i don't either well um you know they what you don't hear about is how many they turn away
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't even know they were turning any away
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they'll help them relocate somewhere else but but they're not they're they're filling up to fast and they're they're just getting to many diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> there and that's
 		something the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> didn't really want to happen you know they're they're stuck with the fact that you've got to take in your family your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jew</ENAMEX> but
 		they're also stuck with the fact they don't want to diversify their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that much
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		they i mean they got a big problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> they don't need any other problems
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um boy</ENAMEX> what a mess
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i'm really surprised that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> didn't take care of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> a long time ago
 	
 	
 		and they just didn't do anything did they they're just kind of sitting there
 	
 	
 		they're sitting there it it it makes me wonder and they've they've got the capability
 		and they've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know
 		
 		
 	