
 
     		
 	
 		i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> talked to somebody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> what is that is it a school up there that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh great great that's wonderful yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i i didn't know that we were going to be talking to mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> i thought it was all scattered out among graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or something yeah
 	
 	
 		is that right yeah we uh we thought the opposite we thought well it's going to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i think they went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that use <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> computers and everything which is fine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> went down to a seminar you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> had uh sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and got the information and brought it back and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		actually they don't talk about much uh of what it's for but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> keeps keeps ask asking me and i'm saying well your computer is eventually going to just answer your voice you know they're they're of course it's very obvious for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with handicaps but in general i guess it would be faster
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		sure
 		yeah you you yeah you could just sit there and talk
 	
 	
 		than typing and everything so
 		oh yeah it's it's uh around the corner
 	
 	
 		reminds me of something i read in an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Asimov</ENAMEX> science fiction thing one time uh-huh
 	
 	
 		right well i mean it's so uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s uh been the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> on a little advertising for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> not that i know that much about the uh voice synthesis but they've been working on it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> you know they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Speak and Spell</ENAMEX> and all of that of course but they're
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they're going to take it much further and i guess in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> and all that a lot of it is going to be like you talk to the computer like
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand one or two thousand ten ten</NUMEX> when you talk to the computer and yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		Hal right
 		that was great well what do you think about the metric system you well what do you do out there are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> you say
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i'm a i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> here um yeah i think we should adopt it i i think we're a little bit backward as far as the rest of the world's concerned
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um i know it causes a problem for industry in a little in a small way but nothing that won't be overcome in a little bit of time
 	
 	
 		yeah well we're not going to have much to fight over because i do too uh being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> have pretty much and i'm not too sure about the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i'm sure all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm somewhat of a car buff almost all of it is metric
 	
 	
 		uh-huh what what what bothers the heck out of me is uh one of these so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> where part of it's put together in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and what you've got is you've got standard and metric
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you go in there with a wrench and you know oh golly it's not a metric it's a standard
 	
 	
 		right
 		right well i i work on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> only and i haven't noticed that that much usually the metrics will fit they're so close there's an overlap
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know there's something funny that i haven't really resolved with metric i've got to really go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and see if it's true i can't remember the size i think it's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh eighteen</ENAMEX> or something like that i have a set of metric and and the old wrenches too and i think that's an exact size of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> and they don't make it in metric they just skip over it and it
 	
 	
 		yeah you're right you're right because mine goes from seventeen to nineteen yeah
 	
 	
 		right and i was thinking i've got to get an eighteen because i don't i don't like i'm so used to when i'm grabbing tools for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to grab for the number you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i don't even bother with the unless i'm working on a bumper or something but the engine parts and all are all metric you know
 	
 	
 		yeah a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine's got a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colt</ENAMEX> and i was doing something to it and golly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of it was standard and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of it was metric it was the most irritating thing
 	
 	
 		i haven't noticed it mostly being
 		yeah well i mean well on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> it was all metric i use my metrics essentially when i work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i don't well i guess uh in changing the oil i guess that's uh i don't even know a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> sixteenths or something like that i don't even remember
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't either i can't convert them i'm hope
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but i was thinking i just had a cheap set of metrics in fact uh
 		i thought well i guess either i lost the eighteen and then i i started to see it in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and i noticed that the cheaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sets</ENAMEX> again i'm calling it cheaper sets minus the eighteen i thought well i've got to go to an expensive place go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> and get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craftsman</ENAMEX> tools there
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and see if i can't get that eighteen i want a full set you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i still haven't checked out to see if they do make the eighteen i i'm sure they do
 	
 	
 		they don't uh you think so i've i've i've never seen one i've never seen one i've never seen one
 	
 	
 		well i guess they do i don't know why they wouldn't
 		oh you haven't really
 		i just thought it was my set so i just didn't have a a good quality set you know
 	
 	
 		no as a matter of fact i don't think is there a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX>
 		i don't think there's a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> either
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i think it's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> did i just say eighteen something that is the same as a three-quarter and it that i i'd rather have it all metric
 	
 	
 		yeah i would too i mean we we're just about the last holdout in the world to to hold on to this old archaic system i mean even <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s gone metric
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> makes equipment for the semiconductor business you know we make not a lot of but we make we were making a lot of our own manufacturing equipment
 		and i bet they have a lot of metrics there i think that uh the only emotional part might be in miles you know mile signs but that that's could be last anyway maybe pick a year <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> say okay we'll slowly change but i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and and even changing the things i mean <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> off i i mean you need to address do you even need to change the signs
 		because for so long <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going are going to be able to equate <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles to kilometers</NUMEX> i mean when you drive around <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> you do the same thing
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		well i think the speedometers don't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> have them both now am i not mistaken i i i look at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> i don't even know i read it
 	
 	
 		yeah most of them do they have the uh yeah they have the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the kilometer</NUMEX> inside and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">and</ENAMEX> of course the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles per hour</NUMEX> great big so you can see it um
 	
 	
 		upper and lower yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i it's silly i don't i don't think that we ought to be any different it causes a lot of problems a lot of times between uh different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in their manufacturing stuff and
 	
 	
 		oh no i don't think so either
 		i don't even know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> are actually doing it without an order i'm not too sure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> needs to order it although i guess they would have to in again mileage signs but uh it
 	
 	
 		well you know even even uh interstate signs and stuff you you can reprint the number of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">kilometers</NUMEX> on on that reflective uh stick on tape stuff that they use to uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh stick on those things and they can just all that's all they have to do i mean that wouldn't cost a great deal of money and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i i just don't see any problems with it i think it's just uh obstinate Americanism
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i think that i i guess it was uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> or more than when they it failed and i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just got tired of talking about it i'm not too sure i guess there was no one really pushing it and no one saying that it was going to mean business to us i think nowadays
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we all would say who are in industry and everything we'd say hey this means business we ought to
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> make everything metric and i just and i see no problem with it at all
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		exactly right i mean
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i i i can think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for instance you take a you take a textile industry and they're selling stuff by the by the yard
 		you know now now there's a big difference between a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a meter</NUMEX> when you're talking about fabric
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i don't
 	
 	
 		well i i i'm ready to convert i i we probably all thought it was strange you know again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> but i don't think there's that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with reservations anymore i don't know if uh
 	
 	
 		no i mean look at all the all the food containers are labeled uh with both systems i mean that's no problem
 	
 	
 		sure right
 		in fact they said it failed and then i guess it has failed but i in in general there was still a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i i i'm not sure it's a total <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">failure</ENAMEX> because so much has converted you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		and i'm not too sure that it's actually not a success more than a failure you know i don't know what percent has actually converted
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i just i just chock it up to this obstinate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americanism</ENAMEX> because
 		they sit there and and they just don't want to learn a new system you know it's just like they they won't learn foreign languages they go some you know they expect everybody to speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh you're absolutely right
 		you that that's a pet of mine too i just wish we all and us down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> of course should all speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we should have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six and eight years</TIMEX> automatically of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> and i i push my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh one is taking <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX> and one has taken <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> but not enough of it and uh i think we we down here especially should speak and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California New Mexico</ENAMEX> and all that really
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure i mean you you look around at all these other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i mean i mean you look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> not only do they learn the metric system they also learn the our system you know and and they also take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> languages
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		i mean well i mean it's no wonder that we're getting beat out on everything in the world because those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> those other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there are working
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah they're working they're out they're studying harder and they're working harder
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean look who's taking the the engineering jobs and the and the math jobs and the science jobs you know they're all Orientals
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean we've got loads of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> just like we do at every other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> around this country
 	
 	
 		yeah what are you taking in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> by the way you say you're in school
 	
 	
 		uh what am i taking uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master's</ENAMEX> in public administration
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh well you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s uh a well i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in college you know and uh who's got down at UT
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> i mean and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> also has gone back for a teaching and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> uh which is you know just teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are have have their native language and not English
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		and so she's going back for that and so i i i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'm supporting in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> now and i guess i ought to go back myself i'm getting enthusiastic because they they're having so much fun you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i i don't hold out much hope for anything coming out of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s i i'm taking it more or less just because i'm interested in it but i'm i'm also taking a uh paralegal course and i i really want to
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		do that more than anything else i i went to law school for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and a half
 		and uh decided well i don't really want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> i mean i knew that going in i just wanted a law degree because it would open all kinds of doors but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just too much work for a uh a degree you're going to hang on the wall and never use so i said well maybe i ought to save some money here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i got out of that and got back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master's</ENAMEX> and then decided well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX> is really the nuts and bolts of the law and that's what i really like yeah
 	
 	
 		sure politics and everything you ought to do what you like uh you i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and even when i was going through engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> halfway through they said up don't need any more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> we've got too many they go through this phase all the time but i think you still should do what you want because uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sure
 	
 	
 		if you're good at whatever you are you know and there's employment
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean
 		
 		
 	