
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well i just got back from taking my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownie</ENAMEX> meeting and then we had this whole can uh a bag filled full of cans and they've been recycling at their school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> she wanted me to just wait and let her dump them off tomorrow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they were filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> cans and i hated to take a big old sack i mean we're talking you know like a lawn bag full of them like i no we'll just taking them up there and put them in the bins anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they get tickets at their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that they recycle either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> or cans and i think that's all
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and they're taking the money that they earn to plant <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		yeah and they've got those bins that just stay there and they decorated them real cute you know with a bunch of big old <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they're getting into it i don't know what they get for the tickets though
 		what do you get for the tickets
 		if you bring stuff
 		oh the class i guess gets the most tickets gets uh gets a party
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so that's not bad yeah
 	
 	
 		that'd be good
 		um i know we
 		i already have them thanks
 		um we're we are kind of getting into recycling now i'm in college and i live in a dorm and we recycle paper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i know there's a glass <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> up here and they recycle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and you know we recycle aluminum cans and all that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		so in each of the dorms you have a place for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ah that's really good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and then when our dorm we whenever our bins are all filled up we take them and turn them in and then we get money for that
 	
 	
 		so
 		hm
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for the dorm and who decides what you do with it
 	
 	
 		yeah we just put you know we just keep it with the dorm
 	
 	
 		and what do they do with it
 	
 	
 		well we buy things for the dorm whatever the dorm needs you know like we have access to a microwave and an oven if we want to cook things and then we buy like cooking equipment and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or we play games like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> games we buy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> games you know it's just different things whatever you know would we vote on it and whatever the dorm would want that's what we buy
 	
 	
 		well
 		i graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> in nineteen seventy two
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we were just um not aware that this was a problem that we ever would need to recycle anything of course you just threw it away
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so a little different and i wanted to do this thing that you can get through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX> to recycle i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> said since we're doing this thing called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Operation Desert Shield</ENAMEX> we're sending letters to all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> and making video tapes and all this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for the whole school you know it was just this big project she didn't want to get into that and i could do it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and i just never got around to it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	

 		but it's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> you know about that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that had died of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX> i think and he was had started this um save the environment club
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is carrying this on and you can get the information to set it up you know or join you don't have to join it as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> or anything i don't guess but you could start your own anyway get a a pamphlet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that'd be good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 		is that what this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> is what you're
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do y'all have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> up there
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's a department store
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K Mart</ENAMEX> except it's a little better than what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K Mart</ENAMEX> sells i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh oh i was like  what's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX> what's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX> no um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know there's i don't really know any other recycling that they do
 	
 	
 		we
 		so you're not picking you're not having it picked up at your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> or anything yet
 	
 	
 		no we no huh-uh we have to take it to a a recycling place
 	
 	
 		huh
 		now in some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> around us they're already picking up the newspapers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well they're doing that here too now that i think about it
 		once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every so many weeks</TIMEX> and you have to pull out all the slicks and you have to wrap them up with string
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and
 		i think that's all they're picking up but you know like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> they've got those bins where you put your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> and your bottles
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		yeah because well my brother-in-law lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and they're just nice plastic bins and you fill them up and put them out with your other trash and they pick them up
 	
 	
 		um oh i never heard of that
 	
 	
 		so
 		do y'all have can banks
 	
 	
 		um not that i know of  no
 	
 	
 		no
 		it's just a big old bin and you just feed your cans slowly in through slot and your money comes out you know every once in a while for however much poundage you've got and you keep feeding it till the light goes off
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		and you get instant cash but they had one that i was putting my stuff in and i went to take some <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and it was gone
 		i don't know but i i located another one <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on the way to work
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah uh we have places where we go and we what we do is we unload our cans it's like a conveyor belt and the belt um separates the aluminum ones from the steel ones because of it has a magnet on it
 		and then they weigh all your aluminum cans and then you get money for your aluminum cans
 	
 	
 		but they don't give you for the other
 	
 	
 		no but now they're going to start giving us money for the other ones too
 	
 	
 		well that
 	
 	
 		before they didn't but i know they're going to start now
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well they're certain places you know where i know you can take your leaded cans but i don't know where they are they publish it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> if you wanted to get into it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		i'm trying but  i just can't recycle everything just not that dedicated
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah uh-huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		well that's all i really know about recycling
 	
 	
 		me too if they would oh i know we're saving
 		our grocery bags now
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah they're t aking those up you can take them to the stores
 		um like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kroger</ENAMEX>'s doing it
 		and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skaggs</ENAMEX> do you have those up there
 	
 	
 		we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kroger</ENAMEX> but not a Skaggs
 	
 	
 		and we they're taking our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk cartons</ENAMEX> and our plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Coke</ENAMEX> bottles there too
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		that's pretty good isn't it
 	
 	
 		you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are getting into it more than we are
 	
 	
 		it sounds like it you'd think you would be
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		huh-uh i've never seen any you know places that do i know um you we reuse our grocery bags now we take them back you you know and use the ones that we have
 		you can like if you have grocery bags you can take them and use them instead of getting new ones
 	
 	
 		you mean where you sack your own groceries
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but we don't have any place that collects the grocery bags
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">huh</ENAMEX> and i don't want to go with those canvas bags right now i'm sorry i'm not that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but you know they do that like i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> uh nineteen seventy three
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and every you know they go all the time i mean it's like they would go almost everyday to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and they had their little bags way back then and fill it up and they had this little bitty old teeny refrigerators
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		that's why i mean they couldn't put anything in it hardly
 		but
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		well what are you going to be when you get out of college
 	
 	
 		i'm a finance major
 	
 	
 		well that's why i started what i did i think i went into teaching
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's a real mess right now
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		oh definitely there's no what let's see we've had the funding we've run out of money we've frozen the money
 		right and they had until the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">fifteenth</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> to come up some formula that would be more equitable to districts different districts according to finances because the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> were getting less money so
 		not as good an education right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now they're trying to take some money away from the richer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> like the one that i'm in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and make us pay our money to the smaller ones and make it more equitable
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and if they can't come up with something by the fifteenth then the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s supposed to decide the courts
 	
 	
 		what do you think the outcome will be
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think they're gonna uh maybe give us a state income tax do you have one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we're not looking forward to it but something's got to be done
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah we've had one as long as i can remember
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		well it's going to hit us
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i don't know
 		it didn't doesn't seem like it would work to take it away when we're using it but maybe i know we're not using it so wisely
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in some of these big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> but other than that well can you think of anything else we need to talk about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um i can't think of anything on recycling
 	
 	
 		me either anything else
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> what do they think about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what do we think about them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i don't  no i never really thought about it  i have no clue what you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> think about Pennsylvanians
 	
 	
 		have you thought about that
 		
 
 		
 
 		um
 		probably a lot more civilized more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um</ENAMEX> refined than a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be down here
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i would hope so i mean you've been together a little bit longer than we have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there's some
 	
 	
 		i i don't know i really don't know anyone from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i've never been there hum-um
 	
 	
 		well i've never let's see i think i have too been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah we went up there
 		now that i think about it on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our long trips we take off on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		she'd be big i don't know  what are you saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holly</ENAMEX>
 		oh my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade and told me to tell you that shboom means good-bye in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> language
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is what you say it is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holly Israel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>  see she's got this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> that she's befriended
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so she's into this
 	
 	
 		oh well is it like a foreign exchange type student
 	
 	
 		huh-uh you know we've had a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> uh people
 		
 		
 	