
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Maureen</ENAMEX> uh could you tell me what type of uh dining out that you like to do
 	
 	
 		well we're probably different from you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> down here we're into uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tex-Mex</ENAMEX> or something like that that tends to be one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> is to go out to uh have some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food we have like um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Chico's</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> new place uh that's pretty good is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pappasito</ENAMEX>'s so when i go out and i like to splurge on eating i usually like to go out and get some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food and make sure there's a basket of chips keeps being  replenished on the table
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is that that's because you're you're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX> there and that's what you're used to you you've grown up that way
 	
 	
 		no i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> here actually um
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> originally and lived in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> for you know a good portion of time going to high school and college there so i've been down here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years</TIMEX> but uh
 		i don't know that's just something that i really picked up on i really did like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food the other thing i like i guess um i don't eat it as often is maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food we don't have as many places around here to eat <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food but um
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		yeah we've got a place down at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Providence</ENAMEX> that's
 		that's called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Hill</ENAMEX>
 		and it's all the old old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX>
 		and
 		they've got some real nice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> down there but what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we usually like to do is is go out and
 		and have something that we normally don't have at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like you can have uh naturally we've got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> up here you know and shellfish and because we live right on the coast
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but that's readily available and we can usually have that at home or we usually throw a steak on our on the grill or something
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but when we go out to to eat we like to go to a better restaurant i like i like jacket and tie um
 		you know when you go out to dine it's we kind of make a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we try to order something that
 		we don't usually
 		have around the house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and as far as um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> type we've got the only thing up here that we have anywhere close to that is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bell</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's not too close to the real thing
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what i say because i i just
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that i hate  you know and laser seminar that they had i don't know if you've seen the book
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then some of the local
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> down there they they took me out to all of these places you know and it's it's really uh
 		it's unique and i think i don't know if it's psychological or not but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> down there is out out of this world we we just don't get the quality up here like like you have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		where did you go for it
 		did you go like to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffbrau Steaks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no we went to uh uh
 		uh i we stayed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Plaza Park Suites</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park Suite</ENAMEX> yeah right across the street yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so we ate there <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> and then we went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picci</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> and had Italian you know where that is
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		over in um can't really
 		tell you what part of the what part of
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> it was in but it was it's supposedly known it was up by one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> anyhow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		and
 		that was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the week</TIMEX> and it was it was you had to wait in line to get in
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		like i said it was noted for you know it's food
 	
 	
 		and what was the name of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picci</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		um okay
 	
 	
 		and then uh oh no let's see i went someplace i can't remember the name of it some other place we went um
 		but we went to one
 		and they serve you i mean the hamburger was a pound of meat
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and the hamburger i know it was it was a huge loaf of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> i couldn't believe it
 		i thought if this is the size of a hamburger down here I'll order hamburger
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then we went to some fast food places that you know during during lunch we went out to some of those and it was good it was um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food i like the burritos and all that but i don't like the spice the hot i
 		i like it spicy but i don't like it i don't like it hot you know where you your
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		roof of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>'s blown off
 	
 	
 		last night we went out and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we were with she uh had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fajitas</ENAMEX> and she had this pepper on the plate and maybe she thought it was a sweet pepper but  it wasn't and she ate it and i was wondering why her eyes were watering
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		she and she had drank all her iced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> and she
 	
 	
 		right and and it doesn't make any difference either if you if you eat some of that stuff and you can drink a gallon and it doesn't seem to put out the fire but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that
 		me it it seems like i don't know how about you do you like the extremely hot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no no i i can maybe eat some jalapenos but i really don't you know ask for those on there i'm more like into the enchiladas and and stuff like that but no i don't really like it hot
 		um i remember meeting somebody <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX> before i ever moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and he put hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> on everything he ate i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tabasco's</ENAMEX> and that kind of stuff on everything he ate i think he must've just had a a stomach that was iron or something
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah yeah that's incredible that and um
 		i'm afraid to take the chance when i go down there
 		to eat a meal like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because once you get it what are you going to do with it if it if it's too hot
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i'm not sure if
 		you know if
 		when they cook down there if they automatically just do that they throw a couple of red peppers in it and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know in the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>
 		because that's what they're used to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and up here we're not really well some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are i guess up here i mean they'll eat fire
 		but i'm just not i'm not i don't mind the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> i love garlic and all the rest of that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the hot stuff oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and that's all you mainly do t hen right <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> how about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well those are my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> favorites
 	
 	
 		yeah you go out for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		you know
 		uh yeah yeah there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> favorite place that we have called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Moon</ENAMEX> that's that's pretty good and uh i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing on the menu that i really love but um we don't
 		do that probably as often we used to do a a quick take out kind of place that wasn't real great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> but we used to do we just liked vegetable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fried rice</ENAMEX> quite a bit
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		just you know as a quick kind of dinner thing that's you know it's not real filling but you know get some veggies and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> and stuff every once in a while we go out to a little bit nicer <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> place
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's what we'll do we'll take some we'll take take out like sometimes on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> um like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef teriyaki</ENAMEX> or or chicken fingers or that type of thing uh egg rolls
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or fried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> because it's easier to get out than to make it
 		uh we'll do that occasionally um do you go out as much now
 		as uh
 		because the economy being
 		such has that
 		put a damper on you or does it make any difference
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well recently we've both been trying to do some diet so we haven't gone out because when they tell you about how much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX> is in all that food you know it really kind of crimps your style there but um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we probably you know maybe go out like once a week on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> usually with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or something we kind of go out um not always you know sometimes we cook the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> at home and have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but i haven't really thought about you know the economy all that much and and eating out we we never really did it a lot but
 		you know we do maybe go out a couple of times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> at least to eat out
 	
 	
 		yeah you know up here it's it's the restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> has fallen off
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh pretty substantially because the the unemployment rate is pretty high
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's uh
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost ten</NUMEX> percent now
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have the discretionary incomes that they had you know overtime has been cut back a lot in certain areas
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but us i mean we still we live more or less like you and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are grown up and they're gone so it's just the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us and uh
 		we tend to go out maybe once a week maybe once every other week something like that but we'll we'll go out for uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh take out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and bring it home
 		um but it hasn't it hasn't it uh it hasn't stopped us yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was just wondering down there it hasn't done anything to you either so your economy is a little bit better though i think down there now
 	
 	
 		well though you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has laid off quite a few in this area and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Dynamics</ENAMEX> has its woes too so that it seems like there's been
 	
 	
 		well
 		oh okay so there's
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> recently you know when big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> uh change their programs and and such that
 		there's been an influx of some unemployed but probably when you spread it out over everybody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it maybe has not changed the percentage all that much
 		you know maybe one or two percent possibly it's hard to say
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it just seems like a lot when you hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that keep continually advertising or stating that they're you know you know cutting out so many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> it sounds like big numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and it depends on life styles too down there i'm not sure if
 		you all tend to go out more down there than we do up here or or if we tend to go out more
 	
 	
 		i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down here must shop for entertainment because we have more shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> within close proximity i mean  it's like we could have shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> even across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from each other
 		there must be a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with a lot of money who just like to go out and shop because we have plentitude of shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> within like a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five mile</NUMEX> radius i
 		
 		
 	