
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		so uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Deanna</ENAMEX> where do you like to fish
 	
 	
 		well we usually go fishing at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toledo Bend</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> uh i i usually don't do too much fishing i usually take my raft and float along behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and get a suntan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh great great
 	
 	
 		but they love to crappie <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> likes to bass fish so um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		what what do you what do you use for bait for crappie and bass
 	
 	
 		for crappie they use shiners
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um bass my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> usually puts a jig or something like that on there for it or a top water bait you know sometimes usually artificial bait for bass
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then um we sometimes get crickets and they they fish for bream
 		and
 	
 	
 		i've never used crickets before do you use them live
 	
 	
 		yeah you haven't
 	
 	
 		what you put put the hooks through their little back and they just jump around under the water
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and and and what are crickets good for
 	
 	
 		bream
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">brim um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and um also they have these uh wasp
 		the the um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">larvae</ENAMEX> is that what it's called wasp wasp larvae
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh oh anytime we can find those my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> just scoop up on those because they are so good for fishing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um they use those a lot but usually it's either shiners or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh just a minute i got to see who that is
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		so anyway uh uh do you ever  fish for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no we usually don't do i mean they catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> i keep saying they because i never fish but um
 		they catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> you on accident sometimes
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and then whenever we do trot lines and stuff they usually get catfish
 	
 	
 		are they are they big ones
 	
 	
 		um uh
 		usually not too big probably maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> pounds you know i've seen some huge catfish
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah i think you have to go deep for those don't you though
 		don't they kind of just kind of scavenge along the bottom of of wherever they are
 	
 	
 		the bottom yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah uh what what kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> do y'all have
 	
 	
 		well we used to just have a little aluminum boat but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> has sold it so he's hunting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> now i think he's looking into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bass</ENAMEX> Tracker
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he found him one <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> that he really liked but we haven't gotten it yet so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah well we don't have a boat we usually fish off the shore or off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> and my i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> that's a senior in high school and he just loves he loves fishing i i don't have the patience that he does
 	
 	
 		well
 		oh i agree
 	
 	
 		uh you know it's it's sitting there on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> and you go <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a hour</NUMEX> and nothing's happened he says no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> i know they're down there let's not go i know they're down there and they're and they're gonna bite anytime and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 		
 
 		we're talking about fishing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> daddy
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh he got into a place where uh we were in there where there was a bunch of sand bass schooling and my goodness
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		he was throwing this was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day last summer</TIMEX> and he every as often as he could throw that hook out there he'd get one but we don't deplete the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> because we pull them up and look at them admire them and take them off and throw them back
 		although he went somewhere with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and fished for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX>
 		and got them and i think it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that he's ever that he's actually prepared and ate what they caught he and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of his the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time they've ever done anything but throw them back
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but uh we we you know we we started with just rudimentary things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worms</ENAMEX> and night crawlers and uh and uh uh gone to uh minnows and can catch just a lot of sandies or even <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> with minnows
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and we take we fish at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> Texoma
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and and then and then just kind of stop there on the way by and get the uh and and get the and get minnows and uh
 		it's it's pretty lot of fun except i say you got to have a lot of patience because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> it doesn't seem like anything's down there at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then other other days uh
 		uh you you can pull them in with some degree of regularity it seems as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> comes when it gets warm and you have calm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> without a lot of wind they seem to be uh far more prevalent
 	
 	
 		well i just do not have the patience for it but i mean we usually um keep our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> that are right size you know that are a good eating size because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> love to eat fish but
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		um the little ones we throw back or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> will bring them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and put them in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> tank
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		throw throw them back and let them get bigger so you can come get them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and catch them next time yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know at at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texoma</ENAMEX> it's such a big lake and we don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> but we're on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in there's a lot of sandy islands out in the middle of Texoma
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they go out and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> around there and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in with these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice chests</ENAMEX> just full of of you know <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve fourteen sixteen eighteen inch long</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		it's the darndest thing i've ever seen and i don't know we we're probably going to have to get us a boat one of these days soon and go out and see go out and see what's really out there
 	
 	
 		they are so expensive
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i know they are i used to have one that we used to ski ski behind
 	
 	
 		oh i love to ski
 	
 	
 		and and before our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> came along my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i used to ski all the time then when the and we kept it on it was an eighteen footer it was kind of big to haul over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> so we kept it at a lake tied up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are very little you can't go out and do things like that and it got so the insurance and the and the uh and the tie up fee uh was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		gigantic compared to what use we were getting out of it
 		so i went and sold it and never bought again and it's too bad now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> they want they'd love to get out there and learn to ski and do the boating and fishing again so we'll probably do something like that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		do you do you camp at the lake a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah we um we usually do probably usually in the springtime or in the fall in the summer
 	
 	
 		but not in the summer
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer time</TIMEX>'s a little too hot
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		um we usually go pitch a tent and we stay out there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> or um for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> matter of fact i think we're going to go again in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the middle of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> we're uh planning a trip down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toledo Bend</ENAMEX> and sometimes we rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		oh
 		um-hum where where is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toledo Bend</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		it's between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> border
 	
 	
 		oh okay it's uh it's on that s ide it's on the east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">east</ENAMEX> side what's what's the nearest big city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um  daddy</ENAMEX> what's the nearest big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toledo Bend</ENAMEX>
 		this lake's huge i mean
 	
 	
 		it's huge yeah and i was i is it out like near <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler or Texarkana</ENAMEX> or Parish
 	
 	
 		he says its exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> way between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shreveport</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay exactly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> way between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shreveport</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> um how how long does it take you to get there from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shreveport</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's
 		um it usually takes us we  it takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX> for us to get there daddy
 		yeah and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> will meet us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> way since he works you you know he lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> he usually meets us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> way and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		do you work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shreveport</ENAMEX> or go to school or what
 	
 	
 		i go to school i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSU</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh what are you majoring in
 	
 	
 		communications
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness i have been on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSU</ENAMEX> campus once i took a recruiting trip for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> there about uh uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or nine years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i was oh i was ever so impressed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> in fact it was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two day</TIMEX> trip and between appointments i got a chance to walk around and see it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh what a what a fabulous darn school it was i was just really really impressed with it
 	
 	
 		well gosh thanks
 	
 	
 		and and i know it's getting off the subject a little bit but i i do you follow a lot of the sports at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSU</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i sure do i try to i mean um
 	
 	
 		okay well we're we're we're very strong uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> fans
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so we we follow your <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> a lot and
 	
 	
 		well great
 		yeah i i also try to follow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech Louisiana Tech</ENAMEX> the
 	
 	
 		yeah your oh of course they are one of the best uh they didn't do as well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> but we saw them we went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and saw them beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longhorns</ENAMEX> in the regionals
 	
 	
 		yeah they are
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they were  i guess they went to the final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and and didn't make it through but we were just uh uh just really impressed with them what what year are you in at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSU</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i am almost a junior  after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this semester</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> i'll be a junior
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and what do you plan on doing when you get out
 	
 	
 		uh i want to be a cruise director
 	
 	
 		oh gee what a deal on like on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Boat huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah kind of i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX> that's a neat thing
 	
 	
 		um i'd like to do that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> and then whenever i get settled down i would like to go back and teach college i'd like to be a professor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		are you you then plan on maybe getting an advanced degree somewhere
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm gonna um go ahead and go straight in and get my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s degree
 	
 	
 		oh at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSU</ENAMEX> you gonna stay there
 	
 	
 		no i'm gonna go to uh i'm gonna send check into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		because they have a um special program a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s program where i can get my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master's</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		what would it take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about thirty hours</TIMEX> or something like that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two thirty six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty six</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		okay so that would be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two long semesters</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> maybe huh
 	
 	
 		um-hum it i mean it's going to take a lot of hard work but um you need
 	
 	
 		yeah okay
 		oh sure sure well i think i think uh uh the best thing to do is i i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> Masters degrees but they both came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if i had it to do all over again i would do what you're planning to do like continue
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you need to get it while you're still hot
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's what everybody has said because once you get out and make that money it's so hard to get back into it
 	
 	
 		it it is it is very hard to go back and
 		and actually the academic part isn't bad when your when you resume because it seems that things come easier because you're more mature and you've got all your life experiences and i thought the academic part would be harder but it really isn't
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because uh it because uh uh i don't know i think the maturity factor uh uh overcomes the fact that you've had a gap
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but nevertheless it's it's so much it's so hard to get back to it and it's it's so much easier while you've got your academic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juices</ENAMEX> flowing
 	
 	
 		well what were what are your degrees in
 	
 	
 		i have uh my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one's in my <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bachelor's in Chemistry</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master's</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physics</ENAMEX> and in uh in Management uh uh uh quality management i've been in i've been in quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and and uh
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 		
 		
 	