
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrd</ENAMEX> Call

            The papers lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Byrd</ENAMEX>'s announcement that he'll make a
motion to dismiss <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment trial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrd</ENAMEX>, described in the usual way as the silver-haired, all-but-marbled
repository of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Constitutional</ENAMEX> wisdom and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> prerogatives," was
basically just counting votes. He said that there weren't enough to convict,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> weren't going to change anything. But as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> puts it, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrd</ENAMEX> has been one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s
toughest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal, and virtually
every scenario for convicting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has included the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">81-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>
Virginian defecting from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were disappointed.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> gave prominent play to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>'s frustrated riposte
from the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>: "You're saying, I guess, that perjury's okay if
it's about sex, that obstruction is okay...."

Times and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrd</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bombshell</ENAMEX> in the context of
moves by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of both parties to get things over with. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> should hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and
adjourn the trial, letting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> vote stand as "the highest form of
condemnation." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead says that the impeachment case "appeared to
lose significant ground." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> appeared hungrier
than ever for a graceful exit from a potentially prolonged trial."

            No one predicts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrd</ENAMEX>'s motion will pass. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> main story is
the clearest about how the surprise announcement was made, in a press release
distributed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>.

            There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> key subordinate trial stories. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> lead
(and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> story; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ran it inside) details a
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subplot</ENAMEX>, complete with a walk-on by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> want a
tete-a-tete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, but she won't talk to them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> say she doesn't want to help "either side." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> called in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> to make her; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late yesterday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> asked a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> district court to revoke
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s immunity agreement if she doesn't play ball with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hyde and Co. Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Holloway Johnson</ENAMEX> will decide over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>.

            The other story addresses how the trial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> progressed. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> segue into it after the big Byrd news; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
offers its usual <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Apple</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Chamber</ENAMEX>" report. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> enjoy the
oddness of the proceeding, wherein <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX>, forbidden to speak, had to submit
written queries to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> through their party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. But all
agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> used the opportunity almost exclusively to lob softball
questions, some of them prearranged.

            Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few weeks</TIMEX> a story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> has rarely been
complete without a reference to the zeal with which he enforces time limits on
oral arguments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. (He's often described as cutting attorneys
off "mid syllable" when the clock runs out.) The papers, with perhaps a bit of
disappointment, note his uncharacteristic laxness on this point as he presided
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> of questioning that was supposed to consist of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX>
responses. The first answer went on for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine minutes</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has a perhaps-too-friendly story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>, who's
visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>: "To understand the significance of this pontiff, it helps to
see him through his own eyes, and measure him by the yardstick of church
history." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is more probing about his effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>'s
infrastructure in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>. He wiped out the liberation theology movement,
which had enlivened the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, particularly by attracting new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX>. Now
they're low on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>, and capitalism stands rampant, with its attendant onus
on the poor. A gently critical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed piece by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jorge G. Castaneda</ENAMEX> makes the same point.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> see the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> scandal spreading past <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>
and touching <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summer</TIMEX>'s games in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>. The papers report that gifts from
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> may
have tipped the balance in a close vote that saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australians</ENAMEX> beat out
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> by but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> votes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> limns the pampered lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, who jet around the world in first-class comfort, accumulating
largess in the form of medical treatment, college tuition, and slick land
deals. Most amusing example: the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, a budding concert <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX> with a knack for scoring high-profile gigs
in upcoming sites for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Games</ENAMEX>.

            From the footnote-to-history <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> comes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">estate</ENAMEX>'s campaign to be compensated for papers taken by the
government after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> resigned. The estate is asking for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$210 million</NUMEX>,
counting accrued interest. Specifically, it wants <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX> for a confiscated
file of telegrams and letters sent in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s famous "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Silent</ENAMEX>
Majority" speech. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Butterfield</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> who stunned <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> with news of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s taping system <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter of a century ago</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> testified that the massive response to the speech was fabricated.
This was known already, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> doesn't say so. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butterfield</ENAMEX>,
now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">72</TIMEX> and sporting a watch with a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> on
it, has the details. He said he enlisted help before the speech from labor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Casey</ENAMEX>, and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. Ross Perot</ENAMEX>, who said he'd bring a
locomotive full of mail into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Station</ENAMEX>. "He did generate a lot of mail,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butterfield</ENAMEX> is quoted saying. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">locomotive</ENAMEX> never materialized.

         
      
   
