
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gloating Rights Act</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the issues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> must soon resolve to
complete its impeachment trial. The situation is also flagged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box. With conviction
and removal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> almost surely off the table, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>,
stress will instead be on: whether or not to call any of the already deposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> for questioning, whether or not to release to
the public the videotapes of their depositions, and whether or not to vote on
findings of fact in the case or on a formal censure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> instead.
Although support for these choices play out largely along party lines, the
papers note that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> support for the choices that make life more
complicated for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has flagged somewhat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the nationwide gas wars, caused by an oil glut and petroleum
industry improvements. The upshot: the national average price of a gallon of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> is now <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">97.9 cents</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 cents</NUMEX> below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> and the lowest since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>.
Adjusted for inflation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, gas prices are the lowest in
history.

            On the impeachment front, despite the handwriting on the wall, there are
still plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> strolling the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> with ink remover.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a letter signed by him and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caucus</ENAMEX>, for a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, requesting that the president
make himself available for a deposition. But even that letter stated that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> would not attempt to compel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to testify.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> sign that there really is light now at the end of the impeachment tunnel
is that according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> expect to lose on their
request for live testimony. Another: according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> acknowledged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> pep rally on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Lawn</ENAMEX>
immediately after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was impeached provoked many in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and promised
that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is not convicted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> would be a "gloat-free zone."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has this too, explicitly crediting the quote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockhart</ENAMEX>.

            An LAT front-pager and a story inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of onetime <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> intimate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gezillionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Berezovsky</ENAMEX> (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> headline calls him the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rasputin</ENAMEX>" of the current scene), were raided
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> by government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> on the trail of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berezovsky</ENAMEX>'s political espionage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the raid uncovered evidence of tapped phone
conversations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.

            An inside story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> piggybacks on a story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> amassing strong evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX>, a leading congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doubter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s truthfulness under oath, said under oath in a civil case that he was
not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> pest control <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> even though at about the same
time he reported to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Hill</ENAMEX> , has turned
up evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> made further misstatements about the amount of money he
was drawing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and also about the amount of speaking fees he
received.

            The USAT front reports that in response to rising passenger "air
rage" over poor airline <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>, a bipartisan bill, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airline Passenger</ENAMEX>
Fairness Act" will be introduced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. Oddly, the story
doesn't say what rights will thereby be protected, although presumably they
won't include the right to intestinally offload onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX> cart (an actual
incident).

            An inside story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that the gay oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocate</ENAMEX> , reports that a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> who was pseudonymously the subject of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> appeared in several gay pornographic films
while he was on active duty. (He had not, says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s story, informed the
magazine of this.) The story doesn't explore whether this fact would be grounds
for dismissal under the present "don't ask, don't tell" policy. Which is too
bad, since it's actually an interesting test case. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> is completely
circumspect in his military life and makes every effort to disguise his
involvement in explicitly gay-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX>-oriented activities to the point of using a
pseudonym, etc., in what sense is he "telling"?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s coverage of the impending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> actions on impeachment includes a
journalism tic that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> deplores. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tonight</ENAMEX>, in an effort to put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> in an awkward position , more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to ask him to voluntarily
testify in the trial." The italicized motive-attributing phrase (italics added)
is completely unsupported in the story. And therefore shouldn't be there. The
telltale sign that such phrases represent the illicit smuggling into a story of
a political opinion is that just below this the story continues, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> has steadfastly said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would not take such a step and
instantly rejected the proposal." Forget the slight note of character build-up
that comes with "steadfastly," but please do notice that this sentence does not
read, "In order to make <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> look bad, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has..."

         
      
   
