
   
   
      
         
            Takedown Ticktock

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> putting diplomatic
pressure on both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to accept a peace
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">accord</ENAMEX> regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> before a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> deadline, while making
preparations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX> in case they don't. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
doesn't front <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, its lead instead illustrating another step <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is
taking from an investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of investigation
with the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> is considering appointing a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> to
inquire into charges of misconduct by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
fronts neither story and leads instead with word that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> will
propose new emissions standards that would require <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivans</ENAMEX>, light <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>, and
most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUVs</ENAMEX> to run as clean as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>. The new rules, says the paper, could
add considerably to sticker price.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> explains that the principal stumbling block to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
agreement is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>, remains
opposed to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> soil. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> spoke to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> on the phone
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, telling him that airstrikes would hit his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> hard. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> is thought to be targeting military communications sites
and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the planned airstrikes would be the "biggest
projection of military power" since a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>-led peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> moved into
Bosnia <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than three years ago</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't explain if this means
just in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> of operations, or if it would also be bigger than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">raids</ENAMEX> recently conducted against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> points out that it was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> bombing that helped force <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to sign the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Dayton</ENAMEX> peace accords that
ended the fighting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>.

            From the reporting, it's a little hard to understand the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> thinking on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s role in all this. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> saying she was
hopeful that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> would participate in any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and that
she believed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> was delivering a message to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> as tough as the one
she delivered to him. But, as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also reports
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> not to stage any airstrikes, and
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> would stand by its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slavic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">brethren</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT front goes long with a fascinating blow-by-blow on the
capture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX> over the byline of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Boudreaux</ENAMEX>, with the
assistance of such stalwarts as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John-Thor Dahlburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Kempster</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>. The story flatly asserts the involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>, and strongly suggests advance
knowledge if not the full cooperation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>. Perhaps the
biggest news of the piece is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s presence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> was first
detected, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> after he arrived, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> still there as part of the
investigation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>'s bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> independently became aware of his presence shortly thereafter.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager covers the nearly tax-free status of cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, a scandal first widely publicized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Barlett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Steele</ENAMEX>
in their celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia Inquirer</ENAMEX> series on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s economic
disparities in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Went Wrong?</ENAMEX>". For instance, reports the
Times , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnival Corporation</ENAMEX>, larger than many Fortune 500 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX> while paying less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> in
income tax. This virtual immunity from tax, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , as well
as similar insulation against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s labor, safety, and environmental
laws, is enjoyed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all 17</NUMEX> major cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lines</ENAMEX> because they are registered in
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, even though their base of operations is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
percent of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> has refused a
request from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> to use a clip from its movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Full Metal Jacket</ENAMEX>" in a
training CD-ROM about how to survive sniper attacks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> based its
refusal on "serious piracy" concerns. In other words, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burbank</ENAMEX> helping
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> stay alive runs a distant <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to squeezing out every last licensing
dollar. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> should remember that the next time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> comes asking
for technical assistance on a picture (as it no doubt did on "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Full Metal</ENAMEX>
Jacket").

         
      
   
