
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> continue milking impeachment for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leads</ENAMEX>. The
LAT sounds the "temporary unity" theme for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, while the WP
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exhaustively</ENAMEX> reviews the legal and political minutiae surrounding the upcoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> relegates impeachment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead and
instead turns to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, the old standby, to explain the creative ways states
are spending the windfall from their victorious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco lawsuit.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> emphasizes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s apparent unity of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> could
easily crumble when it comes time for the decision on whether to call
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. The paper quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX> as putting the odds of a
continuing trial at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">60:40</TIMEX>, but she warns, "If [the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>] vote to
continue, then they're going down a very treacherous path." Already, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Times</ENAMEX> , fault lines are surfacing among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Younger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> lean toward opting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, while older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> favor a
quick cessation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> forecasts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial will either be a
"tedious rehashing of the existing evidence" or "a full <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>-style
spectacle." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> delves into the legal what-ifs of the trial,
including such momentous issues as whether "antiquated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> rules" permit
television monitors on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor. An accompanying WP front-pager
explores the disillusionment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> with their party; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX>
especially are disaffected by the rabid pursuit of impeachment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
off-lead weighs in with the renewed importance of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost</NUMEX>-dusty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>, which will serve as the conveyor for much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> evidence.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $246 billion</NUMEX> dividend owed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX> is going to a slate of random causes such as sidewalk
repair and paying off state debts--oh yeah, and health and anti-smoking
programs too. The amount of intake varies from state to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $25 billion</NUMEX> each, while smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billion</ENAMEX>--although exact amounts are not fully determined because the federal
government, as a major contributor to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> services, is wrangling
for its fair share of the dividend. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> for cash well-spent may go to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, which are considering using their dividends to aid
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>.

            An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" piece explains why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sicilian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> thumbs its nose at the "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX>":
It's a matter of definition. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX>, while real and dangerous, is
utterly amorphous in contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX>, which boasts tight
hierarchical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 10 to 20 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> is composed
of "organized crime." <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">The other 80-90 percent</NUMEX> is a broad swathe of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX>, government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">industrialists</ENAMEX>--in short, the rest
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> both run pieces on the newly released transcripts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> conversing with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. While the soberly analytical WP
comments that the transcripts show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX> shared technology with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
earlier than thought, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> submits to the pure fun of the tape
excerpts. "Scene: a meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> . . . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissinger</ENAMEX>]
doesn't look like a secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>. He is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in captivity who could go
to Paris <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> times and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Peking</ENAMEX> once and no one knew it except possibly a couple
of pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chou En</ENAMEX>-lai laughs.) . . . Anyone who uses
pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> as a cover must be the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> of all time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mao</ENAMEX> {who had
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">concubines</ENAMEX>): So your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are very often made use of? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>,
not mine. It would get me great trouble if I used <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> as a cover. Chou
(laughing): Especially during elections."

         
      
   
