
   
   
      
         
            Eyes Shut

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with what it foresees as imminent renewed political
and economic turmoil in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the continuing rise in cable rates even as the medium approaches
near-total deregulation. Relying on a confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>'s report, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with an exclusive, claiming
that the newest federal edifice in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>
building, is quite vulnerable to terrorist attack. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with a forecast that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> severe late-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow storms</ENAMEX> will hit
much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rocky Mountains</ENAMEX>, while tornadoes will hit
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> may see yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> shake-up as it faces
a cash crunch in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, when it's scheduled to begin making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.6 billion</NUMEX> in
foreign debt payments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de</ENAMEX> facto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> so often in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, has made
getting more loans from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> his primary economic objective rather than
substantive economic reform. But, of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> would like to see some
reform before ponying up more money. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is
"largely incapacitated," he would get involved in loan talks with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> if he
thought it necessary.

            Whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead's headline says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is "amid crisis," a
Wall Street Journal front-page feature runs under
the header: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Resilient Russia Dodges Calamities Predicted After Ruble</ENAMEX>'s
Collapse." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> goes high with the claim by a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> that
"doomsday was a wrong estimation of what would happen, and what will happen."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> enumerates some of the things it says have nonetheless not
yet finished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> off: Average wages down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> have lost their jobs (since when?) and the ruble is off by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX>. But with imports now priced out of the market, domestic production
is on the rise in some industries and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s trade surplus is up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-fold
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from the beginning of last year</TIMEX>. Which helps explain why GDP isn't falling as
fast as was forecast, and why the stock market is "stirring." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
entrenched barter economy means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can press on regardless of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>' ability to pay in cash.

            Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Telecommunications Act of 1996</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports, cable rates have climbed overall <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 22 percent</NUMEX>--more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times the rate of inflation. What's happened, as if you didn't know,
is that while cable price controls came off, much of the expected
competition--such as satellites and wireless cable--hasn't materialized yet.
The result threatens to be what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> is quoted as calling "an
unregulated monopoly."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing, the
government's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> in charge of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> has been warned repeatedly
about risks posed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan Building</ENAMEX>'s large underground garage
and unrestricted entrances. But, says the paper, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> opened
with huge cost overruns, there has been tremendous reticence to create a strong
visible security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">presence</ENAMEX> that would cut down on revenue by discouraging the
public from visiting the retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and convention facilities
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Note: like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that was destroyed by
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck bomb</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> houses a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">day-care center</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front the death <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>,
apparently from natural causes at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 70</TIMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>. Kubrick, was, the
papers note, obsessed with control and detail (in a career spanning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 50</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, he made only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> features) and was one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> commercial directors
to wrest artistic control of his pictures away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>. According to
the coverage, he completed his last movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eyes Wide Shut</ENAMEX> , about sexual
obsession and starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX>, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Media Talk"</ENAMEX> column reports that recently, shortly after the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Journalism Review</ENAMEX> ran a piece by a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
criticizing her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX> cost-cutting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX> chain
pulled all its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> advertising from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AJR</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fox Butterfield</ENAMEX> writes that a new DOJ study indicates that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">carjacking</ENAMEX> is far more prevalent than most crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> had thought--the crime
occurs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 49,000</NUMEX> times a year. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About half</NUMEX> of these involved use of a gun,
and in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX> of them the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> was injured. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butterfield</ENAMEX> notes that the
trend appears to illustrate several unintended consequences of
get-tough-on-crime developments. With the advent of major improvements in car
locks and security systems, unattended locked <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> became much harder to steal,
and drug-related forfeiture programs gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> an incentive to not be
caught by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. A separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> item reports that
an attempt to rob her at a bank ATM and gave the police a getaway car license
plate that directly led to the arrest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> in the crime.

            
               Still not a clue, though. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the rabidly
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> legal foundation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial Watch</ENAMEX> now has its own online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>,
where you can buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial Watch</ENAMEX> report or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judicial Watch</ENAMEX> baseball cap.

         
      
   
