
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX> Class Troublemaker

            Everybody leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> who are making the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> all say that the meeting produced no explosive new information.
Yet there is no agreement about what that dictates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, who sat
in on the interview, say this means she shouldn't be called to testify. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> say the opposite. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that the
questioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> did not include pressing her on any sexual details. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says this was by "prearrangement."
Instead, the talk homed in on the obstruction of justice evidence--in
particular, say all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>, the circumstances surrounding the transfer of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s presidential gifts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
cite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> each (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> identifies him/her as "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> familiar
with the session" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with "a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> at the
interview) saying that yesterday <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>'s pick-up of the
gifts could have occurred later than she previously testified, and hence after
the much-talked-about cell call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> made to her. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> makes it
clear though that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> familiar with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s meeting say that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> made no significant change in her account. And indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
lead says straightaway that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> that she stands by
her previous testimony that no one ever asked her to lie about her affair with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and that she was never offered a job for her silence.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report without any
evident irony that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> interview took place in the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayflower Hotel</ENAMEX>, and note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> a night. None of the
papers says, however, who picked up the tab. Was this congressional
gravy-sucking or defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> gravy-sucking? Or both?

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> exclusive, based on an interview with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s,
provides these nuggets: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> cried herself to sleep <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> upon
learning that she had to come back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> for more questioning; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) She
suffered the "indignity" of discovering that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> had reserved but not
paid for her flight in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. So, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , she and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> purchased her first-class seat. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The insignia "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TSG</ENAMEX>" that appeared on
the baseball cap <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was wearing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> pictures of her
stands for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Shooting Gallery</ENAMEX>, an independent film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
works for. No word on whether the ball cap was part of a product placement
deal.

            The press consensus is that despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s er, re-insertion, the
prospects for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> case <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> winning the right to call her or
anyone else as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> are dubious--indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says they're
"gloomy." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> might take a vote on findings of fact
relevant to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> impeachment articles and then take a separate vote on the
articles themselves. The point of this, the paper quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>
explaining, would be to separate the question of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did from the
question of whether what he did is impeachable. On this latter question, the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page weighs in with a
bit of historical research. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claims that the most authoritative source
on the common law known to those who wrote and ratified <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Constitution</ENAMEX>
includes in its list of "high misdemeanors" that can be committed by those
serving the public trust, both "obstructing the execution of lawful process"
and "willful and corrupt perjury."

            Everybody fronts the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Samaranch</ENAMEX>, apologized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> for the site-selection corruption
scandal currently swirling around the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>, and suspended <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> members
implicated in it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> has surprising news about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>: Despite being a country
that appears to offer its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> little in the way of options or futures, it
does have a stock market. And, more surprising still, it's doing pretty well.
Primarily because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> can't see things getting much worse and also
believe the economy-strangling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> sanctions are bound to be lifted someday,
the market's index is up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">900 percent</NUMEX> since its inception in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a story inside reporting that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">82.9 percent</NUMEX> of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX> say they are using the Internet for research
or homework. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> then points out what it calls a great disparity in
computer mastery between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at elite private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80.1</NUMEX>
percent say they use computers regularly) and those attending traditionally
black public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41.1 percent</NUMEX>). The story goes on to quote two
academics explaining that the results augur a new and widening inequity between
"haves and have nots." But before too much redistributive social policy gets
made around such results, it might be good to add a question to the survey: "Do
you have a luxury sound system or a car <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two years old</TIMEX>, or a luxury
sound <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>?" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX> recalls being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual spring</TIMEX> break for traditionally black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freaknik</ENAMEX>,"
and being amazed at the numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' hot <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and loud stereos. Any
computer/Internet paucity among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> attending traditionally black colleges
may be a function of their own interests and choices rather than of
affordability.

         
      
   
