
   
   
      
         
            Slavia: You Go

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the tense fallout from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s massacre of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Racak</ENAMEX>,
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s expulsion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Walker</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
diplomat heading up the international peace-monitoring mission in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> had blamed the massacre on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , which fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walker</ENAMEX> toss-out, leads instead with yet another
sneak of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address, to be delivered
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will, says the paper, echoing reporting previously in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , propose funding most of his social policy goals, from school
construction to long-term care for the elderly, through targeted tax breaks
rather than through new spending. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> adds to the list of leaked
speech provisions with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s tips that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will ask for more money for
aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> to help contain the threat that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> might fall
into the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>, and will endorse a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX> tax credit for
stay-at-home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column gives a clue to the
need for the latter proposal by reporting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under age three</TIMEX> held jobs, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
which also fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, leads with a story comboing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOTU</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
still-stratospheric job approval ratings, and the beginning of his formal
impeachment defense <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s latest poll (of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,009</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>) indicates
that more than eighty percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s presidency is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>, although <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 24 percent</NUMEX> view him as honest and trustworthy.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> coverage mentions that in addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> being expelled,
the chief war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> for the region, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX>, was turned away by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> when she tried to make her way to the massacre site. It's
the consensus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> that the cease-fire brokered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last October</TIMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> is no more. And indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> cites an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> report of a
post-massacre ambush of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX>, who saw some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Racak</ENAMEX>, as saying the killings were a crime against humanity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
front shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> on display in a village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mosque</ENAMEX> with shrouds over their
heads, where they were apparently shot at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close</NUMEX> range. The papers report that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> forcibly removed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>, to conduct their own
autopsies, which means in all likelihood that international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> will
never be able to confirm what actually happened.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX> of violating his
mandate as head of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700</NUMEX> or so international cease-fire monitors, and both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> carry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walker</ENAMEX>'s remarks condemning the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> for the
killings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also carries <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker</ENAMEX>'s condemnation, but also quotes
him making this odd concession: "Maybe we went beyond the limits [of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX>'s mandate], and that's why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is mad at us."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> has warned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> that he had better take seriously the warnings made
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that warning stopped short of reviving
plans for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> remarks were a "final warning" to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to comply with the cease-fire.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> airstrikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> last
month rattled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> and showed that his system of control and intimidation is
less impregnable than previously feared and weakened his support among his
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protectors</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Guards</ENAMEX>. Now's the time therefore, he
writes, to "really rattle his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX>." He offers such suggestions as turning up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Free Iraq</ENAMEX> extra loud, and having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> declare <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> a war criminal.
And one can't help but think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> was also making a suggestion by passing
along what he's heard about what really happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> when he
died suddenly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> slipped him poison during a tryst,
perhaps by putting it in his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story says that there is a serious crowding problem at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> that has
prompted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Service</ENAMEX> to propose a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> overhaul. The unfolding of
the story shows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is just a little too credulous about the need
for this spending. Examples of "worsening congestion and strain" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House the Post</ENAMEX> cites include: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Storage</ENAMEX> space is so scarce that items for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday decorations</ENAMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX> roll are kept elsewhere"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">; "And</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">China Room</ENAMEX>, where the presidential china is on display, doubles as a coat
room for state dinners"; and "The florists were forced to open boxes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>
on a table set up in the corridor."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has apparently adopted a breakthrough innovation that
enables it to get copy into the paper faster: Each piece gets its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>,
who edits nothing else. How else to explain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s columns by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Glassman</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Sloan</ENAMEX>? They both lead with the exact same anecdote, taken from the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherlock Holmes</ENAMEX> story.

         
      
   
