
   
   
      
         
            Talking <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Bout My Generation</ENAMEX>

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox's</ENAMEX> (independent filmmaker Allison "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lodging</ENAMEX> " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anders</ENAMEX>, if you have to know) feels moved to make a few obvious
points about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>:

            If you were rebelling against the status quo in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s and '60s</TIMEX>, no one
was more uncool than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>. He was everything I and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
rejected--the phony suave with fake self-control, the finger-popping slick. Not
everyone in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> was equally loathsome. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dino</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Gleason</ENAMEX>,
for instance, were all right. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> lacked a sense of humor. He took
himself so seriously . And nothing makes you more bratty and defiant than
a self-important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>.

            The advent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> was in large part an attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> and his
generation, a way of saying no to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sitting on wooden stools under a
spotlight crooning insincerely. Rock 'n' roll wasn't smooth, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>. It was
rough and ragged and raw. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of rock 'n' roll, as almost
every tribute of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few days</TIMEX> has claimed, it was only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oedipally</ENAMEX>, as the
oppressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> figure you were just itching to slay. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> biographer
was on a TV show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> saying that every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> nowadays uses some sort
of phrasing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> invented. That is nonsense. You will hear nothing of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank in Elvis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fab Four</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sonic Youth</ENAMEX>. God knows you will not find it in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimi Hendrix</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Tribe Called Quest</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Country</ENAMEX> and blues are a far more obvious
source of rock 'n' roll phrasing--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Charles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Guthrie</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howling Wolf</ENAMEX>. For attitude, don't look to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>. Look to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>.

            That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> actually had less of a connection to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> than
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> is perfectly captured in a clip they've
been showing over and over again on TV. It's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> doing
that dreadful duet, in which both were forced to mimic themselves as
respresentatives of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Voice</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> succeeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> comes off
as a clueless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> seems embarrassed.

            Compare this to the dignified and not at all campy duet of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bing Crosby</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX> on the infamous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> special in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>. What the contrast
shows is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>, even more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crosby</ENAMEX>, was a symbol of everything we did
not want to be. If you're under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> and you groove on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>
or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fab Four</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Spector</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hendrix</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sex Pistols or Nirvana</ENAMEX>--or if
his death means as much to you as the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lennon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Denny</ENAMEX>,
Cobain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gram Parsons</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tupac</ENAMEX>--well, I'm sorry, but you've clearly forgotten
how cool you used to be.

         
      
   
