
   
   
      
         
            Oral History

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> must
provide whatever nursing care is required to enable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with physical
"special needs"--such as those in wheelchairs or on ventilators--to attend
mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> law governing the educational access rights of the
disabled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> don't have to pay for "medical services," but the
Court ruled that only applies to services provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
which also fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s disability decision, leads instead with the NYC
school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chancellor</ENAMEX>'s threat to quit if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> goes ahead with a planned
tax-funded private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> voucher program, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s top non-local story
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">imposition</ENAMEX> (as promised <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX>) of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> tariffs on
certain <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> luxury goods. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also fronts the story, differing
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> in stating that the new tariffs will
not be imposed before mid-March.

            The coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s call for classroom nursing support notes that it
means fresh mainstream classroom access for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped children</ENAMEX> and
billions in unexpected costs for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, and hence for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that in the particular case that went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> in which a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boy</ENAMEX>, a high school sophomore, was rendered quadriplegic by a childhood
accident, the cost to the school system of his attending classes was as much as
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> per year, compared to the nationwide average of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,495</NUMEX> for "regular"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Regular</ENAMEX>" is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s word; better would have been
"able-bodied.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that nationwide, the additional care could
cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX> per year.

            There is one area that all the stories on this decision gloss over. They
each mention that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in the case was injured in a childhood
accident. All but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> note that it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> accident when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX>. But everybody leaves it at that. Which leaves
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>' nose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">twitching</ENAMEX>. Did one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX>
around with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year-old</TIMEX> on the back? Or let somebody else do so? (Without a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">helmet</ENAMEX>?) If the answer to either question is yes, then here we have a case of
the cost of parental irresponsibility being doled out to everybody else, a
phenomenon the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> should be more curious about.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains that the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> tariff imposed on the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Vuitton</ENAMEX> handbags,
Parma <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pecorino cheese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> cashmere sweaters is a response to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s recent establishment of import limits on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bananas</ENAMEX> grown by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>. The story also reports that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> passed a threat to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Concorde</ENAMEX> from landing in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> in retaliation for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> ruling, designed to promote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aviation</ENAMEX> equipment sales, that would ban many older <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
The story does not explain when or under what circumstances the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> threat
becomes a reality. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> moves are largely
symbolic in that the goods involved and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Concorde</ENAMEX> flights are a very small
part of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commerce</ENAMEX>. (Although they probably disproportionately
affect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> front wash-ups from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX> last night and her new book, out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> from the interview, but stuffs her
words inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headline focuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s claim in her book
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is "a selfish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who lies all the time." The LAT
likens her story to a "romance novel, heavy on grief, despair and passion." And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> her reaction to being presidentially dumped: "All I did was cry and eat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pizzas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sweets</ENAMEX>." The WP passes along her claim that when stung by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> she considered killing herself by jumping out the hotel window, and the
tidbit that to keep potential evidence out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>' hands, her father
burned her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> souvenirs on the family barbecue.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on bio-warfare walked through
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> security <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> carrying <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7.5 grams</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">powdered anthrax</ENAMEX> in a plastic bottle,
and then proceeded to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> hearing where he displayed his deadly sample. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> then testified that in addition he has done likewise "through all the major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">airports</ENAMEX>, and the security systems of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, even
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, and nobody has stopped me."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that thanks to the raging bull market, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grinnell</ENAMEX> (!), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caltech</ENAMEX>--joined the ranks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX> dollar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endowments</ENAMEX>. And then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> asks the very natural question that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> themselves never raise, Why, in light of this investment success, don't
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> use more of their own resources to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>? Why, in other
words, the higher and higher tuitions and the proposed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52.1 billion</NUMEX> in federal
student aid? To drive the point home, the paper quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>'s
calculations that it would only take a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.8 percent</NUMEX> return on its endowment for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> to provide all its undergrads with a free education.

            *Know, like, thyself* The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that in her book, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky derides Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s accent and her "lumpy figure."

         
      
   
