
   
   
      
         
            Missing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead with the run-up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s start of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
impeachment trial. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s air action in the southern
"no-fly" zone over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX>, which
devotes its front-page "cover story" to the eve-of-trial situation in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, leads with a survey out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">213</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> showing that large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>' health benefit plans will go up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 7 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, far outpacing
the current inflation rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5 percent</NUMEX> and making for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big rise
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 90s</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the up-tick is primarily driven by the
consolidation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>, and that it's bad news for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, who typically pay
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 20 percent</NUMEX> of the cost of their coverage. The health cost story runs
inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, the only thing that's really known about the
impeachment trial proceedings scheduled to start in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> is
that they're scheduled to start in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. Comments made by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> in breaks from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s continuous palavering suggest that the fast
track proposal is, in the words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , "foundering," with a number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> bucking their leadership to complain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> are entitled to more time to make their case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, also weighed in with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>
against a fast track. A related fault line is whether or not the proceedings
should include the calling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. On the one hand, a trial without
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> seems odd and on the other, there is concern that with a full slate
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> cannot avoid the rancor just seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. "We
think that would really become a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zoo</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .
Another issue is whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is constitutionally empowered to consider
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">censure</ENAMEX>. Things are so confused that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> has, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to call their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and express their views, a
remarkable statement, says the paper, in light of the public's overwhelming
opposition to impeachment.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s combat over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> represents
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to enforce the "no-fly" zones and of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> to flout them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> sent up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a dozen</NUMEX> warplanes and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> responded with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> firing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. The LAT account
makes it seem that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> fired on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraqis</ENAMEX> simply because they
were in the zone, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> accounts add that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> first illuminated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> with their fire control
radars, indicating possible imminent missile launch (although no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>
actually were). But none of the accounts address the issue this difference
raises: What is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> rule of engagement here? Is the mere presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX> in the "no-fly" zone considered justification or is some further more
conventionally understood provocative act required?

            Also, for a press that's become quite intoxicated with the technical details
of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>, especially when they work, there's a notable lack of
information in the accounts about how each of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> could fail to
hit obsolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> saying
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> had been able to get out of range of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. This
is doubtful, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> were fired within their range envelopes,
which is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> are many times faster than <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>.
More likely is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> coming and then, probably
with the help of distracting countermeasures, made sudden maneuvers the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> couldn't duplicate. Another possibility is that the shots were all
taken looking down at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, with the clutter of the desert
background confusing the radar-guided <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. But none of these matters make
it into the reporting. In addition, only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> run
the incident on their fronts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> puts it on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> saves it for page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have made much of the various safety and
environmental negatives posed by the wild proliferation of sports utility
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>. A front-page WSJ feature adds another to the list. At least in this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s blizzard in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, the "off-road" monsters got stuck in the snow like
crazy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> makes the case <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>. On the
principle that we will want our next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to be everything this one is
not, she writes, "After <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMurphy</ENAMEX>, we will want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nurse Ratched</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
