
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unreasonable Dowd</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with the emerging diplomatic wrangle over whether or not
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s apparently growing enthusiasm for censuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
rather than conducting a full-blown impeachment trial. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> follows-up its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake City Olympics</ENAMEX> probe lead from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> with the news that federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are broadening their inquiry to include possible tax fraud
charges against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> for allegedly using
tax-exempt funds to purchase lavish gifts and other favors for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s top non-local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> claims
that a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> effort to help <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s armed forces defeat drug smugglers
is in a shambles, souring relations between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">73</NUMEX>
helicopters the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> donated to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> have been plagued with
mechanical problems, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, and angry <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> have sharply
cut back on the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> they will commit to the program. And, says the
Times , citing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> flights into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> ceased in late
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, shortly that is, after the start of the vexed program--with smugglers
putting their loads on container <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> instead. The story gives a little too
much free play to the suggestions of various <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> that the root of
the problem lies with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. After all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military
hasn't exactly turned the tide with its anti-drug efforts in this country
either.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead explains that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> sanctions with no
indication that they will bring him down or to heel any time soon has led to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disenchantment</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> concerning their continued
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisability</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is emerging from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Fox</ENAMEX> as
committed as ever to sanctions. The paper quotes a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Dept.</ENAMEX> official
saying that if--as seems likely--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> chooses to end its cooperation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>, "it has literally chosen for sanctions in perpetuity."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , on the strength of interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>,
claims there is a general consensus that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial will start before any
action is taken on censure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> adds though that there is strong support
for censure among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> have also shown interest. The latter suggests, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are looking for ways to avoid a long trial and the
damage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> standing one could bring. As to how a deal is
worked out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Byrd</ENAMEX>, "whose influence on such
matters is enormous," told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> not to try and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> a deal--this
is something, he advises, that should be worked out strictly among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a front-page above-the-fold story reporting that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> has pleaded guilty to federal criminal charges of smuggling
cigarettes into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> through a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> reservation in order to avoid
paying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> taxes. The paper points out that this is a landmark
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, because while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> have long claimed that nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fourth</NUMEX> of
all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> cigarettes sold overseas get there through smuggling rings, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have previously always denied allegations that top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> knew of
or were involved in any such alleged illicit traffic. What's more, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have long argued, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , against higher cigarette
taxes by suggesting that an increase would encourage smuggling. The story,
although reefered, runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . The WSJ consigns it to the
bottom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> paragraphs of a story about unrelated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RJR</ENAMEX> financial news.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> to throw editorial cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> on
the high multiple birth trend as exemplified by those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> octuplets, with
the comment: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]his trend should not be encouraged. Such multiple births are
dangerous to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, who are born so tiny and premature that they are at
high risk of lifetime health complications. Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> emerge healthy,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are faced with an enormous burden of care that few are prepared to
meet without outside assistance. Moreover, the cost of multiple births is very
high...."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Shapiro</ENAMEX> thinks he knows a way out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
Flyntization of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics: An amnesty day for adulterous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
who fess up. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the opening day</TIMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, no less.

            A front-page WP piece reminds us that it's unfair to depict everybody
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> as crooked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clowns</ENAMEX>. After all, not everybody in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has
approved <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $500,000</NUMEX> in payments and salary to a part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clown</ENAMEX> on his
staff. No, says the paper, citing previous reporting by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
Star and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>, a fierce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s campaign finances. Apparently, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clown</ENAMEX>'s family
have also received questionable payments.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> uses her column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to count all the ways the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal
has been bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. It's been bad for journalism, she writes, because
it's left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> "running the show, dishing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dirt</ENAMEX>, while the rest of us try to figure out where the slippery little line
between private and public is." The latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> rightly reminds that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> hasn't always worn white gloves to the keyboard: "Weren't you the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>," he
asks, "who wrote about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> allegedly having an affair with Frank
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>--on the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> could have added that unlike the "dirt" he has dished on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy/Frank</ENAMEX> story has never been substantiated.

         
      
   
