
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balkan Bob & Burning Bush</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with
a report on the increasing cynicism and resignation of the religious right
regarding the political process. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s peace mission to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the dramatic decline in the fire
death rate. In its off-lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports on the building excitement
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s prospective presidential candidacy. The
paper quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidant</ENAMEX> of the as yet undeclared <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in summing up the
ferment: "the fires are burning as hot as the sun . . . it's saddle up and
ride."

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , while some of its influential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are complaining about the lack of obeisance on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coalition</ENAMEX> is struggling to coalesce around a clear strategy and a single
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes the forthcoming publication of a book
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Moral Majority officials</ENAMEX>, arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> cannot correct
what is wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , concludes that the troubles of
the religious right will increase the willingness of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to
distance themselves from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>. Oddly, this analysis does not factor in
the effect of the failed impeachment move on the mood of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s announcement that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> Kosovars
are prepared to sign the interim peace accord that emerged from the recent
talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> would not grant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> a visa,
forcing the former-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> to exercise his influence from neighboring
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Macedonia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes the scheduled arm-twisting visits of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkan</ENAMEX> "contact-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>, leading up to the
resumption of talks on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> looks on the bright side of
things, noting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s assertion that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kosovar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acquiescence</ENAMEX> might pressure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> to accede. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> emphasizes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> "failed to clinch a
deal" and that agreement remains "uncertain." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> does not spare
the "most embarrassing" details of what it portrays as a misadventure,
including the fact that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kosovo Liberation Army</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stood Dole</ENAMEX> up, leaving him to wrangle over the telephone with another guerilla
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead reports that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX> responded to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8</NUMEX>
million fires, down from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.3 million</NUMEX> fires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years earlier</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
fire deaths totaled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,050</NUMEX>, dropping from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6,215</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that
the good news is due to many factors, including: the increasing prevalence of
smoke alarms, major strides made in the treatment of burn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, tougher
building codes, tighter standards for fire resistant furnishings, migration of
many hazardous jobs overseas, the growing percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> that are eaten
outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, the increase in the use of microwaves and the decrease in
smoking. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt Weldon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> fire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caucus</ENAMEX>, offers an alternative explanation: when the economy is strong, "they
don't need to commit arson or bail out a business."

            In its off-lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> the flames of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> buzz in
anticipation of the launch of his exploratory committee <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The paper
reports that a slew of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> arrive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> to pledge allegiance, offer
assistance and grab a piece of the action. According to the papers the support
is unprecedented for a first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> and is "both spontaneous and
organized." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> will deliver letters
personally pledging support to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, as they were instructed to do by veteran
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> led with a special report alleging that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> made a leap in their nuclear capability using secrets stolen from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alamos</ENAMEX> and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> attempted to sweep the issue under the rug to
avoid disturbing its "strategic partnership" with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The WP picks up
on the story, pointedly noting that the espionage was previously
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , goes on to cite actions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has taken to toughen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> denials that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sought to minimize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
espionage. The paper avers that "a former top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> told The
what may have been revealed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> 'because they already had done
advanced work in this area.'" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that the alleged spying was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cases of purported espionage. Is The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> downplaying the
Times scoop or did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> overplay its hand?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> fronts a report that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 10 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are allergic to latex. The allergy impedes the careers of medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> because latex gloves are required by many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. While normally reports on <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">allergies</ENAMEX> might not rouse the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX>, I'm sure most will read on to discover that, indeed, the afflicted are
equally irritated by latex precautions for other extremities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes
that due to the balloon factor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s birthday parties are also a
menace.

         
      
   
