
   
   
      
         
            DiMaggio Streak Ends

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade</ENAMEX>
Commission's announcement on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that it has settled its antitrust suit
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel Corp.</ENAMEX>, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> before the trial was to begin. The settlement
is also the top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , which doesn't front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>, leads with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s rejection of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>'s appeal of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX>
bombing conviction, a story that nobody else fronts. The appeal had alleged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> prejudice brought about by news coverage of the case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> explains
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> turn-down still leaves room for additional appeals, which
could delay the imposition of his death sentence for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. What gets a lot of
top front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> with pictures everywhere is the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe DiMaggio</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 84</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> after lung surgery.

            The papers explain that the central issue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> case was whether it was monopolistic for the company
to require computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to share details about their machines as a
condition for their getting information about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> chips. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had
gone to trial it ran the risk of being legally judged to be a monopoly, which
the papers explain, could have many adverse legal consequences across a wide
range of issues. The settlement avoids that branding in return for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s
agreeing to very specific provisions--not detailed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>--governing
when it can withhold technological information from computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>. Both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> say that many thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s case might have
been hard to win.

            Everybody notes that the settlement, in its low-key, no-name-calling style,
stands in distinct contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s approach to its legal tussle with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and everybody says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> went this way precisely to avoid
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> beating it thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has been suffering. (For all the comparisons
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> case, none of the papers explain why the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is being
pursued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX> and the other by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s irenic bent reflects
the change of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, from the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> who was a
"merciless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">litigator</ENAMEX>" to the current <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, who personally
successfully negotiated a longstanding patent dispute with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>'s chief
competitor.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> discrepancy in the LAT account of the settlement: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says
the agreement calls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to "mend its strong-arm tactics." This is
bad newspapering because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> isn't admitting it practiced strong-arm
tactics, and besides, the use of the phrase makes it appear as if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is condemning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, which it shouldn't really be doing
without first adducing a great deal more evidence about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s practices than
it does in this story.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>, the Taiwan-born
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> at the center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> bomb spying controversy,
was fired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, after being questioned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. Although not formally
charged with anything, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> is now officially the prime suspect in the case.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe DiMaggio</ENAMEX>'s passing draws tremendous ink volume. Besides the sprawling
front-page coverage, there are editorials in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , as well as a
strong op-ed presence, which includes the effort in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX>, of "Where have you gone, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe DiMaggio</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fame</ENAMEX>, explains that when
they met, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee Clipper</ENAMEX> protested that he hadn't gone anywhere--he'd just
finished doing a Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coffee</ENAMEX> commercial, not to mention being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowery Savings Bank</ENAMEX>.

            Despite the general consensus that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiMaggio</ENAMEX> was exactly the kind of quiet,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">workmanlike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> that is practically gone from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> and fields, a
sort of anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX>, if you will, it's useful to note, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> does,
that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiMaggio</ENAMEX> held out for more money (he wanted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $40,000</NUMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> were offering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX>.) And the LAT op-ed page runs the
piece he wrote right afterwards to mend the fences with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, in which he
advances the same "if movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> can get it, why can't I" arguments you hear
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But clearly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiMaggio</ENAMEX> knew not only on which side his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> was buttered,
but also who buttered it: his op-ed was titled "I am <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lucky</ENAMEX> to Be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ballplayer</ENAMEX>."
Lest the coverage completely disappear into the metaphorical, in his WP
column, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> cites some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe D</ENAMEX>'s stunning stats. Yes, there's the
familiar <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX>-game hitting streak. But there's this more recherch, one: The
number of times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiMaggio</ENAMEX> was thrown out in his major league career going from
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>? Zero.

            
               Did we miss something? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a story under the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">For Alexander, '96 Loss Sowed Seeds for 2000 Victory</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
