
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Culturebox Says: Sue the Bastard</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalists</ENAMEX> tend to think that libel law exists to let rich and famous
slimeballs escape criticism, but there are times when the law, even the
notoriously <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>press <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> version of it, does what it's supposed to do:
protect the innocent against unfounded accusations of crimes of a heinous
nature. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>'s refusal to air <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Broomfield</ENAMEX>'s
documentary about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Love</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Cobain</ENAMEX>, at least not without
substantial changes, for fear of being sued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>, is taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> as
evidence that on occasion, sir, the law is not an ass.

            In the movie, currently being shown on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> screens in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broomfield</ENAMEX> tracks down wierdos of the you-couldn't-make-these-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>-up variety
to get them to accuse Love not just of being a jerk, but of being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broomfield</ENAMEX>'s freak show includes a sadist-turned-rocker with the eyes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Manson</ENAMEX> who all but acknowledges he'll say anything for a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. A crazed
and abusive former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grateful Dead</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> from whose unparental loins it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX>'s tragedy to have sprung. An eerily slow-spoken private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> straight
out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX> movie. A nanny with suspiciously strung-out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. All
have theories about why and how Love killed her late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>. None offers solid
evidence or is remotely credible.

            Love may or may not be likeable--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> suspects she's both phenomenally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">talented</ENAMEX> and a glorious bitch--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broomfield</ENAMEX> isn't addressing that question.
His main objective appears to be to air these patently ludicrous accusations.
What else could he do? he asks us plaintively. After all, she wouldn't talk to
him. She even got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> to pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX> into pulling out of the project.

            Reviews have been mixed, but smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who should have known better have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dismissed Broomfield</ENAMEX>'s journalistic malevolence as fun, wacky, postmodern, an
expose of the seamy underbelly of fame by a renegade who eschews the boring
objectivity of the documentary tradition. They're so impressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomfield</ENAMEX>'s
adversarial stance toward celebrity culture that they overlook the main
achievement of the film, which is (here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> must repeat herself): to air
accusations of murder without offering evidence that the accused is guilty of
anything other than being an ambitious loudmouth and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>.

            Another reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are letting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomfield</ENAMEX> get away with it: As the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman Show</ENAMEX> also made clear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, sadism makes for great
television, and great television excuses everything. Think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed Harris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">torturing Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>, the whole world watching in thrall.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broomfield</ENAMEX> too is something of a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sadist</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> know that,
having seen more of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broomfield</ENAMEX>'s movies and regarding him as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unprincipled</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger &</ENAMEX>
Me . But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> and think that where
there's smoke, there may be fire, might not realize that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX> or
so, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broomfield</ENAMEX> has made movies whose sole purpose appears to be to stalk,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">torment</ENAMEX>, and libel the controversial female public figures he chooses as his
subjects. Then he claims it's because they won't cooperate with him.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily Tomlin</ENAMEX> sued him for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.5 million</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> simply eluded him.
Accused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> serial-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aileen Wuornos</ENAMEX> did talk to him, but, as the movie
also demonstrated, she was sadly ill-equipped to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who was exploiting her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">notoriety</ENAMEX> and who might help her out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi Fleiss</ENAMEX> he just ambushed, after
digging up all sorts of unbelievable charges about her then failing to refute
them.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Love</ENAMEX> denied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broomfield</ENAMEX> the rights to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cobain</ENAMEX>'s music and tried
to get his movie quashed, she may not have been acting as the poster-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> perhaps naively tried to turn her into, but she
was exercising her constitutionally-guaranteed right to protect her reputation
against the worst form of libel there is. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> cheers her on.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
