
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twentieth-Century Foxes</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRENTWOOD</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-one million</NUMEX> dollars for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> to star in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Psycho</ENAMEX> , whose main virtue is it allows him to apply jumper
cables to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s body parts? Can you say, "I hate my young female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>?"

            But it's nice he's getting the big payday, because after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, you'd
think this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> had in it for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX>. First, of course, came <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>,
his death the beau ideal of an on-time departure, given his image's pendulum
swing over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three decades</TIMEX> from ultracool to camp to ultracool once
more. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>--the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> who ever sued a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> for writing a book
that, in his view, made his life seem too boring--was pronounced dead in the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cedars-Sinai</ENAMEX> emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week earlier</TIMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50-year-old</TIMEX> man
collapsed and died of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra overdose</ENAMEX>, his heart seizing up after taking just
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tablets</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coincidence</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, probably.)

            Then came the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Piazza</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> catcher,
had been shipped off to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Marlins</ENAMEX>--the first major move for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was purchased by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>. Piazza
was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX>' best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> on the field, its most popular with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, and
its most expensive to keep. He and his rocket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> had
recently turned down a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-year</TIMEX> offer from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $80</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza</ENAMEX> publicly dissed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX>' proposal, which made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlins</ENAMEX>
deal look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>'s up-your-nose-with-a-rubber-hose payback, especially
given <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piazza</ENAMEX>'s long-running romance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SoCal</ENAMEX> lifestyle.

            Baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, such as the godlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Gammons</ENAMEX>, have noted that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> with an improved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> ... but what's interesting about
the deal is the way it flies in the face of traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> sports-team
wisdom, which holds that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in this showbiz-savvy market needs
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stars</ENAMEX>--marquee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>--to attract attention. Exhibit A: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry West</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Laker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, now seeking a basketball title with movie and rap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaquille O'Neal</ENAMEX>
alongside fresh-faced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phenom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kobe Bryant</ENAMEX>. Exhibit B: the faceless and fan-less
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A. Clippers</ENAMEX>.

            Piazza was that kind of A-list <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> didn't care--a decision in
keeping with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> strategy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> has taken a lot of heat for
being the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> which didn't seem to care about shmoozing talent.
When they wouldn't pony up huge bucks for TV and film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James L. Brooks</ENAMEX>
after he brought them The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpsons</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">The War</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Roses</ENAMEX> , he took still more money at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> bid goodbye to
the producing/directing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Devlin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roland Emmerich</ENAMEX>, who've just
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">made Godzilla for Sony</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> made Speed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> without
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keanu Reeves</ENAMEX>, and lost a bundle. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this year</TIMEX>, they took plenty of heat
for not paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Cameron</ENAMEX> despite reaping zillions from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX>.
            

            The results? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Brooks</ENAMEX> is still a brilliant moviemaker, but while he gave
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Maguire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">As Good as It Gets</ENAMEX>, he also saddled that
studio with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> non-starter I'll <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Do Anything</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> will open, but its legs are suspect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Cameron</ENAMEX>'s pending
divorce may go further toward explaining why he didn't arrange to see a lot of
money from his blockbuster right away than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s greed does.

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> is doing fine. It has the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X-Files</ENAMEX> movie on the way, a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 million</NUMEX> picture with a cult following so large, the film'll get to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million without</ENAMEX> breathing hard--even though it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> after shooting had
ended before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> was allowed to read past page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> in
the script. Something <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Mary</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Farrelly</ENAMEX> comedy, has nifty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">word-of-mouth</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> has the right to distribute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Lucas's</ENAMEX> inevitably
lucrative Star Wars prequels.

            And while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> struggles to find meaning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX>-mania, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s newly-minted, longterm deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aussie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auteur</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luhrmann</ENAMEX>--who directed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DiCaprio in Romeo and Juliet --</ENAMEX>shows that they do
get it, after all. Titanic was an impossibly bold undertaking, cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>, and made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times its cost worldwide. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romeo and Juliet</ENAMEX> was a
slickly-shot retelling of an timeless story, cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 million</NUMEX> and made more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times its cost worldwide. Which success would appear less taxing to a
studio's resources and more easy to repeat? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>-averse approach hasn't
always made them popular--just ask all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> still wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Piazza</ENAMEX>'s
number--but it might make them Most Likely to Succeed.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Connelly</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
