
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boy Vey</ENAMEX>

                   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRENTWOOD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>--As we begin the autopsy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys R Us</ENAMEX>--the beer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'n</ENAMEX>' boorishness, boobs 'n' bang-bang, jeans 'n' sneakers, rock 'n' freaking
roll pop culture that won the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>--it might be wise to determine a time of
death. What'll it be: the day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Cobain</ENAMEX> killed himself? The day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olbermann</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>? The day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Watterson</ENAMEX> stopped drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvin</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobbes</ENAMEX> ?
       Or was it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, when an action film starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> got
squashed in its opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> by Lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX> --featuring a fully
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clothed Heather Graham</ENAMEX>; the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> ; and a
human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> count of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> . Some of us around here still
remember when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titanic</ENAMEX> was going to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultimate Boy Movie</ENAMEX>, based on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultimate Boy Tragedy</ENAMEX>, courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Cameron</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultimate Boy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Lee Curtis</ENAMEX> in That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dress</ENAMEX>, shot down her cleavage, and
blew up a bridge beneath her.
       <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Philby</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys R Us</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Movie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>
Movie's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clothing</ENAMEX> led to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celine Dion</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Heart Will Go On</ENAMEX>" and to the detritus
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leomania</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 weeks</TIMEX> atop the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> box office, beating
the pants off such movies as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild Things</ENAMEX> --whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Culture</ENAMEX> appeal was
summed up by its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Richards</ENAMEX> when she told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> , "I don't want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> to see my breasts. I'm hoping he'll cover his
eyes."
       Meanwhile, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Heart Will Go On</ENAMEX>" has pulled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different albums to the
top of the charts, humiliating new releases from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Halen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Jam</ENAMEX>. But
the music industry has been hip to the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys R Us</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilith Fair</ENAMEX> out-grossed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lollapalooza</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recording Institute of America</ENAMEX>, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> bought
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Reznor</ENAMEX> was singing, "I wanna fuck you like an
animal"; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Not Tonight</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li'l Kim</ENAMEX> and a gaggle of female rappers
were demanding oral satisfaction.
       Elsewhere on the cultural landscape, the news for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Culture</ENAMEX> gets
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bleaker</ENAMEX>. Television? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> words: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> . Talk radio? <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Goodbye,</ENAMEX>
Rush ... hello, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>. Even sports are under siege. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> women's hockey
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> wins the gold medal? No problem ... but when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s hockey <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> loses
and gets frisky with a fire extinguisher at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic Village</ENAMEX>, they
practically have their citizenship revoked. After years of watching locker-room
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrations</ENAMEX>, I thought I was supposed to enjoy it when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> got rowdy. Not
anymore. Check out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, where golden-armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">QB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Bledsoe</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> for
stage-diving during an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everclear</ENAMEX> show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> slugger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mo Vaughn</ENAMEX>
still can't get a long-term contract after a couple of strip club
incidents.
       Has every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> male teen had his allowance suspended or his
part-time job taken away? They're not buying records or movie tickets or novels
or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arch Deluxes</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nikes</ENAMEX>. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who make <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Budweiser</ENAMEX> have so
little faith in the buying power of their core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> that they're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">test-marketing Catalina Blonde</ENAMEX>, a near-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> expressly designed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. And
just when you thought the sport utility <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> craze could four-wheel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>
Culture back to the mountaintop, here comes the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">VW Bug</ENAMEX>, complete with a "Drive
it? Hug it? Drive it? Hug it?" ad campaign so insufferable it makes <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello Kitty</ENAMEX>
look like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp</ENAMEX> 
               Fiction .
       So where can <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys R Us</ENAMEX> make its last stand? There are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>'s
unashamedly foul <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pamela</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>, who could undergo a million makeovers like the one she just received
and still be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Video</ENAMEX>. My hopes were pinned on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.J.</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> gray <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> nursed back to health by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sea World</ENAMEX> and then released into
the ocean. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.J.</ENAMEX> promptly ditched the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> (!) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transmitters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> had
implanted to monitor all perigrenations and breeding patterns. Track this, you
aqualosers! Born free, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>! J.J showed up just when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> were in gravest
need--in between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Hefner</ENAMEX>'s calling off his divorce and the release of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> --to remind us that, whether we see them or not, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s males
are out there, ready to resurface. Trouble is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.J.</ENAMEX>'s a she.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Connelly</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
