
   
   
      
         
            A Tip for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parents</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s expected congressional
testimony by a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> weighing in against renewing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>
Counsel statute, which is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has
officially taken this stand, and marks a reversal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>'s longstanding
support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IC</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times plays this story top-front, but leads instead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s meetings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> with top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, in which she
expressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>'s displeasure with their recent crackdown on opposition
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, but was nonetheless encouraging about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s chances of joining the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> sees the meeting as illustrating the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s persistent separating of human rights and economic
issues when it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>, reading her stance as more of a "honeymoon is
over" break from past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton China</ENAMEX> policy, but leads with the pledge by what
it calls one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most aggressive labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> to organize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, especially those who are salaried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of
large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with revelations at a congressional hearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> cannot
perform some of the basic accounting and record-keeping tasks it expects of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>. According to the story, based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report, sloppy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> practices
meant that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first nine months of 1998</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> doled out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 million</NUMEX> in
fraudulent and wrong refunds and that it lost track of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Blazer</ENAMEX> and a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> laser printer. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> didn't dispute the charges, but attributed the
problems to outdated computers and personnel turnover, problems it's
addressing, says the paper, but which take time.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (which scrupulously credits
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> for all such details), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Deputy Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Holder</ENAMEX>
will testify that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IC</ENAMEX> statute cannot be fixed, but also that there is no need
to do so, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> can investigate most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> wrongdoing itself. When
there would be a conflict of interest in doing so, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Holder</ENAMEX> will say, the DOJ
could still name special counsels. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> don't say how this capability
is thought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to avoid the perceived most problematic
feature of the current law: that if an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> is to be truly not
controlled by the executive branch, he must be virtually immune from dismissal.
Both papers show how times have changed by quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> was plumping for the statute's renewal: "It is my firm
conviction that the law has been a good one, helping to restore public
confidence in our system's ability to investigate wrongdoing by high-level
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> previously broke the
news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> operating in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> employed equipment
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence services, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> deepens the story with the claim that such infiltration
went on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>, was without the knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, and
produced much valuable intelligence that was completely unrelated to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>' assignments. This contrasts, the paper explains, with previous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> reactions to the original story according to which any
such use of intelligence equipment or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> was done with the full witting
cooperation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> and produced information related to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX> mission. The story contains excellent detail about how the covert
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> collection worked: the radio relay system used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> to transmit images from the hinterlands back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> concealed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antennas</ENAMEX> used to intercept <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> military transmissions. The story also reveals
that some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> hanky panky, as did an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>, whose radio message about the operation was intercepted by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> intelligence. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> what was up, says the
paper, they weren't told.

            The fronts at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s main group of pediatricians has substantially backed off its long-held
neutral position on circumcision for male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> now holds that the
practice is not essential to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s well-being and that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> should not
be coerced by medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>" into having it done. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> says
that if the procedure is done, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> should receive pain relief beforehand.
The report does say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> should respect opting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> on
religious or cultural grounds.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> has more than a passing interest in a civil case written up
in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . Seems a federal court jury awarded
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> (later reduced to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX>) to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> when she
suffered a breakdown after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> shift and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> turned
down her request to switch to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. The column also passes along heartening
news about ex-welfare hires: they quit at a much lower rate than other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.

            
               First the credibility, then the credit. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reliable Source</ENAMEX>" in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> went book shopping during
his ski vacation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, he tried to pay with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> card. There
was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> problem: it was expired.

         
      
   
