
   
   
      
         
            Fur Enough?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a new poll purporting to show that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> condemn the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> for its handing of the impeachment trial, with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> taking most
of the blame. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also gives prominent top-front play to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s testimony by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, which is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> news is, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> : no news. The only exception is that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecutor Asa Hutchinson</ENAMEX> that he now remembers having breakfast with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> occasion, something he denied in previous questioning. This
could be significant, explains the paper, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> also insists that at
that meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> told her to make sure notes she'd drafted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> were not found. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> still denies that. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s award of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$107 million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> abortion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> it found were threatened by anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>' "Wanted" posters
of abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and by their web site comparing such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. The verdict is also the top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . It is also fronted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> but runs inside at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says its phone poll of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,058</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> suggests that the public
views the impeachment process, not as an honest investigation of possible
crimes committed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> but as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> drive to undermine him.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> finds that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> think impeachment by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> was adequate
punishment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> didn't need to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> to reach a
decision, and doesn't need to make public the videotaped testimony it decided
to take anyway. The paper sums up the popular sentiment thus: "Enough already!"
The poll finds that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just under half</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> feel the whole thing
will make it harder for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to win elections in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence of the LAT anti-abortion web site story mentions
that the site featured blood-dripping fetuses, a fact not mentioned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . Nor by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . Why the silence?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> stories explain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> defined
"threat" in such a way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> could consider the impact on the mental
state of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff doctors</ENAMEX> of nationwide violence aimed against other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> points out that this definition departs from
the standard laid down by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, which limited "threat" to
those words that produce or are likely to produce "imminent" lawless action.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says however, that the trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s approach reflects current
appellate case law. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> effectively sums up the troubling side of the
wider definition of "threat" by quoting one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> saying
that under it, "virtually any document that criticizes an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">abortionist</ENAMEX> by name
is threatening. I think the effect on political protest will be
devastating."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the annoying tics of newspaper coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> awards is the
tendency to not cover the final money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judgement</ENAMEX> with the same vigor as the
initial sum. Therefore, it's a good start that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that most of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> in this case have preemptively gotten rid of their assets and
hence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> will probably never collect <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a cent</NUMEX> of the millions
mentioned in the headlines.

            A front-page story at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and stories inside elsewhere describe what
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> calls a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry Mason</ENAMEX> moment" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial.
Lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Boies</ENAMEX> got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> to admit that
there was a major inaccuracy in the video the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> played in the courtroom
in an attempt to show that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">disengaging MS' internet browser</ENAMEX> from its Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX>
software makes the latter run slower. The inaccuracy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boies</ENAMEX> said, drawing on a
frame<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-by-</NUMEX>frame analysis revealing the continued presence of a browser screen
tag, was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">browser</ENAMEX> had not actually been removed. Later in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>,
after what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> describes as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX>'s "frantic" phone calls back to
company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HQ</ENAMEX>, he changed his account to say that the software in the video really
did have the browser removed, but that the screen tag usually signifying
browser <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> had mistakenly not been removed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> sees the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> defense as
"reeling," and says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> with the balky video is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> straight company
witness to retreat on the stand from a staked-out position.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> may be about to
implement an unprecedented consumer notification procedure relating to one of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s most cherished <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX>: fur. The city council has, says the
paper, agreed to hold a special election on requiring all local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">furriers</ENAMEX> to put
warning tags on their garments that would read: "This product is made with fur
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> that may have been killed by electrocution, gassing, neck
breaking, poisoning, clubbing, stomping, or drowning and may have been trapped
in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX>-jaw, leg-hold traps." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> can't help but notice that this
story includes far more detail about methods of extinguishing life than any of
the stories about that anti-abortion web site.

         
      
   
