
   
   
      
         
            Boom or Robust

            The papers all lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy's latest and cleanest bill of
health yet. Figures released by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> show that the economy
expanded by an unexpectedly vigorous <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.6%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last quarter of 1998</TIMEX>, with
inflation and unemployment still deep in remission. The papers explain that
recession anxiety may actually have helped ward one off: fiscal turmoil in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>
resulted in low long-term interest rates and commodity prices, which in turn
have kept business brisk and spending high. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> story actually quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>
official; most of the valedictory analysis comes from exuberant Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>. The giddiest of the lot is quoted in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> : "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> economy is the wonder of the
world," he tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report more slaughter of ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> at the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. The latest atrocity is a mass killing
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> during a raid on their supposed stronghold. In
response, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronter relays, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Administration</ENAMEX> is shopping
a plan around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> to commit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000-5000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to an
international cease-fire-monitoring force in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. While the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> papers
report on the killing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> devotes a large chunk of its story to
fretting over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX> will be involved in the monitoring
effort. Although he's been busy fending off an ethics investigation and tending
to his investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s business, he's still solidly in the loop, and will
probably find a way in.

            Speaking of ethics and investigations, everyone reports <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision to spare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> an independent counsel
investigation into his alleged cover-up of campaign finance chicanery in the
last Presidential election. All papers report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision effectively
truncates the possibility of further investigations into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
fundraising for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 1996</TIMEX> run. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> writes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>'s campaign finance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> has been continually stymied by
unfavorable court decisions and lack of cooperation from essential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>,
and will soon close shop.

            As for the daily impeachment trial update: the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subpoenaed</ENAMEX>, and their depositions scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. Meanwhile, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report on the waning popularity of the
conviction-without-removal plan posed by some moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> earlier this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, whereby the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> would be found guilty of the facts of the case but
allowed to stay in office. The plan is drawing criticism from both ends of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectrum</ENAMEX>: conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> fear it will siphon off pro-impeachment
support, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> argue that it's a backhanded way of punishing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> without satisfying Constitutional standards. "You can't be a little
bit pregnant," <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Breaux</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . Instead,
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are leaning towards brisk, bipartisan, post-trial censure of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece focuses on the culture clash between zealous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Managers</ENAMEX> and their more deliberative Senatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> lord
it over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, acting "wiser and better" than their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>, claims
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> irate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>.

            An LAT front pager describes how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Labor</ENAMEX> has
added teeth to its efforts to eliminate the wage gap between the genders. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>
now make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">74 cents</NUMEX> for every dollar earned by their male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>-a mere
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15-cent</NUMEX> improvement since the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Equal Pay Act</ENAMEX> outlawed gender-based pay
discrimination way back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>. Now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of simple coaxing and lobbying
are over: a well-funded compliance office at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> conducts "glass ceiling
reviews" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that hold government
contracts. Those found to intentionally discriminate against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> must pay
punitive damages, back pay, and/or wage increases. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> have called
this approach too aggressive: "it's like trying to catch a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> with an A-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>"
protests one dissenter. But even more of these bombs may detonate soon:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s budget allocates more funding to equal-pay enforcement, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may soon expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1963 Act</ENAMEX> to allow for greater damages awards.

            Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> describes the near-hysterical reaction to a recent
foray by a much-worshipped icon who made a rare venture out to share his
message with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>. Preceded by pomp, shielded by minions, and thronged by
reverent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX>, he meditated and preached on race, poverty, morality, and
the significance of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming millennium</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> screamed. Grown women
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shrieked</ENAMEX>. Little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> cried from happiness," the story recounts. Sure, the
pontiff was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>; but this story describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s
visit to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> public school to plug his new charitable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
