
   
   
      
         
            Voting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convictions</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the extra-innings <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
negotiations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, stressing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s statement that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> will
not bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> if the continuation of the stalemate is due to objections from
both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. The other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> also front the story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the heartening nuclear weapons agreement reached over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>, a story fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
but carried inside at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with the
call by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> of both parties from their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> national meeting for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to quit the partisan bickering of the
impeachment and get back to issues of concern to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> such as education.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USAT</ENAMEX> leads with renewed efforts by state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> to find ways to
curtail the deceptive sales practices of sweepstakes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>'s
Newspaper also runs a news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> "cover story" on the problem that there's no
accepted name for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>. (How about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Noughties</ENAMEX>? Or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uh-Ohs</ENAMEX>?)

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> talks have been extended until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-Tuesday</TIMEX>. The consensus is that the big sticking point that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> reject
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> insist on is the proposed presence on the ground of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeeping force</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that one modification being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">explored</ENAMEX> to close the deal is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> with a significant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> component,
which would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> to save face
because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has been a staunch supporter of his. And perhaps not explicitly
calling it a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> has this linguistic gambit as well.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> have stepped up their rhetoric against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airstrikes</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> have been more "prickly"
than anticipated, hesitating to sign an agreement that doesn't explicitly
promise an eventual referendum on self-governance for the region, a stance the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also reports. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> is offering in
response the promise that the international community will consider the voice
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> in the region regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s final status. But there is no
explanation of what this could possibly mean.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> talks were a lot
different--face to face, cordial and very successful. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>' prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> agreed to warn each other of missile tests, swap information on
nuclear strategy, and to quit testing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">nukes</ENAMEX> altogether. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> made no
progress on the disputed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Himalayan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kashmir</ENAMEX>, but they agreed to try
again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> points out that the agreements regarding nuclear
weapons were significant because the proximity of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> equals
shorter missile flight times, which make unrecallable missile mistakes more
likely.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that a planned sale of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450 million</NUMEX> communications satellite to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> may be
kaboshed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> (via not granting the necessary export licenses)
because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and elsewhere that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> military is
involved in the deal. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is now, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ,
conducting "end-user checks." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that the deal would come at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are on the verge of releasing a report
concluding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s military has profited over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> from stealing and
buying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> equipment.

            The WP front reports a growing reaction in a number of legislatures
to the ever-increasing number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are prevented from voting because
of their criminal records: give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX> back the right to vote anyway. The idea
is, says the paper, picking up support from mainstream civil rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, for example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> has a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> under consideration that would restore convicts' right to vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>
after they complete their sentence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says civil rights groups
have pushed this in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s disenfranchised
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX> live there and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 31 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are ineligible
to vote. And adds the paper, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderates</ENAMEX> are reluctant to reject the idea
for fear of appearing racist. "With the huge number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> disenfranchised,
you're really not open to all of the citizenry in making decisions," is one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX>'s defense of the idea.

            The WP front reports that a former school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> who was fired for
sexually harassing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> is getting a disability retirement payment of about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38,000</NUMEX> per year--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the norm (for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
doesn't say)--for a psychosexual disorder that makes him unable to supervise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> without trying to get them to have sex with him.

            
               
                  Thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>
                According to the LAT front, rising
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX> was recently on the receiving end of this assessment
from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>: "A black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> voting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> makes about as much
sense as a chicken voting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colonel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
