
   
   
      
         
            Large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurd Cheese on Ice</ENAMEX>

            A story that had been lurking in the back pages for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>--the saga of
on-the-lam <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX>--explodes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> into everybody's lead
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> suddenly in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> custody following his dramatic capture by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> rising up in often violent
protest.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rioters</ENAMEX>' wrath was not primarily the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurd</ENAMEX>'s principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, but mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, because Ocalan
was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> under the protection of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> when he was seized. The
papers report on street riots and several cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>' self-immolation
resulting in serious burn injuries. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>' violence exhibited "extraordinary coordination," and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> sees it as "disciplined."

            The papers do a good job of providing the historical context to all this--
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>, numbering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 25 million</NUMEX> and without their own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, have
sought one since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>. (But only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Treaty</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sevres</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ottoman Empire</ENAMEX>.) For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> has been leading
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> in a war for autonomy, most recently from
a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>, which expelled him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last year</TIMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> military
pressure. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say, holds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> responsible for the
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> deaths occurring during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insurgency</ENAMEX>. Which is
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocalan</ENAMEX> faces the death penalty in the trial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> is now preparing.

            The papers note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> insists it had no direct hand in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s
capture, but also that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX> said that the
government is pleased with his apprehension. The LAT observes that in
none of this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> saying it didn't help locate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ocalan</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> runs as its off-lead a story nobody else
fronts--the comment by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who oversaw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit
that she will explore the possibility of imposing civil sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for
providing misleading testimony about his affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in the
case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> points out that a finding of civil contempt could force
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">tens of thousands of dollars</NUMEX> and might even jumpstart any
attempt by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> to indict him.

            An oddity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story: It claims that "for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
weary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s remark was a "dispiriting development." Yet the
piece goes on to note that calls made by the paper to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> were
referred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert S. Bennett</ENAMEX>, who had no comment. So how does
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> were dispirited? It doesn't.

            Inside stories at both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> take a look at a new
troubling report about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Customs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> has filed with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> stresses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s findings that it is
very vulnerable to drug-related corruption. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> covers the
corruption angle too, but also has some discouraging information on the
personal searches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX> conducts: Whereas <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, the hit
rates on these searches bordered on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX>, of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,076</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> who
had to take off part of their clothing for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Customs</ENAMEX> inspection in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 98</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 21 percent</NUMEX> were found to be carrying illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.

            Stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> describe a study
coming out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in JAMA concluding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> examining young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
frequently miss head injuries linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse. The study holds that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> were especially unlikely to identify such abuse-suggesting injuries if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were married and white. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
front reports that strollers and mattresses that can injure or kill small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will be recalled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosco</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer Product Safety Commission</ENAMEX>.

            A story in the WP business section illustrates the profound degree to
which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> now depend on sales of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> to foreign countries. For instance, this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX> will sell only one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-16</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>--its
production line for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> is being kept alive by sales to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Emirates</ENAMEX>, of a model more modern than those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Air Force</ENAMEX>. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F/A-18s</ENAMEX> were recently sold to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> sporting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> so deadly that it had
previously been restricted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s column pointed out that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s
tenure as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> found that it was marked by her tendency
to put political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> on her payroll. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> mentioned as an example
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Masing Will</ENAMEX>, who it identified as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> made a telling omission here. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> did not say
that Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> is also the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> opinion
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>. In other words, the paper exhibited the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-too-typical journalistic
tic of exposing potential conflicts of interest involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> while
ignoring those involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homework</ENAMEX> assignment for the next
political cycle: find a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> column critical of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
