
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House It Gonna Work</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s revelation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>-appointed
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>" of the impeachment case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> are leaning
towards conducting a full-bore trial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, complete with the
examination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with the latest in a string of
encouraging crime stories: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s own survey of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> homicide statistics
shows that the total number of murders in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> largest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> is down
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> compared to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
murder rate has dropped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27 percent</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, resulting in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28-year</TIMEX> low.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with initial government data showing that most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are in compliance
with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> welfare reform requirement that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> hold
jobs or actively prepare to do so. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> points out, however, that
many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are not meeting the law's required percentage of working two-parent
welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and that the government statistics do not show whether welfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have found good jobs.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads, as well as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager,
report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>' aggressive position puts them in conflict with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, who just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX> had come out in
favor of a quick timetable that would probably preclude hearing from most of
the scandal's key figures. And it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, the papers remind, which
controls how an impeachment trial will proceed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> said they were stunned and
angered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s disinclination to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. One is quoted as calling it
"a slap in the face of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> agree on the necessity of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, whereas both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> mention that one of their
number holds they should be called only if absolutely necessary.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead breaks an exclusive: A little-known national security
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutique firm</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vector</ENAMEX>, which went under <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> and whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was
a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Intelligence Agency</ENAMEX>, is being investigated by
several federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> specialized in the highly secretive
business of acquiring foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and radars for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are looking into irregularities surrounding some
of its deals. Such as allegedly procuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> that
somehow never got into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> hands, and whose current whereabouts are unknown.
Or, as part of a deal to procure <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, supposedly giving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
sensitive technical information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> shoulder-fired Stinger
surface-to-air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>. This story has some familiar elements that could give
it legs: phony paperwork to disguise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>' true destinations and colorful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> crossing back and forth between private deal-making and
government-sanctioned covert operations. Can you say <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>?

            The papers continue to cover the apparent threshold-crossing performance of
e-commerce. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> notes an obvious but unanticipated
consequence: an upsurge in business for such non-netly concerns as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postal Service</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Express</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>.

            Back to the impeachment witness-or-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> story for a beat. The
Times is alone in observing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> were "amused" by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> split on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. The use of that word, in the absence of either direct
or indirect quotations from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>, raises a host of issues: Were those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
really so unsophisticated as to reveal such a politically loaded emotion in
front of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>? If so, then why aren't we told what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> said? If
not, then shouldn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> back down to "seemed amused<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" Or to "were said to
be amused by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>?" This is not trivial, because communicating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> amusement is likely to have adverse political consequences for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and so it seems only fair to insist that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
make it clear that it's not being spun--or spinning.

         
      
   
