
   
   
      
         
            All Dictioned Up

            Once again the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> impeachment trial is the consensus news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s installment given over to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s votes to press on and to
closed-door depose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. The decisions were virtually straight party
votes, with the sole exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Feingold</ENAMEX>, who
voted against dismissal and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. The headlines at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Senate Will Hear Witnesses"</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Senate Votes to Take Testimony"</ENAMEX>--focus on
the immediate event. The big print at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
takes a longer view: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Senate Refuses to Dismiss Case and Agrees to Call</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky; Daschle Sees Clinton Survival</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s smaller subhead notes
that the vote count shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX> is right, a point that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> elevates to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> line of its banner headline:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Senators Reject Ending Trial</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/56</NUMEX>-44 Vote Shows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> Lacks Margin to
Convict."

            The meaning of the votes is best summed up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which states
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> they have the chance to make their
case and that in all likelihood doing so will not matter. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX>, is quoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> as seeing the glass <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> full: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">It</ENAMEX>
shows the strength of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>' case," while another, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, opts for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> (or more) empty: "I'm glad those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> weren't at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valley Forge</ENAMEX> or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alamo</ENAMEX>."

            The papers turn from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How will it end?</ENAMEX>" to "When will it end?"--addressing
the trial schedule from here on out. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says that if the three
depositions just approved don't drag out and aren't sensational, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> will likely not conduct the full-blown discovery it has recently
threatened. (But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes a possible obstacle: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>
are continuing to press for live testimony.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says there are
endgame disagreements inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Ruff</ENAMEX> on the side of
speed, opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX>, on the side of thoroughness. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other tidbits that only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> got the news of the votes, he was on the phone with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and several
western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">salmon restoration</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> will
be questioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Bryant</ENAMEX>, "because he was the questioner Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
disliked least when she met with several of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> off-leads word that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> will announce <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that it is buying
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> (burying until deep in the story the part of the company
being left behind: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX> was motivated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX>'s strong
brand image based on safety and because the average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volvo</ENAMEX> sells for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX>,
twice that of the average <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>. The story is carried inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and is flagged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat</ENAMEX> had offered more money than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automaker</ENAMEX>,
but that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> has become viewed as the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">acquirer</ENAMEX> of choice," because of its
track record of injecting capital and expertise into new purchases without
diluting a brand's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial decries the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Armed Services Committee</ENAMEX>'s approval
of increases in military pay and pensions even more generous than those
recommended in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> budget. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> makes a good distinction
between rendering military pay strictly comparable to civilian pay and making
military pay high enough to attract and retain sufficiently qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in
the various specialties the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> require for true readiness. It's the
latter that the budget should reflect, not the former. The editorial goes on to
suggest that the readiness pay standard should be applied <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> instead
of long-term. It should be added that there's a simple extension of this idea
that would help retention of the right kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> while avoiding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste</ENAMEX>:
target pay raises and bonuses not just to combat specialties but also to
combat-oriented tours of duty. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Ranger</ENAMEX> is no doubt deserving of an ample
extra reward when he's jumping out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and sleeping in a foxhole, but not
when he's serving as a clerical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>, returning to his
nice suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> in time for dinner with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            Everybody's been talking about the growth of online stock trading, but today
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front and inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the emphasis is on the
growth of online stock trading problems. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says investor
complaints about online trades have quadrupled over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Levitt</ENAMEX>, is quoted in both saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> must not let
the ease of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> transactions goad them into trading too quickly or too
often.

            In a front-pager headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Official's Vocabulary Lesson/Some Words are Defined by More</ENAMEX>
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dictionary</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> tells how on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> a white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> resigned after many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in his agency
complained bitterly over his use of the word "niggardly" in a business meeting
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> white and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> black. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that
"niggardly" is etymologically completely unrelated to "nigger" (it has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> roots and means stingy) and says that if in fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> used the word
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">innocently</ENAMEX> and in its correct context, then the loss of his job is "truly
remarkable." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> cites other phrases that will have to be dropped if the
standard of this case is widely adopted: "a chink in the armor," and "a nip in
the air."

         
      
   
