
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rational Exuberance</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s stronger than expected
economic growth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the final months of 1998</TIMEX>. The story notes that the state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> dovetails with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> report issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, indicating
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s gross domestic product grew <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.1 percent</NUMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with an exclusive, reporting that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> stopped issuing new licenses for
the export of military or dual-use equipment to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> due to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
suspicions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> had provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> jamming
codes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> report
that condemns <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s recent record on human rights, including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
squelching of the formation of a opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, religious expression and the
freedom of the press.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> pairs its lead on rosy job growth in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> with an
analysis of the "nearly sublime" national economy. The paper observes that the
torrid pace of growth has confounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prognosticators</ENAMEX>, who had widely expected
that contagion from the international economic crisis would slow the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
expansion. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts the revised GDP numbers, pointing out that
inflation dipped to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.0 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, the lowest level since the launch of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sputnik</ENAMEX>. The papers report that the Dow retreated because of fears that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>
will raise interest rates to cool the exuberant economy.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> exclusive informs that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> has
investigated allegations of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> breach of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> security and concluded that
there has been "no compromise of technology whatsoever." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> suspected
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX> were giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> codes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in exchange for a radio
jamming system to disrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> observes that
animosities between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, long the most serious tension within the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliance</ENAMEX>, have worsened with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> affair. The exclusive notes that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> said" that "some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>" plan to press for more information
and are dissatisfied with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> response. Is this sourcing detail a clue
as to why a story of dismissed suspicions, which are sure to stoke
international sensitivities, turned up as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's lead?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>'s rebuke of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in its 22nd
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> human rights report, observes that the criticism came on the eve of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, at a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is being attacked
for being to easy on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reefers the story. Though each
story provides some detail on human rights flashpoints, no story notes that the
report covered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">194</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and no story explains that the report is compiled
to provide an authoritative basis for international affairs decisions by the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. In what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> promoted as a
major speech on foreign policy challenges, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> advocated an active
role for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> throughout the world and defended his policy of
engagement in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , report in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front-page</ENAMEX> articles.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial calls on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to address Juanita
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s assertion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> raped her in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. The editorial evinces
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s discomfort with this disquieting story and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s discontent
with the terse denial issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
opines that "the public and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> are in a muddle as to what to think" and
that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is banking on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s story's lacking legs." Of
course, the editorial itself lends the story legs.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports on the debate over the
accessibility of academic writing, which has been stoked by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Said</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> denouncing abstruse writing. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said</ENAMEX>'s article provoked
"discourse" is not simply a factor of his having recently assumed the
presidency of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Language Association</ENAMEX>. Said is considered a prime
offender when it comes to inaccessible communication. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> informs
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Philosophy and Literature</ENAMEX> , has started to hold an annual
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bad Writing Contest</ENAMEX>, in which leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> take the prize. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> refers
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to an Internet site that automatically creates an impenetrable
"post-modern" essay each time a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> logs on.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT Metro Section</ENAMEX> conveys a cautionary tale: beware of
flying bovines. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern California</ENAMEX>, a wandering <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">750-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX> was hit by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northbound Mercedes</ENAMEX>, which sent it hurtling into the path of a southbound
pickup. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tragically</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> was killed when the airborne heifer smashed
through the windshield of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> and struck him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. The bovine
bounced off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and was hit by another pickup. Curiously, the story does
not report on the condition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cow</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
