
   
   
      
         
            Trial By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> jilts impeachment to lead with local
weather--a massive ice storm that knocked out power throughout the capital
area. But electricity still crackled through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>; lead stories
Times (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ) report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s testimony was more credible than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s, and turned up the pressure for calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> produced no breakthroughs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> as they slowly pounded in
their case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes high-up that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McCollum</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s main
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to break out sexually explicit terminology. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCollum</ENAMEX>
also challenged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettie Currie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vernon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tellingly</ENAMEX>, speculation is shifting
from whether there will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> to who they will be. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
certainly on the wish-list of some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            Diversion from the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight-hour</TIMEX> slog, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gladly</ENAMEX> noted by all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Harkin</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late-afternoon</TIMEX> objection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s repeated
references to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is not a mute <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">maintained Harkin</ENAMEX>--it can set rules and make motions too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> agreed and set the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> scrambling for linguistic innovation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harkin</ENAMEX>'s point, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, was highly symbolic: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> stress that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is not merely making an innocent or guilty verdict, but also passing
judgment on the import of the crime.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>' editorial pages keep pounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial perseveres in its "irrelevancy" campaign
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s removal and shudders, "It is hard to imagine how the
appearance of Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> or Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX> could galvanize the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to convict
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial moans that the "mind-numbing" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
speeches "do more to inure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s offensive conduct than
all the tortured arguments his various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> can muster." Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> opine that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> has yet to prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s conduct
is sufficiently egregious to warrant his removal.

            All papers front the latest on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s economic roller-coaster: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> stock market leaped <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> decided to
let its currency, the real, drop to market level (the real obliged, plummeting
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> percent more). Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rejoiced</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s perceived courage--the
real decision being an abrupt about-face by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>--and the Dow
jumped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">219</NUMEX> points.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> from the international monitoring mission in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> get
inside coverage all around. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> was shot in the shoulder (and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> wounded) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> by unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> who deliberately
fired on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>. Separately, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> reportedly killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
ethnic-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. Both incidents, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note, underscore the extreme
volatility of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> situation.

            Everybody flags a truly bizarre impeachment spin-off: the firing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of the American Medical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lundberg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lundberg</ENAMEX>'s high crime (or
misdemeanor)? Publishing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> based on a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> survey about
whether "oral sex" constitutes "having sex." (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59%</NUMEX> voted no.) The timing of
course is no coincidence--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lundberg</ENAMEX>, who adores media attention, had hoped
to impact the impeachment debate. With the publicity about his demise, he
really has a chance--that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 20, 1999</TIMEX> issue may become the most-read
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">JAMA</ENAMEX> ever.

         
      
   
