
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max Senate Comedy</ENAMEX>

            The impeachment trial continues to lead all around. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s big story is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s closed-door debate of a motion to summarily dismiss the charges
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The debate went until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 10</TIMEX> PM <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> time
last night and will continue again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The secret session came about after a
motion to hold all impeachment deliberations in open session was defeated. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead editorial calls the shuttered approach "an affront to the public."

            The papers report that with the matter of whether or not to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>
hanging in the balance, much of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was taken up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> trying to
gin up a fast-track strategy that would bring the proceedings to a close
expeditiously without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. But, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, none has the votes yet.
And so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are encouraging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> to
cut down their proposed witness list. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> appears ready to do so,
with a list including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Podesta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> are
leaning toward calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> and away from calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Currie</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
adds that there has been some interest in calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, whom the paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reveals</ENAMEX>, was debriefed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecution staffers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, such interest waned. One wonders why, given that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> had to say in his dry run was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
expressed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> about the gifts he'd given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times all report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> submitted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> questions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> says neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> nor anybody else there
will provide answers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> sees the stonewall as a sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
is confident he'll win the case.

            The papers report that one idea being kicked around by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote
on whether the charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> are true and another on whether he
should thereby be removed from office. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> offers the best
explanation of why this is attractive to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>: This would be a stringent
form of censure, but the finding of facts would only require <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> votes, which
means it's doable.

            Everybody fronts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruling that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>
must be an actual headcount, not the statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sampling</ENAMEX> that's alleged to be
more accurate. The main political impact of the decision is that it will affect
how many congressional seats each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> gets, and perhaps will also affect
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> occupy them, because the conventional wisdom is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sampling</ENAMEX> favors <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, by being more able to include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>.

            The WP front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> enforcing the no-fly zone
over southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> at an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>air site and that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
claim <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> were killed when one of them went wide of the mark.
Later, says the paper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> acknowledged that a brand-new type of
video-guided missile may have missed its intended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">target</ENAMEX> and hit houses
instead. Significantly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> attack was preemptive, part of a tougher
effort to suppress <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>air activities without waiting for full-blown
attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>'s criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
campaign in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and the incident is inside at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .

            Another story receiving wide play--front at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flagged</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> news box--is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s decision to climb
down from its previous plans to ship its new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pentium III</ENAMEX> chip with the capacity
to allow Web sites to identify a computer. The feature has been called "cookies
on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , inspiring privacy concerns among many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">netizens</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports a new development in the music business in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>,
inspired by a recent rash of charges of song ripping-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">off-</NUMEX>-plagiarism insurance.
Huge legal fees involved in successful defenses against such charges by the
likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Lloyd Webber</ENAMEX> are cited as creating the market. The
policies--underwritten by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lloyd's of London</ENAMEX>--provide coverage for all damages
and defense costs in such cases. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> special requirement: taking out the policy
must be kept a secret, to avoid inviting lawsuits.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> answers some questions tendered here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> regarding
the financing for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s sudden blowing into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. Her travel expenses,
including luxury accommodations at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayflower Hotel</ENAMEX>, are being paid by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">such time</TIMEX> as she is called to testify at the impeachment trial.
Then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> pays for them.

         
      
   
