
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corpse Maneuvers</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the acquittal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Ashby</ENAMEX> in
connection with the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that occurred when the airplane he was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">piloting</ENAMEX> struck an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> ski lift in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. The story is also top front with
pictures at the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> go with the announcement yesterday
by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> that their budget plan will set aside money
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> while also providing for a tax cut. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says
this is a vague proposal, with the size of the tax cut still undefined. But the
paper does say that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next ten years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> aims to use all the
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> budget surplus for tax relief, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
would devote some of it to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, special savings accounts, and extra
defense and domestic spending. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> proposed tax cut
before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> election will be quite modest, growing to "historic" dimensions
only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">subsequent years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with bad news for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>: low reading scores. The death of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Blackmun</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 90</TIMEX>, makes everybody's front, the headlines making
it clear that his authorship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Roe v. Wade</ENAMEX> opinion is at this point viewed
as his signal legacy.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> squealed with joy at the
verdict, but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashby</ENAMEX> took the news undemonstratively. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says he was
sitting when the verdict was read. Unlikely. The other papers have him
standing.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Relatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , sat in "shocked
silence." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, said he was
"baffled" by the verdict. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says he was "infuriated."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> make it clear just how sweeping the acquittal
was: Not only was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashby</ENAMEX> cleared of involuntary manslaughter and negligent
homicide but also of charges of dereliction of duty and destruction of
property, even though he was flying lower and faster than the rules allowed.
None of the papers mention it, but the trial outcome is part of a disturbing
recent trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. What do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX> shootdown of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> airliner, the "friendly fire" missile attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> during
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tailhook</ENAMEX> sexual assaults, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Air Force</ENAMEX> shootdown of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> no-fly zone all have in common?
Miraculously, the military justice system found that none of these actions was
anybody's fault.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead says a new federal assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX>' reading skills shows that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 20 percent</NUMEX> of them are proficient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, putting the state <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to last (only in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>) in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> in this category. As if realizing what the study suggests about the
cognitive prowess of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, the paper points out that the federal
assessment "also" showed that eighty percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> are
not proficient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> main "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece argues
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s decision to keep his distance from the press in the
wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and Broaddrick allegations has hurt the public's
understanding of his policies. And will hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>' understanding of them
as well.

            Follow up: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, in discussing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruling that physically
disabled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are entitled to the provision of publicly-funded continuous
classroom care, this space wondered how it was that none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> covering
the decision seemed at all curious about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled boy</ENAMEX> in the case could
have been paralyzed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> accident as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year-old</TIMEX>. Well, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers couldn't take it any more and quickly found out some further interesting
facts: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> was injured when, after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> put him on the back of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motorcycle</ENAMEX>, the baby blanket that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> placed around his shoulders became
entwined with the cycle's drive shaft, breaking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s neck and snapping his
spinal cord. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> and accepted a
settlement offer of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX>. Leaving aside the question of how it is that
anything about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> design or manufacture could have been nearly as
implicated as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s ill-advised decision to put the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year-old</TIMEX> on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motorcycle</ENAMEX>, it should be noted that that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX> was primarily proffered
to pay for the costs entailed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s injury. Hence, here's a crucial fact
not reported in any of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s stories: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had already been
given more than enough money (by their own estimate) to provide for the
additional cost of keeping him in a mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>.
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> rather peculiar preparation made for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior Department</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. Seems <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">honchos</ENAMEX> decided to
use a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5-foot-</NUMEX>wide version of the departmental seal as the event backdrop, a
seal featuring blue, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>-capped mountains, an orange <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">sunset</ENAMEX>, and a buffalo
grazing. Problem was, it was discovered late in the game that the buffalo is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anatomically</ENAMEX> correct he. And that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> when he spoke at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> would be
standing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wags</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "right near its anatomical correctness." Hence
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last-minute</TIMEX> airbrush job by government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, avoiding the appearance of
any interspecies sensuous gestures.

         
      
   
