
   
   
      
         
            Sovereign of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleaze</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead predicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy will falter in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. The
top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> differ on how
to conduct the impeachment trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>' drive to obtain credit for cuts in waste gas
emissions.

            An ursine LAT lead says the economy is headed for big trouble in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Reasons include: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) political uncertainty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a record-high
stock market, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) economic instability in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) a squeeze on
corporate profits. Seems like a safe prediction for a paper to make: if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is correct, they can scream "I told you so," but if another year
passes with no economic downturn will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> be reminded of this lead
story?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is split on how to proceed with
impeachment hearings. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s bipartisans, who
favor a streamlined approach, and a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that wants a full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
trial with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and detailed testimony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s approach calls for an early
vote on whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s crimes merit removal from office. If less than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> think they do, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> would close the impeachment trial and
begin considering censure. Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> feel
that a full-scale trial is the only way for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to make a valid judgment
and perform its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitutional</ENAMEX> duty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees the intra-party rift as
"a crucial test of [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s] own and possibly his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s political future."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> approval of a global-warming
treaty pending, major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> are spearheading legislation that would
ensure they receive credit for cutbacks they have made in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> emissions over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> thinks that passage of such legislation
would soften <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> resistance to the treaty and help align industrial and
environmental goals.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> environmental stories on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front blows the
whistle on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Caribbean Cruises Ltd.</ENAMEX>, which got caught dumping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> in
international water, lied to cover it up, paid a fine, apologized, and then got
caught dumping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> again. The article chronicles <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RCC</ENAMEX>'s elaborate attempts to
escape punishment, employing no less than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorneys General</ENAMEX> in
its lobbying campaign. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> still refuses to turn over results
of its internal investigation, a federal investigation into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Caribbean</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">systematic pollution</ENAMEX> and falsification of records is ongoing.

            As always, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Magazine</ENAMEX> --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lives They Lived"</ENAMEX>--
is devoted to the "old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>" who have died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous 12 months</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
profiles include the obvious choices--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy Rogers</ENAMEX>--but
there are also stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto Bettmann</ENAMEX>, who began his photo archive with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> suitcases of photographs carted out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazi Germany</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Gellhorn</ENAMEX>, who
covered wars from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patagonia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>; and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuisinart</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">La-Z-Boy</ENAMEX>, and bubble <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX>. All of the obits
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">speak</ENAMEX> fondly of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>, save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>: Former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX> is
castigated for both his racism and his superficial renunciation of it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>,
the profile argues, claimed to have repudiated racism but used issues such as
crime and welfare as veils for old-school segregationist politics. The most
lives seem to have been lived by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eldridge Cleaver</ENAMEX>, who spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> as a
convicted criminal, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Black Panther</ENAMEX>, a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moonie</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mormon</ENAMEX>, and a conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
