
   
   
      
         
            Hi, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fidelity</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the likely easing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of some
restrictions governing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> also flags this story in its front-page
news box. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> reefers the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> story at the bottom of its front, while leading
with the endorsement by new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray Davis</ENAMEX> in his inaugural
address of a plan to increase diversity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s university system by
admitting the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> of each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> high school graduating class.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that the proposal would counter the effects of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Proposition</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">209</NUMEX>--which among other things banned affirmative action in state university
admissions--by raising the numbers of minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> admitted at the expense
apparently of other higher-achieving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> elsewhere. The state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of</ENAMEX>
Regents, of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, could take up the idea <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>. The
biggest mystery of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> has to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead, which also covers the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> inaugural. The story somehow
manages not to mention the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> solution. ("Specific policy proposals,"
explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , "will be saved for release later in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>.")

            Is this merely faulty reporting or a conscious attempt not to alert the
majority of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that a law they voted for--but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is
against--is about to be undone? Similar news tailoring seems to be going on at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which in an inside story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, delays until the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-to-last paragraph word of his <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> plan and never mentions that it
threatens to undo Prop 209.

            The main upshot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> moves, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> would be able to receive more money from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and family
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, there'd be more direct flights between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and direct
mail service would be reestablished. Additionally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Orioles</ENAMEX> would
be allowed to play the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> national baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, once here and once in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. The papers report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> recommended the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> ease-up to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and that he is expected to announce it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            The papers all note that despite the new measures, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration is nonetheless resisting bipartisan calls for a more sweeping
opening to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, such as dropping the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37-year-old</TIMEX> economic embargo altogether.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> offers a domestic political reason for this continued
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intransigence</ENAMEX>: a desire not to hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>
presidential election. "That's something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> can do right after he's elected,"
the paper quotes a "senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>" as saying.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> emphasizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> angle a bit more than the others, even
working that detail into its headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Ready to Play Ball with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX>' losing record <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX>, leading the reader
to wonder why they, rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series-</ENAMEX>winning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, were tapped
for this bit of diplomacy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> advances a plausible answer: unlike
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> don't suit up any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defectors</ENAMEX>. None of the papers
mention why <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> may be especially well suited to this particular irenic
cause: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> was once a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>, even drafted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX>.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story reports on the latest impeachment defense thinking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. One
example according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> : The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are planning to
argue that when their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> denied he had sexual relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, he could have been focusing on the role of intent made relevant by
the definition of sexual relations he was given. That definition referred to
fondling certain parts of the anatomy "with an intent to arouse or gratify the
sexual desire of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>," and it could be argued that no one has proved
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had any such intent even if he did in fact touch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> as she
testified. In other words, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s earlier position was that he didn't
have sex with her, this new move is that he didn't have sex with her on
purpose. Note that for this to work, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have to argue that
not only was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> not trying to gratify <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, but he wasn't trying to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gratify</ENAMEX> himself either. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puhhhhleeeeze</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> front features a story recounting horror tales of domestic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">servants</ENAMEX> brought to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> area by various foreign diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> and
then treated horribly. A separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> inside focuses on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s
tale of working for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> without any time off for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three cents</NUMEX> a day for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">staffer</ENAMEX>, who also beat her. A question: Before doing these stories, did the
Post look into whether or not any of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are likewise
underpaying, or otherwise mistreating their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>? Not to mention making
sure they have proper visas and legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> withholdings.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP TV</ENAMEX> column reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Franken</ENAMEX>, in preparing a new spate of
shows for his about-to-be-resuscitated news spoof "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lateline</ENAMEX>," reached out to
various political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> to do some script doctoring. For a show having to do
with something called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moral Coalition</ENAMEX>," for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franken</ENAMEX> got former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> the script. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jokes.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> censor cut <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for being too racy.

         
      
   
