
   
   
      
         
            Can <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America Stand Pat</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s
report on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> problem. (The report was first discussed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> runs a story on it
inside, as does the New York
Times .) The top non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is the consummation of
the long-awaited deal by which the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> have agreed to pay a lumber <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$480 million</NUMEX> to preserve
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Headwaters Forest</ENAMEX>, which had been the largest stand of
ancient redwoods in private hands. This also makes the LAT front. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Headwaters</ENAMEX> too, but leads instead with growing support in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for walling off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> funds from the rest of the federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>. The main divide among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of the move, the story explains, is
between those who want to do it now and those who want to do it gradually.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> introduced a gradual plan. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gradualism</ENAMEX> has the
advantage of allowing for a combination of new spending and tax cuts near-term
and shoring up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> in the long haul. The story delays until the
13th paragraph the news that all current talk of budget surpluses depends on
counting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> among general revenues, and never mentions that in
business accounting, earmarked pension funds are not considered among a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>'s
assets.

            The subhead over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> story says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> report "cites
vulnerability but little risk of disaster" and the story proper quickly
includes calming words from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>. Nonetheless mentioned are potential
problems with paychecks and medical records, and accidental nuclear launches.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead stresses the risks a bit more, with its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> paragraph
mentioning computer crashes, disruptions leading to civil unrest in some
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and the risk of terrorist attacks amid the resulting confusion.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> plays terrorism lower. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> make the point that whatever Y2K
risks there are will be more acute in many foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> than in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead reports the murder of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bwindi Impenetrable Forest</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> to see rare mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX>. The story also makes the LAT
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> among the dead were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> were said to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of machete-wielding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>,
remnants of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> that massacred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half a million</NUMEX> rival <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tutsi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tribesmen</ENAMEX> and moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes that
tourist treks aiming to see mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorillas</ENAMEX> became popular after the movie
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gorillas in the Mist</ENAMEX>," about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dian Fossey</ENAMEX>, but oddly does not
mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fossey</ENAMEX> was also murdered in the jungle.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes above the fold with a picture for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s decision
to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> time. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, the paper
reports, launched his effort with a speech criticizing economic globalism, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>, immigration, affirmative action and abortion. His peroration was "As they
say, mount up and ride to the sound of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report" informs that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
capability to accept tax payments via credit card has become unexpectedly
popular among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-wealthy</ENAMEX>. Already, says the paper, at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> have asked to charge <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $1 million and $9 million</NUMEX> on their Amex
or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX>. And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 20</NUMEX> have asked to charge <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $100,000</NUMEX>. Can you
guess why? Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> points out, charging <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 million</NUMEX> could rack
up enough frequent flier miles to buy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> first-class round trip tickets
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>.

            The claws are out and the fur is flying as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> show, (during which,
reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a "good kisser" who
"struggles with his sensuality") opens <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>. The LAT front quotes a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX> saying, "This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s appetite for the salacious, the sexy and
the personal is truly a bottomless pit...." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentator</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX>,
who goes on to say, "Most pudgy little princesses from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> don't get
themselves into this kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jam</ENAMEX> and make all this money." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX> and TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Regan</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> "isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. She's an adulterer and she
should be walking around with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">scarlet</ENAMEX> A." And she "seemed more interested in
making money than contemplating the deep meaning of her actions." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regan</ENAMEX> tried and failed to land the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> book, but
didn't mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regan</ENAMEX>'s commitment to asceticism and deep contemplation
included publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
