
   
   
      
         
            Impeaching Cobblers

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s mood as it prepares to conduct the impeachment trial.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> puts its daily take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
inside and goes instead with a story first tipped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> will
propose a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> tax credit for those requiring long-term medical care
or for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> who take care of them, a proposal that is also fronted by
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . The latter leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> snowstorm and
the travel havoc it's wreaking.

            The main news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' leads is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s chat shows--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
senatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> talked, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> --and the main new
information coming from them is that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
should postpone his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address if the scheduled date--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>
19th--should find his fate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> still unresolved. This suggestion,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , "signals a growing recognition that the impeachment trial
will inevitably slow, if not stop, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> from conducting the public's
routine business." (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> wishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> had noted here that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
produced virtually no non-budgetary legislation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> even without such a
distraction.)

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX> are
emerging as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of a full trial with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, in opposition to the
fast-track view favored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lieberman</ENAMEX> and several
others. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House-Senate</ENAMEX> divide on impeachment matters is put on sharp
display in a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Face the Nation"</ENAMEX> remark by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Leahy</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
quoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> : "They flunked the exam in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. They hope to do
a make-up exam in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, and that's not going to happen."

            The papers report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s long-term tax credit proposal will be accompanied by a
call for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to distribute over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX> $<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million</NUMEX> per annum to state and local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> for support to caregivers. Also,
the plan will call for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to locate affordable long-term
care policies for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. There is no firm word in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> about how
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.2 billion</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over five years</TIMEX>) program will be financed, although their
educated guess is that the money will come from eliminating some corporate tax
loopholes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story has a lot of missing nuts and bolts. For
instance, how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> would the proposal affect? Is the
credit duplicated or divided among multiple caregivers for the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>? And
doesn't a tax credit ignore the plight of the disabled and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caregivers</ENAMEX> who
owe <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $1,000</NUMEX> in taxes? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> raises this last point and says
the credit does those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> no good--no small matter, since, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> goes
on to explain, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of the elderly pay no income taxes at all.

            By the way, an administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that he's happy
if the proposal helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on the impeachment front, "but that's not the
rationale for it."

            A WSJ front-page feature documents the frenzy of interest in Internet stocks. On-line auction company
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay Inc.</ENAMEX>, for instance, recently in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only ten weeks</TIMEX> increased its stock value
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> times, a feat it took <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> to achieve. But the trend, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says, doesn't just signify the surge of a particular market
sector--rather it shows the rising degree to which online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are
influencing the market. And since these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> move in and out of stocks at the
drop of a low-commission web trade, the upshot is that investor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stampedes</ENAMEX> can
now happen faster than ever before.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story reports how the rather militant advocacy of
condom use by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX> may be the way to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> situation
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> from going the way of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. At the very least, the stance has helped
keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> infection rate among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX> (going rate: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cents</ENAMEX>) at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 5 percent</NUMEX>, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 50 percent</NUMEX> for those in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bombay</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT front runs a feature detailing the battle in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> between
"hacktivists"--politically-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX>--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> over the
so-called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Chinese Firewall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>'s system of filters designed to keep
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> from accessing online news and other sites that induce doubt
about the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> line. Besides the obvious politically sensitive
sites, according to the piece the official firewall servers also screen out the
likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parents</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacker groups</ENAMEX> operate, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> continents and include contingents in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of their latest tactics is their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unverified</ENAMEX> claim that they have inserted
into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> computer system a program that allows users' screens to be
viewed remotely by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hackers</ENAMEX>. In a spoof of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Office</ENAMEX>"
program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> call this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan Horse</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back Orifice</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
