
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Goes</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> is dead.

            Come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> will depart and make room
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX>--but not yet announced--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> was dropped
at a hastily convened meeting at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 this morning</TIMEX>. Indeed, many of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> were still sipping their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> when word went
out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> wanted to address "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>." And so they gathered in what is
known as "the piazza," an open space adjacent to the corridor where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>'s senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> sit.

            Sporting a simple blue suit, her hair streaked with just the right amount of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> walked into the piazza and started speaking while stragglers were
still making their way up the stairs. This was, she said, a very difficult
thing to do, but she had been presented with an opportunity that she simply
couldn't refuse. After uttering the usual platitudes about how <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> is the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in the business, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> became farklempt
as she pronounced, "I love you all." Then, of course, came the hugs--along with
tears from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>'s inner-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> who are surely wondering what all
of this means for them.

            And what does it mean for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> can only speculate.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> is certainly responsible for bringing in most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s hottest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, and here we're referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like the unrivaled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Gladwell</ENAMEX>, both of whom cut their teeth at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . Some will probably follow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> to her next stop, a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> venture
formed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> that will publish a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and books, as well as
produce films and television shows. (She will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairwoman</ENAMEX> and a part
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.)

            But what will become of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ? During <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>'s tenure, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> were always talking about "the mix"--the never-ending
struggle to strike the right balance between the slashy and the serious. The
charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> was too fond of the former is by now a cliche. It is also
probably the last thing on the mind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Si Newhouse</ENAMEX>, who suddenly
seems concerned with turning a profit at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. And who can blame him?
greatest money pits in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> magazine history." Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florio</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> has lost a whopping <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$175 million</NUMEX>. It's no
space with the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Si</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>.

            As for who will preside over this dark day in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> history, we
can only report what we have gleaned from the rumor mill over on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">43rd Street</ENAMEX>.
The most obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> seems to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graydon Carter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> (if not
celebrated) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> who has perfected the formula for the
profile that simultaneously glamorizes and eviscerates its subject. It seems
less likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> will go with an inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, though if he does, the best choice might be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Stewart</ENAMEX>, a
respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newspaperman</ENAMEX> who did a tour as Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>. Dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> include Remnick
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Andersen</ENAMEX>. To this mix, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> would like to add a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> of its
own: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chip McGrath</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> . A
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff member</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker , McGrath</ENAMEX> was passed over when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gottlieb</ENAMEX> acceded to power, but over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> he has done a
bang-up job at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Review</ENAMEX> , giving it all of the heft of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Review of Books</ENAMEX> with none of the intellectual snobbery. All the while,
he has been writing nifty pop culture pieces for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine</ENAMEX> , so he seems to have that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredient</ENAMEX> of "the mix" covered as
well.

            Place your bets.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Mahler</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
