
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Company Not Excluded</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s anticipated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> not guilty votes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second day in a row</TIMEX>, gives the top
of the paper to something else--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to the horrors of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>'s
famine--and tucks impeachment just underneath, but festooned by the front's
boldest headline type.

            The papers spend most of their impeachment ink counting votes and recounting
bits of closed-door speeches press-released to them. They note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olympia Snowe</ENAMEX>'s announcement that she will vote to acquit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on both impeachment articles means there's a very good chance the
perjury charge won't even get a simple majority, and some chance that the
obstruction charge won't either. It's also reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> might vote no on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or both articles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is most definite
about this, citing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> close to her saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> will vote no twice.

            On the other hand, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> also widely thought
to be not guilty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bennett</ENAMEX>, announced
their intention to convict on both articles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> as
predicting that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>" will become "a synonym for an elegant, well-crafted
lie." But this isn't much worse than the remarks by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Feinstein</ENAMEX>
quoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> : "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> acted immorally. He acted recklessly.
He acted disgracefully. He willfully misled the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and his judicial system. In doing so, he brought shame
and dishonor upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and especially upon himself." And
she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> .

            The papers say that after the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midday</TIMEX> impeachment vote a formal censure of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will fail. Then there will be an attempt at an informal censure, which,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> explains, would be read into the record but not acted on.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s solemn mood was "somewhat tarnished" by
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> planned an all-out drive to help <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> win back the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House.</ENAMEX> Wonder why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> doesn't mention that it was where those
reports <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> appeared. The papers mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> plans to address the
nation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> after the trial's conclusion and that he will be mindful not to
repeat the celebratory mood of that post-impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Lawn</ENAMEX> pep rally. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WP</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX>'s response to the question, What did he want
to hear from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? "As little as possible."

            A story reefered on the WP front quotes "several knowledgeable
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>" as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> will seriously consider whether to
run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> once the
impeachment trial is over.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> top front features an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, complete with a large color photo
of the heavily made up and made over stay-at-home federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX>. According
to the story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> says she betrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to save her from being
abused by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. "I would hope some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> would do for my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> what I did for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, despite the fact that it looks horrible...,"
the paper quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> saying as she broke down in tears. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> also says that
it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s idea for her to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>, and for her to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reveal Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s affair to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> also tells the
Times that she had her first discussion with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October, 1997</TIMEX>. She also admits telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> the lie that she was turning
over on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> had also been the target of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> sting
operation.

            Everybody fronts the precedent-setting verdict of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> finding that
several <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> were legally responsible for the criminal use of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firearms</ENAMEX>, awarding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> in damages to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenager</ENAMEX> wounded in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
shooting. The decision is likely, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, to lead more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and more
shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> to mount such liability lawsuits. It's a bit curious that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , a paper read in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with its share of shootings, chooses to put
the story on the very bottom of the front page, below a story about the
scandal-driven rise in sex talk and one about the possibility of more flights
being added at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Airport</ENAMEX>. Similarly, why is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> waiting
until page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> to tell us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has decided to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> as part of a multi-national peace-keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>? And why is
everybody else likewise paying little attention to this?

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front-pager claims that despite a stock price and profits that
continue to climb, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s power in the computing world is beginning to
wane. The story points out that in contrast to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, a few computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are now offering PCs not just with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> instead of Internet
Explorer but even with non-Windows operating systems. Also, the story notes
even though Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> consolidation continues to proceed at a furious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pace</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> hasn't made a major acquisition since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> brought its case
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uh</ENAMEX>, like, wasn't that the problem in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire state Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> shouldn't gloat when he
attends a fund-raiser in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, but adds, "I'm not sure anyone
[there] can control their passion."

         
      
   
