
   
   
      
         
            Whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Ox</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>?

            With little news breaking on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with dependably
worrisome issues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> sets off on a whirlwind tour of trouble
spots all over the planet (potential violence in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, economic crisis in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>) and frets about the impact of
impeachment on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> stewardship of global stability. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reviews weather-induced havoc in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead describes the easy end run that insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> have found around the
legally mandated minimum coverage for mental illness. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mental Health</ENAMEX>
Parity Act only requires that dollar limits on mental health coverage equal
those for general medical services. So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> simply mete out
treatments in non-monetary denominations, like number of visits and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is expected to close the loopholes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.

            The LAT fronts a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-day-old</TIMEX> interview in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
prevaricates about how to handle his role in an impeachment trial. Yes, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> requires him only to preside over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and to break any tied
vote on verdict or procedure. But can he lobby <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> to vote against
impeachment? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> opines that it would be "inappropriate" for him to
"buttonhole" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hedges</ENAMEX>--if he's asked, he will "feel free to
communicate with them in full." In this spirit of indecision, the interview was
conducted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, "downplayed" by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, and then "embargoed"
until the safety of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> news lull. Meanwhile, the piece doesn't
articulate the stickiest and most obvious of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>'s conflicts of
interest: how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s own presidential ambitions could influence his performance
as referee.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the LAT front the agreement between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belarus</ENAMEX> to merge their currencies, synchronize trade, and relax political
barriers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LAT</ENAMEX> describes the deal as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step of a full-on
merger, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that a) it's not really a merger, because
the plans are just too vague and b) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belarussians</ENAMEX> are considerably more
gung-ho about it than their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. The deal brings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> the
chance to flex its slackened superpower muscles, but at the cost of providing
shelter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belarus</ENAMEX>' destitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, bankrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and bone-dry
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belarus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lukashenko</ENAMEX>'s dubious record: he extended his term in a dummy referendum, and
has been known to gag the opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> and imprison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports inside that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have been able to protect
an eggshell-fragile cease-fire in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story inside the WP
reports that Western monitoring forces will continue to saturate the area in
order to prevent more fighting. However, ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> seem eager to
shatter it at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any minute</TIMEX>: "We will win or we will turn to dust," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .

            A survey by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> tolerate but do not
condone homosexuality. A front-page feature, one in a series on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American</ENAMEX>
Values", maps out the ambivalence many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> feel about the issue: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72%</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> call "gay sex" unacceptable, but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a robust 87%</NUMEX> say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>
should have equal rights and opportunities in the workplace. The piece suggests
that gay rights may become the same kind of ideological litmus test for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">electoral</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> as abortion. However, the ideological confusion reported
in the survey is complicated by unclear statistical reporting: although the
credentials of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> are described at length, the size and nature of
the sample is not.

            The WP front page also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> are no longer
relying on simple tote-bag-giveaways to raise viewer contributions. Instead,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> are scrapping their fusty regulars for fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and self-help
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gurus</ENAMEX> who capture minds and pocketbooks with lectures on "spiritual healing"
and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de</ENAMEX>-toxifying your negative emotions." Reaction within the public
television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> has ranged from sheepishness to horror. But perhaps these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> are banking on very, very long-term loyalty. The title of one
videotape sent to thank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> for their pledges by "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lecturer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>, investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>
Null: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How to Live Forever</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
