
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lovely Linda</ENAMEX>

            "She can't dance/She can't sing...but she's got to be a part of that pop
music thing." The words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Crenshaw</ENAMEX>, who once played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX> in
Beatlemania , came to mind <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> with the news of the death of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda McCartney</ENAMEX>. For most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> was one of the most universally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ridiculed</ENAMEX> figures in pop music, her shortcomings as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> all
too vivid on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul's</ENAMEX> records and, especially, his tours. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wag</ENAMEX>
got his hands on a soundboard tape of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>'s microphone during a performance
of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey, Jude</ENAMEX>," and radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> put its one flat note into heavy rotation.
That, combined with the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groupie</ENAMEX>-in-shutterbug's-clothing
conjured up by an infamous piece from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay Felker</ENAMEX> era at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> , established <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> as a figure of almost singular unpopularity (the
"almost" courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoko Ono</ENAMEX>, who in the public's addled mind, bore the added
stigma of breaking up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>.)

            Why this should be, when it wasn't her idea to join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wings</ENAMEX> in the first
place, and when by all available evidence she kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX> wildly
happy--and with him raised a flock of spirited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> whose achievements are
beginning to come to light? Had she been born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years earlier</TIMEX>, she would have
been the decorative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> who kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> satisfied as she gave him a
stable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades later</TIMEX>, she'd have been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baby Spice</ENAMEX> with a brain,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Love</ENAMEX> on speaking terms with her biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Abdul</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> instead of a choreographer.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> now becomes the odds-on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Album of the Year</ENAMEX>
Grammy, but it's worth noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Moments</ENAMEX> in his life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s death in
particular, have not brought out the best in him. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>
hoped he'd serve up wrenching, emotional music--his version of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>" from
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plastic Ono Band</ENAMEX>"--and it just doesn't seem to be in his nature. All the same,
the critical re-assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> is already upon us, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>'s death will
speed things along. That assessment will overrate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>'s post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>
output--in particular, I'm guessing, the music he makes next, just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tug</ENAMEX> of
War was overrated in the wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s murder--and underrate his work in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>, an explosion of pop craftsmanship without precedence, overshadowed
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lennon</ENAMEX>'s mediagenic personality and subsequent martyrdom. I feel like in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, it'll be safe for me once more to admit that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> was my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">favorite Beatle</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bitch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bitch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bitch</ENAMEX>: I've always been grateful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Wurtzel</ENAMEX>
for teaching me the meaning of the word <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schadenfreude</ENAMEX> . It was a concept
that came up a lot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> immediately following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s installation
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> of my acquaintance
gleefully counted down the moments until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wurtzel</ENAMEX> was deposed as pop music
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>. Her writing since certainly confirms that rock 'n' roll was not her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX>, but the idea that the value of her provocative thoughts is
somehow debased by her candor about her personal life, or by her willingness to
appear topless on the cover of her book, is hilarious. In case you missed it:
that battle was fought in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> won. So get over it... My first
(and only) conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wurtzel</ENAMEX>, during a sort-of job interview, placed
her on my short list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fluff & Folders</ENAMEX>, right alongside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Sawyer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fluff & Folders</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so charming on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> meeting that
if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> were to ask me, "Can you do my laundry <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">tonight?</ENAMEX>" my only response would
be, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fluff & fold?</ENAMEX>"...

            
               A Magazine About Nothing: There's plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buckshot</ENAMEX> being sprayed at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Hirschberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> in the wake of l'affaire
Seinfeld , in which the sitcom icon obtained a pre-publication copy of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> story being written about him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VF</ENAMEX> says their investigation
indicates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirschberg</ENAMEX> gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> the piece herself. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hirschberg</ENAMEX> denies the
charge. Believe whom you will, but it's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jerry</ENAMEX> who behaved most caddishly by
reading a yet-to- close story about himself, requesting corrections, firing his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">publicist</ENAMEX>, and afterwards--his stated pleasure in the story
notwithstanding--leaving both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and magazine twisting in the wind publicly
by not taking the blame for wanting to check out the piece in advance. Like he
doesn't know that's against the rules.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Connelly</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
