
   
   
      
         
            Listing Badly

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> impeachment trial continues to dominate, leading all around for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">umpteenth day</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s plot point is the impending vote on whether or not
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> should depose (in closed sessions, on videotape; public testimony in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> would require another vote) the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>
have requested--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>. The
witness list was shortened, says the coverage, in order to attract more votes.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX> should also see, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, a vote on a motion to summarily
dismiss the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' consensus is that the
votes are there for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> but not for the dismissal. The papers flag
another developing witness issue: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> have urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to
ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to voluntarily testify, a request the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has already
rebuffed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>'s visit is also a staple of the fronts. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
the headline reads, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Thanks John Paul for 'Spiritual Guidance</ENAMEX>.'"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says the inclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> in the
trial would extend it to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least mid-February</NUMEX>. Everybody notes that one of the
arguments put forward by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX> against
calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> is that it would necessitate a comprehensive "discovery"
process that could lengthen things by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.

            Everybody notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> have promised the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> that they
would question <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> without getting into any sexual details. Regarding
these matters, they would, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , merely ask her to reaffirm
her grand jury testimony. They would instead focus on what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> knew about
matters relating to the obstruction charge, such as her job search and her gift
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peregrinations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
say that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> remained on the short list because he was not called back to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> testified to it and hence has never been asked
about some of her recollections. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> is wanted because of the
possibility that his testimony will illustrate how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lies to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> were
used to spin the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> and for his alleged role in planting negative
stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The big surprise in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>' list is that it does
not include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> saying that this was
because her account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> coaching her is undisputed. Regarding why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is on the list, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Bryant</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, may have given away the
game with his reason, quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times : Wouldn't you want, he asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, to observe her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">demeanor</ENAMEX> and "look into her eyes"?

            The ethical murkiness involved in reporting this scandal is apparent in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> contend with the rule that makes it illegal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to
comment on what is said in their closed door sessions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes an unidentified
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> characterizing both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s off-limits meetings, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> refers to several unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> in its description of a
witness-related compromise being worked out behind closed doors. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , obviously relying on the accounts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>, says that the sessions sometimes involve shouting. Now, didn't
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> who spoke to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> do something as illegal as perjury? And
aren't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, in encouraging them to do so, guilty of the equivalent of
suborning perjury?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> say that a fresh report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX>
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>'s weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s regime is
continuing to conceal past and present illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> programs. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> papers
note that the report has created new tensions between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>,
which wants to lift the sanctions currently binding on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. In light of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, the lead editorial at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian/China/France</ENAMEX>
anti-sanction stance, "make-believe."

            The LAT front and inside stories at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aircrews to adopt more
aggressive rules of engagement as they enforce the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> "no-fly" zones. They
are not limited any more to attacking whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> assets attack them, but
may also strike at any part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> air defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> that's endangering
their missions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead editorial points out that this new more
aggressive stance does not necessarily have the endorsement of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">therein</ENAMEX> lies one of the hidden crises behind the manifest one: While one
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> are locked in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>, the
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> is unilaterally making foreign policy. And the press is
contributing to this myopia. When was the last piece you read noticing the
parallels between our no-fly enforcement and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf of Tonkin</ENAMEX> naval presence
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 60s</TIMEX> or between our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> mission and the ill-fated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX>?
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story reporting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> may send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> runs
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> and doesn't mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Act</ENAMEX>. Which, in fact, despite the
quite widespread deployment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in hot scenarios, is virtually never
mentioned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
