
   
   
      
         
            Save the <I>Snooze</I>!

            Nothing delights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox's Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> as much as poking fun
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> . "Apropos of nothing (again), <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News goes with a military cover: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Submarine</ENAMEX>!," gloated
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> recently in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Other Magazines"</ENAMEX> column. "(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three weeks ago</TIMEX>, it
published an equally untimely cover on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20th century</TIMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX>.)"
It's easy to bash a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> does the same thing at dinner parties,
when he isn't shopping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s job all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. That's what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX> is up to, if a profile in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washingtonian</ENAMEX> is to be
believed.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s unsolicited advice to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shush</ENAMEX>. A
quick review of the charges generally leveled at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Fallows</ENAMEX>, a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> big-think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and much-made-fun-of media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>. He
prefers the long view to the short run, stinting reporting for analysis. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. He
has little or no news judgment. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is boring.

            Point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is just not true--if anything there's too much information in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> piece. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> wrote somewhere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, reading a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snooze</ENAMEX> article rather like being buttonholed by a retired admiral with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> too much time on his hands. But you get more hard facts and historical data
from the admiral than from almost any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.

            Point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Translation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX> runs stories no one else runs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s poor
news judgment is another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s smart market positioning. Rather than go up
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> with fewer resources, he publishes
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> -style tweaks on the news and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scours</ENAMEX> beats
undercovered by the other newsweeklies: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, the auto industry,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, religion. Hence the (quite enthralling) cover story on life aboard a
nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX>.

            Point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> is not untrue, but not new either. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snooze</ENAMEX> is actually
less boring than it used to be, and besides, newsweeklies are boring by
definition. The task of boiling down what the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> needs to know
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each week</TIMEX> is fundamentally unglamorous. Nobody in the media really respects
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newsweeklies</ENAMEX>--not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> who work there, who would rather be pushing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">envelope</ENAMEX>, not their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> in journalism, who measure a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>'s worth by
the number of his scoops. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> outside the media bubble (and that's
everyone who makes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsweekly</ENAMEX> his primary news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>) want their world
reliably summarized. They don't care about the very latest wrinkle in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft-Department of Justice</ENAMEX> antitrust negotiations. They don't need a fancy
you-were-there lead.

            Which leads us to what has inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox's</ENAMEX> news-peg-less rant (in the
best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallovian</ENAMEX> tradition): the juxtaposition in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past weeks</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pieces of
cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reportage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prophets of Pop Culture" and</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Entertainers</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th Century</TIMEX>." By media-bubble
standards, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's package outstrips <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> 's by a furlong.
There are fancy names--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Douglas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Vendler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terry</ENAMEX>
Teachout, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Tannen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witold Rybczynski, Ingrid Sischy</ENAMEX>--and
up<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-to-the-minute</TIMEX> critical judgments. And yet the cumulative effect is
oppressive. There's too much too read. Everything is monumental. Everyone is
celebrated. The world just isn't that dramatic and fabulous. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Culturebox</ENAMEX> wound
up loathing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Joyce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T.S. Eliot</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> with equal passion. What
else can you feel about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was "the shifting, stormy center of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
popular music in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very century</TIMEX> when the music was
invented"?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , on the other hand, has neither names nor big-deal profile
subjects. Its package is sizzle-free, shorter (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15</NUMEX> vs. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">146</NUMEX> pages), and
infinitely more original. The choice of profilees reflects not a fixation on
celebrity but an enthusiasm for the underappreciated: network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarnoff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Paley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who created television as we know it; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hemingway</ENAMEX>, interestingly seen as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> nonfiction; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crosby</ENAMEX>, rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> emerged from the experience
modestly enlightened, rather than desperately out of breath. Which, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>,
is all she asks.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
