
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lingua Franca</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> for academic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX>, have a hot scoop: They've learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Mackay</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of an
acclaimed new biography, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Graham Bell</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wiley</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sons</ENAMEX>), has been accused of plagiarizing substantial portions of his book from a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bell by Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert V. Bruce</ENAMEX>.
(What does Culturebox mean by "acclaimed"? For once, that question actually has
a good answer: Former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholar editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Epstein</ENAMEX> devoted a
three-and-a-half page review to the book <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last April</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> called it "compelling." To its credit, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's review hinted strongly at the possibility of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plagiarism</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> emeritus at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University</ENAMEX>, has argued in a letter to
Wiley that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mackay</ENAMEX>'s book is heavily indebted to him for much of its research,
structure, and even language. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> doesn't know the first thing about
plagiarism law, but she has looked through both books (cursorily, it's true)
and sees what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> means: Several passages, including descriptions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">birthplace</ENAMEX>, of a demonstration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s "harmonic telegraph," and of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s
battles with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward M. Gallaudet</ENAMEX> over sign language, are startlingly similar.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mackay</ENAMEX> uses the same details and quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> uses, even putting them in the
same order, albeit with slight changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX>. The flow of narrative in
several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mackay</ENAMEX>'s books echoes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce's</ENAMEX>, without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Mackay</ENAMEX> having
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">improved Bruce</ENAMEX>'s insights much. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mackay</ENAMEX>'s book, however, is shorter (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">310</NUMEX> pages
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">497</NUMEX>).

            But the real shocker is that in his acknowledgements, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mackay</ENAMEX> thanks the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic Society</ENAMEX> for allowing him use of their vast archival
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holdings on Bell</ENAMEX>, in what he calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Room</ENAMEX>. In fact, as Lingua
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franca</ENAMEX> 's trusty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have confirmed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> archives were
transferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic Society</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Room</ENAMEX> no longer exists. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>
looked at papers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Room</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic Society</ENAMEX>, as he
makes clear in his acknowledgements, and cites them in his footnotes
regularly. It's hard not to conclude, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mackay</ENAMEX>'s mistake, that he never
actually saw those papers, except as they were written up in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX>'s book.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiley</ENAMEX> has put a hold on further shipments of the book. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
corporate communications, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Spilka</ENAMEX>, points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiley</ENAMEX> is not the
original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>: It licensed the book from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> house <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mainstream</ENAMEX>
Publishing. But, she says, "We are encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James MacKay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bruce</ENAMEX> to
amicably resolve the matter." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> isn't talking, but he does confirm that
he's negotiating a settlement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiley</ENAMEX> and tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> he'll probably
have more to say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. Stay tuned.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
