
   
   
      
         
            Worth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRENTWOOD</ENAMEX> -- "I am so fucked."

            It's not exactly "Where's the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>," or "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoomp</ENAMEX>, there it is" or "Read my
lips," but as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catchphrases</ENAMEX> go, it looked like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>'s odds-on
choice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> back. The line was to have been uttered by a
camcorder-wielding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Godzilla</ENAMEX> , as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>'s scaly foot
came thundering down towards him. Godzilla , though, wanted a PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
rating, which--by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPAA</ENAMEX> lore, if not regulation--limits a movie to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> "fuck."
The epithet was apparently already being used elsewhere in the movie, and so
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> did not survive.

            And what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> would you most expect to use the phrase in real
life? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>, whose film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> recently had its nationwide
release moved to just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> opens ( Bulworth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">debuts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> nationwide next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>). They call it counter-programming, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> calls it suicide. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bulworth</ENAMEX> throughout its entire theatrical run can gross what
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> makes over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Memorial</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day holiday</TIMEX>, there will be champagne
all around at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>.

            That, of course, is the kind of bottom-line thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> says he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">despises</ENAMEX>. So let us not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulworth</ENAMEX> on the basis of its box office.
But let us not judge it on the basis of its noble intentions, either. Is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> really "a celluloid shiv..shoved deep in the heart of
the...status quo"? Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> asserts that private enterprise has a stranglehold
on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics. This is a surprise to whom, exactly? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s press
interviews--filled with wonderful anecdotes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford Odets</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huey Newton</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>--have been more entertaining than a lot of the movie, much of
which is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> rapping, and rapping badly. It's an updating of the idea that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drove Ishtar</ENAMEX> : that we'll be endlessly tickled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suave</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
looking (intentionally) goofy. That, I fear, is a miscalculation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s
image isn't so iconic in the minds of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s moviegoer that subverting it is
wildly hilarious. As for the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulworth</ENAMEX> the politicized <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-Boy</ENAMEX> could
send shivers down the spines of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Murdochs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perelmans</ENAMEX> of the
world....please.

            Granted, this is a smart, provocative movie, with a performance from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oliver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Platt</ENAMEX> that is truly off-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tha</NUMEX>-hook, a film reflective of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>-long
concerns over the corruption of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> by money. Why it's being released
now--instead of in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX>, when more serious-minded moviegoers could warm to
it and keep it commercially viable through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first quarter</TIMEX> award <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>--is
anyone's guess. But just like the rappers with whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> hung out to prep
this picture, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> has a pretty good idea of what subject really
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obsesses Beatty</ENAMEX>, and he hasn't touched it since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shampoo</ENAMEX>. Why not? It
seems a waste. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> not making movies about sex is like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>
not making movies about conspiracies.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Connelly</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
