
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kip Kinkels</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">19th Century</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Jonesboro</ENAMEX>, now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>--are schoolyard shoot-'em-ups the product
of inadequate gun regulation or violence on TV? Let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> stop you before
you debate this silly point again! The answer is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, whatever Sissela
"Mayhem" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bok</ENAMEX> may tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . How does <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> know?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teenagers</ENAMEX> have been up to this sort of thing since long before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mighty Morphin Power Rangers</ENAMEX> . Take this scene from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s favorite childhood book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Farmer Boy</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Ingalls</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilder</ENAMEX>, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilder</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s memories of growing up in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 19th century</TIMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Almanzo Wilder</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>, is loath to go to school because he hates watching the
school's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> toughest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> beat up yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and drive him out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingalls</ENAMEX> writes: "These big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen or seventeen years old</TIMEX> and
they came to school only in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the winter</TIMEX> term. They came to thrash
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and break up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. They boasted that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> could finish
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> term, and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> had."

            Literary embellishment? The exaggerations of memory? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Kett</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Virginia</ENAMEX> and the leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> of adolescence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kett</ENAMEX> cites an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1837</TIMEX> report written by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of public education himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace Mann</ENAMEX>. In it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX> calls for reform
to correct an intractable problem: the "breaking up of rural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>." "It had
the status of a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX> practice," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kett</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Schoolmasters</ENAMEX> often expected
to be tossed out the window. Sometimes it was just a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> ritual to let off
steam. Other times it was not so much fun."

            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> activies common in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 19th-century</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kett</ENAMEX>:
wild student riots on college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>, sometimes leading to the deaths of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1820s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> set off a keg of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gunpowder</ENAMEX>); high school duels involving knives or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, sometimes culminating
in the deaths of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>; scrimmages between higher and lower classes,
sometimes leading to massive injuries on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side or the other, or both.

            What calmed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> down in the latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>? The introduction
of less brutal disciplinary methods; sports, particularly football; the
increased presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>; the levelling off of class differences between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX>, who were usually wealthier than their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, regularly underscored that point by beating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> up.)

            What about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>? "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> were not as ubiqitous at the time as you might
think," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kett</ENAMEX>. "They were very expensive because they had to be handmade."
That began to change in mid-century, with the development of small-arms
manufacturing. So where were the random <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooters</ENAMEX> of the second half of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19th-century</TIMEX>? "You have to remember that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kip Kinkels</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1850s</TIMEX> weren't
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kett</ENAMEX>. "Those kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just didn't go. If you were very
unhappy, you took off and went somewhere else. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of
perpetual rage, he'd probably wind up on a whaler."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
