
   
   
      
         
            Don't Ask Y2K

            As befits the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day of a holiday weekend</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> reheat and serve a
smorgasbord of mostly familiar issues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a budget forecast story: despite ample surpluses, spending caps mean
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> must scrounge together funds sufficient for its activist
domestic and military agenda. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the final story in its series on
tolerance and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> values. Spouting a long stream of poll numbers and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> quotes, the story pronounces that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' divergent opinions about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> reflect "an unresolved debate about fundamental values". Only
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> fronts the situation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>: the lead describes
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> attempts to lure <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> into missile range and threats to fire
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> patrolling the no-fly zone. The story appears inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>, but goes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unmentioned</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> front-pager reveals that condoms distributed to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> are not only unpopular and scarce--they're also defective. Condom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> dump their second-rate products in the region, and scattershot
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">inspection</ENAMEX> efforts fail to screen out the duds. As a result, many condoms
dispensed by well-meaning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are leaky,
corroded, or ill-fitting. So even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> who practice safe sex--the
putatively reliable way to protect themselves and stem the continent's <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
epidemic-- are still vulnerable to infection.

            The WP front describes how anti-drug efforts have trumped human
rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> policy towards <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> had cut off direct aid to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> military because of its dodgy record of corruption and
human-rights abuse. But now the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> will provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> with
training and funding for its war against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>, who are in cahoots
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Colombian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX> responsible for the bulk of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin smuggled</ENAMEX> into this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.

            An inside piece at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> explains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> factor behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>'s recent call to raise military pay: lured by high
salaries and quality of life, juicier retirement packages, and limitless
opportunity for advancement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> trained in finance and technology are
retreating to the private sector. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> quoted mentions
the "higher calling" of serving his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. But he also points out, "If you go
to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Andersen Consulting</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur Andersen</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coopers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lybrand</ENAMEX>, at
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX> point you'd be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> editorial page calls on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> "to fashion a strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> of censure that would require <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to acknowledge, at last, that
he lied under oath", and then to get on with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" says it's hard to predict how Chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX> would run an impeachment trial because a) his
much-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sough</NUMEX>-after book actually gives scant indication of what he thinks of the
process and b) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> would serve as officiator and not as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. So all we
have to go on, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX>'s general modus
operandi, which is by all accounts decisive, commanding, and efficient.

            An inside piece at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> quotes comments made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> while he was in office, but disclosed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only this week</TIMEX> in the lawsuit over
his still-unsettled estate. On his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Screw</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> and the rest."
On the military: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of bitches are not interested in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." On
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in government: "A pain in the neck, very difficult to handle." On <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>:
"There are just not enough competent ones, so you put incompetents in and get
along with them, because the symbolism is vitally important." Why? Well, said
the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, "you have to show you care."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager recites the litany of problems posed by Y2K
situation: too much code, too little time, too many unpredictable consequences.
The situation is spawning new cottage industries, including code-checking,
litigation over compliance, and community-preparedness movements. Another Y2K
growth area unmentioned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> : a surfeit of near-identical
stories featuring an increasingly familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>, and
predictions. Far more practical is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Magazine</ENAMEX>'s guide to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s millennial soothsayers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard W. Noone</ENAMEX> predicts that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 5</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, the planet's crust will shift and oceans will be frothed into "maelstroms
of death"; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meade Ministries</ENAMEX> warns that the "world will soon be engulfed in a
sticky white substance"; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Priestess of Morningland</ENAMEX> preaches that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> will land a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFO</ENAMEX> "the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priestess</ENAMEX> does not comment on the possibility that under the burden of Y2K
troubles, air traffic control will be down.

         
      
   
