
   
   
      
         
            Hijacks Hijinks

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> looming beyond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s groovy vibe, mostly
surrounding the issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> supply is drastically low. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About half</NUMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has only a day's supply of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> to transfuse, whereas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>
is the norm. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is to be applauded for closing the story with phone
numbers for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to call--a nice change from the tendency news sections too
often exhibit of viewing the guise of objectivity as more important than
actually helping somebody. In that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>, this space proposes that each member
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> give blood <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. Or come to think of it, let's not
leave out the media--how about saying you can't opine on TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> unless
you've rolled up your sleeve? (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And TP</ENAMEX> promises to give <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> too.)

            With the possible exception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have no one on
staff who's covered a presidential impeachment before, so they are still
feeling their way into the proper kind of coverage. So far, they've pretty much
opted to lead with the story whenever possible, regardless of whether or not
anything has actually happened. Thus we get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead falsely
telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> that disputes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, censure and the very
impeachability of the acts in question are "disagreements that became clear on
the television interview shows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>...." and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s flash that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s written response to the charges to be submitted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> will "not
break new ground."

            A front-page LAT piece observes that there are a number of
anniversaries coming up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that could stimulate popular
political expression and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s repression of same: the 10th
anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen</ENAMEX> massacre, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20th</NUMEX> anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democracy</ENAMEX>
Wall, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People's Republic of China</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">50th</NUMEX> birthday, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">80th</NUMEX> anniversary
of student activism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial notes that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
recent clampdown on political organizing, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> have been
arrested, and goes on to complain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has put
virtually no pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in response. For instance, says the paper, there
is no evidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> will propose even a mild censure of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for the
upcoming meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> has a word for
this attitude of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>: "deference."

            Some worrisome travel safety items <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> masquerading as airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> have been able to smuggle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>, hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">grenades</ENAMEX> and bombs past security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> or have
gotten the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> sent in through exits. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> whose laxness is revealed
was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX>, now known as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAirways</ENAMEX>, but an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airline</ENAMEX>'s security record is about the same as other big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that although post-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX>, cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> are required to
carry enough lifeboats to save all those aboard, this is not true of commuter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ferries</ENAMEX>, dinner-cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX>, gambling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX>-watching <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> or airport
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shuttles</ENAMEX>, which usually do not. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> dispatch stating
that a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> drove into a river near <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Berlin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> not too long ago
because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s computer navigation system did not tell them they needed to
stop and wait for a ferry.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also says that much-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">bruited</NUMEX>-about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> test turned out to
show that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> is definitely not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>." In
the current edition of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> issues a non-retraction
retraction, leading not with a concession but with word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> is "doing
well" after learning of his non-paternity, and exulting in his column's once
again having satisfied his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' expectations of "details on events rocking
and shocking those unfortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> who rise to power!"

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section piece on the forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX>
revelations of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress members</ENAMEX>' affairs says the write-ups won't be as
explicit as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report.

            According to a front-page feature in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> are getting
pretty creative in trying to protect themselves against a rising tide of armed
car-jacking. There's the cyanide-laced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brandy</ENAMEX> left in the glove compartment, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">concealed buffalo gun</ENAMEX> that shoots up at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hijacker</ENAMEX>'s nether parts, and an
outward-firing flame-thrower. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> piece of info the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> doesn't get: Would
all such devices be illegal in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> claims to be mystified <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about the intense loyalty Bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> inspires. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, try this--it's sort of like the intense loyalty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> inspires.

            Both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Kamen</ENAMEX>
column in the WP make fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strom Thurmond</ENAMEX>'s speech patterns, each
going so far (crediting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Barry</ENAMEX> for the device) as to offer "translations"
into standard <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurmond</ENAMEX> remarks. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Papers wonders if either
paper has ever offered such translations for anybody besides a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> white
male.

         
      
   
