
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Depose or Deep Pose</ENAMEX>?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s questioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> leads at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with the unveiling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s proposed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7 trillion</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead is a poll putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, and purporting to show
that each right now would beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. The story also states that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s vote on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s impeachment would not
affect most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' attitudes towards him or her, and that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> also
think impeachment should not be an issue in the upcoming presidential
campaign.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> leads say that the questioning will focus on the obstruction
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> charge. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> are now saying the perjury
charge is "doomed." And both say not to expect any big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bombshell</ENAMEX> from the uh,
big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bombshell</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> does go on at some length though to say that based on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s prior grand jury testimony, she could in fact represent a substantial threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, who has never before
been asked about her testimony, but presumably will be when he's deposed later
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>. For instance, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , when first asked about some
pages he made to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> he was certain he wasn't
calling her to ask about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX>'s revelations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. But later he said that's exactly what the pages were
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> testified that he never had an inkling during his assist to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s job search that she and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> were intimate. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
testified that she told <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> this. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> said he did not discuss
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case affidavit with her beforehand and only skimmed it
afterwards. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> swore she showed him a draft and discussed a wording
change with him.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal 2000</TIMEX> budget proposes
billions in new spending while preaching fiscal conservatism, via combining
such liberal domestic programs as urban housing vouchers and classroom
construction with cherished <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> priorities like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, the police
and small business. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says that with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> and
now this budget, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has moved into a policy vacuum created by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of
scandal and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' failure during that time to offer their own
coherent response to the long-term problems of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s costliest domestic
programs.

            Front-page stories at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and inside stories
elsewhere describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">just-announced</ENAMEX> discovery that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> is linked to a virus found in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chimpanzees</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Africa</ENAMEX>. The virus does not sicken the chimps but apparently, after jumping
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> through the blood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">exposure</ENAMEX> involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chimpanzee</ENAMEX> hunting and
slaughtering, transmutes into the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> virus. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> hope that investigating
this process will help them learn more about ways of combating the disease. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lengthy Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> takeout points out a possible side
benefit of the news: focusing more attention on the extensive "bushmeat" trade
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> that is decimating the chimp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> adds that many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> aren't happy to be identified as the original source of a viral
plague that's infected <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. (Odd locution: there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nations</ENAMEX> that are?)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reported that for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military has asked for the power to take charge in the case of major terrorist
strikes on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> soil. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the story is developed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> as
well as at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> . As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reported
previously, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s coverage mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> some civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> have
about this unprecedented augmentation of domestic military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> effort is typical in repeating the calming assurances of DOD
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, quoting one who emphasizes that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> wouldn't get involved
in law enforcement." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> is left puzzled, since it seems obvious that if
a military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> were to take charge during any sort of domestic terrorist
strike it would have to do precisely that, and besides, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> is
already involved with law enforcement. Remember those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> who shot that
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rancher</ENAMEX> while on a stakeout a while back?

            A front-page WSJ feature uses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> e-mail exchanges
released in connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s myriad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> cases as well as
interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to tell the story of what the paper calls
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s heated internal conflict over whether or not to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abandon Windows</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX> PC operating systems in favor of a
programming base that would run on any kind of operating system reachable via
the Internet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coterie</ENAMEX> of Internet "doves" inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s senior
reaches even, says the piece, once produced an in-house strategy presentation
called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Java Is Our Destiny</ENAMEX>."

            In the course of his assessment of the likely impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal
on the book biz, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Streitfeld</ENAMEX> points out
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Toobin</ENAMEX> has performed the "journalism
equivalent of a triple lutz": writing books on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OJ</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill-Monica</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
