
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ignoble</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s commencement of closed-door
impeachment deliberations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> reefers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> doings (to a story
running on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>) and goes instead with the report on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> bid turned in by an independent ethics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, which found <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in funny money and implicated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Olympic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> (in addition to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> already fingered). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports a
significant reaction to the muck raked thus far: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Hancock Insurance</ENAMEX> has
dropped plans for placing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> ads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>
report gets prominent front play at the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the deterioration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
early warning defense against nuclear missile attack, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, has
gotten to the point that for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> cannot see any of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of land- and sub-based missiles
aimed at them. The upshot is a much increased risk that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> would make
a "serious miscalculation." That's tech-speak for "accidentally blow the world
up." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> follows up inside with a fascinating interview with the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who decided on a hunch that an apparent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1983</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ICBM</ENAMEX> attack was a false alarm and so didn't start <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War III</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , citing unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, says that in closed
session (the result of a sunshine motion missing the required <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> votes), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> spoke one at a time for or against the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> impeachment
articles. The mood, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , was somber and without partisan
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sniping</ENAMEX>, but the speeches were almost all along party lines. The LAT
lead quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> saying that each of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> to speak thus far
has used up his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">full fifteen minutes</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains its access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>' versions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> by stating that although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> rules forbid the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> from divulging what occurs in closed session, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> had voted in
open session to allow each other to essentially reiterate what they said behind
closed doors.

            While it's flatly assumed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will not be removed from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> suggests that a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> in each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> will cast
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">crossover</ENAMEX> votes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also sees the idea of censuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
losing momentum.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the WP front a federal appeals
court ruling, almost surely headed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, holding that for
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> covered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina and South Carolina</ENAMEX>--a criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>'s confession could be held to
be voluntary and admissible even if he was not read his <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Miranda</ENAMEX> rights.

            The WP fronts the surprising results of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> study to cover the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> range of sexual problems since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kinsey</ENAMEX> reports <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly one-third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> suffer from sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dysfunction</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of the study, which appears <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX>, say this is
"a significant public health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>." There is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> hopeful finding
though: college educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are more than twice as likely not to suffer from
lack of sexual desire as those who did not complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who
complete <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> also tend to complete something else, suffering much less
premature ejaculation than male high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropouts</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> thinks
this data could be the basis of the best stay-in-school ad campaign of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports inside on what amounts to a quick reward for its
story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX> exposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>'s covert pay-for-play book review
scheme: a complete climb-down by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Henceforth, reports the
Times , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> promises to disclose when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> pay it to
feature specific books. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> question, though. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Papers notices that the
book review portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> online site leads to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble</ENAMEX>
web site. Doesn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> receive money from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble</ENAMEX> for
this? And if so, isn't this arrangement similar enough to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> to
have warranted mention? And isn't this especially important since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> dispatch inside reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> turnout in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last November</TIMEX>'s elections--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36.06 percent</NUMEX>--was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s lowest in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56 years</TIMEX>.
Highly partisan, negative campaigns seem to be implicated. But on the other
hand, in an item elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Apparel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manufacturers Association</ENAMEX> cites the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal for a positive
trend: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third quarter</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX> hike in lingerie sales.

         
      
   
