
   
   
      
         
            This Cock-eyed Caravan

            
               Item : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> release <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Hartman</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">911</NUMEX> call.

            No one would ever accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> of not being interested in the foibles
of the famous. But the by<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-now</TIMEX> routine procedure of making public the tape of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frantic</ENAMEX>, teary cry for help has never failed to shock and appall. Surely no one
believes that the reason these tapes are made public is because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
a right to know if their emergency services were performed appropriately.

            
               Item : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> lose <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ginger</ENAMEX>.

            Now this is news, and not just because it got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those great Brit
tabloid expressions, "blazing row," into papers worldwide. Who, if anyone, will
replace her? Culturebox keeps imagining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handlers</ENAMEX> sitting in a
conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> mulling over prospects (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Mother of God</ENAMEX>! It's another fax from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley MacLaine</ENAMEX>!") At first our money was on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marilu Henner</ENAMEX> -- you know: red
hair, kinda curvy, sings and dances, good with the media -- and Culturebox
thinks "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi Spice</ENAMEX>" has some zip as a name. But to keep their position as the
most-talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, it's clear whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX> must hire: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
"Gazza" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gascoigne</ENAMEX>, the once-brilliant, always-troubled soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> who was
recently denied a spot on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British World Cup</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX>, and in the process blew
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> off the front page and next to the recipes and the crossword
puzzle.

            
               Item : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockers</ENAMEX> to raise awareness for plight of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
benefit shows.

            The way rock & roll has been selling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>--as in, Not At All--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>
may need to stage a raising-awareness benefit for the plight of the electric
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guitar</ENAMEX>.

            
               Item : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21 million</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psycho</ENAMEX> .

            Does everyone realize now that they got taken? That he never had any
intention whatsoever of doing this movie? His list of "approved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>"
allegedly featured just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> names: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>,
why not ask for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lean</ENAMEX> while you're at it?) From here, it looks an awful
lot as if the whole purpose of this charade was to get a little faux buzz for
an all-but-unknown production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>...and in the process, get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiCaprio</ENAMEX>'s
price locked in for all to see--above the fold in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> --at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty-one</TIMEX>
big ones. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission</ENAMEX> accomplished...until <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually started taking the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> seriously, and in the wake of the bad press for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leo</ENAMEX>'s taking the role
of a sadist, everyone released statements denying that anyone had agreed to
anything. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> will recall when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAA</ENAMEX>'s ace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Meyer</ENAMEX>
locked in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX>'s price at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> per by cutting a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-picture deal for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sly</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One year later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> was running
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>. None of those movies has ever been made.

            
               Item : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Si Newhouse</ENAMEX> buys <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wired</ENAMEX> .

            To: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Si</ENAMEX>

            From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Si</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Re</ENAMEX>: Plans

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Assure Louis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>: You still matter! Founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> = permanent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX> in growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wired</ENAMEX> ! Move forward together!

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ask James T.</ENAMEX>: whatever happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annie Flanders</ENAMEX>? You know, the one who
started <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Details</ENAMEX> ?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna W.</ENAMEX>: Your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> is the biggest!

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wired BOBook</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horo</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cyber</ENAMEX>)scope! Take old "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athena Starwoman</ENAMEX>"
column, change "planets" to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processors</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Saturn</ENAMEX>" to "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX>
rising" to "digital revolution."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Confide to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graydon</ENAMEX>: no one else has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> your size!

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) Slip "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seinfeld Online</ENAMEX>" piece to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry S. Take</ENAMEX> out reference to AOL
handle, YADASTUD

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) Lunch with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth W. Convey</ENAMEX> message: your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> rules!

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jukt Software</ENAMEX> -- not bad! Why didn't
Wired have this?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>) Commission feature: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget Jones</ENAMEX>'s ONLINE diary

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assure Tina</ENAMEX> B: your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> eats all theirs for lunch!

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Connelly</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
