
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Unmasked</ENAMEX>

            The video appearance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> runs an across-the-top feature on the
fertile subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> and plays impeachment as a lead just
beneath. Predictably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s excerpted deposition, as well as those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, got melded into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> spin machine:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> claimed that the videotaped testimony bolstered their case while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> asserted exactly the opposite. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said Clinton</ENAMEX> lawyer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole</ENAMEX>
Seligman, "We must have attended a different deposition.") Consensus: The
airing of the videotapes did little or nothing to change <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>'
opinions.

            Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s physical appearance provoked partisan variance: Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thad Cochran</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>) described her as "vulnerable, youthful, and very young."
Other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, loath to abandon their image of a manipulated young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>,
echoed his spin. The papers however uniformly present <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> as confident and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">articulate</ENAMEX>, even seemingly older than her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>, which headlines
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> story "She's Nobody's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Niece, Thank You</ENAMEX>," gives a thumbs-up
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s get-up: "A sensible suit, pearls, heavy makeup, and a
semi-lacquered hairdo."

            In an inside-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> sideshow covered by "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> submitted an
affidavit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> contradicting parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>'s
deposition. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, testified that he had never told
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> a "stalker." Hitchens however alleges
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> used this characterization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> several times during a
lunch discussion they had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , received a phone call after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> testified suggesting that
they call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitchens</ENAMEX>, which led to the affidavit.

            All papers front the update from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX> voted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to transfer power to Crown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> lay
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unconscious</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> from death and sustained only by a respirator.
Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s distraught <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> continued to pray for a miracle cure.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> pledged a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> package to shore up the foreign-aid reliant
country even as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordanians</ENAMEX>, worried about the ramifications of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">King</ENAMEX>'s
death, started trading their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jordanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dinars</ENAMEX> for dollars. The WP
reports that even an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has joined
the global grief for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>: "Our hearts are with our brave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> who we hope will overcome this ordeal." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> story
says that over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, are expected for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Hussein</ENAMEX>'s funeral.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook</ENAMEX>" piece proposes establishing a moral "yardstick" for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> intervention in international
conflicts: If for example the war death rate exceeds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
national murder rate, then we should strongly consider military (as well as
humanitarian) involvement. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight</NUMEX> recent conflicts (plus <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Haiti</ENAMEX>, which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> contend are vital to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> national interest) meet these criteria.
In a current application, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> support intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>,
where well-armed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> could easily put down the scraggly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> who have
terrorized the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital city</ENAMEX>.

            Through this impeachment ordeal, the individual most to be pitied may be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>, having endured through his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, wants out. Thus when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>
proposed a brief <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mid-afternoon</TIMEX> break, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> responded, to ripples of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">laughter</ENAMEX>, "Let's keep going."

         
      
   
