
   
   
      
         
            Robeson Revised

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox's</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Mahler</ENAMEX>, editorial page <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">weekly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forward</ENAMEX> --wishes to note the following for the record:

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul Robeson</ENAMEX> would have turned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>, which makes it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> we
celebrate him in conferences, film festivals, books, reissues of concert
performances -- even an unsuccessful campaign to create a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Robeson</ENAMEX> stamp.
Robeson posthumously won a lifetime achievement award at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammys</ENAMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, he'll be honored at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Hall</ENAMEX>.

            A typical quote from the ongoing encomium: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]hat made Robeson
controversial was his willingness to step outside the frame which usually
contains the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and his status as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> to advance a complex
program of civil and human rights changes around the world and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Stewart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robeson</ENAMEX> exhibit at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mater</ENAMEX>.)

            That's not all that made Robeson controversial, though, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of
the far right and far left has emerged to drive that point home. From a recent
cover story in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Affairs</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
Party: "As the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centennial</TIMEX> celebrations are taking place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, many are
shamelessly going out of their way to distance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robeson</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>.
Unfortunately, if these lies go unanswered, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>'s legacy will be at war with
the life he actually lived. We cannot allow the ruling class to praise him, in
order to tear him down. We cannot allow them to turn <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Robeson</ENAMEX> into an ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberal</ENAMEX>. The real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Robeson</ENAMEX> was no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX> -- he was a freedom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolutionary</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20th century</TIMEX> giant." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarvis Tyner</ENAMEX>, a vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> couldn't agree more. In its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> issue, author
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Schwartz</ENAMEX> writes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robeson</ENAMEX> commemorations is the latest attempt
to sell the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a "falsified" and "upside-down" version of their
history.

            Whatever the real version of that history would look like, one thing we
know: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robeson</ENAMEX>'s committment to communism was not good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robeson</ENAMEX> visited <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> during the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> purges, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> released the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Yiddish poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Itzak Feffer</ENAMEX> from a labor <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and had him cleaned up to see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robeson</ENAMEX>. As the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> sat in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Robeson</ENAMEX>'s bugged hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feffer</ENAMEX> gestured
emphatically to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robeson</ENAMEX> and scribbled him notes in a desperate attempt to
convey the fact that he and numerous other prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> cultural figures
were going to be executed imminently. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robeson</ENAMEX> got the point. Still, when he
returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, he continued to preach support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stalin</ENAMEX> and
denied that he had witnessed any anti-Semitism while in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>. Only after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robeson</ENAMEX>'s death did his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> finally reveal the truth.

         
      
   
