
   
   
      
         
            Death Rays from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outer Space</ENAMEX>

            Here's an article that reads like an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">X</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Files</ENAMEX> episode: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invisible</ENAMEX>
pulsing rays! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airplanes</ENAMEX> that fall from the sky! Government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coverups</ENAMEX>! The point:
To solve the unsolved mystery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> Flight 800. The claim: That the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> may
have been accidentally downed by electromagnetic rays emanating from military
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aircraft</ENAMEX> and destroyers travelling nearby. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of
... aesthetics? The real mystery, though, is why the story was emblazoned last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> on the cover of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX> for high-minded literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brahmins</ENAMEX>, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> --and why, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>'s
debate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>.

            The theory is so elegantly paranoid Culturebox longs to believe it. It goes
like this: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>. The skies are alive with powerful surges of electromagnetic
energy radiating from the high-tech war <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> that crisscross the heavens
rehearsing their maneuvers. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, having lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>
to these waves--which wreak havoc with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>'s electrical system--has
created shields to protect its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessels</ENAMEX> against them. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> have
not been similarly protected. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. The spark that ignited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA 800</ENAMEX>'s fuel tank
could have been caused by one of these misdirected power surges, since there
were several military <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX>, and even a naval destroyer
travelling nearby at the time. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> has negligently failed to consider
this possibility.

            What really charms <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>, though, is the story's
intellectual-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> angle. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Scarry</ENAMEX>, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> of
literature and moral philosophy. She was writing a study of the social contract
that exists between the military and the civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in a democracy,
when she came across on article on electromagnetic interference (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMI</ENAMEX>) and
decided to follow up. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,000</NUMEX> words and many long footnotes later, here she is,
demanding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX> investigate--and there they are, paying lip service to
her seemingly crankish request by saying that yes, yes, they have, and that
further tests are being conducted.

            One wee problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarry</ENAMEX>'s scenario is that few of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> she cites
actually think it's likely. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Physicist</ENAMEX> and electrical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.V. Giri</ENAMEX>
peer-reviewed the piece for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYROB</ENAMEX> and recommended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>.
Nonetheless, he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX>, "It is not likely. ... It takes an extremely
powerful signal to come that far and result in this sequence of events. The
source has to be so powerful, and the signal has to find some coupling path to
the fuel sensors, and that's not easy because there are many obstacles in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between</TIMEX>."

            On the other hand, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as another</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Shooman</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> study on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMI</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> on risk assessment--puts it:
"Most accidents are a sequence of rare circumstances. If you asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about
a lot of accidents, if you said: Could this happen? They'd say: This is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">implausible</ENAMEX>."

            At the very least, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Culturebox</ENAMEX>, whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer vacation</TIMEX> begins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> on a
flight that follows the route of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>, is alarmed at the prospect of being a
passenger on an unshielded <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shooman</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> commercial airplane
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> are aware of the problem, but consider the cost of correcting it
prohibitive-especially if their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> aren't required to follow
suit. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> is not comforted. It shouldn't take a moral philosopher to
point out that that attitude doesn't exactly conform to the social contract,
whether between her and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, or between her and the military
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contracters</ENAMEX> who also build civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> that are supposed to get her to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> safely.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Puppeteering 101</ENAMEX> : As an exercise in spin analysis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> puts
this question to you, dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>: Who looks more like a buffoon in the wake of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX>'s leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mortimer Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, who pretends he
didn't fire him, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Evans</ENAMEX>, who doth protest too much that he did?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> votes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
News , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> did not "think it was time for a change," as he told the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> . In fact, ever since he went to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> made
nothing but gestures of support toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fallows</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX>, on the other hand,
was openly going around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> offering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX>' job to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>.

            So how did a spinmeister like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> get stuck in the humiliating position of
jumping up and down to claim responsibility for something he didn't have the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> or possibly even the inclination to do? For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallows</ENAMEX> gave
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX> no time to get their story straight. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>
were negotiating the terms of his departure--specifically, the severance
package--and when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX> refused to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX> one, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX> announced that
he'd been fired before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> could.

            Culturebox discerns a tragic poetic justice in all this. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> was in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows's</ENAMEX> shoes when he was being pushed out as head of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, which raises the question: Why didn't he see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallows</ENAMEX>' move coming? The
answer says everything about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> has become. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who
strayed into the snakepit of media-executivedom for a brief, unhappy stint. He
doesn't need a cover story or another job as a high-powered media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>, so
he has no incentive to lie about his departure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>, once a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and the
kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who'd stand up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX> and get fired for his trouble,
is now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for whom announcing to the world that you were fired is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unthinkable</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
