
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace of Prints</ENAMEX>

            As befits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are relatively quiet, finally getting to lead
with the cold-snap set-pieces they've been denied by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of balm. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> tells of a nation plagued by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cancelled</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX>, giving us along the way the definitive holiday
crisis quote: "How can I tell him he might not get to see his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bubbie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boca</ENAMEX>?"
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> home in on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s freeze, which has done serious
damage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s orange <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX>--destroying, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , more than a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> said "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX>," but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s settles on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager reports that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Moynihan</ENAMEX> came out in favor of censuring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rather than removing him from office. This despite, notes the
Times , his earlier comments criticizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for not adequately
apologizing for his affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and his opinion that perjury
might well be an impeachable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>. The reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> offered is that
ouster would "destabilize the presidency." The paper explains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s
stance is "particularly credible" because he is not running for
re-election.

            A piece inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> braces with the reminder that a full blown
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> trial could scorch plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, stating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is prepared to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to testify that she
frequently exaggerated the details of her trysts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT front features a take-out on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>,
soon to preside over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s impeachment trial. The piece notes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> wrote a book about impeachment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, in which he discussed the two
most significant previous impeachments (both unsuccessful), that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Chase</ENAMEX> and of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Johnson</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes
that the book, for much of this year one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX>'s most sought after, is
out of print. And that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> has just announced a reprint run of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25,000</NUMEX>
copies. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> has stamped his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Court</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collegiality</ENAMEX> and efficiency--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last September</TIMEX>, for instance, he led a judicial
conference in which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,701</NUMEX> appeals were considered and voted on before lunch.
The story features an anecdote purporting to show how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> punctures
posturing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, in which the pin cushion part is assigned to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> quote cited doesn't seem particularly pompous. In effect, the
tale merely serves as a device for taking a swipe at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, which may be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">justifiable</ENAMEX>, but this piece doesn't bother to justify it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX>, used the same anecdote and committed the
same sin with it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>'s official analysis of that plane crash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in
which a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">bomber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> broke formation and disappeared with a plane full of
bombs and was later discovered to have crashed into a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> mountain. The
report calls it a suicide, ascribing it to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captain</ENAMEX>'s mental
turmoil over his mother's religiously based pacifistic disapproval of the
military and over a failed romance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> deny this, claiming
instead that something happened on the flight to make their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> lose
consciousness. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes that the report is silent regarding two
widely mentioned rumors--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> was taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> off to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX>,
and that he committed suicide because he was a tormented closeted gay. The
Times itself is oddly silent about some relevant context though, never
noting that the sort of speculative psychological explanation indulged in here
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> is strikingly similar to that wielded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> when, in its
initial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> report on the disastrous gunnery explosion aboard the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> , it posited a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">crewmember</ENAMEX>'s gay-tinged suicide. So the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> missed
being reminded that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> case, a straightforwardly mechanical
cause for the mishap was ultimately found instead.

            Today, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36 years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Baker</ENAMEX> files his last "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Observer"</ENAMEX> column. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> has read tired and grumpy of late,
but his best columns have always been wonderful correctives to everybody
else's. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX> recommends his book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Growing Up</ENAMEX>" as an autobiography of
the absolute <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> rank.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> dispatch inside reporting that a retiring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> has expressed "grave doubts" about the guilt of some of
the convicts executed during his tenure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> notes that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past ten</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years or so</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">53</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on death rows across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> have been released on
DNA grounds. "But how about before we could rely upon <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>?" the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> is quoted
asking. "What happened to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?"

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP AP</ENAMEX> item reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> pardoned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">33</NUMEX>
convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">offenses</ENAMEX> ranging from going <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AWOL</ENAMEX> to blowing
up a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> convicted of lying.

         
      
   
