
   
   
      
         
            Not Without a Hitch

            Everybody leads with the wrap-up of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s impeachment trial closing
arguments and the set-up of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s deliberations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times headline suggests the drama associated with a criminal trial:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s Fate is Now in Hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Jurors</ENAMEX>." Down below in the body
type, though the stories get more real. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says there is "virtually
no chance" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will be removed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says his acquittal is "all but assured." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> face
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">near-certain</ENAMEX> defeat." Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> is the realest: "It's also unclear whether
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will formally reprimand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> once he's acquitted."

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's headline isn't even about the what of the verdict--it's
about the how: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Closed Senate Debate Likely</ENAMEX>." That's because there don't appear
to be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> votes required to suspend the rules, a point that the WP
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also cover in additional front-page stories. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead
editorial finds the prospect of closing the doors on the impeachment
deliberations "inconceivable." For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the main unanswered question
is whether enough <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> would join the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to keep either of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> impeachment articles from winning a simple majority.

            In light of the presumed outcome, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees the rhetoric coming
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> from both sides--each of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Ruff</ENAMEX>--aimed not so much at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> as at the
history books. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruff</ENAMEX> worked in references to peace in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> dipped into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry V</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Agincourt</ENAMEX> speech, as
well as quotations from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de Gaulle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Septimius Severus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace Mann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gibbon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Bellow</ENAMEX>. The WP notices the cumulative effect of this hot
air front moving through: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> after another getting up from his desk to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stretch</ENAMEX> and wander to the rear of the chamber.

            The only thing resembling impeachment news is the Hitchens/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> saga.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> wrote a letter to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> asking for a postponement in the start of deliberations to allow the new
questions about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>'s truthfulness to be addressed. He was turned
down. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> himself makes an appearance on the WP op-ed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>: "What a fuss! What a load of phony differences without distinctions!
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> has already told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> concocted this foul
story, with its equally foul implications. He has now admitted to telling some
such version to 'friends' of his as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> (and I still consider
myself to be both). That story got into the press, a lot. The message was
therefore delivered to Ms <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QED</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchens</ENAMEX> goes on to say that he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">devoutly</ENAMEX> wishes he'd written an intended column on the matter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week earlier</TIMEX>,
so that he "could have been a truer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" by warning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> off making
"any unguarded statement." But that having not happened, he sees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> as
"being readied to be used as yet another human sacrifice by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX>." One
question about all this: Was it fair for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchens</ENAMEX> the
room to defend himself when the legal constraints <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> is under no doubt
kept him from being able to write a column of his own about the matter?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last summer</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> destroyed a purported pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> with cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, saying that it was in fact making nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quickly raised doubts about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it raises more, with an inside piece stating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemists</ENAMEX> hired by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> examined soil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and found no traces of
chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> compounds. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> problem though: although the piece makes it
clear that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemists</ENAMEX> have the same monetary tie to an interested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> as
any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert witness</ENAMEX>, the headline does not. It simply says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Experts</ENAMEX> Find No
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arms Chemicals</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bombed Sudan Plant</ENAMEX>." Not a false headline, to be sure, but a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misleadingly un</ENAMEX>-nuanced one.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager warns that the social ill effects of fearing the
Y2K problem--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> runs, hoarding of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and gas, fires caused by newly
acquired wood stoves and a rise in gun violence accompanying the upsurge in gun
sales to those fearing post-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millennial</NUMEX>-bug civil unrest--could end up being
much worse than any pure outcome of the problem itself, especially since the
actual problem is being attacked with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> of remediation.
According to a story flagged on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front, not all of the hoarding will be
done by cammoed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cabins</ENAMEX> either. It turns out that in
anticipation of possible Y2K-driven supply interrupts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> are
planning to take on more inventory than usual in the last part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Which
is driving a search for extra <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse space</ENAMEX> and could even effect the GNP.
And wait, that doesn't include the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1.999K</NUMEX> problem! For that, check out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week</ENAMEX>." It seems that certain older software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> use
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9999</TIMEX>" to signal an error or the end of the program. Which means <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 9</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> may be a bit of a glitchfest. There are, says the paper, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> such
problematic dates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
