
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Reitman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Man of Mystery</ENAMEX>

            So...the next time you hear someone railing about how stupid the star system
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is, and how no A-list <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> is worth the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> he or she is paid,
show them the opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> figures (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$31.6 mil</NUMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Truman Show</ENAMEX>
and ask them how much they think the movie would have made if, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> had been its star. Remind them, while you're at it, that even if they
make the dubious claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bridges</ENAMEX> is a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Truman Show</ENAMEX> is a more effective movie with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrey</ENAMEX> in it, because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> walks into the theatre caring more about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carrey</ENAMEX> than about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX>.
And therefore, walks into the theatre, period. More <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem to have checked
out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s performances of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Truman Show</ENAMEX> than attended the entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> theatrical run of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Weir</ENAMEX>'s last movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fearless</ENAMEX>, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">starred</ENAMEX>...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bridges</ENAMEX>.

            So...<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>'s second big question is answered "Yes." (The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>'s first
big question involved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> and the answer was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No."</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next weekend</TIMEX>,
with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Six Days, Seven Nights</ENAMEX> another question gets answered. The question
-- ah, you think it's going to be "Will <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> accept a openly gay woman
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne Heche</ENAMEX>) in a big-screen hetero romance," don't you? Well, guess what:
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> haven't accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> in a big-screen hetero romance since
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Weir</ENAMEX> served up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly McGillis</ENAMEX> as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Amish</ENAMEX> hottie in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Witness</ENAMEX>. Run
down a list of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> -- Greta
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scacchi...Julia Ormond...Alison Doody...Annette Bening</ENAMEX>, each of them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 20</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> younger than he -- and see if you can recall any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">onscreen</ENAMEX> sparks flying.
Not hard to understand why that big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> blanched at the prospect of coughing
up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70 million</NUMEX> bones for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Scott-Thomas</ENAMEX> to star in a<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">, um,</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnian</ENAMEX> romance"... a concept almost as cinematically unlikely as "Amish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hottie</ENAMEX>."

            No, instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> asks, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can Six Days</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Reitman</ENAMEX>
reinvent his career <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reitman</ENAMEX>'s career is a lesson in big-screen
comedy over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two decades</TIMEX>. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reitman</ENAMEX> who first found a way to
marshal the talents of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Murray</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ramis</ENAMEX> for the big screen --
culminating in the phenomenal success of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ghostbusters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramis</ENAMEX> once said
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reitman</ENAMEX>, not unkindly, "If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan</ENAMEX> had directed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Emperor</ENAMEX>, it
would have been <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">102 minutes</TIMEX> long and had a big chase at the end."

            But by the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ghostbusters 2</ENAMEX> came and went, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> were
directing their own movies. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reitman</ENAMEX> moved on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivan</ENAMEX>
played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pygmalion</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arnold</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galatea</ENAMEX> in a series of high-concept comedies:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX>, 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kindergarden Cop</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Junior</ENAMEX> . For a post-coital
shot in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins, Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reitman</ENAMEX> set his every facial muscle
for maximum comedic effect. Their collaboration was wildly successful, but
would prove to be the last stand for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>-driven, high-concept comedy.
Because waiting in the wings was...

            ...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>, whose uninhibited roar through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ace Ventura</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pet</ENAMEX>
Detective reshaped the movie-comedy landscape <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX>? He
don't need no stinkin' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>! All of sudden, over-the-top, decidedly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">un</ENAMEX>-directed performance were the rage (especially since sitcoms, once the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of such physically gifted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Randall</ENAMEX> on
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Odd Couple</ENAMEX> , had become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>' shows in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> mode.)
As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carrey</ENAMEX> racked up hits, other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic actors</ENAMEX> followed suit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Murphy</ENAMEX> had
been trapped in a series of stultifying high-concept comedies...now there he
was, farting his way through the hugely successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nutty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX>. To
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, the comedy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> seemed as disposable as the aging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ingenue</ENAMEX>.

            So...time for another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Reitman</ENAMEX> incarnation. And here it is: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
an action/romance with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. Can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford</ENAMEX> carry a love story?
Can you have an adventure film with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> big stunt? Will it be a
Romancing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>? One thing's for sure about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven Nights</ENAMEX> : It'll last <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 102 minutes</TIMEX>, and have a big chase at
the end.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Connelly</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
