
   
   
      
         
            Pilot Error

            While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post all have big impeachment trial post-mortems, the actual lead in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is something different.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">blistering</ENAMEX> crackdown
by a no-nonsense <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> district court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Kendall</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> who've been calling in sick for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last week</TIMEX>. (It's illegal
for them to actually strike.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story, much more colorful than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front-pagers on the same subject, has the judge
comparing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> extortionists, promising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> that its
assets will fit in the "overhead bin of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piper Cub</ENAMEX>" after he got through with
it, and even pointing out that many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> had learned their trade while
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> armed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>. (That last is a cheap shot; as the paper notes,
some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> are combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> who risked their lives for the country
at the time.)

            The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s conditional decision to
participate in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> peacekeeping mission in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says about 4000
Army and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> will be stationed in the southern part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>--if the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> fighting a civil war there can come up with a
cease-fire agreement in the negotiations currently under way in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. That's
not for certain. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , ever suspicious of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
motivations, goes out of its way to report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> "expected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s announcement to draw concentrated news coverage and commentary to
compete with lingering musings over the trial"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , playing the
story just below its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-column lead, details the complex and delicate planned
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mobilizations</ENAMEX> and postings of the multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.

            But back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead is just a poll story, the old
news that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> didn't like impeachment, want to get back to business,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>, etc. The companion story, a news analysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Hook</ENAMEX>, sees "the
makings of a honeymoon" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> Both sides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hooks</ENAMEX> reports, want to get down to
legislating. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> analyzes the scandal's effect on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> elections.
In a nice passage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Balz</ENAMEX> writes, "Virtually every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> contemplating a
presidential campaign will look in the mirror <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> and see a possible
answer for what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> wants after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>"--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Scout</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX> the antidote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s locker-room antics, and so forth.
Those who make it to the end of the story will probably say amen to the closing
quote, from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>: "I think [the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>] probably will not
want to hear the word impeachment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another 120 years</TIMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also has a very long, intensely reported recap of the
political phenomena that, all along, seemed systematically to help the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and hurt the right. It includes a trenchant "for want of a nail" tale
explaining how an early <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt-Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> agreement to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
Report under wraps broke down. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> was incommunicado <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> the report
was unexpectedly delivered to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, even as an overheard remark of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s enraged a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>, leading him to introduce a motion
to make the report public.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's main impeachment post-mortem-- pace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Hook</ENAMEX>--is a
pessimistic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> hate each other, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says.
(This is a follow-up to a ferocious inside story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> ran <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full year</TIMEX> of pent-up disgust at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> off his chest.) The most telling point of analysis in the piece comes
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, who says that since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> won't be able to get
anything done anyway, he might as well concentrate on electing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.

            The WP fronts a look at how certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake Cityans</ENAMEX> went nuts to
get their burg an <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>. The conclusion: "The decision to go low, to do what
ever it took to win, was a step-by-step and relatively open process involving
large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." A major report on the LAT front page details
how tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> strong-armed smoking-cessation-aid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to keep
them out of the smoking wars.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a classic obit to show off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, about the best polo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> ever, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecil Smith</ENAMEX>; the piece, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Litsky</ENAMEX>, effortlessly takes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when the sport was played by the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Rogers</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> watched games. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>,
led a dusty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> to take the national championship away from the
hoity-toity <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX>. He continued to ride up until he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Magazine</ENAMEX> 's cover look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> is marred by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">banal</ENAMEX>, sycophantic writing ("...within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX>, [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>] has put them
at ease. He has that effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Dubner</ENAMEX>'s tiresome
injections of himself into the story ("We first meet up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early Thursday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>..."), and minor irritants like referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> by
her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name. (A female movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exec</ENAMEX> gets the same treatment.) In this context,
it's not clear whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> or the subject appreciates the irony of the
profile's key scene--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> fatuously defending the behavior of his close
personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morality</ENAMEX> is defined not just by a sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dalliance</ENAMEX>") as he puffs contentedly on a cigar.

         
      
   
