
   
   
      
         
            Sudden Death

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USAT</ENAMEX> leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jasper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s quick death sentence for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs it on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Guatemalan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s finding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> provided money and
training that enabled the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Guatemalan</ENAMEX> military to commit "acts of genocide"
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX>-led <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maya Indians</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36-year</TIMEX> civil war. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guatemala</ENAMEX>, as its top non-local story. The WP
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>'s quick response to the threat of local government lawsuits
against gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>: engineering legislation that makes such suits
illegal. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are
being targeted for such bills. An example highlighted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is the bill
currently advancing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> that would make it a crime
punishable by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to five years</TIMEX> in jail and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> fine for any local
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> to file suit against gunmakers--consequences
rarely suffered, it should be noted, by those convicted of illegal gun
possession or discharge.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> upon his condemnation as "unrepentant and
smirking," and notes that he is the first white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to face execution for
killing a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> goes on to report
that since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> reinstated the death penalty in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>, nationwide
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> have been executed for killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">123</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> have been
put to death for killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. Presenting this statistic without also saying
the total number of convictions of crimes of each sort leaves the reader
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ill</ENAMEX>-equipped to determine what it really means. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> don't mention
it, but this story should give pause to anyone who thinks the death penalty is
a deterrent. The unspeakable crime took place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that leads the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX> in executions.

            The WP front follows-up on a story it broke inside <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>: a
vicious on-air reference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jasper</ENAMEX> crime by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> talk radio
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Tracht</ENAMEX>, aka "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Greaseman</ENAMEX>." On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracht</ENAMEX> followed up a
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX> song with the comment, "No wonder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> drag them behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracht</ENAMEX> was fired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> (not only from his
radio gig, but also from his position as a volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy sheriff</ENAMEX>). The true
mystery of the whole episode is, Why wasn't Tracht canned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> when he
referred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> with the line, "Kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more and
we can take a whole week off"?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says that while the broad outlines of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aid to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemala</ENAMEX>'s military have been known, the report confirms that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s
training of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemala</ENAMEX>'s military in counterinsurgency techniques "had a
significant bearing" on the human rights violations it committed, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">torture</ENAMEX>, kidnapping, and execution. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> catches the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemala</ENAMEX> spinning: "I believe that the report's focus is
appropriate, that these were abuses committed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemalans</ENAMEX> against other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemalans</ENAMEX>--the result of an internal conflict." The difference between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> stories is striking, with the former high up
stressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> role, while the latter only mentions it in passing.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's longtime foreign affairs op-ed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenfeld</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, has the intellectual
rigor to nonetheless play out the arguments against the unilateral presidential
commitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> there. His column takes on the demand being raised in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX> over the signatures of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> obtain authority from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for any such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> before embarking
upon it. The toughest argument against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenfeld</ENAMEX>'s position, which he doesn't
really answer, comes when he notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s position is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX> are examples of presidential use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> without prior,
formal congressional authorization. The problem is that unlike in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>,
in neither of those cases was the recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> where our forces
deployed opposed to our being there. In response, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenfield</ENAMEX> cites pressing
humanitarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. But the response to this obvious: if those
concerns are substantial, they will hold up just fine in the congressional
debate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War Powers Act</ENAMEX> requires.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that as part of its deal to purchase advertising space
on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> billboards, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Postal Service</ENAMEX> received the use of luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and hockey venues around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The postal official
quoted in the story miraculously can't provide an estimate for the regular cost
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX>. But he does say the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX> were used to promote customer
relationships and to reward outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ought to try
to see how many actual letter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX> ever saw the inside of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> airs out some rumors about who may yet be called to appear as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> trial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Candidates bruited</ENAMEX> about include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dell</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Case</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. And there's always the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hail</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> pass" of calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> in the flesh.

conducted a survey concluding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in neighborhoods they perceive
to be unsafe are less likely than those living in safer areas to engage in
physical activities like walking a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> or pushing a stroller. For this, we
needed a study?

         
      
   
