
   
   
      
         
            Free <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy</ENAMEX>

            Banner headlines in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> announce the acquittal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson Clinton</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> feature prominent subheadings emphasizing
that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> articles of impeachment failed to muster a simple majority.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article 1</ENAMEX>, alleging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> committed perjury in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, was defeated
by a vote of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55 to 45</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> crossed party lines in rejecting the
charge. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Article 2</ENAMEX> garnered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> cross-overs and failed on a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-50</NUMEX> vote. All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> voted for full acquittal.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> devotes its entire front page to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s acquittal, yet
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of the big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to headline the sinking of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Feinstein</ENAMEX>'s attempt to force a vote on censure.
Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> voted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56 to 43</NUMEX> to consider the motion denouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
"shameful, reckless and indefensible" conduct, pro-censure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> fell short
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> required. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> provides great detail on the
staging of the drama's denouement. Its overview story reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> scripted each stage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the final day</TIMEX>'s proceedings, down to the
language <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> used to announce the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acquittal</ENAMEX>.

            The predictability of the proceeding is noted in a front-page trial journal
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . This piece reports that the solemnity of the voting was
disturbed by murmuring in the press gallery only when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> voted not guilty on the perjury article. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> overview notes that "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> argued that the
votes signaled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> had erred in sending forth impeachment articles."
The story does not say which <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> advanced this view.

            The LAT highlights the collegiality that marked the closing of the
trial, headlining its scene-setter "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bipartisan Spirit Soars</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
quotes lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> saying "the genuflection to bipartisanship has a
certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> of civility to it, but it means <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side is disadvantaged, and we
were." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that back slapping abounded after votes were
cast. The WP takes note of the presentation of a plaque to the Chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> (surely an extra-constitutional action.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> front separate features on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s rose garden apology and expression of "profound sorrow" for
triggering the events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story emphasizes that
the speech struck a conciliatory and hopeful tone. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days ago</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had vowed to exact retribution from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>
at the ballot box, it does not pause to compare and contrast.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers front</ENAMEX> separate articles on the reaction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>'s statement that he does not think
Independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> should indict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asa Hutchinson</ENAMEX> also expressed the opinion that it
was "time for [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>] to finish any report and move on." Perhaps that was what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey Graham</ENAMEX> was getting at when the stated, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cleansed</ENAMEX>."

            In other news, according to a story reefered on the front page of the
Times and reported inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
will announce on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> will be deployed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> if a
satisfactory agreement is reached between the "warring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>" currently
negotiating in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chateau</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. The tentatively planned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> would form a small part of the "predominately <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> totaling
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeline Albright</ENAMEX> floated this
plan <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, but promised to consult with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> before making any formal
commitments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes that the mission would probably be headed
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX>. What will <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> think about this?

            While all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> devote much space to the long-run ramifications of
the impeachment trial, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the LAT bury what could
represent an important change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential</ENAMEX> elections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Secretaries of State</ENAMEX> adopted a plan that, if implemented, would
reverse the increasing compression of presidential primaries, and the
importance that they place on early fundraising. The plan preserves <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> as the first caucus and primary respectively. The remaining
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> would be grouped into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> regions: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX> would hold their primaries in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early March, April</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>,
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> - with the order of the primaries rotating each Presidential election.
The story notes that getting the necessary approval by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> could be difficult.

            At the close of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s drama, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> were confronted
with the bittersweet question of what they would do next. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Breaux</ENAMEX> planned to head home for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mardi Gras</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogan</ENAMEX> exulted "I'm going to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Disneyland</ENAMEX>! On <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> seemed to have
less well-formed plans, he simply declared: "You're looking at a free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>!"

         
      
   
