
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stating His Case</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All Clinton All the Time</ENAMEX> extravaganza leads all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> run banners focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOTU</ENAMEX> pitch to save
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> by investing some of the budget surplus on its behalf in the
stock market and also to use some of it to subsidize a new system of individual
retirement accounts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> doesn't use a banner, but instead runs
separate headlines over its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> lead and
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-day-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s-defense impeachment off-lead. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times uses a banner that says it all: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Sets</ENAMEX> Out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vision; Defense</ENAMEX>
Opens." The defense, conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Ruff</ENAMEX>, even though
basically foot-stomping, and punctuated by a too-exquisitely timed choke-up
evocation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruff</ENAMEX> of his late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha Beach</ENAMEX>, gets good reviews.

            As all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> address was eclectic, including not
only the revelation that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has decided to sue tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to recover cigarette-related health care costs, but also the intent
to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> and to boost defense spending. But
the capstone of the speech, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposal to apply the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 15 years</TIMEX>' worth of budget surpluses to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and individual retirement accounts.
There is much mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> enthusiasm for tax cuts instead, but only
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> flatly observes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> never explained how he would pay
for most of his new ideas, and that some stand little chance of passage.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is good on the particular politics of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security proposals, saying that it is classically <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonesque</ENAMEX> in that it
preserves the program's size but only by accepting something that was anathema
to earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>--partial privatization.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> focuses the most on the partisan response <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> received,
noting (along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) that impeachment trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge Chief Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> didn't show up, and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, all
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, also stayed away.

            The papers contain some interesting thoughts on how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deployed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOTU</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> of deflecting his impeachment predicament. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> off,
everybody notices that he didn't mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>word at all. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says
that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> had been leaking various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SOTU</ENAMEX> proposals but
held back its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> plans and its new tobacco legal strategy to
insure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s program, rather than the mounting of his
defense before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the day</TIMEX>, would drive the coverage. Both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> note that the amount of new and substantive policy in
the speech was designed to portray a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who intends to stick around.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that the speech was in its own way the ultimate
impeachment defense: revealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> focused on the issues
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really care about, and hence might help him maintain the strong poll
ratings that may be his ultimate lever with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> sitting in judgment of
him.

            The LAT fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>'s publication of a
report stating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> "badly misgauged" the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial meltdown.
The story is carried inside everywhere else. The report admits that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> was
slow to see the extent of the banking overhaul required, but also notes that
very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> saw things more clearly. But even though many have said that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>'s bailout <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> of imposing higher interest rates and slashing
government spending exacerbated the spin-out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, the report says that its tight money approach was basically right. A
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial isn't convinced,
pointing out that just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> led a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$41.5 billion</NUMEX> bailout of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, now in deep crisis with a rapidly disintegrating currency.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> run inside stories reporting that
the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> decided <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that embryonic stem cell research is not ruled out by the ban on
federally funded embryo research, because the cells aren't embryos. They don't
have the capacity to develop into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>.

            The WP fronts the news that for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>, burglars
have broken into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of a polling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> working for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, stealing sensitive campaign material. A campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisor</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying, "We hereby declare the demise of the coincidence
theory."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> goes cutesy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, dedicating his column to
the regular broadcasts of what he calls "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Tom Radio</ENAMEX>," the daily
pronouncements of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ® <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-old</TIMEX>, in the process probably setting some kind
of record for the number of occurrences of the word "mommy" in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
op-ed piece. Such "domestic bliss" pieces are a sure sign of trouble. For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
reasons: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> stoops to cover his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, you can bet he's
stuck for ideas; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) Unless one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is terribly unusual, such efforts
violate a great unspoken but true taboo: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Other Peoples' Kids Are Boring</ENAMEX>. For
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at least, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>, once a world-class war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>, is just the guy
sitting next to you in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> who just has to show you pictures of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kid</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
