
   
   
      
         
            Getting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Less Real</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
flashing its sensitivity to world finance, is alone in leading with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s
devaluation of the real (and runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> more real-related items inside), but the
story does get big play everywhere. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times 's top non-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> news story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> travelling
call, complete with huge portrait and above-it-all MJ quote, pretty much the
standard treatment of the story at all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s expression of
confidence regarding his impeachment trial chances, pointing out that such
informal statements are probably all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is going to get from him. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> lead is that a government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> report to be published today
will urge a new package of better benefits for military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead notes that the decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to allow its currency to shrink
in value by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 8 percent</NUMEX> upset financial markets all over the world.
It probably didn't help that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s central bank
suddenly resigned or that it's widely believed any economic troubles in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>
will severely affect the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>. Which would be of no small
interest to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> each point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> now
accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fifth</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exports.

            Maybe it's the dismal science rather than dismal writing, but from the
Times coverage, it's a bit hard to follow the logic of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s move.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the devaluation eases pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> to defend its currency
by spending its reserves keeping interest rates high, and that the government
describes its move as a way to restore consumer confidence and credibility
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> doesn't say how this is supposed to work.
After all, if the currency is falling, won't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> be motivated to take
what they've got and convert it to a more stable currency before things get
worse, thereby putting more pressure on the real? And why is a devalued
currency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preferable</ENAMEX> to increased interest rates? They both suppress consumer
spending and hence both contribute to the kind of transnational recessionary
contagion that is the main worldwide economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> at the moment. Similarly,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section "cover story" says that if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>'s central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> can
trim interest rates, "domestic industry can worry less about paying its debt
and more about borrowing to resume production." But if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s money is
worth less, don't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> just have to borrow more to accomplish any given
thing? Maybe this is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ Brazil</ENAMEX> story is getting at when it
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were furious that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> didn't seem to have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coherent</ENAMEX> plan.

            The WP <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eve-</TIMEX>of-impeachment coverage is all scene-setting: A
front-pager headlined "Caught in History's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spotlight/Five Senators Prepare</ENAMEX> to
Shoulder a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Most Unusual Burden</ENAMEX>" and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> breaking the news that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> when he gets home from work he gets into
his pajamas (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cotton</ENAMEX>, just so you know). But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> impeachment off-lead
manages to break a little news: Despite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s official agreement to
table the matter for now, a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> has met secretly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to work on
issues related to calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts somewhat disturbing news from the cancer wars, a story
that's also flagged in the WSJ front news box and runs inside at the
WP : According to a new study of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">639</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, there is a technique that
reduces the chance of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> among high-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>: removing both breasts while they are still healthy.

            Running inside at both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is word of what could
well become known as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the Israeli</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> scandal. It seems
that burglars broke into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Greenberg</ENAMEX>, a prominent
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollster</ENAMEX>, and took sensitive campaign strategy and fund-raising
materials relating to the prime ministerial candidacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenberg</ENAMEX> client <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehud</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barak</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> retirement coverage offers yet more proof that the leading
untreated malady among sportswriters is hyperbolic myopia. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a
story inside headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Retirement Sends Shock Around a Small Planet</ENAMEX>," but at
least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> front notices that in his press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> frequently referred to himself in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">3rd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. That egomaniacal touch
somehow didn't strike the sportsoids at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> as like,
completely wacked.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page features <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>-inspired thoughts on athletic
retirement over the byline of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>. It's a fairly pedestrian effort that wouldn't make the page if it
had been written by say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonnie Wheeler</ENAMEX>. But here's the weird part: the credit
line for the piece states that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonnie Wheeler</ENAMEX> assisted with this article." Now
does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> really expect us to believe that all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> who grace its op-ed space with solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bylines</ENAMEX> have produced their great
expectorations with utterly no help? If not, then what gives with the sudden
truth in packaging for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammering Hank</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
