
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Potemkin Villages</ENAMEX>

            Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Weir</ENAMEX> poking gentle fun at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seaside</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, when he set
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Truman Show</ENAMEX> there? Were the faux-neighborliness and
picture-perfectness a hint that he considers the planned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, with its
gingerbread <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX> and white-picket fences and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>-trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> terminology ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New Urbanism</ENAMEX>") and grander utopian ideals, a Potemkin
Village? After all, even this architectural utopia has turned out to have its
downsides: onerous zoning and architectural restrictions, rules about what you
can and cannot do with your garden, a general atmosphere of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>-mindedness that can grate on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, if that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> (like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>)
starts to develop a live-free-or-die approach to things. ...

            If so, the satire has gone over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>' heads. Seaside town <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporter</ENAMEX> that as soon as the movie opened, they
started getting calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> looking to rent one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">270</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cottages</ENAMEX>
available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renters</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the movie's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> commented, "I recall we made
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Witness'</ENAMEX> (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>), and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX> tourism went up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lancaster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX>)." ... Which reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> that the first maxim of movies
debunking the illusion of movies is: It doesn't matter how devastating your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">expos</ENAMEX>, of an illusion, if the illusion's a pretty one, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will always
want a piece of it. ...

            Speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Truman Show</ENAMEX> : What if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
announced an event celebrating the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> novels, to be chosen from a
list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of which just happened to have been published by
publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that had donated big money to the event? Or if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> was to
pick the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> paintings, most of which were painted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windsor</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oils</ENAMEX>, a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>? Seem corrupt to you? So why is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Film Institute</ENAMEX> doing the same thing with its top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> films, to be chosen from
among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> preselected <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> movies, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> are ... <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twentieth Century Fox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miramax</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia/TriStar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM/UA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polygram</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic Pictures</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIVE Entertainment</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orion</ENAMEX>. And
what is the stated purpose of the event, which will be broadcast on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> and
promoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ? To stimulate video rentals. ...

            And as long as we're asking annoying questions: Where are all the great
films of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cassavetes</ENAMEX>, most of which have not yet been released on video?
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shadows</ENAMEX> , which is on the list, is not one of his best--it just happens
to be out on video.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditto for</ENAMEX>, say, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> and
long-acknowledged classics? But second-guessing the list is too easy a sport.
The more important questions: Why are we selling off our greatest cultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heritage</ENAMEX> to the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bidder</ENAMEX>? OK, OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> understands that the
dictates of the market supersede nitpicky aesthetic judgments, no matter how
right they happen to be. But must we celebrate our tainted taste on
television?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
