
   
   
      
         
            Tape That!

            Impeachment-driven press lockstep is back, with all the majors leading with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s decision to admit into evidence not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> live but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorex</ENAMEX>.

            According to the coverage, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> votes fixed the impeachment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endgame</ENAMEX> and put the proceedings on course for a wrap-up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. The end
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will</ENAMEX>, guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, be an acquittal on both the perjury and obstruction
counts, with no finding of facts in lieu of a conviction, but, after the trial,
very possibly a resolution of censure. The vote not to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in person,
note the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one in the proceedings that didn't follow party
lines: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> voted on the winning side, against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> sees "impeachment fatigue" in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s debate, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says there was little ardor or urgency in the speeches, comparing the whole
thing to a "cooling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">souffl</ENAMEX>,." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> captures a flash of emotion
here and there, noting that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> said, "If one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> has failed
to personally sit through this deposition and every deposition, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> is
not equipped to render a verdict on the impeachment trial of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> reports that when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> asked for up to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> to question <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chamber</ENAMEX>, "a clearly disgusted" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX> reacted with an audible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gasp</ENAMEX>.

            The decision to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> deposition tape into evidence for next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s phase of the trial was reached over the objections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.
Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> note that presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Craig</ENAMEX> argued in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> that the tape would add "to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">agony</ENAMEX>, to the embarrassment, and to the humiliation" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. The
Post points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote on video admissibility contains a
rider that excludes any statements made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> after the end of the
direct response to the last question, meaning that a statement by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> at the
conclusion of his appearance and an apology offered to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> at the end of hers will not be disseminated.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead editorial says the real action now is the
behind-the-scenes negotiations among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to arrive at a censure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Feinstein</ENAMEX>
are shopping a draft that condemns <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s actions as "shameless,
reckless and indefensible." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> would go for that, says the paper,
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will "rightly" insist on language reflecting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
knowingly lied under oath, tampered with evidence and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, and attempted
to interfere in the progress of a civil rights suit.

            The LAT front features a piece summarizing the witness depositions. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is asked if she thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is an intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, she
replies, "I think he's an intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." At this remark, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> full
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> "erupted into laughter." And in his
depo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> haughtily offered his version of the separation of powers
doctrine: "I do not view the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as giving me instructions."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have just
presented evidence that drug-resistant versions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> virus are more
prevalent in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> than previously thought. They say <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX>
percent of those newly infected are carrying forms of the virus resistant to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicines</ENAMEX> used in the combination-drug therapy most
successful in treating <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>, and that perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> are being exposed to
viruses resistant to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports an incident that could become another scandal for the NYPD: A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> was
shot to death by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> city cops who in all pumped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> rounds into him. The man
was unarmed, and no weapon was found near his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> report a new revelation made by the German
firm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deutsche Bank</ENAMEX> in its attempt to placate <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> whose property
ended up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s accounts so that it can receive approval of its planned
takeover of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bankers Trust</ENAMEX>. It seems there
was one little building project the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> helped finance but never mentioned
until now: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Auschwitz</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the
competition to develop a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> airplane for all the services, has thus
far racked up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 million</NUMEX> in cost overruns. The quoted response of the general
in charge of the program says a lot about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s attitude towards
sloppy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>: "This isn't an end-of-the-world problem." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
points out that the debacle is "somewhat ironic" in that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> is supposed
to be "low-end." One glaring defect in the story: it doesn't breathe a word
about what problems are causing the money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hemorrhage</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>, convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bomber and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramzi Yousef</ENAMEX>, convicted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> bomber, are both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
super-maximum security federal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">penitentiary</ENAMEX>. And according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP TV</ENAMEX>
column, the two talk when they're in the exercise yard together--about old-time
flicks they've enjoyed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner Classic Movies</ENAMEX>, which they see via the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prison</ENAMEX>'s free cable hook-up. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> wonders if they were watching last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCM</ENAMEX> featured "Escape from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alcatraz</ENAMEX>," "I am a Fugitive From a Chain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gang</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Great Escape</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
