
   
   
      
         
            This <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ain't Selling Out, It's Buying In</ENAMEX>

            Ah, the golden age of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>! Few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are more credulous about that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fabled</ENAMEX> era than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> who cover the media industry. How else to explain
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> recent articles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> lamenting the decline of editorial integrity in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
magazines?

            In its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business</ENAMEX> section <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> described a proposed
joint promotion by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogue</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeth Arden</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arden</ENAMEX> sends free products
to Vogue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. This, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> wrote disapprovingly, is "only the
latest example of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> are exploding the traditional business
boundaries of the magazine industry." (Other examples: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> generating
in-house research for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>; free trips for New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertiser</ENAMEX>'s cruiseship; and more Vogue hijinks, such as a
lecture series at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogue -Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX>
party in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamptons</ENAMEX>.)

            Leaving aside how delighted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> would be to get freebies from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Arden</ENAMEX> (doesn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> know how much that stuff costs?):
What's new about this? When did women's fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> exist to do anything
other than push <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>' wares? Consider this tidbit from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hope in a Jar:</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Making of America</ENAMEX>'s Beauty Culture by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Peiss</ENAMEX>, a just-published
history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> beauty industry:

            "When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. Walter Thompson</ENAMEX> conducted an investigation of the toiletries market
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pond's</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCall 's Service Department</ENAMEX> mailed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen hundred</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">questionnaires</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women readers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel Rawson Cades</ENAMEX>, beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Companion</ENAMEX> , opened her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' mail to the ad agency.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bazaar</ENAMEX> introduced a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Debutante Department</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX> to gain market
information for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>; it surveyed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-to-do</ENAMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,
rewarding each with a grab bag of cosmetic gifts. Similarly, in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-thirties</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delineator 's Beauty Institute</ENAMEX> called upon eight
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hundred</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to be 'beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>' for product development and
marketing purposes."

            Given the unillustrious history of the beauty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, it seems foolish of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogue</ENAMEX> 's co-promotional side deal stand for any
ominous larger trend in the industry. Also, in what way is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vogue</ENAMEX>
deal corrupt if it doesn't directly affect editorial copy? Not that
Vogue copy isn't corrupt, mind you--everyone knows that beauty
books feature only the clothes and cosmetics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. It's just that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogue</ENAMEX> 's latest scheme strikes us as an unusually innocuous way to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pander</ENAMEX>.

            Which brings us to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Wednesday</TIMEX> it broke the
story (later reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> too) that, in exchange for a lecture
or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> will be flown to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> and other idyllic spots for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>'s cruise courtesy of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertiser</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Observer</ENAMEX> treated this as a stealth attack by
business on editorial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> considers it proof that the world is a
wondrous place for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. I mean, no one's even asking them
to write articles about the cruise line!

            Besides, this isn't new either. The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> has sent its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> on freebie cruises before, and not under much-maligned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX>. Staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Singer</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> that he took the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Queen</ENAMEX>
through the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi River</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blessing</ENAMEX> of then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Gottlieb</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> was the late <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gill</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> gave lectures and were paid "cash dollars," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singer</ENAMEX>. "We
wouldn't have done it otherwise. They really made us sing for our supper. ... I
didn't have any ethical qualms or quibbles. I wasn't going to write a travel
piece or anything."

            In a memoir whose title <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> is too lazy to dig up, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Gingrich</ENAMEX>, a
founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , recalled that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> began
going bareheaded, the business side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> tried to stem the decline
of an valued advertising category by decreeing that all male <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> wear hats or be fired. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCalls</ENAMEX> sent its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">questionnaires; Vogue</ENAMEX> wants to send them make-up. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Esquire</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> wore unfashionable hats; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> go on cruises.
What was that about the world getting worse?

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
