
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bolts From The Bluenoses</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the party-line-breaking announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> that they will oppose both articles of impeachment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> gives this story the boldest headline on
its front but leads instead with word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Mellon</ENAMEX>, who
died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days ago</TIMEX>, has bequeathed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75 million</NUMEX> in cash
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> pictures--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van Goghs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seurats</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manets</ENAMEX>--worth
many times that much. The headlines focus on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> Picks Up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> Votes" is typical--with the exception of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's, which steps back to provide the context: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Majority Verdict in</ENAMEX>
Doubt <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">For Conviction on Perjury; Obstruction Faltering Too</ENAMEX>."

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> bolting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Chafee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Jeffords</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specter</ENAMEX>. Everybody quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specter</ENAMEX>'s intention to vote not "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Not Guilty</ENAMEX>," but
rather "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Not Proven</ENAMEX>." Yet, nobody says if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will actually let him do
that. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crossovers</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">semi-</ENAMEX>joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slade Gorton</ENAMEX>, who announced he will vote against the
perjury article but for the obstruction article. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> adds that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Stevens</ENAMEX> will do the same thing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>
saying there will be additional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> crossing over. Meanwhile, during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> a stream of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> announced that they would be voting against both
articles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that although failing to get a simple majority has
no constitutional relevance, such an outcome could become a "potent political
weapon" with which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> could depict the
impeachment as an illegitimate abuse of power. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Way has announced a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> campaign
to unseat <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s words "did the bidding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s
highly vocal and organized far right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also report that censure is fading fast, foundering on a
combination of strict constitutional readings and disputes about precise
wording. They all report that among censure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> a fallback has emerged:
getting as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> as possible to sign a letter condemning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
behavior. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lieberman</ENAMEX> saying that such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">document</ENAMEX> has already garnered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> signatures.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page feature warns that
whatever bipartisanship emerges after the impeachment vote may quickly fade.
And indeed, a front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece reports, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sourcing</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is so furious at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> that he has vowed to help defeat
as many of them as possible in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> elections. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has already, the
paper says, signed on to congressional campaign fund-raising events in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> attended a rally at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> designed to whip up support for his pet national service program,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmeriCorps</ENAMEX>. He wants, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> to increase the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX>'s size from
its current <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40,000 to 100,000</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> makes a point of
reporting that it found <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the rally who've never heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmeriCorps</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> does what it can for this status quo, running the story on page
10.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> each report on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeeper</ENAMEX>'s attempts to display a poster of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ho Chi Minh</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> flag in
his video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>'s window. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>, is thought to have set up the
display to anger certain of his neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Saigon</ENAMEX>"
neighborhood, home to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese Americans</ENAMEX>, many of whom fled
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> just ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> or only after being imprisoned by
them for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>. The papers report that after being previously beaten,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">picketed</ENAMEX> and served with an eviction notice because of his window display, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> won the right in court <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to put it up again. But immediately upon
arriving to do so, he was set upon by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> in front of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and hit in
the face.

            Consider <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "Business Bulletin" item about a type of
software that measures office worker skills. It mentions the location of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and lists its web site <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URL</ENAMEX>, which, in the on-line <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> is
hot-linked to the site. What governs such mentions? Does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
test such items before giving this sort of play? On the assumption that no
money changes hands, what propels such a small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> from such a small
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> when, as in this case, it's not making news?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX> has issued a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PARENT ALERT</ENAMEX>" in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> about the
Teletubbies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinky Winky</ENAMEX>." The problem is, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falwell</ENAMEX>,
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is meant to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> but carries a purse. Plus, "he is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purple</ENAMEX>--the gay pride color; and his antenna is shaped like a triangle--the gay
pride symbol."

            Just about everything in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> makes you wonder about the piece
inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> politics headlined, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tories Turning</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tips</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
