
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX>come-on

            The death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> leads at all the majors save the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>, which
top-fronts the story but leads instead with a story about state spending on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX> survey shows, says the paper, that state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have, despite winning the right under welfare reform to control a
sizeable portion of federal welfare funding, left unspent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12</NUMEX>
billion available to them in a recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine month</TIMEX> period. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> attributes
this to the steep decline in the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on welfare, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slowness</ENAMEX> to develop new welfare programs, and their desire to save money for
the next recession.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> died in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, as was his wish, after being returned unconscious
from unsuccessful <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> treatments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> His passing was announced to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> by his oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hours later</TIMEX> was sworn in as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>. The
coverage emphasizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s connections to the many different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> politics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls him a "unique <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacemaker</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> has
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s assessment: "When peace finally comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>,
his name will be inscribed upon it." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> departed for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> for funeral ceremonies accompanied by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>. The papers note that also in
attendance will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>. It may just be a case of de mortuis nihil nisi bonum , but
only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead notes (albeit rather low in the story) that King
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> sided with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> invasion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.

            
               USAT kicks off a series on worldwide <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asbestos</ENAMEX>, stunning with the news
that an epidemic of asbestos-related diseases emerging in the poorer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of
the world will in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 30 years</TIMEX> kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> involved
in mining and manufacturing the stuff. Those who will die, says the paper,
include <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> aborigines, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant laborers</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sweatshop workers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead takes note of what it calls a significant nationwide
pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> nullification. The most concrete sign of the trend, the paper
says, is the sharp increase in hung <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the norm was considered
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX>, but recently that rate has doubled and tripled in many locales.
Federal criminal cases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> average <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> and some
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> now report rates of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs a
supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> inside about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> advocate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> nullification on a hung
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> drug case <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> who was later convicted of failing to disclose her own
drug conviction during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> selection.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a home run business story on its bottom front, detailing
a quiet change in the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> handles the book recommendations and
reviews it runs on its site and emails to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>--it now charges publishers
for many of these reviews. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> is now the price tag for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">premium</ENAMEX> package for a newly released computer book, which includes the top slot
on the site's home page, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> profile or interview, and "complete
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> editorial review treatment." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> calls this "a rather
delicate move for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, which has distinguished itself with its thoughtful
editorial voice." (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disclosure: Today's Papers</ENAMEX> was once--it likes to think--one
of those thoughtful voices.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that their site
space is not for sale, and that most of the books featured do not bring a fee,
but several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that books they back with ad dollars
are rarely rejected. The piece notes two big problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s advertorial
effort: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) It makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> wonder if the raved book is really good or just
paid for; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) It puts books published by the generally more penurious
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> at a competitive disadvantage, regardless of content. The
piece also says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barnesandnoble</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, is
preparing to launch a similar advertorial program <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Outlook</ENAMEX>" documents the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s extraordinary residential
real estate boom. Compared to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, sales of existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> were up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. The numbers are so good that future results may trail <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s for
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next decade</TIMEX>. The story notes that housing purchases are a function of
household formations, which are a function of demographics, which augur a bit
of retrenchment. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>, who are responsible for much of the
growth, have probably peaked in household formation. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is getting
older, and old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> move less.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" went "beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>" to survey the
workplace experiences of some other recent interns. Give the paper credit for
noting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> job where the problem was hardly an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intern</ENAMEX>'s getting too much
attention. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">intern</ENAMEX>'s account reads in part: "I have just completed my first
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> of work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York Times</ENAMEX> ....I enter in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">mornings</TIMEX> without
anyone saying hello and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX> in the evenings without anyone waving
goodbye...."

         
      
   
