
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mills for Their Grist</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>, of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different kinds, dominates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times go with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s effort before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> go with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>' renewed interest in erecting a missile defense
system.

            The papers report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lawyers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> waged an aggressive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The day</TIMEX>'s arguments are widely seen as a continuation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>'s willingness to not only question whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX>'s facts mandate
impeachment but also to question the facts themselves. But for the most part
the coverage makes it clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> was nonetheless not the
scalpel but the broad brush.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' consensus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl Mills</ENAMEX> (the
papers want whenever possible to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> and they love new
faces), responded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>' charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had violated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>' civil rights with what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls a "spirited defense"
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s civil rights record, referring along the way to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopkeeper grandfather</ENAMEX>'s penchant for selling to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> when few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> would.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mills</ENAMEX> also put her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> firmly in the civil rights pantheon of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mills</ENAMEX>'
civil rights salute high, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> puts it at
the very bottom of its account. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also plays it high, but then
late in its story flatly states that in making this response "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mills</ENAMEX> strayed
considerably from the facts of the case." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> dings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mills</ENAMEX> for
saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case was thrown out without mentioning that the president
paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$850,000</NUMEX> to make it go away.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX>
speech was a "home run," mooting his impeachment. And they all quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Craig</ENAMEX>'s claim that "if you convict and remove <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, then no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will ever be safe from
impeachment hearings." But none of them wonder, Why would we want that?
Obviously, impeachment was designed as a sanction that would regulate
presidential conduct, a feature utterly lost if it were to become a dead
letter.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead flatly states that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> plans to construct a
primarily ground-based anti-missile
defense system by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> and that the next federal budget, due out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX>,
will plan for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10.5 billion</NUMEX> spread out over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> for just that purpose.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> goes on to point out that most of the hardware that would go into
such a system has never been tested. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that although the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> is sure the new system will be developed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has not
given final approval. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> emphasizes not the hardware but the
legal constraints, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> wrote to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
broaching the topic of renegotiating the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Anti-Ballistic Missile Treaty</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> have signed so as to allow the development of the system. Both
stories emphasize that the renewed interest in missile defense has been
prompted by the rather sudden development of long-range <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> by rogue
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also fronts the story.

            Another Rashomon effect is on display in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s congressional testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> about the just-announced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
proposal to allow some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> funds to be invested in the stock
market. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls him "wary" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says he sees a
"possible threat." Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says he "opposes" it and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says he "assails" it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news box and the LAT
front report that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> has ordered the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> to
pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$116 million</NUMEX> in punitive damages for refusing to cover an experimental
treatment for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> who later died. The papers say the award is another
sign that the public feels health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are too bottom-line
oriented.

            Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> is a great example of a piece that gets beyond the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oft-</ENAMEX>repeated facts. It's a commonplace now that the Brady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> has kept
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> out of the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX>. But it turns out, reports the
paper, none of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 13,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (mostly convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX>)
stopped so far from buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s recently instituted instant
background check has been arrested, even though trying to buy a gun by lying
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX>'s background is a federal crime.

            Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl Mills</ENAMEX> for a minute: None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the
civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> she compared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to were also secret philanderers.

         
      
   
