
   
   
      
         
            For You, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just 1999</TIMEX>

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all days</TIMEX> of discretionary news, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> revert to type.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with money--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euro</ENAMEX> is here. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> politics--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> is
trying to hammer out a workable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> consensus on impeachment strategy.
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with smog--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> rejects
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s smog control strategy as being too lax. Vexed items <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
wants in and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> wants out include mandated ride-share programs,
pollution controls on restaurant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">char-broilers</ENAMEX>, and tougher regs on aerospace
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead and front-pagers at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> all
report that finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> yesterday celebrated the first
technical step towards a common <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency--formally locking in the rate of exchange
of their individual currencies with the euro, which provides the starting point
for trade in the new currency come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The rates mean that the euro will
start out worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.17</NUMEX>. As the papers explain, although actual euro notes and
coins will not circulate until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 2002</TIMEX> (at which time national currencies
will begin phasing out), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and stock exchanges of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">henceforth</ENAMEX> required to carry out all non-cash transactions in euros.

            An inside piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes a euro-related problem <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S</ENAMEX>-based and
other transnational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> on the Continent haven't quite gotten their
minds around yet: wage transparency. That is, the advent of the new currency
will make it suddenly easy to compare salaries earned in different countries
for the same work. The story mentions a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of thought according to which
the euro's transparency effect will eventually tend to make salaries more
comparable across borders, with the suggestion that the uniformity will be
established at a level closer to the high salaries than the low ones. But it
doesn't explain why the reverse couldn't turn out to be true instead.

            It has always seemed a little odd for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> to insist on coming out on such
dead news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Years</ENAMEX>. A lot of it is just so much
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strutting</ENAMEX>--sure, spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is alright for those weenies
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> or USAT, but we're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> over here for chrissakes. And the
result is that when the world predictably stops on its axis, the workaholic
papers have to absolutely cram <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 inches</NUMEX> of new information into <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60 inches</NUMEX> of
space. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's lead about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> is a case in point: its narrative,
about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s proposing a strategy for avoiding a full trial and an instant
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">censure</ENAMEX> deal and how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> are less than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thrilled</ENAMEX>, was pretty much the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's lead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> too. The suck-it-up
publication policy seems even less sensible given that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> now have the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX> vehicle for transmitting what little holiday news there is: their web
sites. Save the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>.

            In the spirit of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, marked down to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial page
hurries to a consideration of the millenium. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> grand manner,
citing the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dionysius Exiguus, Herod</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> calendar, the page
finally comes down in favor of getting blitzed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. Thanks to its
ever-more supple closing times, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also includes a ground-level account
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX> action last night, featuring the biggest and most orderly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>, and cops. And oh yes, at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who "marked the passing of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> by vomiting
discreetly against a corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viacom Building</ENAMEX>...."

            Just when you thought it couldn't get any wilder than that--it does and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> decides to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PARTAAAY</ENAMEX>!! At least, that's what the
WP front says he's gone and done--with a headline stating "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Makes It</ENAMEX>
Official: He <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Will Run in 2000/Filing Establishes Presidential Campaign</ENAMEX>." Why
then does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> say instead with its headline that what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is doing
is "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forming Organization</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> Bid for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>," and with its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> type
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> "will take his first formal step toward running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>"? Which is it? Is he deciding to run or running to decide?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> inside feature stories about what's
being done to those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who gave themselves up to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>--they're being sent on a beach holiday. Oh sure,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , they have been so hounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> that to
avoid questions they've had to stay inside their beach <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX>, but they've been
provided with security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> to protect them from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose lives they've
ruined, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says there are reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s given them
each <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> expense accounts for the trip. And nobody's worked them to death
or bashed their heads in with a shovel.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have tried every way possible to tie up this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX> in a ribbon and present it to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX>. Finally, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> finds the right words. They're not his.
They're Hers. It turns out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s adios to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> is the
fitting farewell to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>: We're really sorry for everything that's happened.
And we hate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
