
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saigon, Flanders</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magna Carta</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and the New York
Times --lead with the hyperbolic rhetoric of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> as
they closed their argument on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> impeachment trial. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> rammed home its point that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged lying meets the
standard of "high crimes and misdemeanors" and is not the sex-sullied
triviality that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> contends. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>)
give high marks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey Graham</ENAMEX>, who made the pertinent point that
perjury has dethroned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> in past impeachment trials. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry "Hotshot</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Historian" Hyde</ENAMEX> wrapped up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> with grandiose allusions to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forefathers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> intoned, "If we [view <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as above the law], we break faith with our
ancestors from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunker Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Concord</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Flanders</ENAMEX> fields, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Normandy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iwo Jima, Panmunjon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saigon</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX>." Separately he invoked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magna</ENAMEX>
Carta, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ten Commandments</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> Law, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg Address</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spirit</ENAMEX>
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'76</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front page analysis spotlights the (predictable) shattering
of the bipartisanship illusion, a theme that resonates throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
coverage. The partisan rancor was symbolically illustrated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> penned a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX>
proposing the formation of a bipartisan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to map out potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX> icily rejected the idea as premature.

            The reigning consensus after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> did a surprisingly
good job, and the burden now shifts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to forestall
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonites</ENAMEX> will have to improve on their vague snipes of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three days</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> railed against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and invoked
the the "interests of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" refrain.

            An illuminating piece inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> article reports that foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are jumping on the lucrative <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco
bandwagon and suing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. Guatemala,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> have in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX> filed what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philip Morris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justifiably</ENAMEX> calls "copycat lawsuits" to recover <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>-paid health care
costs and other damages. The legal merit of such claims by foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> is shaky, legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> say.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sunday Report</ENAMEX>" says that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s largest
education grant program (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$118 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX>) has bombed. The
program, called <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Title 1</ENAMEX>, was meant to zap the gap between rich and poor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> but has achieved minimal discernible progress. The reasons? The money
is spread too thin, and too much of it goes to hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tutors</ENAMEX> and part-time
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teachers</ENAMEX> ("paraprofessionals") rather than full-time certified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> ethnic-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>" allegedly shot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> turned out to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> massacred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, many of whose mutilated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> were
discarded in a mass grave. The story, coupled with gruesome photos, runs on all
fronts. The papers conclude that this could sound the death knell for the
disintegrating peace agreement.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports inside that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX> may soon--finally--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">be nominated</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Sources</ENAMEX> say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holbrooke</ENAMEX> has almost cleared the
financial disclosure investigation that has delayed his nomination. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> tiff over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> has made it a particularly
precarious time for the ambassadorial seat to be empty.

            A squib inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" promisingly entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burping Cows and Space Toilets</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beam Me Up</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>!"
doesn't disappoint. The piece contains choice excerpts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Traficant Jr.</ENAMEX>'s occasional <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one-minute morning</TIMEX> harangues on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor.
(Quite often he concludes with "beam me up," a rhetorical plea to the Starship
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX>.) Here's the space toilets classic:

            "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>, space. The final frontier. The search for new life, new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">civilizations</ENAMEX> and now new toilets. That is right: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> has a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX> space
toilet. You strap yourself in and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> high-pressure air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> aid your relief ...
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>, I say [it] is time to call out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roto-Rooter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> ... Beam me up,
Scottie, nature is calling."

         
      
   
