
   
   
      
         
            Defensive End

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> end his prosecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>? No time
soon, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> lead. With conviction by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
unlikely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> now contends that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> can legally be indicted while
he still holds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. His indictment could remain under secret seal, and a
trial would almost certainly be postponed until his term expires in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. The
unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>" of the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>) also allege that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s decision to indict will be unaffected by the outcome of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
trial. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s furious reaction: "Somebody
ought to tell [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>] he's not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">101st</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story reiterates that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> doesn't consider his mandate at
all eroded by public disapproval: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prosecutors</ENAMEX> do not take polls to decide what
to do," insists <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> front the latest of these poll results: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> favor censure, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX> think the
charges should be dropped altogether (what do the other <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> want-- removal? The
paper doesn't say). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> poll is less dramatic, finding that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> support censure but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX> support conviction and removal. A
front-page news analysis in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> explains how historical vanity
could induce both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to unite around censure. Censuring the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> would make <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> look <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and responsible but also
pragmatic and unpetty. And censure would let <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> distance themselves from
the tawdriness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s misdeeds while still preserving the requisite
modicum of party loyalty.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports inside that conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> will
announce his nascent Presidential candidacy on this morning's talk show
circuit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX> is a formidable fundraiser with an extensive grassroots
network-- in the last election cycle, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 90,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> pledged an average
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">PAC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>; but without the buzz of a
national reputation, he'll be lucky to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many</NUMEX> votes as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>.
Another story inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> are
attempting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-style, to appropriate issues on which their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> are traditionally strongest. By churning out legislation supporting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> grants, local control, and parental involvement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are
hoping to re-zone education as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> real estate.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> front <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s authorization of air strikes
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, to begin if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
don't start talks on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX>-drafted peace plan by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Saturday</TIMEX>. The talks
will take place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and must conclude by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 19</TIMEX>. If a settlement is
reached, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> plans to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000</NUMEX> peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000 to 5000</TIMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> would come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> puts the number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as high as 7000</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> each front long feature stories about how
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> engender and monitor relationships among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>. The
Times reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX> has become a lively center of
discourse-sometimes too lively for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s admittedly tame taste. AOL
enlists <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers patrollers</ENAMEX> who delete 'offensive' messages from chat
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and message boards and assign demerits to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>. The company
recently nixed a heated discussion on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, raising questions about
possible <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> obligations to allow open discourse. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
story describes the far more laissez-faire approach taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX>, the
explodingly popular site that allows users to barter, trade, and sell
everything from pez dispensers to can openers. Even though the company
facilitates actual commerce, it approaches regulation lightly, relying on its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to report on behavior deemed less than "eBaysian". However, anyone found
abusing the feedback system is instantly "vaporized" from the site. Its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eBay</ENAMEX> as a utopian online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, but angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> are calling it
"an ineffectual police <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, doling out random discipline without due
process."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Magazine</ENAMEX> cover story examines the decline and fall of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> in general, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gambino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in particular. The wiser of
the wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have gone legit; the dumber ones (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gotti Jr.</ENAMEX>) preside
over sagging profits and faltering allegiances. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gotti</ENAMEX> sees himself as a victim
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government</ENAMEX>-led persecution, and compares <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> breakups of organized crime
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Government</ENAMEX>'s treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>. Gotti
has even tarnished the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppolaesque</ENAMEX> grandeur: the piece mocks his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> (a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">minivan</ENAMEX>), his attire (mock turtlenecks), and choice of repast (country-fried
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">steak</ENAMEX>).

         
      
   
