
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Truman No-Show</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with details from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s questioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> supervision at a posh hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suite</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
puts this as its very-top-of-the-page "talker" but leads with a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s
ruling blocking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' recently passed Internet porn law, which would have
made it a crime for commercial web sites to purvey material harmful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>
without employing the "electronic brown wrapper" of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> collecting
information off an adult ID or credit card. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , in a front-pager on the ruling, notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> in the
case include sex advice sites, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>, and those of major media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, but doesn't say whether the list also includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXX</ENAMEX> web <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX>.
(It's a little suspicious if it does and nobody mentioned them.) The paper
leads with a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>-after on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposed budget.

            The coverage goes high with word that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> deposition, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> was done,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> didn't question her--a sign they saw no fresh
challenges in her remarks--but instead issued a one-sentence expression of
regret "on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>" for all that she's been through. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> didn't provide any new information (to
the "dismay" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ), she also didn't retreat in
any way from her past testimony. In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that more than
once she answered a question simply be referring to her prior accounts before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> finds her demeanor more guarded and coached
than previously, so much so, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> tells the paper, that she should
teach corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> how to testify.

            The papers make it clear that the scandal's B-plot is now the controversy
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story, allegedly based on information from an
associate of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>, revealing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has concluded he has the
constitutional authority to indict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> while he's still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.
Indeed, right before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> interview, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> filed a motion in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> charging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> with "illegal and
partisan leaking." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead editorial says that with this story,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> "appears once again to have skirted legal proprieties and
invited further disrespect for its motives by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clumsily</ENAMEX> trying to manipulate the
political climate." But why can't this be said also of the press--morally, if
not legally? After all, every bit of information in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> today about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> interview is there because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> pressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> to violate laws
about leaking. Not surprisingly, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> says
that "the issue of who leaked news of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s indictment research to The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> is a phony <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead summarizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> budget proposal as channeling the
preponderance of forecasted surpluses into fixing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
as well as to new expenditures in the areas of defense and social spending. A
companion story says that under the budget, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>, senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> would get more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 cents</NUMEX> of every government-spending dollar.
(Question left unanswered: how many cents is it now?) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> quickly derided the plan as a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> strategy that unfairly
preempts across-the-board tax cuts.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> effort illustrates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s current personnel
crunch via the situation aboard the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>'s newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5 billion</NUMEX> aircraft carrier <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> --meant to be run with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 400</NUMEX> more crewmembers than it could
muster for the warm-up cruise currently underway in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> has
come up short despite such amenities as TV sets in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost every sailor</TIMEX>'s berth,
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, a barber <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> and automatic teller machines. The
main problem is the vibrant civilian economy with its array of high paying and
terrestrial jobs for many of those trained to work in aviation and engineering
specialties. The piece seems a little credulous about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s staffing
plight. For instance, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> question it doesn't raise, but seems worth asking: If
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> can, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a number of years</TIMEX>, make the plans necessary to design
and build an aircraft <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>, how come it can't, over that same length of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, plan for the personnel demands caused by the likely ebb and flow of the
outside economy?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column reveals yet another
sign of the strong economy--the job of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">butler</ENAMEX> is making a comeback. And leave
it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> to explain that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> honchofest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Davos</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, despite sounding like a cushy getaway, is actually well, brutal.
Featured atrocities: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big</ENAMEX> shots have had to do without email or limos, and the
conference exerts strategic entourage control, meaning that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Robinson</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> for human rights, has had to scrape by with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> personal
assistant instead of her usual twelve.

         
      
   
