
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Truckers</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the apparent victory in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s first free election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olusegun Obasanjo</ENAMEX>. Both
papers report that the defeated challenger has charged vote fraud. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with word that a congressional study to be released today
concludes that despite the much improved air quality in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Basin</ENAMEX>,
Angelenos are still breathing unusually dangerous levels of cancer-causing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pollutants</ENAMEX>, yielding a risk of cancer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">426</NUMEX> times the safety standard established
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s request that a federal
commission study the legality of taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA samples</ENAMEX> from every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> arrested
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, as opposed to the current practice of taking them only from those
convicted of violent crimes and sex offenses. An inside story at the WP
reminds just how pressing this issue is with a report that research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
are working on a palm-sized DNA <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> that cops could use on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saliva</ENAMEX> or
semen at a fresh crime scene to clear or implicate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> report that the margin of victory in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of votes, and that therefore the
fraud observed on behalf of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> by international election monitors
including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> probably did not affect the outcome. Given that
allegations of fraud are the spine of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX> story, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are rather
vague about what is thought to have gone on. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes no further
than quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> as saying he'd observed stuffed ballot-boxes and inflated
vote tallies. (He's also quoted referring to "results that were manipulated,"
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't explain how this differs from the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> infractions.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that in one location, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> complained about being
unable to vote and leaves it at that. Also, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obasanjo</ENAMEX> was a
former military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruler</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, but neither mentions in their capsule
governmental histories when he ruled or under what circumstances he ceased
doing so.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that the congressional bad air news about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> will
probably spur the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to establish a nationwide network for monitoring
cancer-causing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollutants</ENAMEX> in the air. The story says that despite the breathing
bummer, it used to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> worse before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Clean Air Act</ENAMEX> was adopted in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. Some of the biggest news here is buried after the "jump." For instance,
why wait until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">18th</NUMEX> paragraph to reveal that the information in the study
was previously collected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, which never released it?
Or until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">22nd</NUMEX> paragraph to mention that the risks of getting <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Socal</ENAMEX> air are still much lower (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 250</NUMEX> times lower) than the risks of
getting it from cigarettes?

            The WP front says that a comprehensive study released yesterday
concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who work outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> are not harming their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The story says that via standardized tests and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> interviews,
the study concluded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> worked during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three years</TIMEX>
after giving birth were not significantly different from those with unemployed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>. But since, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the variables considered
included how many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was employed and whether periods of
unemployment were interspersed with her working, it's curious that the story
didn't include any comparisons across those parameters. Do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only ten hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> or who knock off completely during the
summer fare better than those who work more? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't say. It also
would have been interesting if the paper had mentioned whether the study's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisabeth Harvey</ENAMEX>, has any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Ditto for the status
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> here, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Vobejda</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" describes the blooming of a little-known
economic phenomenon cropping up here and there in small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> threatened
by the outflow of local cash to say, big retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain stores</ENAMEX> in the nearby
city: the creation of local currencies, good only in town. There are now, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX> such local denominations, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ithaca</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">HOUR</TIMEX> (the
original--created <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years ago</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley BREAD</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX>'s
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't say) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barter Bucks</ENAMEX>. Surprisingly, local
currency is clearly legal. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> law prohibits local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> issuing money,
but not nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectives</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts a story by ace auto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Bradsher</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>'s move to incorporate aging-friendly features in new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, like
oversized control knobs, larger trunks for golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, and ignition keys that
go on the dashboard rather than on the steering column (arthritic wrists find
they're easier to turn there). And stand by for seats that swivel out for easy
entry and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX>. This is driven by demographics--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past decade</TIMEX>, the median
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>'s age has gone from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 to 47</TIMEX>. But the car <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are
proceeding slowly and minimally, lest they turn off legions of younger
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> reports that a forthcoming book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> says
that after he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, he became a devotee of the book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"How to</ENAMEX>
Choose the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sex of Your Baby</ENAMEX>," and subsequently fathered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> after following
the book's dictates, which included drinking strong caffeinated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> before
sex. The big news here: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> drinks <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
