
   
   
      
         
            Uniform Pay Raise

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
decision upholding the limitation on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> rights of illegal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immigrants</ENAMEX> imposed by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> immigration reform law. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> ruled that an
illegal's claim of being banished from this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on political grounds is not
a defense against deportation that requires additional federal court hearings.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s passage and sending on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> a military
pay and pension package that exceeded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s proposal.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with a compendium of Y2K alarms from aviation bigwigs,
congressional reports, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. The upshot is that aviation control
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> are
sufficiently millenium buggy that they could suffer computer problems
equivalent to those created by a massive snowstorm. But the story's
headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Flying Risky</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX>"--seems a bit shrill given that the
text below also credits <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> with having undertaken fixes
that could mean only minimal disruptions in those places.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> makes it clear that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> also forbade illegal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>' use of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to fight deportation until they have
already exhausted all administrative procedures. In short, the ruling supports
the way in which current immigration law deprives illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> of a
defense and a venue. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that even before this decision, the new
law has produced a much more active deportation rate, and so even though the
decision doesn't have that much direct impact because comparatively few illegal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> claim political persecution, it may still cut a rather wide swath,
because in the words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , it has "great potential to intimidate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> and make them wary of speaking out about any political matter for
fear of drawing attention to their illegal status."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> features of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s military pay bill, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , are a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.4</NUMEX>
percent pay raise across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, increased educational aid funds, new
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">401</NUMEX>(k)-style savings accounts, a return to a higher retirement pension rate,
and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> to the low-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> eligible for food stamps. The paper
reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> favors pay increases but only if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> increases the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s overall budget to pay for them. Otherwise,
explains the paper, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> may have to cut training or spare parts to afford
them. The story, by experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Schmitt</ENAMEX>,
communicates the widespread sentiment among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that these
costs are inevitable if readiness is to be maintained. But there is no
discussion of such readiness-enhancing but cost effective ideas as targeting
bonuses for the specific warfare specialties where retention is worst, or
restricting them to those in combat specialties (a surprisingly low percentage
of military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>). Nor does the story mention that service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> receive
a portion of their compensation tax-free, receive housing subsidies on top of
their salaries, and pay below-market prices for goods at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base commissaries</ENAMEX> and
exchanges. Or that they typically become eligible for their pensions in their
early forties, and hence these shouldn't be viewed as needing to be competitive
with civilian post-65 retirement packages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> coverage is silent
about these wrinkles as well.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the WP front a study being published <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England Journal of Medicine</ENAMEX> that seems to show that the race and sex of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> presenting with chest pains
determine the course of treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> pursue. Previous studies had produced
similar differences, but have been generally discounted as based on such
differences as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX> severity, insurance coverage, or patient preference.
But, explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, this study eliminated those explanations by using
demographically diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> describing their chest pain from identical
scripts. It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> that passes along the reward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> received for
participating--a bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams-Sonoma</ENAMEX> tomato <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>.

            The WP fronts the greatest hits from the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX>
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. In it, says the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> says she's no
longer in love with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, that she's through having affairs with
married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and that she wants to apologize to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for the yearlong
political ordeal she helped trigger.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> feature reports that one of the fastest
growing job categories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranks</ENAMEX> have
doubled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>, to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a story inside poking fun at the list of top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> most
important news stories of all time released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by a panel of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. The piece notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Killing Fields</ENAMEX>" genocide does
not make the list, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Ruth</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">60th</NUMEX> home run does (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#89</NUMEX>), finishing
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> places newsier than the election of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston Churchill</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX>
explosion outranks <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Leap Forward</ENAMEX>. And while we're at it, how, pray
tell, could the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">San Francisco earthquake</ENAMEX> finish <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> places ahead of the founding
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
