
   
   
      
         
            The Latest Unfashions

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> profile of literary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>/professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curmudgeon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steiner</ENAMEX> characterized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steiner</ENAMEX>'s career as
"a celebration of the virtues of being utterly out of fashion." (Steiner
modestly concurred: "I know an embarrassing lot. Terrible.") Once again, the
Times has spotted a trend. Although background research is out of
fashion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, we boldly did a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nexis</ENAMEX> search. Hard to believe how many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been courageously bucking fashion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 days</TIMEX> alone! Here
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 55</NUMEX> out of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">214</NUMEX> things deemed "unfashionable" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between March 21 and today</TIMEX>:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Being loyal to one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Personal sacrifice on behalf of one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. The piano accordion
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Good speechwriting
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Good screenwriting (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">in Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>'s
piece attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> )
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. The music of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Lloyd Webber</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. The belief that keeping one's job rather than changing it frequently makes
one's life and work more rewarding
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disliking</ENAMEX> television
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. Difficult poetry
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. Going to church
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>. Being middle class
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>. The literary essay
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX>. Folk music
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>. Artistic virtuosity
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>. Wine
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX>. Reticence
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. Duty and obligation
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>. National pride and glory
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>. Making sure that nuclear energy is safe
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21</TIMEX>. Employing the jobless and providing lasting benefits for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> as a
whole
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX>. Landscape painting
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>. Fat
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerity</ENAMEX> and directness
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25</TIMEX>. Integrity
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26</TIMEX>. Love
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27</TIMEX>. A feeling of irritation at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who wear open-necked shirts and no jackets
when their female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companions</ENAMEX> are more elegantly attired
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28</TIMEX>. The ideal of knowledge for its own sake
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">29</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Denver</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>. The attempt to construct a total work of art
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hootie</ENAMEX> and the Blowfish
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32</TIMEX>. Passion about one's family
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Taylor</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34</TIMEX>. Political commitment
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leigh</ENAMEX> depicts it
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> bush ballad
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">37</TIMEX>. Believing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rembrandt</ENAMEX> is a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">38</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s issues
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39</TIMEX>. Religion
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whites</ENAMEX> of modest means and fundamentalist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">41</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.O. Wilson</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">42</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43</TIMEX>. Values and family
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44</TIMEX>. Poverty and need
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">45</TIMEX>. Cacti
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46</TIMEX>. Political comedy
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47</TIMEX>. Corporal punishment
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX>'s proposal to cut the payroll tax
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49</TIMEX>. Riesling
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX>. Journalism
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>. The view that the market is getting set for a boom-bust cycle
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>. Refusing to get trapped in sterile quarrels over issues like borders and
the treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> in such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>. Learning for learning's sake
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Steiner</ENAMEX>'s essay "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humane Literacy</ENAMEX>," and its assertion, "Who would be
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> if he could be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>?" (In a review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steiner</ENAMEX>'s book by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Dirda of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> )
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">55</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sullivan</ENAMEX>

            By contrast, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renzo Piano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pritzker Prize</ENAMEX> in
architecture, "likes to think of himself as unconventional " (italics
ours), according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> has no doubt that he
does. After all, being unconventional is fashionable. Almost as fashionable as
being unfashionable.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
