
   
   
      
         
            This <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just In: Generalissimo Maslin Is Still Dead</ENAMEX>!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BRENTWOOD</ENAMEX> -- In this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, you know you're in trouble when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s taking shots at you. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dissing Titanic</ENAMEX> -- as she did during a visit with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> filmmaker
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> -- might have seemed terminally unhip. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madame</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>
proves to be down with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX>, providing the latest evidence of the
plummeting public image of the film's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Cameron</ENAMEX>.

            From the moment <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>'s name was announced as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Best</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>
Awards, his standing out here has been in free fall. Declaring "I'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woo</ENAMEX>-hooo!" to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a billion</NUMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> will do that, I guess, especially
when you're quoting your own, notably un-nominated screenplay. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just days later</TIMEX>
came his ill-advised assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>'s
sanctimonious anti- Titanic thumbsucker. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>'s mad- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-hell diatribe,
which called for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turan</ENAMEX>'s "impeachment," got gleefully picked up by everyone
from the newsweeklies to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doonesbury</ENAMEX>.

            With <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than a billion dollars</NUMEX> in box office receipts from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX> ,
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Cameron</ENAMEX> should give a rip what any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> thinks is anyone's guess, but
at least he's keeping it out of his movies. The forthcoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> --from thin-skinned action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roland Emmerich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Devlin</ENAMEX>
-- apparently features a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebert</ENAMEX> who gets squashed like a bug, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sidekick</ENAMEX> named...ah, maybe you can guess. Why, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellas</ENAMEX>? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX> dubbed a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-headed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willow</ENAMEX> monster the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebersisk</ENAMEX> and christened his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">villain General Kael</ENAMEX>. (The name of a movie bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> usually bears close
attention. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was seated next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Solomon</ENAMEX> at the premiere
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bogus Journey</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> was introduced to the
movie's antagonist, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Nomolos</ENAMEX>. "It's my name backwards," whispered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>. "I
can't believe they let me keep it in.")

            
               Yo, Chatterbox! That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is kicking our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">asses</ENAMEX>!....<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Exclamation</NUMEX> points, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-dots, vim, vigor, vitality!...Fatal
Attraction-relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> playing like unrequited
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX>-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX> romance!....Refers to himself as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>," even with tough,
tabby, gift-from- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gods columnist</ENAMEX> name of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey</ENAMEX>"...You don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb</ENAMEX>
Caen wished he'd been named "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey"</ENAMEX>?...Question: can Culturebox shamelessly
ape wildly successful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> style? Answer: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hell</ENAMEX>, yes!...

            
               Item : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX>'s production <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> buys rights to life story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liz</ENAMEX>
Tilberis, likable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bazaar</ENAMEX> who's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bravely</ENAMEX> battling
ovarian <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. Culturebox sez: Get with the program, Meg! You were born to
play serial statutory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary LeTourneau</ENAMEX>, and all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> knows it!
You'll have what she's having!... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Item : Apocalyptic drama Deep</ENAMEX>
Impact , about a comet hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, said to be leaving screening
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences bathed</ENAMEX> in tears. Culturebox sez: Being moved by a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> blockbuster
makes you feel like a sap; it's like crying at an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> commercial.
Armageddon , about an asteroid hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, still seems likely to
make more money by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>'s end... Item : <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">New</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redford</ENAMEX> movie, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Horse Whisperer</ENAMEX> , due to open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15th</TIMEX>. Approximate running time: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 hours</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty-five minutes</TIMEX>. Culturebox sezZZZZZZZZZZ: Only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things in this world
longer than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Horse Whisperer the National Hockey League</ENAMEX> regular
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Foster Wallace</ENAMEX> novel; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liam Neeson</ENAMEX> in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judas Kiss"....</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Item : Hip-</ENAMEX>hop war of words erupts between up-and-coming rapper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canibus</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten-year</TIMEX>-on-top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LL Cool J. Culturebox</ENAMEX> sez: Move over, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushdie</ENAMEX> and
LeCarre! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuttting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> MCs is a longstanding rap tradition, but the murders
of rap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tupac Shakur</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notorious B.I.G.</ENAMEX> pretty much shut down the
diss-record business. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canibus-LL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> has been feisty enough to get
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> nervous, but no one's grabbing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kevlar</ENAMEX> running suits
yet.... Item : <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Jerry Springer Show</ENAMEX> bans onstage,
you're-a-ho-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX>- you're -a-ho fighting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> says: Should boost
ratings for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heat-Knicks NBA</ENAMEX> playoff series! Decision will certainly come as a
relief to TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> market, where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>
carried a freeway suicide live on the air.... Item : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> spends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> shooting love scene for new movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet Joe Black</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> says:
Thank god for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX>!...

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Connelly</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
