
   
   
      
         
            Witless for the Prosecution

            Everybody leads with the emerging ground rules for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> impeachment
trial that starts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The headlines emphasize various aspects of what's in
the works. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> big print stresses the likelihood of live
testimony, particularly that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
headline dwells on the probability of a "full trial" leading to a vote on the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> articles of impeachment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times header says the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is in "turmoil" and claims that the
trial may "eclipse all public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headline</ENAMEX> says a short trial is unlikely.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, what is emerging from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s full shift of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> pre-trial conferences is a trial of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some weeks</TIMEX>' length that will lead
not to a censure vote, but to an up or down vote on the specific charges the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> brought against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, perjury before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> and obstruction
of justice. A trial that will probably include live <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. As the papers
went to bed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> question remained unresolved, but indications are that
a list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 8 and 15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> to be subpoenaed will be approved.

            But apparently the procedural discussions are far from over. For instance,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> might start out
the trial by offering a motion to dismiss, requiring only a simple majority to
prevail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also observes that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> get to call
live <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> may want to do so as well, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucianne Goldberg</ENAMEX> the most likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> also makes this point, but quotes Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Dodd</ENAMEX> saying that once the door is open to calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, the
danger is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> yields control of the proceedings to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> have offered
to stipulate to certain evidence in return for an abbreviated trial. No word on
which evidence, though. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX>
believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> likely to be called--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>--may not be that problematic because none is hostile to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX> saying,
"Our position continues to be no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>." On the other hand, USAT
reports that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and voted for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> margin.

            A big story that broke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inadvertently</ENAMEX> omitted from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> (without getting too specific, let's
just say it had something to do with either a faulty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T1</ENAMEX> line/browser interface
or too much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> with dinner): namely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> had in
fact been doing something that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> had long accused them
of--providing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> with intelligence information not
related to their assigned task. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that in
response, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> acknowledge that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> had
received intel from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>, but that this was only a "byproduct" of
their inspection chores. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> saying something
stronger: that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> worked undercover on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>
gives chase too, reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> employed a sophisticated
eavesdropping device that automatically transmitted signals from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s communications network to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. National Security Agency</ENAMEX>. The
deal, says the paper, was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> did this in return for getting
worked-up information back from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSA</ENAMEX> relevant to where and how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> was
hiding evidence of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> programs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that the head
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX>, has issued a blanket denial of the spying
charges.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's other bit of detailed intelligence reporting for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> received secret design information for the
most modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> nuclear warhead, the one that sits atop the submarine-launched
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Trident II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ICBM</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> suspect an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> working
at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>. The incident occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX> and was
only discovered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> is still investigating. There is debate about
what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has done with the purloined information, but, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-nineties</TIMEX>, it did test a warhead similar to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Trident's</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> headline proclaims that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bonus Was Cut</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Nearly 50%</NUMEX> Due to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mediocre Earnings</ENAMEX>." But in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph the reader
learns this means <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisner</ENAMEX> received a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> bonus of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX>. That'll teach
him.

         
      
   
