
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Back On Drugs</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s quickie trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> for
a meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernesto Zedillo</ENAMEX> that focused mostly on the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' future plans for combating drug trafficking. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>, leading instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s expected announcement
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that it will initiate the creation of quick response "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">strike forces</ENAMEX>" of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,000 to 5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to ultimately replace its current <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II-</ENAMEX>era
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 12,000 and 15,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>. The new
smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> will be designed to better meet the exigencies of post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>
threats and scenarios. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> issue not decided yet, says the paper, is whether
the time-honored names and insignia of current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> will survive in the
new scheme.

            The backdrop to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> trip is the continuing skepticism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
about the vigor of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s prosecution of the drug war. The papers take
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remarks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> should not be penalized for its
performance in this area to mean that he plans to recommend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this month</TIMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> again certify the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as a reliable anti-drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>.
Failure to do so, explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , would mean possible
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and a frosting of relations between the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            The visit also addressed non-drug matters, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX> signed agreements to increase air travel between their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, to
suppress the spread of tuberculosis, and to improve communications between law
injury. And according to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zedillo</ENAMEX>, in
their only public appearance of the visit, cited the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAFTA</ENAMEX>. In true
Beltway fashion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> spends most of its lead discussing the visit's
domestic political angle--that for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
can undertake a foreign trip without being dogged by scandal. Indeed, the
Post big print relegates "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>" to the story's subhead and never
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mentions drugs</ENAMEX> or trade, opting instead for the headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Enters</ENAMEX> a
Renewal Phase."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pager</NUMEX> looks beneath the veneer of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s
self-described accomplishments as head of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> to discover in her
tenure there a more mixed record. Yes, she is a fund-raiser par excellence, and
she did preside over the resolution of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> problems.
But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> outside study of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s
management style wanting and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have noted her tendency to add political
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> to her payroll, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Masing Will</ENAMEX>, the communications director
for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign. Then there was the prime-time television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> "spectacular" made with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>'s funds that
prominently featured Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and ran <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> before she stepped down to
consider a presidential run.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that net income at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones Global</ENAMEX> stock
index rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 4th quarter</TIMEX>, a sharp improvement over the third
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>, which the paper takes to signify that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> consumer's appetite
continues apace.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> run front-page obits on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> figure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrlichman</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> put theirs inside. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-headed domestic policy maven turned criminal was convicted and
imprisoned for his role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> cover-up and the burglary of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Ellsberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX> is quoted in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> epitaph saying of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ehrlichman</ENAMEX> that "he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
War and a tough-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> atmosphere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> effort
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">credits Ehrlichman</ENAMEX> with a bit more of a stand-up attitude than that, quoting
him saying in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> that he ran into trouble because "I abdicated my moral
judgments."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s letter to the WP notices something telling in a previous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story about "deadwood" federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. The story had mentioned
that in its effort to better understand the problem, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personnel Management</ENAMEX> had "interviewed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> who directly managed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,114</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. Of that total, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">429</NUMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> themselves." In other
words, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">629</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> in the sample were directing the work
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,685</NUMEX> nonsupervisory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, which translates to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
