
   
   
      
         
            Not Taking the Initiative

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s ruling that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> referendum process should
be maximally free of government-imposed obstacles, a story that also makes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
fronts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads with word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has sent an
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$850,000</NUMEX> check to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> as settlement in full of the sexual harassment
suit she had brought against him. None of the other papers runs this story on
its front, which makes sense since the decision to pay was reached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> (the only real news coming with the actual check is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> of the
money was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> puts it on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>, thereby enabling it to
get on instead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> is God and God is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX>, with not
just a combination lead and "cover story" but also an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-page "pullout keepsake"
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other stories inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with an impeachment run-up story.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, mostly in the West and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">midwest</ENAMEX>, provide for voter referenda, and that they have been a particular
effective vehicle for pursuing socially controversial positions. Such
controversy, explains the paper, had led several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> to
try to stem their use. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the Supremes
struck down <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>'s laws requiring that circulators of
initiative petitions be registered to vote in the state and wear identifying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">badges</ENAMEX>, and have their name, address and pay on file. The mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6-3</ENAMEX> ruling
argued that such regulations conflict with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> value of
uninhibited communication with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Senate Braces for Days of Judgement in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Momentous Trial</ENAMEX>," is mostly such desiccata as that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> will
sit as both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>..." and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation of possible crimes
became a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearlong</TIMEX> running national soap opera...." And in an apparent Iron Eyes
Cody memorial moment, it claims that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Leahy</ENAMEX> first
heard the articles of impeachment formally presented, "a single tear coursed
his cheek." Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>: if a story's headline is built around words like
"anticipates" "expects," "awaits" or "braces," odds are good there's not much
actual news in it. But the second half of this story does include some
observations that drive home the oddity of the looming process: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asa Hutchinson</ENAMEX>, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Hutchinson</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX>, is related
by marriage to the accused.

            Another sports story getting prominent play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is the auction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">70th</NUMEX> home run ball. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> say it fetched just upwards of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.7 million</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planned Parenthood</ENAMEX> and
several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> have brought a private federal civil suit against the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietors</ENAMEX> of an anti-abortion Web site that suggests abortion providers
are like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> the names and faces of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> providing the
procedure on a Wanted Poster-style list it calls the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deadly Dozen</ENAMEX>." Included
in this list was the name and likeness of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> shot by a sniper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>
in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. This is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> such lawsuit brought under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
federal law that prohibits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> or threats of force against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abortion</ENAMEX> clients
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to wrestle with what exactly on a Web site
constitutes an illegal threat.

            A piece inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> asserts that a speedy impeachment trial will
probably not disrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' legislative agenda, because "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> rarely
does much in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first few weeks</TIMEX> of a new session." But why not go further and
use some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's research horsepower to actually document this
idea--with a chart covering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent sessions</TIMEX> that graphs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' legislative
output against the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months of the year</TIMEX>?

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> dispatch in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> states that a new study in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> shows
that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> got <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">salmonella</ENAMEX> from alfalfa
quoted as suggesting therefore that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> "should consider this danger when
deciding whether to eat <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">alfalfa sprouts</ENAMEX>." Now, what exactly is the cash value
of that "guidance"? Does one dare eat the stuff or not? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> should avoid
passing along scary information nobody can do anything with. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX>
says either get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to come across with more info or pass on the
story.

            At the very bottom of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Commentary</ENAMEX>" page is a small-print
item "For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Record</ENAMEX>" stating that in a previous article on the page, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Radical Reconstructionist Thaddeus Stevens</ENAMEX> was "incorrectly described." But no
more detail is given about this. Not explicitly stating previous mistakes in
such correction notices is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> policy. But this seems ill-advised. In
this case, for instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> is left wondering what horrible goof is
being suppressed, when actually it's just that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> was mistakenly described as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX> has, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , identified and
responded to a new potential threat to its supersupersupersecret spy
operations. Henceforth, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> are off-limits to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furbys</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Spooks</ENAMEX> who have
already brought the toys into their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are advised to "contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staff</ENAMEX>
Security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> for guidance."

         
      
   
