
   
   
      
         
            Extramarital Sex in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>!

            Concealing an extramarital affair is easy as long as there are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>.
Just look at the depths to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> has been forced to sink in his
effort to prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was getting busy with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.
Gifts, such as dresses and books of poetry (even that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Whitman</ENAMEX>),
represent only circumstantial evidence, and tape recordings of private
conversations are problematic in their own right.

            Indeed, it seems that even love letters are not always dispositive. Which
brings us to the case at hand: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorena Hickok</ENAMEX>, the First
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter pal</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> relationship between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hick</ENAMEX>," as the First <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady</ENAMEX> called her, has been the subject of all
manner of speculation over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. Yet despite the existence of reams of
charged correspondence between these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, the precise nature of their
relationship has never been definitively established.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Faber</ENAMEX> penned a biography of the cigar-smoking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hickok</ENAMEX> in which she concluded that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> had not in fact been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years later</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanche Wiesen Cook</ENAMEX>, offered a starkly
different assessment. Not surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s book proved controversial, and
she eventually responded indignantly to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX> : "Why
are so many wedded to a stereotype of a frigid, sublimating, forever lonely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX>?"

            The opportunities for romance were no doubt there: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hick</ENAMEX> had a small bedroom
in the northeast corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> for much of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s tenure. So was the
motive of revenge. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> was said to be carrying on with his personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missy Lehand</ENAMEX>. And after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> found <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s trove of love
letters to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Mercer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> slept in
different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX>. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hick</ENAMEX> would not necessarily have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s
only dalliance; much has also been made of her relationship with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
state trooper and presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Miller</ENAMEX>, who was 13 years her
junior.

            Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Kearns Goodwin</ENAMEX>, whose own <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> book on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roosevelts</ENAMEX> was
critical of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> for getting carried away, acknowledged that the letters
between <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hick and Eleanor</ENAMEX> "possess an emotional intensity and a sensual
explicitness that is hard to disregard." But after this brief lapse in No
Ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kearns</ENAMEX> recovers her scholarly detachment: "Yet the essential
question for the biographer is not whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX> went beyond kisses
and hugs, a question there is absolutely no way we can answer with
certainty."

            She is, of course, right on both counts, yet idle curiosity persists. So
what do the letters say? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> has not yet seen the galleys of the new
book, but can offer up a couple of the more florid lines gleaned from previous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biographies</ENAMEX>. From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lorena to Eleanor:</ENAMEX> "I've been trying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to bring back your
face...and the feeling of that soft spot just northeast of the corner of your
mouth against my lips." From <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eleanor to Lorena: "All day</ENAMEX> I've thought of you.
Oh! I want to put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> around you; I ache to hold you close."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Mahler</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
