
   
   
      
         
            Trial and Error

            Day <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> impeachment trial leads all around. The coverage
reflects the event's two contrasting sides: Austere formal procedures cloaking
raucous partisan disputes. The LAT especially emphasizes the rigmarole, with
the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of its story sprinkled with time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX> and scene-setting ("A few
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 A.M.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry J. Hyde</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>-member
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that will present the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, entered through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chamber</ENAMEX>'s back double-doors.") and a top-front featuring a magisterial wide
shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> swearing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>. But in all
the papers the in-fighting eventually prevails--it may be a very old sausage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">recipe</ENAMEX>, but they're still making sausage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> and many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want a plan that allows the calling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, while most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> want one that does not. The attendant
complications make it seem that this could well turn out to be the trial of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries</TIMEX>.

            At times the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' tick-tocks descend into such inside baseball that it's
unfathomable that they're of any interest to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> who's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. Thus we find the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reporting, "At this point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX> said
he was learning for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, in phone calls from puzzled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, that
he was being blamed for blocking the bipartisan caucus. 'I was flabbergasted,'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX> said. 'I didn't know about any plans for any meeting.'" The leadership
finally agreed to a closed meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to try and iron
out the trial's procedural rules. None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, by the way, explains how
it can be that the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> can go into closed session. What is there to
prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> from doing the whole trial in closed session? Or for that
matter, all the rest of its business? The papers don't say.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNSCOM/US</ENAMEX> espionage story, broken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days ago</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> , appears to have legs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
government admitted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> went into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in the guise of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX> and left an eavesdropping device behind that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> allowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and "a select <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>" within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to monitor the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communications</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> who protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> and conceal his
weapons of mass destruction. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a front-page story on the
matter that says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> denies that it ever placed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> on the UNSCOM
staff, although the story also says the take of the eavesdropping operation
almost certainly helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> plan <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s bombing campaign. That
paper adds that the exposure of the gambit is thought by some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> to have
handed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> a short-run propaganda victory.

            The papers don't really get into it, but it's hard to see how this use of an
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> with special privileges is any different than say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s
use of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> to house bioweapons production, or the already widely accepted
practice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> relying on the information provided by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>-based TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> to monitor its air offensives. In short, everybody in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> situation has exploited "dual-use" technology for privileged
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. The only difference that could justify approval of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dual use
and condemnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> dual use is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> is evil and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is not.
If this point is accepted, the controversy disappears and if not, then why is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> taking steps against his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> it's not taking against say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> have
recently discussed an AT&T buyout of the latter's media properties,
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft Network ISP</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MS portal</ENAMEX> Web site and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
In return, says the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> would want money from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and also a deal to
have AT&T promote <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows NT</ENAMEX> software. (And to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Risor</ENAMEX> killed.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> has held talks at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> regarding
this matter with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX>, the phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has since cooled on the deal
because "it may not want to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s money-losing Web sites."
Sniff.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that in an email recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Air</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Force general</ENAMEX> in charge of enforcing the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> no-fly zone wrote "It's
a good day for bombing." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says he "exulted" in saying this. What proof
is there of this? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't say. And it needs to, because the statement
is one that could be made quite straightforwardly (as part of a briefing, say),
by a military professional without any untoward implications, like "It's a good
day for driving."

         
      
   
