
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Military: Mo' Problems, Mo' Money</ENAMEX>

            A slow news day yields different leads at all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> papers. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s proposed spending increase for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the growing number of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-only" welfare cases. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> of using money marked for education on
pork-barrel projects.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that on the advice of top military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will propose the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> increase in defense spending in nearly
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> and the largest since the cold-war <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX>'s. The added spending would
"address growing strains...caused by aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and increasing operations
overseas." The article says that the move might be an attempt to undercut
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> criticism about the decline of military readiness during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
presidency. The piece also predicts a lively struggle in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> over how to
pay for the increased spending.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead claims that in a growing number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are ineligible for welfare are receiving public assistance. Most
are either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> or those living with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>
because their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have lost custody. While welfare reform and a strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> have gotten many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> off the dole, welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> seem to present a
reform-proof demographic. The piece notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> cases represented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
percent of all welfare cases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>, but they now represent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 20</NUMEX>
percent. A question that is not addressed in the article: is the percentage
increase a result of more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> cases or of less overall cases? How about
a simple comparison of the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> cases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX> to the
number of cases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>?

            While bringing home the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> is not a new congressional hobby, doing it at
the expense of educational programs is, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33 billion</NUMEX> budget includes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only about $3 billion</NUMEX> in
discretionary funding, i.e. money that pays for "innovation, reform, research,
and investment." And it is from this discretionary pool, that representatives
"went hog-wild" securing money for projects in their home districts, according
to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>.

            How slow a news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> was it? A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-page article details <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX>'s
"huge psychological and physical presence" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guam</ENAMEX>. Not only have blue-light
specials made consumer goods, which were previously subject to local
price-gouging, more affordable, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kmart</ENAMEX> has become a social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, too. On a
typical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekday</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one tenth</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam</ENAMEX>'s population) visit the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">store</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
