
   
   
      
         
            Vidiocy

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">developments</ENAMEX>--approval of a trial schedule that could bring things to a close
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 12</TIMEX> and a contentious vote about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> resulting in the
possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> may end up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor. (That's just
an expression.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , betting on impeachment fatigue, puts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
testimony status inside and goes its own way with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s faltering role in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">International Space Station</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> has just learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
won't be ready with the next piece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> on time. And this comes on
top of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s decision to keep its own aging <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mir</ENAMEX>, in orbit, raising
fears that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and its programmed contribution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $10 billion</NUMEX> cannot
be depended on.

            The coverage explains that each impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> will be questioned for
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> by each side. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, one from each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, will supervise. The
witness plan authorizes videotaping of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, but requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> votes of approval before their
videotapes can be shown in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> could be called
to testify before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in person. (Even so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says in its
lead's subheader that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s votes "could pave way for public broadcast"
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> tapes.) Also decided <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> cannot
seek any additional evidence or testimony uncovered during these witness
depositions without getting the approval of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Daschle</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> call this provision giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daschle</ENAMEX> a "veto" power
over the subsequent course of the trial. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes much higher than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> with word that the notion of a "split decision,"
where a finding of fact is voted on in addition to the ultimate issue of
impeachment, is still a live option.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> expressed concern that the
schedule is actually open-ended, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX>, threatening that
the defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> might well respond with delays of its own. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> visited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to attend a
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">memorial</ENAMEX> service for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawton Chiles</ENAMEX>, a onetime <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>,
with the paper noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chiles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> made a clear reference to the
impeachment trial by stressing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> in attendance the importance of
mercy. But it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , in an inside story, which observes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
in his brief remarks eulogizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiles</ENAMEX> seemed to take an oblique swipe at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Feingold</ENAMEX>, the lone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> to vote against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two days</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off-leads and inside stories elsewhere report
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Carnahan</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponent</ENAMEX> of capital punishment,
commuted the death sentence of a convicted murder to life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> without
parole after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>, during his recent visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Louis</ENAMEX> appealed directly
to him to "show mercy" in the case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was convicted of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX>
killing of a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> along with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled grandson</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s appearance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Budget</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> gets
the usual amount of ink. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front emphasizes his warning not to
count on projected government budget surpluses to fix <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>,
primarily because budget forecasts have proven to be so unreliable. The
WP front seizes on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s declaration that the boom in Internet
stock prices is "good for our system," in that it's channeling capital to
promising new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX> before they actually turn a profit. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
inside piece notes instead that despite his doubts about the reliability of
surplus projections, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s advocacy of using surpluses
to draw down the national debt and to help fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> piece on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>'s appearance
stresses this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> stance.

            According to inside stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine General Anthony Zinni</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>,
testified at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that he had reservations about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s proposal to arm opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> because such
a move could create a "rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>" there that's even more destabilizing than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. None of the stories mention the prime recent example
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zinni</ENAMEX>'s concern: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> at war with each other and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with worldwide terrorism were incubated by a concerted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> mission
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> to arm indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> occupiers. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> account of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zinni</ENAMEX>'s appearance reports that he also resisted
calls to expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> air campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> to include attacking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">airfields</ENAMEX>. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> shoot-down <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> bristled at this, saying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zinni</ENAMEX>'s testimony was an "insult to my intelligence." Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> has introduced a new term for what the
administration would like to see happen in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>: a "regime change." The term
has the advantage of avoiding mention of such gritty matters as arms shipments
or coup plots, etc.--sort of like referring to death as a "health change."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports on a minor variant of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> problem: pre-paid
headstones with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">precarved year</TIMEX>-of-death prefixes reading <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19</TIMEX>--,
owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who are living longer than they expected to.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> is mulling easing
anti-drug

         
      
   
