
   
   
      
         

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> lead with the continuing widespread
violence in the wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>'s seizure on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> insurgent leader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX>, now jailed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> island <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. The story is also
top-front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> was marked, report the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>,
by dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> around the
world. The most serious incident was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consulate</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> shot to death <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> who were part of a hammer-
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>-wielding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> storming the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. Sixteen other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob members</ENAMEX> were
wounded. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead is a story nobody else fronts: A small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX> fraud-prevention database <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> recently discovered to have
purchased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 22 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> license pictures from the state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Carolina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> has been quietly supported
in its efforts by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $1.5 million</NUMEX> in federal funds and technical assistance
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>. The story says that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> claims to be
merely in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of fighting credit and check fraud, congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of the aid and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> envisioned using the photo file to
combat terrorism and immigration abuse.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> have been targeted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurd</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rioters</ENAMEX> because of the
suspicion among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mossad</ENAMEX> helped effect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s capture, a suspicion,
say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> denies. Some of the headlines are clearer than others
about what happened. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">3 Kurds Shot Dead in Revolt</ENAMEX>" doesn't say where or
by whom. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Israelis Fire on Kurds as Mob Storms Consulate</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unaccountably</ENAMEX> leaves to the small-print subhead the news that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>
were killed. Best is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">3 Kurds Shot Dead</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guards</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX>
Protest."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protester</ENAMEX> was killed when he tried to take a
pistol away from an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy guard</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the dead in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berlin</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and says the rioting there may "foreshadow a
season of deadly discontent as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> spread...." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> do a good job explaining the German background to the story--last
fall, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerhard Schroeder</ENAMEX>, aware of the sensitive mix of the
larger number of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, decided not to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> to
hand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX> over on an outstanding arrest warrant. But, notes the paper, doing
so would have spared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ocalan</ENAMEX> the death penalty he now faces, and hence might
have produced far less domestic upheaval. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says, for instance,
that since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s arrest, tensions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurd</ENAMEX> "have
reached the breaking point," with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamburg</ENAMEX> and
several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> fast-food stands already firebombed.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead spends a good deal of ink high up addressing the
question of whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> helped carry out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s abduction, but
waits until the last sentence of the piece--at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the 34th</TIMEX>
paragraph--to state the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s denial of involvement.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front feature reports on a
little-noticed consequence of more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>, many of them twin-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX>,
waiting later and later in life to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>: elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> now have
to gear up to teach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> about parental death. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> principal is quoted saying he assures students
"this is a fluke." But the piece makes the case otherwise: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 23</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> were born to every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 35-44</TIMEX>. But by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, that rate rose to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX>, while death rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in that bracket have dropped
only slightly.

            The LAT front and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> inside report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
district <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> has decided to accept an appellate court decision reversing
the murder conviction of ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Black Panther</ENAMEX> Elmer "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Geronimo</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pratt</ENAMEX> because a key
witness lied on the stand when he denied being a police informant. The case has
long been a flash point in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> race politics, attracting the vocal involvement
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnnie Cochran</ENAMEX>, who, although mentioned in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , goes oddly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unmentioned</ENAMEX> in the LAT account.

            The USAT front reports that, in what is probably the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> posthumous
presidential pardon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will today pardon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry O. Flipper</ENAMEX>, the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Point</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1877</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flipper</ENAMEX> was accused of
embezzling fort funds. Although acquitted of that charge, he was convicted of
another stemming from the original case. Burying the news seems pandemic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>:
this story waits until the last paragraph to inform that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> stole the money
and accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flipper</ENAMEX> of doing it out of racial hatred.

            As he has done many times before, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Herbert</ENAMEX> uses solid
reporting to detail a police outrage. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it's a case of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Honduran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant</ENAMEX> who
tried to step forward to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> cops what he knew about a collision
involving an unmarked police <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. For his trouble, he was flipped to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX> and beaten so severely that he went blind in one eye. Recently, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX> sued for false arrest and excessive force. One passage in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX>'s account
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vividly</ENAMEX> demonstrates arrogance in blue: When, in open <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>
accused of body slamming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX> was asked to demonstrate his actions, he
did the same thing again full force to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. And, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX> notes, grinned
while he did it. Fortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> weren't laughing. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, they
returned an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.2 million</NUMEX> verdict against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
