
   
   
      
         
            No <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese</ENAMEX> Checkers

and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s revelation that a
special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s secret report concludes that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two</TIMEX>
decades <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have transferred significant amounts of military
technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, thereby damaging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> national security. This story is
also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , which leads instead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s
proposed plan for a streamlined and quick impeachment trial, and at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
which leads instead with polling showing an easing of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' fears about
Y2K. Despite any general Y2K calming, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-pager notes a dawning realization
among technology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>: come next <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>, many of them will be not at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, but at work monitoring their computers' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX> performance.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> report was unusually bipartisan, receiving unanimous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> approval and finding <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> acquisition of military secrets
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transpiring</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> alike. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees in the findings a criticism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> policy
of loosening export restrictions, which, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, the committee
wants re-cinched. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> points out that the pot-and-kettle aspect
of the findings may help deflect criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. The congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>, prompted by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX> describing the unsupervised
flow of sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s strategic rocket programs,
confirmed that transfer, but, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, went much further, also
uncovering the theft by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> of nuclear weapons design technology from
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> and examining the too-loose export controls governing advanced
computers. Also included was a look at the covert donations to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
political campaigns made during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> election by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> aerospace
executive. The papers draw their information from remarks made by the committee
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Cox</ENAMEX>, but, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , it's unclear exactly how
much more the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> will ever be allowed to learn about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX>'s findings.

            It's been known for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> favored a streamlined trial for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but what's new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are
some of his details. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the proposal would have the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> voting by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth day</TIMEX> of the trial about whether or not the alleged
offenses, even if proven, would count as high crimes and misdemeanors. If that
proposition didn't get a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> majority, then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> would move on to
consider censure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> impeachment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>
expressed "major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>" about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>'s plan to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>--mainly
that it doesn't provide for the calling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> succinctly explains why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> plan is gaining ground in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>: it gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> an opportunity to avoid a long trial, while at
the same time affording <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> some kind of vote on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
impeachment.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a second straight day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> anti-aircraft fire drew a tough <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
response. This time, after a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was shot at, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> warplanes hit
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> implicated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and smart bombs. As it did
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX>, yesterday <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> again claimed to have shot down a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>.
The papers all note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> denies this, but none observes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
hasn't done something that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> who have shot down <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> have done since
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Baron</ENAMEX> got bagged--produced wreckage. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s goal is not so much
to shoot down a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> as to keep the no-fly zones in the news, his
strategy may be self-defeating: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> puts the story above the fold,
but repetition is driving it inside elsewhere--page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> finds front-page space <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> for what you might call the
Y2K problem for classicists--there is no agreed-upon way to
write out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> numerals. Who cares? Well, explains, the paper, there
are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> (How to mark the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cornerstones</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>?), and the movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> (How to write the copyright date at the end of the credits?). Thank
on this.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX> makes the point that the rescue of those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">balloonists</ENAMEX> is rich-dude welfare. How much welfare? Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guard</ENAMEX> to run the numbers and learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rescuing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Branson</ENAMEX> and company
cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130,275</NUMEX>. And, he adds, under the law the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX> cannot
even send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX> a bill. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hooray for Cohen</ENAMEX> and is still
amazed that news stories don't routinely do this kind of math. For instance, TP
is still waiting for a news story that states the cost so far of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">octuplets</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
