
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atomic Bombshell</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead reveals <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s plunder of nuclear technology from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laboratories</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>'s subsequent mishandling, avoidance, and suppression
of follow-up investigations. The story, sourced to unnamed "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>,"
gives damning shape and detail to recent news rumblings about illicit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
acquisition of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> defense technology. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980</TIMEX>'s, reports the paper, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chinese-American scientist</ENAMEX> working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> government laboratory sold
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> the recipe for launching multiple warheads from a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>, thus
providing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> with the "backbone of a modern nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>" and a
near-duplicate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most advanced atomic tools. The espionage
was detected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> noticed the stunning similarity between
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>. They also found evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> had been
continually exploiting lax <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> security measures to steal information. But the
thefts were only haltingly investigated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, and no arrests have ever
been made.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Notra Trulock</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX>'s chief of intelligence and the sole
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of the account, continually tried to alert higher-ups at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> about the size and impact of the theft. But his
repeated warnings were brushed off ; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Moler</ENAMEX>, the
then-acting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>, told him to withhold his findings from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>,
who could use them to criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s policy towards <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The
Times also suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> itself downplayed the findings
in order to protect its delicate rapport with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Finally, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> Trulock
secretly shared his findings with a bipartisan congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> monitoring
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> security situation.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> underestimate the story's import, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> quotes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who rank the breach as far worse than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> committed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX>, and on a par with the misdeeds perpetuated (also at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX>) by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julius</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethel Rosenberg</ENAMEX>.

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> front page reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
are threatening military strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> provides Taiwan
with missile defense systems. The story carries no mention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">revelations</ENAMEX>, but emphasizes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> tensions have already chilled to
their coldest point in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> front ebullient reactions-- from
the stock market, the bond market, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> cheering in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bleachers</ENAMEX>--
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX>'s announcement of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>'s strong job growth and low
inflation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> tucks the story inside. The Dow Jones average hit
new highs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.8%</NUMEX> rise to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,736</NUMEX> points, and bond and interest
rates dipped in deference to the good news. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturing</ENAMEX>, the one sector to suffer job losses, has become bifurcated
between commodities-based industries, which are vulnerable to overseas
recession, and consumer products, which are less so. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story
offers a more measured tone, with now-familiar caveats about unsustainable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pace</ENAMEX>. It also backgrounds the jobs report with helpful descriptions of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">methodology</ENAMEX>. (Example: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX>'s job growth stats are based on the
relatively small and volatile 'household' survey, which polls <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> on how
many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household</ENAMEX> are working, instead of wage reports from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>. The latter are considered broader and more reliable).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> has struck down the ability
of rape and domestic violence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> to sue their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attackers</ENAMEX> under federal
civil rights laws, a power first granted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1994 Violence Against Women</ENAMEX>
Act. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> are desirable venues for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> because of their high
damage awards and relatively lax statutes of limitations, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> found
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' claims outside the constitutional scope of its jurisdiction. The
account doesn't remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that even at the time of the bill's passing, the
provision was generally considered a socially sympathetic but legally
overambitious expansion of federal court power.

            In the latest report of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> mishaps, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Times</ENAMEX> fronts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s
sheepish acknowledgment that it has been treating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">630,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> to special
natural-disaster-area privileges, even though most haven't been beset by any
natural catastrophes at all. The poorly written rules give interest-free loans
on late taxes to any and all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of areas deemed disaster areas, instead
of those actually impacted by the event.

            Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> explains how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Ethics Committee</ENAMEX> ruled that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">swanky Club</ENAMEX> seats in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s new sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> are actually-- whaddya
know!-- inexpensive enough to be considered 'nominal' gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX> usually retail for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$98</NUMEX> a pop, but if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> types refrain from reading the free programs and parking in the
complimentary <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethics Committee</ENAMEX> will consider the seats worth a much
more acceptable <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$49.50</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
