
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Person</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mood: Conditional.</ENAMEX>

            Can a memoir have the authority of history? That's a question Culturebox
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ponders</ENAMEX> ... uh, every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and again. She didn't expect to ask it about the work
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund Morris</ENAMEX>, though. It was his pleasing intellectual conservatism--his
defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s manly colonialist aspirations, for
instance--that made the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> seem such a
suitable choice for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s invited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> to dinner
to be interviewed for the position of official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> surely
wasn't thinking: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ah</ENAMEX> yes! Let's bring this fashionable memoir <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> face to
face with the Gipper!
            

            What a surprise, then, to come across the following title in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> fall catalogue: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>: A Memoir of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edmund</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>. This is the most eagerly awaited political biography of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>? In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> received what was at the time the biggest advance ever
paid for a work of serious nonfiction: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX>. He was granted unfettered
access to the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> while he was still in office. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 13</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slighter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographies</ENAMEX> appeared, obligatory deference was
paid to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>'s forthcoming magnum opus.

            But a rumor floated: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> had lost presidential favor. The book was late
(it was due in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> told a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was
"impossible to understand," a dilemma that had caused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> to experience a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>. (He later clarified: "What made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> uniquely difficult
was that he was incurious about himself.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> would reveal that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">faculties</ENAMEX> had been on the decline since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, when he was shot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> was now so advanced that he no longer knew who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> was.

            Could <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> have turned out to be rebarbative to the biographer's art--so
emotionally hollow as to be uncharacterizable, perhaps? Is unlimited entree
less a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX>'s blessing than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX>? In an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> downplayed expectations: "If you want to
know what happened at a specific meeting, read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lou Cannon</ENAMEX>'s book. I'm investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>; my book is a
study of his life and imagination, and his gift for stirring the
imagination."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris dismisses Culturebox</ENAMEX>'s doubts, saying his book will retain the
breadth and depth of a biography: "It's just simply the fact that I spent a lot
of time with him in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and had the chance to talk with him a lot.
It's a privilege most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX> don't have, at least not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographers</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presidents</ENAMEX>. We schmoozed a lot and had long dialogues."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culturebox</ENAMEX> says: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hmm</ENAMEX>.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
