
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Jury</ENAMEX> Dullification

            Day One of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> impeachment trial leads all around. Banner headlines
are the order of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> headlines focus the most on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s alleged conduct, with the former citing charges of "perjury" and
"obstruction," and the latter charges of "egregious and criminal conduct."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX>'s big print emphasizes procedure, with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prosecutors: Call Witnesses</ENAMEX>
Against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>." The WP header combines form and substance with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prosecutors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lay Out Clinton</ENAMEX>'s 'Scheme'" running over a reference to their request for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. But only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> headline mentions what this is all
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s attempt to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from office.

            The WSJ observes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> who spoke
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> have substantial courtroom experience with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dept</ENAMEX> or as
local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>, and that they emphasized the more difficult to prove of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> impeachment articles, obstruction of justice.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> excels <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> at focusing on clear detail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes a
new argument from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Sensenbrenner</ENAMEX> on the topic of whether
or not perjury counts as a high crime or misdemeanor, namely that bribery is
listed as a high crime and under federal sentencing guidelines, perjury and
bribery carry the same penalty. Also, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that makes the
striking point that despite all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s presentations and those to come, the
rules of impeachment leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> "free to vote as they choose for whatever
reasons they cho[o]se or for no stated reason at all, without regard to the
usual rules of evidence."

            Among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who pressed the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The NYT</ENAMEX>
gives the highest marks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asa Hutchinson</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX> made some fresh points out of familiar details, and then the paper
clearly states them: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) In response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> claim that any help
given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> in her job search was not a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">quid</NUMEX> pro quo because the
help preceded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX> showed how
nonetheless the job search assistance effort became markedly more urgent once
she did have such a role; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) To the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
could not have been attempting to sway <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>'s testimony because his odd
conversation with her took place before she was called as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hutchinson</ENAMEX>
observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had just been questioned at length in the Jones
deposition about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> and hence it was clear to him then that she was likely
to be called; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) To the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s denial of a
sexual relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was literally true because of the odd
definition of such relations he was presented with, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX> points out that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s denial predates the appearance of that definition and hence should
be considered a common sense falsehood that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> encouraged. By contrast,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> spares the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> these details, saying only that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hutchinson</ENAMEX>
presented his case "with a bit of folksiness and some narrative drive."

            The difference here is an important one. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's assessment occurs
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead, a piece lamenting the absence of cross-examination and witness
breakdowns. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Von Drehle</ENAMEX>, immediate past honcho of the
paper's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section (not, please note, its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Substance</ENAMEX>" section), marvels
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> could sit still and pay attention to all this. His piece runs
under the headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On The Floor, The First Day Wore On, On, On</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>, is similarly restless: "Who'd have thought," he
asks, "that making history could be such excruciatingly ponderous torture<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" In
other words, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's lights, it's not that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
are mean-spirited, unfair, or immobilizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. It's much worse than
that: they're not entertaining . This confusion of merit with style is
catching on. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead editorial, arguing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s misdeeds are
not impeachable, is headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We've Heard it Before</ENAMEX>."

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter jets</ENAMEX>
have attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> anti-aircraft and surface-to-air missile batteries. But the
majors' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> have consistently stuffed these incidents inside. Indeed, the
Post dispatch is on page..<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.25</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
