
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo Kiss</ENAMEX>-Off

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the renewed outbreak of fighting between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> as the peace talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> falter. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
off-leads that development, but leads with a story first tipped by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
decision to reject the sale of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> business
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">consortium</ENAMEX> because of concerns about hurting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> security and boosting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
military capabilities. This story is also on the LAT front. Both
Times run top front pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> fleeing from the fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
fighting, documenting that their number includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> also off-leads <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> but its lead
is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s signal from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that despite
recently endorsing a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> across-the-board tax cut, it will no longer
press very hard for it, because, says the paper, of stiff opposition from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> who fear the plan is too costly and politically risky
because it smacks of favoring the rich. Into this breach, explains the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , will go an attempt to scale back the marriage penalty paid by many
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-earner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>, and other targeted tax relief proposals. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with the upswing in federal health care fraud prosecutions, resulting in
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">unprecedented</ENAMEX> numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> going to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Sixty</NUMEX>
percent of these cases involve bogus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> billing. The story's
headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feds Triple Health Fraud Cases"</ENAMEX>--commits the sin of a vacuous
comparison, but the body explains that the baseline year for the comparison
with current prosecutions is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead describes the erosion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> talks. It spells out
the stumbling blocks: the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> want an eventual referendum on independence
written in, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> are balking at the interposition of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the tactical
situation is likewise deteriorating. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are now
moving large numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> in violation of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> cease-fire. And some of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,300</NUMEX> unarmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> of that agreement
have come under attack from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobs</ENAMEX>, and some have been beaten by
uniformed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>.

            It's becoming clear from the coverage that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> negotiating strategy--to
get the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and then threaten the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> with airstrikes--has
come a cropper because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> have been, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's
words, "flabbergasted" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>, especially by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> frequently argue among
themselves. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that they've never had to make collective decisions
before. And as one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> tells the WP : "We can't jam the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>
until we get the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> suppression of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX> deal reverses its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>-long policy of promoting such commercial
sales, making it likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will interpret the quashing of this
transaction as a fundamental retreat from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy encouraging expanded
economic relations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Dept.</ENAMEX> approved of the sale, but
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> opposed it on the grounds that the technology involved
could result in making <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s ICBMs more accurate. The paper pushes down to
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">18th</NUMEX> paragraph news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> included questions about the
behavior of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes Electronics</ENAMEX>, the satellite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX>, in the consummation of
prior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> satellite deals, in which questionable briefings to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and a questionable hiring of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> took place.
This suppression of news is particularly odd here because these very relevant
facts were turned up in previous Times stories.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> go inside with news that in an alternative
universe would be explosive--a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s finding that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cabinet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">secretaries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Babbitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>, are in
civil contempt for failing to produce records of accounts
held in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> doesn't mention
the names of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> paragraph. Also, the paper never
mentions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in this case, who suggested the failure to produce
smacked of official deceit, had previously harshly ruled against the
administration in the matter of whether or not closed meetings of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>-led health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> were illegal, levying a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> fine
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> goes right out of the box with mentions
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babbitt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubin</ENAMEX>, and cites the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s previous ruling.

            In reporting on the news that blue <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi Strauss</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downsizing</ENAMEX>, headline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have trouble finding a new, er, wrinkle.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> opts for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Company Cuts Jobs, Closes Plants, As Sales Shrink</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popularity Fades</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reader Kerry Lauerman</ENAMEX>, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> , alerted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers to something odd about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watts</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was quoted comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> voting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX>
supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colonel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>. It turns out that this is not a fresh quote, but
rather has been attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in newspaper articles going back at
least to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s instance wasn't even the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time the quote has
appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. It's bad enough that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> missed this, but
shouldn't an LAT <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> have noticed?

         
      
   
