
   
   
      
         
            Spring Breakdown

            The whimper-not-a-bang end for now at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> talks leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> puts the talks on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> and instead leads with
the guilty verdict in the race-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tinged</ENAMEX> dragging murder case in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jasper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
which off-leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> talks and fronts the murder conviction, goes with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s imminent reevaluation of the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> statute, which,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, will probably either not be renewed at all or will be
substantially revised, primarily because of widespread dissatisfaction with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> the law worked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a similar piece inside. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> "cover story"
on the statute is more categorical, saying flatly, "there is virtually no
chance that a scandal-weary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>" will renew it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rashomon</ENAMEX> reporting reigns supreme in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
talks. The talks ended with nothing signed, no peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in place,
and no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airstrikes</ENAMEX>. Instead, there was the surprise quartum <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">quid</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> saying they "understood and accepted" the proffered
Western peace plan but would take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> off to check in with the home
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> before signing anything. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees this as a "major setback" for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and drives home the tenuousness of the situation by
noting renewed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> fighting and passing along <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence
reports of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> troop movements "in apparent preparation for a large-scale
offensive." Somehow though, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with the glass-half-full
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headline</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reversal, Say They Will Sign Peace Pact</ENAMEX>," and
calls the outcome a "limited success." But even within such a cheery take, the
paper has to admit that it will be difficult in the interim for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to
intimidate or contain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> sees a
"piecemeal success," but does point out that the result is very close to what
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few days ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> called "a worthless piece of paper."
(Actually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> informs, the non-result is on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX> pieces of paper.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> further brings out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s non-accomplishments by noting that
thus far, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> have refused to even discuss military and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> issues.
Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> points out high and clear that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>' promise to sign would quickly evaporate if they meet with strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX> criticism before the talks reconvene.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supremacist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John William King</ENAMEX> was convicted
of capital murder in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jasper</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 2Â</NUMEX>® <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and that the jury immediately
plunged into the case's penalty phase, which could result in a death sentence.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are awaiting trials for their alleged part in the grisly
murder of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49-year-old</TIMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's coverage of the case
includes some good detail on courtroom spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> appeared in court with his
hair grown out so as to cover the pentagram tattooed on his skull and in a
turtleneck shielding the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> symbols on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King's father</ENAMEX> offered his condolences to the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            Contemporary reporting has a hard time lighting on a topic unless it can
find a way to make it into a political story, preferably one about a
personality conflict. Witness the story about competing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> trade bills
inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> bill was devised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse L. Jackson Jr.</ENAMEX> and the
other by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Rangel</ENAMEX>. So naturally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> waits until the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> paragraph of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> paragraph story to say what the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bills are and
how they differ, and none too clearly at that. Far more important apparently,
is taking up the top of the piece with the back and forth sniping between the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bill <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> will broadcast
its long-held interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>, who claims that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>, raped her. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , which
has not previously covered the story per se, weighs in with a lengthy account
of its halting path thus far. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> includes this interesting detail, which drives home the unusual course the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> story took getting to the WSJ op-ed page: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Murray</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>, says he <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> found out about his
paper's article by reading about it on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>'s web site.

         
      
   
