
   
   
      
         
            Pontifficating

            All the majors lead with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s defense in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and lavish most of their attention on the concluding speech given by
former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Bumpers</ENAMEX>.

            The consensus is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpers</ENAMEX>' aw-shucks style and his rhetorical flourishes
were viewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> as a refreshing contrast to the lawyerly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nit-picking</ENAMEX> (such as that displayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX>,
who also spoke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>) that had heretofore carried <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Apple assesses Bumpers</ENAMEX>' effort as "rare eloquence" and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> calls it an "extraordinary appeal." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> plays high <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpers</ENAMEX>' challenge to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
not to vote for impeachment in order to avoid heightening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s alienation
from their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> plays this much lower. The papers note
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpers</ENAMEX> made no effort to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s conduct, calling it
"indefensible, outrageous, unforgivable, shameless." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes high
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpers</ENAMEX>' view that nonetheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s actions "do not even come close
to being an impeachable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>" because they were not "political offenses
against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpers</ENAMEX>' observation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should have thought
about the consequences of his actions beforehand. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> leaves out what
happened next, which is however reported by the WP : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpers</ENAMEX> pointed at
his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, saying, "Just as you and you and you and you, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been caught in similar circumstances, should
have thought of it before." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> is also alone in noting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpers</ENAMEX> broke new ground for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> by explicitly citing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s high poll numbers as a reason to acquit.

            The coverage suggests that in the wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpers</ENAMEX>, momentum is building
among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to press for a quick resolution of the trial, even to the point
of omitting all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> emphasizes this more than the details of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpers</ENAMEX>' speech. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's lead editorial calls for bringing the
trial to a rapid end. It's recognized all around that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the proceedings
will enter a far more spontaneous stage, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> submitting their
questions in writing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs questions
submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. It will be interesting to see if the actual questions
posed are equally sharp.

            The off-lead at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s murder
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinas</ENAMEX> was found guilty by the trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> of being the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the successful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> assassination of a fast-rising political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. He
was sentenced to fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. The outcome signals, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> no longer enjoys its traditional impunity.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" runs some poll
figures about the budget surplus: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX> prefer using it for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29 percent</NUMEX> want it to go for domestic spending, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 22 percent</NUMEX>
favor tax cuts.

            The LAT front carries an exclusive account of a particularly twisted
computer crime. In the first prosecution ever under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s cyber-stalking
statute, an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (who, natch, lived with his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>) is being
tried for using the Internet in an attempt to set up the rape of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
had spurned him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> sent out email and posted online ads purporting to be
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> suggesting she desired to act out fantasies of being raped. The
postings resulted in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> showing up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> at
various times, although no rape occurred. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was caught with the
assistance of the Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> involved, which included <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotmail</ENAMEX>.
It's hard to know what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> could have done to protect herself, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes--after all, she didn't own a computer.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX> is returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. But it's
an inside piece at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> that has the most surprising news about the
upcoming visit--this time, he has corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheraton Hotels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes-Benz</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> defend the practice, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , as a way of avoiding
charging the poor to see the pontiff. Perhaps the wackiest papal product
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">placement</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Frito-Lay</ENAMEX> promotion that plays off the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">papa</ENAMEX>,"
which--thank God--means both "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
