
   
   
      
         
            Albrightness

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> convening face-to-face talks
between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbians</ENAMEX> regarding their fighting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> inside and goes with word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are deep in
discussion about what to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> win its
antitrust case. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also puts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> inside and leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX>'
claim that it could resume a normal schedule by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> come back to
work under a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s threat of heavy fines if they continued staying out in
support of pay parity for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> of newly acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno Air</ENAMEX>. The paper
reports that as of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> were on the AA sick list,
down from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,100</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. One detail missing from this and
usually from other labor sick-out stories: When so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> miraculously
call in sick on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX>, does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> ask for a note from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and
if so, do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> then lie?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> had already been
ensconced in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> country <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chateau</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> showed up and
got them to sit down together. (What had they been doing there until then,
passing notes? The papers don't say.) Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>
as more open to the basic terms pushed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>--primarily the interposition
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>-led peacekeeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> that would include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>--than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>. But they differ a bit about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s assessment of prospects. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes her high saying, "There is every indication they will be
ready to sign by the time the conference is over." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes
her saying "I will not be able to say that the path to agreement is clear or
that success is in sight" before having to leave to report back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's account stresses personal conversations <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> had with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegations</ENAMEX>. Details: she reproduced a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> lullaby from her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>
childhood for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> and told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> that he should
model himself on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX>, political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the IRA who foreswore arms
for peaceful leadership. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the LAT account dwells
instead on the concerns expressed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> by some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> congressional big shots
regarding a possible new deployment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>, a concern
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> relays inside in a separate article.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s discussions about what sort of
remedies to ask for if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is found in serious violation of anti-trust
law have become more detailed recently because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> feel the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is
stumbling in its court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX>. A forced breakup is currently envisioned by the
government as coming in two flavors: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Carve MS</ENAMEX> into one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that sells
only the Windows operating system and one that would sell other MS software
products, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Split the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or more</NUMEX> nearly identical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>. The
big questions in all of this, says the paper, are: Would such moves really
create new competition? And which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>? (Perhaps if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cloning</ENAMEX> technology continues to pick up speed, the latter problem can be
avoided.) This story obviously comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, but since that's so
obvious it's not clear why they don't fear looking too confident of victory
while the trial is still in progress.

            Like a decapitated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> still racing around the barnyard, the papers
continue to front impeachment-related topics. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes top-front
with a piece wondering if a post-scandal return to political civility is upon
us, and above the fold with the debate within the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranks</ENAMEX> about
whether or not to make impeachment a major issue in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential
campaign. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager reports on a new poll finding that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> approve of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> acquittal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> but blame him
for the impeachment trial. Similarly, most say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> should end attempts
to censure him, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should have to face criminal
charges either now or after he leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> covers a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> meeting of moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> worrying about how to repair the image
to their party that they say was inflicted by its prosecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The
piece quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> saying that "the good news is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still like us," and then reports that the
meetings were held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Doral Golf Resort</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spa</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> run stories inside about the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> study of crimes involving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Indians</ENAMEX>, released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>. Salient findings include: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of
violent crime more than twice the national average, and unlike most other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, where the large majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> are the same race, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX>
percent of those committing crimes against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX> are not <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX>. The report
also notes that the rate of murders by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>, which is below
the national average of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7.9</NUMEX> per and the white rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">4.9</NUMEX> per.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> television column reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&E</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Biography</ENAMEX>" profile
of likely presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> reached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> in its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> airing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. But the column also reports that a recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Biography</ENAMEX>"
broadcast on the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro wrestler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> did more than twice as
well.

         
      
   
