
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torn NATO Watch</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> brings the deadline for agreement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> peace talks, and
everyone leads with the standoff between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslav</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> over the latter's compliance with the proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">accord</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> reiterated his staunch refusal to withdraw forces
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>--"even if the price is bombing"--and shunned meetings with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> responded by threatening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX>, to be
launched immediately if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> doesn't accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX>-drafted compromise
and evacuate the great majority of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pointedly</ENAMEX> reminds its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s last threats of air strikes were
scrapped for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last-minute</TIMEX> negotiations, which merely won admittance of an
unarmed monitoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> (a far cry from military withdrawal). The papers all
quote the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> as saying that strikes will definitely be ordered if the
deadline passes without agreement, but they give varying impressions of when
the first bombs could actually fall. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times puts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> "on the brink" of launching strikes, with "warplanes
ready to scramble," but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> writes that bombing would have to wait for
final approval from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member officials</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "set no
clear timetable" for action and that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">48 to 72 hours</TIMEX> would pass between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>
orders and actual strikes.

            Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story includes this reflection on the impeachment
verdict, shared by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> during his news conference on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>: "I think
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> has been, in effect, re-ratified."

            Politely acknowledging <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s LAT scoop, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead
confirms and elaborates on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> involvement with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdullah Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s
capture. Anonymous government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> admit that throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> on the lam, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> funneled surveillance data on his whereabouts to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commandos</ENAMEX>, and lobbied <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> against
sheltering him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> stress that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> had no "direct involvement" in
the pursuit, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> did no more than monitor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ocalan</ENAMEX>'s
movements.

            The WP fronts allegations made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>, known
throughout the impeachment scandal by her Jones lawsuit alias "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jane Doe No. 5</ENAMEX>,"
that she was raped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> conducted
off-the-record interviews with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>, but wasn't granted
permission to print them until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>? By the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in the Jones
case? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't say). Details of the alleged encounter echo the ones
revealed on the op-ed page of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> :
then-gubernatorial candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> invited an innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> to have
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> in his hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and then forced himself on her, biting and bruising
her lips. Previously, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> both denied the allegations and kept them from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> deemed her story too shaky
to pursue. But the allegations were reviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> anyway, in a
sealed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> just prior to their vote on impeachment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> offers no
speculation as to how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s accusation might complicate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
legal troubles or the dimming scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that she
remained silent until now out of fear and shame, but is now talking in order to
teach her twin granddaughters the value of honesty: "I want them to say, `<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">That</ENAMEX>
was a neat thing you did.'"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the LAT front a new effort by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX>
to avoid musculoskeletal disorders in the workplace. Ailments such as carpal
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">tunnel syndrome</ENAMEX>, lower back pain, and tendinitis account for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of all
serious workplace injuries <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>, and guidelines will require <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 2</NUMEX>
million <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> to prevent and treat their assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line workers</ENAMEX>, database
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clerks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, among others. Business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have long opposed such standards on the theory that compliance will
cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than the $15-$20 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> currently spent on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>'
compensation for these injuries.

            A story inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media titans</ENAMEX> are
already wining and dining Presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopefuls</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are on an unabashed fundraising mission, but
the moguls are simply trying to "enliven the presidential dialogue" and
"stimulate discussion on meaningful subjects." The story does not consider that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> may have more practical reasons for securing political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friendships</ENAMEX>. For example, no mention is made of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Diller</ENAMEX>'s extensive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX>-and-internet-business holdings, which could be massively affected by
regulatory legislation expected from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>. The gatherings,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sighs Diller</ENAMEX>, are "simply a reaction to the emptiness of the current retail
political process."

         
      
   
