
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Radar Days</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s skirmish between an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi anti-</ENAMEX>air <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> battery and several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> combat aircraft enforcing
the no-fly zone over northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
fronts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, but goes instead with the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> to
defy international pressure by not putting on trial two top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>
who just defected into his custody <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> combat is on the front below the fold, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> is nowhere in sight
and the lead is the real possibility that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> will be canceled
combined with a warning from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> that if so, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> might start their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>. It's not just USAT that puts such
a high premium on sports--according to a story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>'s Newspaper runs
inside, in the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> poll of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">runaway</ENAMEX> number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> was You Know What, but number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> was the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire-Sosa</ENAMEX> home run race.

            The papers report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> began when an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
battery fired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> then fired
radar-seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and laser-guided bombs at the battery, destroying it.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqis</ENAMEX> claim that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqis</ENAMEX> were killed and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was
almost certainly shot down. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> doesn't dispute the death toll but
dismisses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shootdown</ENAMEX> claim as groundless. Everybody quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s defense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>' response and his support for continuing
to control much of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s airspace. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explain that
the no-fly zones were not explicitly established by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>, but are rather a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> creation. The WP mentions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
made this complaint, but doesn't address the fact of the matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
adamance about the zones fits well with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's claim that many in the
know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> believe yet another military confrontation with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is
inevitable in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weeks ahead</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has the most tactical detail on the incident, saying that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> fired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> without providing radar guidance until the last
possible instant, to deny <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> counter-targeting, a technique, the paper
points out, that bagged an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. The papers note
that the incident came after much belligerent talk from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> and after
they directed ineffectual anti-aircraft fire toward a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>, giving rise to theories that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is trying to undermine the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
policy of containment among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> suggesting a more prosaic explanation: "I think what he's trying to do
is shoot down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX>."

            The LAT top front quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s assertion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security computer system is "now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> compliant" with standards and safeguards
protecting against Y2K problems. Even so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> say it
would be premature to declare that the problem has been beaten throughout the
federal computer world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> carry the story
inside.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> front page story reveals that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> most crowded
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> commercial airline routes (and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of the top <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX>) have one thing in
common: they go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> flight, for instance, averages
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87 percent</NUMEX> occupancy. Overall, says the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> flights are departing on
average <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71 percent</NUMEX> full.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes top-front with an update on a media story it has broken
ground on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">before</TIMEX>: the increasingly pronounced split between the races when it
comes to the popularity of TV shows. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, for instance, the paper
reports, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seinfeld</ENAMEX>" finished but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50th</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>, while the number one
comedy among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> was "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Between Brothers</ENAMEX>," which finished <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">112th</NUMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>.
The preference trend, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> explains, influences the way the shows
look. Since, for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> rarely watch shows with mostly black casts,
and since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX> focus on the more numerous and generally more affluent
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, network shows on in prime time with black or even integrated
casts have become relatively rare, reversing a trend towards cast integration
that was big in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 70s and 80s</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> sums up the situation by saying
there's now a "chitlin circuit" on TV.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that preliminary figures suggest that Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commerce</ENAMEX> really arrived this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas season</TIMEX>, finally exceeding the hype. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> has a stat about non-holiday Web
activity that drives home the point that some sort of benchmark has been
passed: the total worth of the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Schwab</ENAMEX> has just
surpassed that of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill Lynch</ENAMEX>. The significance of this is, explains the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwab</ENAMEX> does <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54 percent</NUMEX> of its trading online. So, the
biggest online brokerage house is now just the biggest brokerage house.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> business section story claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> has been
deeply stung by the accusations against him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> opens with an
anecdote that's evidently supposed to humanize him but which will probably have
the opposite effect. It seems that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> took several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dozen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on a vacation trip out West, and at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point they stopped at a
restaurant for dinner. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>, a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> eating nearby
joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and proceeded to mercilessly tease <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, amazing all of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>. But in fact, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>" were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, hired
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and coached by him in detail.

         
      
   
