
   
   
      
         
            Why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You Should Stop Worrying and Learn to Love the Market</ENAMEX>

            Is it possible that the
skyrocketing stock market is in fact underpriced? Is the recent market
turbulence just a tiny price that long-term stock-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> pay to enjoy
very large excess returns over bonds? Or, to put it another way, were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
whining during the recent downswing about the exact reason they get such
spectacular long-term returns?

            These
possibilities are raised by an article in the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Economic</ENAMEX>
Perspectives , and by a gloss that contemporary history suggests be put upon
it.

            The article, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"The Equity Premium Puzzle</ENAMEX>," asks a
question that should strike joy in the hearts of stock-market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. Why,
ask noted finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Siegel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wharton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Thaler</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>, has the long-term rate of return for stocks consistently
been so much higher than for fixed-yield assets? Over very long periods of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, the excess return of stocks over bonds yields staggering differences in
profit.

            For
example: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibbotson Associates</ENAMEX>, the finance-statistics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, has found only one
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX> period, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1928 to late 1948</TIMEX>, when the rate of return on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bonds exceeded the return on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">S&P 500</ENAMEX>, and that was by a small
fraction of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> percentage point. This period included many start points when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX> opined about the excessively high price of stocks. Another example that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thaler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> use is particularly attention-getting: If you had bought
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bills in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925</TIMEX> (because you were worried that the stock
market was considered too high and too speculative), and held them until the
end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, you would have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,720</NUMEX>. But if you had put the thou into a broad
portfolio of stocks, you would have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$842,000</NUMEX>. The difference comes from an
average rate of return for the bills of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.7 percent</NUMEX> and for the stocks of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10.1</NUMEX>
percent.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> call this difference in yields
between stocks and bonds the "equity premium" or the "equity-risk premium." It
is the premium in the form of a lower rate of return that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are willing
to pay to own bonds or notes rather than stocks, supposedly because stocks are
a great deal more dangerous. But what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thaler</ENAMEX> ask--and what many of
us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> have long asked--are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> key questions: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Why is the risk premium
as high as it is? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Why, for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, especially long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX>,
should there be any risk premium at all?

            As to the
first, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thaler</ENAMEX> use a series of complex equations and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> to find
(as have other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> whom they cite) that the risk premium over the past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two centuries</TIMEX> has been almost insanely high. In fact, even for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any 20-year</TIMEX>
period, the standard deviation of stock returns from the average return--i.e.,
the range within which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of all returns fall, used as a rough measure
of volatility--is far smaller than would justify the immense premium <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
give up to own bonds or bills with definite coupons and payment on maturity.
Or, to put it another way, looked at from the perspective of time, stocks are
simply nowhere near as risky as their rate of return compared with bonds would
seem to indicate, at least so far in finance history.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> find, moreover, that this is a worldwide
phenomenon. Even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> where stock exchanges disappeared or were curtailed
due to war or political catastrophe--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>--returns to
stocks exceeded returns to bonds over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long</TIMEX> periods.

            Only when stock returns are
considered on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-to-year</TIMEX> basis is there even a hint of enough risk in
stocks to generate a risk-aversion premium such as exists. And even there, the
fluctuations do not appear to compel as large a risk premium as exists, unless
the aversion to risk is irrational.

            But the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> question is even more beguiling. Why should there be any risk premium at
all for long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> if, on a consistent basis since the beginning of
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>, the returns to long-term stock-holding have been
and are dramatically greater than to debt-holding? Why shouldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> sell
bonds and buy stocks to the point that bond prices are so low and stock prices
so high that the returns on bonds over time approximate the return on
stocks?

            
How long, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thaler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> ask, will it take
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to get wise to the fact that the equity premium is just too
damned high? They assure the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that they, like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, have their retirement savings in stocks. They say they know
that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 20 years</TIMEX>, if not for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>, they will be safe
in predicting that stocks will outperform bonds no matter what the short-term
turbulence. (Indeed, they point out, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX> periods, bond returns
actually vary more widely than stock returns.)

            And here, current history
adds a major point. If all (or most) holdings were for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a year</TIMEX>, one could
see why stocks--which can fluctuate scarily in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>--might command a large
risk premium. But if the composition of the market has changed considerably, so
that it is now composed largely of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> investing with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year</TIMEX>--or
greater--horizon, might this not change the valuation of stocks, bid up their
prices, and lower the equity premium? Especially now, when any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> can
obtain almost perfect diversification with index funds and index options--and
thus get the exact return of the market as a whole.

            More immediately important,
it puts the market's recent, quickly overturned correction in quite a different
light. All that volatility, upsetting as it may be for the short-term <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>,
is simply the small price stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> pay for vastly superior long-term
returns. If we didn't have this kind of upsetting move occasionally, we would
not get the risk premium at all, because then everyone would only want to hold
stocks. Maybe we should stop worrying and learn to love this roller coaster,
which has its dips but really does eventually climb to the sky--or at least has
done so thus far.

         
      
   
