
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> Chance

            On a gray <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> afternoon
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, I found myself back at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nantang Church</ENAMEX>, an otherwise nondescript
building that rests on ground given to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuit</ENAMEX> missionary by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> four
centuries back. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtyard</ENAMEX> outside I bumped into several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parishioners</ENAMEX>,
all politely curious about where I was from and what I thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            Ordinary
stuff, in most places. Yet, for most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, "ordinary" is a huge step
forward. At the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> I attended in this very church <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a decade ago</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, who made up most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregation</ENAMEX>, kept their distance from
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> such as myself. This time was quite different, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> calling for restrictions on trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> would do well to
keep in mind that the greater freedom--or, at least, the lower levels of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apprehension</ENAMEX>--with which many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese Christians</ENAMEX> now practice their faith owes
itself in large measure to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s economic opening to the world.

            This is not to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> now respects freedom of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>. But when <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> declare that things are getting worse, it
prompts the great unasked question: Compared with what? With what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years ago</TIMEX>? With what we are likely to get even in the best of
circumstances <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? Or with some romantic abstraction about what we would like
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to be? (Also see "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX>? Part <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>'s
"Cross-Purposes:
The spurious campaign against the persecution of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>.")

            Viewed
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, much criticism now leveled by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> seems
less a snapshot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1990s</TIMEX> than a caricature drawn from the
high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days of Maoism a generation ago</TIMEX>. Perhaps that's because few of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have taken the trouble to spend much--or even any--time there, or to
consult with their fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> who are actively
exploiting opportunities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. One notable exception is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Shea</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puebla Institute</ENAMEX>, whose wider experience may explain why her recent article in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crisis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> at least acknowledges that many "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident intellectuals</ENAMEX> argue against" tying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> to human rights.

            
At the heart of the problem there exists a
simple impatience for the long-term give-and-take any real <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy
demands. The immoderate language employed, moreover, is often both intolerant
of those who would achieve human rights by other means and out of touch with
current realities. For example, an open letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eve</ENAMEX> of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--signed by former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">right activist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neuhaus</ENAMEX>--claimed that the "campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of faith has been
intensifying rather than diminishing." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bauer</ENAMEX>, another signatory, claimed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> that human
rights are being sold out "in order to sell a few more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Macs</ENAMEX>."

            For those
of us who have seen firsthand the dramatic improvement in the lives of ordinary
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> that opening the market has brought, this agitation against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
doing business in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is baffling. Indeed, for unregenerate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Communists</ENAMEX>
such as me, it is the height of irony to now find ourselves attacked as being
"pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>." Nor do I speak as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller Republican</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has helped
build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yangzhou</ENAMEX>, and I doubt that
anyone has devoted more editorial space to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s repellent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-child
policy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Undeniably</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> remains a nasty place for many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christians</ENAMEX>, who, in many parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, risk harassment and detention
simply for practicing their faith. And their co-religionists abroad should be
encouraged to continue to document and publicize these abuses, such as the
ransacking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bishop Joseph Fan Zhongliang</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> just before
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>. But, as one missionary who has been building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
decades put it to me, "Almost everything that is said about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
is true for some part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. But it no longer comes from the center
[<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>]."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to whom I mention this have little patience for such fine
distinctions. But in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> they can make a world of difference. Just last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Faison</ENAMEX> reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> how economic growth is
fast eroding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s control over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> lives, in this case
with respect to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-child program. The new mobility of labor means the
government simply cannot exert the control it could when everyone stayed put
and depended on the work unit for everything. At an even more basic level, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faison</ENAMEX> pointed out, more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are now able to escape
once-mandatory abortions by simply paying a fine. As anyone involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
will tell you, you can do a lot more than the rules suggest as long as you
don't rub the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>' noses in it. How many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> who signed the
letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> know, for example, that some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">government-appointed Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bishops</ENAMEX> have been reconciled with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>?

            
This kind of progress is messy, but it is real
and palpable. Surely it is no coincidence that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> most cut off from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> and business (and embargoed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) have been among the
most miserable for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> and human rights: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. It
is a slow process, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> looks more and more like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>. Ask <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese Christians</ENAMEX> what they want from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, and they will not talk about linking trade with human rights. It is
more likely they will talk about help in building <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and developing
stronger links with their co-religionists overseas.

            What
matters most for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> is not where religious freedom
ranks on some abstract scale of good and bad. What matters is how to make a bad
situation better, how to widen the cracks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX>. Instead of
walking away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Christians</ENAMEX> should be rushing in.

             

         
      
   
