
   
   
      
         
            The Taste for Taboo

            
               NOTE: This article
contains links to images that many will find distasteful.
            

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Freund</ENAMEX>

            
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,427</NUMEX> words; posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 18</TIMEX>)
            

            At the height of the pop
misery following <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s eminent historians
appeared on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> to discuss the meaning of it all. Asked if the intense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grief</ENAMEX> would have any lasting results, she suggested that it might affect the
public approach to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> and predicted that the paparazzi accident
photos then known to exist would "never see the light of day." She'd barely
finished her prediction when the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panel members</ENAMEX> broke in. Those pictures
had already been published, they noted glumly: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> tabloid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bild</ENAMEX> had printed them that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. (If you want to see the crash photo
that appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bild</ENAMEX> , click here and scroll down.)

            The printing of such a photo
was news in its own right. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> allegedly was hounded to her death by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photographers</ENAMEX>, displaying or even looking at pictures of this kind was
interpreted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> as venal: an assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s memory, if not an
endorsement of the crime. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bild</ENAMEX> are an old media model
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>; the Internet soon kicked in with even more pictures, overwhelming the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photomoralism</ENAMEX>. (For a sampling of distasteful Internet offerings, click .)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> pictorial taboo and
its underlying moralism turned out to be remarkably evanescent, and a secondary
morality tale has arisen to explain why: It's the Internet's fault. The new
technology, according to this view, is a tool of cheap voyeurism, capable of
smashing public decency with unprecedented speed and efficiency. But even if
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> assumes a degree of voyeurism in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> case, the charge misses the
point. Such imagery has long been a tool of popular grief in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
culture.

            The fact is that the
very intensity of the reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s death made the viewing of such photos
more likely, not less so. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photography</ENAMEX>'s relationship with grief is an intimate
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, that relationship seems to have played itself out in
familiar ways: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> sought out photos of her in death--including spurious
ones--because she was important to them.

            We have always found ways--excuses, if you like--to look at
documentary images of violence and death. Whatever our level of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acknowledgment</ENAMEX>--tabloid exploitation or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> refinement--we categorize such
images intellectually and emotionally, transforming appalling scenes into
objects of sentiment, pieces of evidence, and even works of art. Indeed, the
cathartic opportunities presented by such images, whether sentimental or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aesthetic</ENAMEX>, have a long history of overwhelming any questions of documentary
value.

            At the high end of culture,
death imagery commonly becomes art, especially in the case of war photography.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generations</ENAMEX> have pondered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Gardner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>'s justly
famous photos of the dead at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gettysburg</ENAMEX>. The battle ended, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> lie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hauntingly</ENAMEX> in fields of stillness, a "harvest of death," in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardner</ENAMEX>'s own
phrase. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Harvest</ENAMEX> .) Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of these photos noticed
some time ago that the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> seem to show up in different places on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battlefield</ENAMEX>, and they concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> had "arranged" the dead
in order to achieve pleasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tableaux</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most famous of all
photographs is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Capa</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1936 Moment of Death</ENAMEX> , taken during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Spanish Civil War</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to see Moment .) It presents a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> as he is shot, capturing what usually is interpreted as an instant of
noble sacrifice. In his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The First Casualty</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip Knightley</ENAMEX>
examines this picture and its history at length. Paying homage to the great war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photographer</ENAMEX>'s courage and talent, he nonetheless notes the conflicting stories
of the photo's origins, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capa</ENAMEX>'s own silence about the image in his writings, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>' questions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knightley</ENAMEX> carefully concludes only that the
photograph "turns out not to be the clear and simple statement of fact that it
otherwise appears." Yet, assume that this famous still was not portraying an
act of slaughter: Would it be a relief or a disappointment? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> see what
they want in pictures. Even in pictures of death.

            At the level of mass
information, we readily grant ourselves permission to look at such images.
Terrible scenes of massacres, bombings, and the like are displayed almost
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">rotten dot com</ENAMEX>
provides constant updates on such atrocities.) To the degree that we regard
them as goads to compassion and involvement (as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>),
showing them is a purported moral good. But it is easy to take this idea of
death imagery as important evidence and to expand it into an excuse that
legitimizes the sort of voyeurism we have just seen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> case.

            That is just what has
happened with a number of shocking images involving famous and beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>.
The view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kennedy</ENAMEX> lying in a pool of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> has been reproduced
regularly for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 30 years</TIMEX> with minimal objection or concern about his
family's feelings. It is regarded as a valid news image, but what does it
really tell us?

            Worse, autopsy photographs of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX> have been published in many books, including some that have
been best sellers. (If you really want to see the so-called "death stare,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">click</ENAMEX> .) The conceit, of course, is that careful scrutiny of these images may
reveal something important about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX>'s assassination. For that matter, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">dreadful Frame 313</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zapruder</ENAMEX> film with its cranial explosion may be one
of the most-reproduced images in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent decades</TIMEX>.

            There is by now a whole
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> of such images, many of them reproduced to illustrate conspiracy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">narratives</ENAMEX>. Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> pictures frequently link to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>
conspiracy sites. For some, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s pictures are also "evidence" of a deeper
plot. Even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX> autopsy picture has been published under the same
guise. (Those willing to confront a startlingly changed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn</ENAMEX> can click .)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> find the excuse they need to see a photo. Even the wrong excuse.

            It's easy to interpret this as popular depravity, but the
matter is not so simple. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Autopsy</ENAMEX> pictures, common enough on the Internet, are
not a popular genre; nor are the death photos of just any famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
Crime-scene photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Brown Simpson</ENAMEX>, notorious as her death was, caused
little stir. The death images that have received the greatest attention have
something important in common: All of them are of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been subject
to popular hagiography, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are the public's most beloved figures. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">biggest-selling American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> of all time was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX>
issue that published pictures of a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>. Now we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>.

            The emotional relationship
between grief and photography dates to the very birth of the camera in the
Victorian period. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last century</TIMEX> surrounded themselves with
photographs of dead family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> posed in their coffins, a practice so
widespread as to be an important source of income for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>. Such
photos--compiled in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lesy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wisconsin Death Trip and</ENAMEX>
elsewhere--now appear macabre. (If you want to see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, click .) But we are
looking at them with detachment, the emotionally "cool" state that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
developed after <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Victorians</ENAMEX> weren't
cool: They subscribed to a veritable cult of grief. "No home ever reaches its
highest blessedness and sweetness of love and its richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fullness</ENAMEX> of joy till
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sorrow</ENAMEX> enters its life in some way," wrote one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> quite typically in an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1882</TIMEX> family advice manual.

            Their attitude applied to
beloved public figures as well as to family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>--which is precisely why
death photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> were forbidden in the wake of his murder.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Stanton</ENAMEX>, apparently concerned that a trade in such
images would develop, refused to allow any to be taken. Given the intensity of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> hysteria, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX> surely was right.

            The proof is that, over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> "death portraits" surfaced after all. They are, of
course, all spurious. One can see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Days</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Meserve Kunhardt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip B. Kunhardt Jr.</ENAMEX> (You can see an enlargement
of the two images below by clicking .) These images have various origins, and
it is unclear whether they were posed, misrepresented, or innocently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">misidentified</ENAMEX>. But the result is the same in any event: At some point, they
were accepted as authentic by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who esteemed the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and they
were treasured as such.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> find the value they
seek in an image. Even the wrong image. That may be a pseudo-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> in the
notorious Internet picture, but there's nothing new about such spurious images
and nothing false about the emotions that have led so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to look at
them.

         
      
   
