
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich Redux</ENAMEX>

            Granted, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>'s
isn't the very <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name that comes to mind <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> when you think about
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX> in trouble over twisting the truth. But if there ever was a
moment that showed the importance of finding the fine line between spinning the
facts and dispensing with them, this is it. For an object lesson in the
difference, consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> redux.

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, 
                  Slate
                reported that in parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Locked</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> , his memoir of his term as labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> fabricated
quotations and distorted events. Moreover, the changes appear to have been
systematic rather than random, crafted to create <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>-style set pieces in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> was the embattled decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was savaged by ruthless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> vermin. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read
the original story.) The real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for whom nasty lines had been constructed
were not amused.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> replied that his book was faithful to his experience
as he remembered it, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> were unfairly attacking him yet again, that
the discrepancies were minor, and that he would correct them in a future
edition. Now the new edition is here, in the form of a paperback with revisions
and a new introduction.

            In this
new introduction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> again portrays his variances with reality as mere
memory slips. "Memory is fallible," he writes. "Where I have subsequently
learned of errors or misinterpretations I have made changes in this edition. In
no instance, however, are the changes of material importance to the story I
relate."

            
The book's disputed passages come in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
broad types. First, denied quotations. In his new introduction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> says,
"You are duly warned, had you not assumed it already, that most of the quotes
in this book should be considered paraphrases rather than verbatim accounts, as
is often true of memoirs." But many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> quotes have denied the
substance as well as the precise wording of the quotations ascribed them. Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Olav Sabo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>, denied that he had said the following of his fellow
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>: "We're owned by them. Business." Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> leader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Michel</ENAMEX> denied that he had told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were
"out to destroy. They'll try to destroy anything that gets in their way." And
so on.

            In the
new edition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> has not changed these disputed quotations. You just have to
decide whom you believe.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> sort of dispute involves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s interpretations
and characterizations of events and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lane Kirkland</ENAMEX>, the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>, comes in for rough treatment in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s book, and he
wrote a bitter letter complaining about it. He especially objected to an
account of a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> at his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, at which his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ilena</ENAMEX> (according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>) exclaims in horror, and the whole table falls silent, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>
"puncture[s] <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>'s high-society ambiance" by mistaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mint</ENAMEX> jelly for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>.

            The new
version makes some small but revealing changes in the party scene. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lane Kirkland</ENAMEX> said had been fabricated have been removed. Ilena
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirkland</ENAMEX> still exclaims "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>!" as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> makes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mint jelly</ENAMEX>. But she is now
a solicitous hostess rather than a tactless snob: She is "apparently concerned
that I will embarrass myself." That's nicer. The scene has been subjectified,
too. In the original, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> was
"appalled like the rest." Now, "I imagine he is appalled like the rest."
Before, various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> "stare at me silently." Now, "I feel as if everyone is
staring at me." No one can dispute that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> felt and imagined what he says he
felt and imagined. But the moral is the same: "I might as well have farted 'The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Star-Spangled Banner</ENAMEX>.'... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>'s right: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> sucks." Again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> need
to decide for themselves how likely it is that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> would bring a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> dinner party to a mortified standstill by mistaking jelly for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>.

            
The final, most striking category of
discrepancy involves public events where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> records exist and flatly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contradict Reich</ENAMEX>. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> such case--a presidential press conference at which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> supposedly bombard him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> with nasty questions,
none of which appears in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> transcript (the actual questions were
quite pedestrian)--he makes no changes. Much more interesting, however, are two
episodes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> has overhauled.

            In one of them, a
congressional hearing on the minimum wage becomes an "attack ad" as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>
Saxton, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, jumps up and down in his chair "like a schoolboy" and crudely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">berates Reich</ENAMEX> while a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>-and-circuses audience laughs and applauds. In fact,
most of the spoken lines attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saxton</ENAMEX> were made up, the real hearing
was dully decorous and, as far as I could tell from the videotapes, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> was politely catatonic. In the new version, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> sticks to the
transcript and accurately quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saxton</ENAMEX> droning on at length about studies and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saxton</ENAMEX>'s statement is partisan but monotonously real, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s complaint is not that he was attacked but that he had "no real chance
of getting a hearing at this hearing."

            He still
exaggerates the hostility displayed, and says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saxton</ENAMEX> "won't let me answer"
when in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief economist</ENAMEX> is later allowed to deliver a
lecture-length reply. (To compare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s new version with the original, click
.) But this time he gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> story basically right: The point of
most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> hearings--for all concerned, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>--is
not to listen and learn but to talk and score points. In real hearings,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adversaries</ENAMEX> brandish impressive-sounding studies and tell sob stories, rather
than making buffoonish personal attacks.

            In the original book, one of the most striking incidents
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, allegedly all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> and smoking cigars (straight from
central casting). In the original, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> is set up by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> and then
ambushed by a hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">questioner</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, and when he tries to answer with
an eloquent Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> speech ("My fist is clenched. 'Sure, you and your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> have done fine. But what about your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>?' "), he is drowned
out with boos and hisses. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> erupts in cries of "Bullshit!"
and "Go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>!"

            For anyone
who knows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, the idea that a roomful of slick corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>
would treat a sitting labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> this way is preposterous. And they
didn't, of course. In his revision, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> gets rid of the cigar shtick and
again substitutes actual words, while trying to preserve what he can of a sense
of hostility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s pedantic speech is quoted accurately but characterized as
a "tirade," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s answer is given as the mumbling equivocation that it
actually was ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, I will get back to you with all the information on it.
That was the information I have. You have different information"). Instead of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boos</ENAMEX> and shouts, we have only "I hear hisses from several locations." Well, we
cannot dispute that he thought he heard hisses--though the transcript reports,
and the transcriber remembers, only scattered applause and laughter.

            
Here again, the new scene has been spun rather
than fabricated. The level of hostility has been exaggerated, but through it
the real <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, rather than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>'s fantasy, is recognizable.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> to compare the new and old versions.)

            In both
revised scenes, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is still a nasty place, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> still shines as a
perennially beset paragon of decency. But the issues are of interpretation, not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">falsification</ENAMEX>. Locked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> itself makes some shrewd and
unflattering comments about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> games of spinning and posturing;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich portrays</ENAMEX> himself as an innocent who knows little of such things. But in
fact, both as labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and as memoirist, he plays the game as well as
the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>. The next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>--his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>--should read this new edition
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attentively</ENAMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, however, it may be too late to revise.

            If you missed our link to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rauch</ENAMEX>'s original story in 
                  Slate
               , click here. And
compare the "old" and "new" versions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incidents that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> retools: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">execs</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
