
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Potatoes</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> Foer

            After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">150 years</TIMEX> of
calculated disregard, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> potato famine has suddenly forced itself onto
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> political scene. Thanks to a bill signed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>, starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next fall</TIMEX>, high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> will be legally
required to study the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> potato famine. The legislation amends a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> act
that mandated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> take a course on human rights violations "with
particular attention to the study of the inhumanity of genocide, slavery and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>." Now the mandate also covers "the mass starvation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1845 and 1850</TIMEX>."

            Similar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> are pending in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, and a bill pending in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> would require
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX> to include the potato famine in all the model
curricula it concocts. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> of the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Patrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX>
parade in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> have made the famine the "theme" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year's march</TIMEX>,
claiming it's a much under-studied instance of genocide. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have
lobbied for the issue of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> postage stamp commemorating the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> anniversary of the calamity.

            The campaign bespeaks the transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
life. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> were on the way up, intent on mastering and merging into
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society, they viewed the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Hunger</ENAMEX> as a somewhat shameful
episode--a tragedy to be cordoned off in the past and overcome. Now that most
have made it, the ethnic remnant that once ruled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammany Hall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, and anointed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>, has retreated into
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">victimology</ENAMEX>.

            Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>
face virtually no discrimination, some have embraced a politics modeled after
the campaigns of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> demanding their fair
historical due--that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> recognize their old hardships.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tammany Tiger</ENAMEX> has died and come back as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient Order of Hibernians</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Irish Teachers Association</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish American Foundation</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Caucus</ENAMEX>--interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and old fraternal orders playing new
breed-identity politics.

            But the
potato-famine campaign, and the historical interpretation it aims to canonize,
has more to do with the present than the past.

            
Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> or slavery for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">African-Americans</ENAMEX>, the potato famine is the omnipresent, haunting presence in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> history. Consider the event's magnitude. At the start of the famine in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1845</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 9 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years later</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX> had dwindled to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">6.5 million</NUMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two million</NUMEX> had emigrated, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> had died.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">famine</ENAMEX> is also synonymous with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> oppression. Kept alive by folk
tradition, the idea now reverberates in political symbols and pop culture. In
speeches, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX>'s
political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>, continues to evoke the famine to condemn <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> occupation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>. IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> held by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> have famously used hunger
striking, in part to allude to the famine--the most monumental historical
example of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> tyranny. Or take folk rocker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinead O'Connor</ENAMEX>'s song
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Famine</ENAMEX>," released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>. Its lyrics argue that labeling the calamity
"famine" fails to draw enough attention to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> role in provoking
it.

            These arguments draw on an interpretation of the famine
that has flourished since the event itself. It goes like this: In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1845</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fungus Phytophora</ENAMEX> infestans arrived on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Isle of Wight</ENAMEX>, off the coast
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>, when an infected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato peel</ENAMEX> from an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> washed ashore.
Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">blight</ENAMEX> had spread across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scandinavia</ENAMEX>. But because of a deliberate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> policy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> bore the
brunt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> refused to curtail exports of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, which could have fed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, and heartless absentee <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX> evicted starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>. For their part, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> claimed that
laissez-faire policy precluded intervention in the market to halt the crisis,
and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> needed to pull themselves up by their own bootstraps. But,
the interpretation goes, it was really racism and anti-Catholicism that led the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> to sit on their hands.

            By
treating the potato famine as a human rights violation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> potato
amendment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> assumes a variation of this interpretation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural</ENAMEX>
disasters don't violate human rights. As in the case of slavery and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, alongside which the famine will be taught, there must be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">culprit</ENAMEX>.
And that would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> made this explicit at the bill's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX>
signing ceremony: "History teaches us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Great Hunger</ENAMEX> was not the result
of a massive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> crop failure, but rather a deliberate campaign by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> to deny the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the food they needed to survive."

            
Too bad for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who will be taught this
partisan line; most recent historical evidence doesn't support it. In the
1960s, a revisionist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> proved that limiting wheat
exports would have made only a puny dent in the calamity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX> action
wouldn't have mattered. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> intervention to assist the
starving assumes a more contemporary idea of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s responsibilities that
doesn't jibe with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-19 th -century</TIMEX> realities. If <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> got hit
hardest by the famine, it was because it depended more heavily on the potato
for sustenance than other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.

            Although scholarship
continues to ascribe some culpability to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>--for instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
did contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> dependence on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>--most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> emphasize
the famine was primarily a natural disaster, and conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> inaction
was hardly part of a deliberate plan.

            Even the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish</ENAMEX>--the ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>--have distanced themselves from the New York
legislation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Times</ENAMEX> , one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>,
questioned the hyperbolic rhetoric of the amendment's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> in the state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assembly</ENAMEX>. And an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, recently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for a
symposium on the famine, has refuted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>'s description of the famine and
distanced the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> law.

            Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> privately admit
they assented to the legislation because they were impressed with the ferocity
of the support for the bill. "It's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX>," concedes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assemblyman</ENAMEX> from upstate
who voted for the measure. "A necessary move to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> vote. We all have
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX>, and they care." Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> descent (from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syracuse</ENAMEX>), who vocally opposed the bill with the argument
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> shouldn't dictate high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curricula</ENAMEX>, has received
threatening phone calls that accused him of selling out his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> were deluged with calls, denouncing them as "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Irish</ENAMEX> bigots." And
that was after the bill passed overwhelmingly.

            It's a
sectarian sort of reaction: Either you are for us or against us. And it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">symptomatic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have fewer doubts about the more radical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>
nationalism than do most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have celebrated
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>, which raises the bulk of its funds in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. Yet,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has never garnered <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 15 percent</NUMEX> of the vote in an election in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 2 percent</NUMEX> of the vote in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irish</ENAMEX>
elections.

            
This tendency for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> to
take a harder line on nationalistic issues than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> still living back in
the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is not, of course, peculiar to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. It's the
"Diaspora
chic" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Liu</ENAMEX> described earlier in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>: the recent tendency of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> to think of themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in exile, a component of the
greater national obsession with finding one's roots. It is evident in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' increased visits to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish American Foundation</ENAMEX>
calls them "pilgrimages"); the burgeoning membership of fraternal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient Order of Hibernians</ENAMEX> (now at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>); and rising contributions
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Friends of Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, it raised a record
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX>).

            The lure of the diaspora may
be more atavistic for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> than other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About 30 years ago</TIMEX>, it
seemed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would cease to identify strongly as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s election to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the success of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grace Kelly</ENAMEX> proved that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WASP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>, which long impeded access
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, was crumbling. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irishness</ENAMEX> meant less to society, it
meant less to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>. Along with mass culture, the advent of television and
movies worked to eliminate the differences among ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. Also,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suburbanization</ENAMEX> shattered the old urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pubs</ENAMEX> and fraternal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">societies</ENAMEX>, that once provided the ballast for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.

            When an identity is
contrived or reconstructed in exile after a long fallow period of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonidentification</ENAMEX>--as in the potato-famine campaign--it's bound to be more
radical than the real thing, like the religious convert who becomes more
zealous than those born into a religion. The emotional connection to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motherland</ENAMEX> becomes more intense than the connection to reality. The result is
romanticization: Terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like the IRA become freedom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blight</ENAMEX> becomes genocide.

         
      
   
