
   
   
      
         
            Trading Places

            We all know why trade with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is vital: It exposes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilizations</ENAMEX> of the industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">West</ENAMEX>. It also instructs them about
how things can be different from what they are in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>--where all
power resides in the bloody hands of a narrow oligarchy and a broader <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bootlickers</ENAMEX>. The best way to change <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s abysmal human-rights record is to
"engage" China so that its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has a stake in the good opinion of the
rest of the world.

            And we
all know why no trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> is vital: It would give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> and his
lieutenants a powerful boost. Prosperity from trade would strengthen the regime
and delay democratization. The best way to nurture civil society and dissent in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> is by embargo. Only by making the economic failure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>
crystal clear can the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> "help" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>.

            This <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> hypocrisy is bipartisan: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is eager
to vote for sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> and reluctant to vote for sanctions on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is eager for "engagement" with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and happy to sign the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms-Burton</ENAMEX> act punishing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s inconsistency is no worse than the
inconsistencies under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>, and other prior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">administrations</ENAMEX>. The legacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>, the hatred of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>
emigrants, provocations like the shoot-down of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brothers to the Rescue</ENAMEX>" planes
over international waters (along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s belief that he is strengthened
by confrontation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) have brought us to this point, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are comfortable with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set of principles for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> and another for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>. The embargo has been tough luck for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> who cannot buy or sell in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, but it has made
little difference otherwise.

            But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>' different principles for trade with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> are about to cause it
trouble, thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>--the newly established referee
to police international trade disputes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was so proud to establish
(and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to vote for) at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1994</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is supposed to ensure
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> stick to the spirit and letter of the trade-liberalization
agreements they have signed, and to authorize sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that
break the trade rules they had agreed on. It keeps other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> from
breaking trade commitments that benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in exchange for
keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from breaking trade commitments that benefit those
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and it keeps all of us from indulging in the everyone-loses pattern
of trade sanction and retaliation. If we in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> (or even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>) the time, a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> is in our interest.

            
Yet now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>--noticing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> for
the very first time since the signing ceremony--is trying to make sure it gets
off to a bad start. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>-punishing <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms-Burton act</ENAMEX> denies <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
visas to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that use <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> or equipment seized by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX>, and threatens the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> themselves with financial judgments
by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>. Because of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms-Burton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is threatening to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fine Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> if its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> sells <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>-made pajamas, and is
denying <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> visas to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadians</ENAMEX>
point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms-Burton</ENAMEX> infringes upon their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>' sovereignty and
violates <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> commitments under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>. They are right. In retaliation, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>
promises to fine the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> if it does not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell Cuban</ENAMEX> pajamas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> ask that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> hear the case and authorize
sanctions against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. This is exactly the kind of messy dispute
that calls out for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referee</ENAMEX>--like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>.

            But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> counters that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> threaten the "national security"
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> has no jurisdiction over such
national-security matters. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> declares it will boycott
any hearing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> schedules.

            Now this is a strange position for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to take.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms-Burton</ENAMEX> clash is shaping up to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>'s first big case. A strong
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> will block a lot of measures that hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy in the long run, if
it is allowed to gain strength and authority. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> proves powerless in
its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big case, all will observe that its rules are only binding when the
strong wish them to be. The point of having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referee</ENAMEX> would be lost.
And a chance to remove trade disputes from the cycle of unilateral sanction and
subsequent retaliation would be lost as well. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> "wins" the
dispute over the jurisdiction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX>, then in the long run, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy loses</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade</ENAMEX> liberalization has been
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> (and by some counts, the only) achievement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration. The creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> was the capstone of trade
liberalization. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> had, in fact, been first proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin D.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry S. Truman</ENAMEX>. It was one of three sister <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> (the
sought to establish. They had wanted to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-World War II</ENAMEX>
international economy a free-trade, free-investment economy oriented toward
growth--in sharp contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">pre-World War II</ENAMEX> economy riddled with high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tariffs</ENAMEX> and import controls and oriented toward stagnation. But tariff-loving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> killed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1940s</TIMEX>.

            Thus, the
putting-in-place of the final piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>'s grand design
for a free world--a piece that they had tried and failed to put in place in
their day--would be an accomplishment to be proud of.

            
So why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s aggressive defense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Helms-Burton</ENAMEX>? Why the willingness to weaken his major substantive achievement?
It's not that he has changed his mind and is now pursuing a general policy of
"linkage" between trade and democratization that applies to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>. Consider
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> again: It exports <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX> of its GDP, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. Today
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s economy is more vulnerable to coordinated sanctions that would cut off
its exports to industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> than ever before, yet it seems less open to
democracy than ever before. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have drawn conclusions from the
collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>: that if they allow dissent or take steps toward
democracy, they will be dead or jailed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>; and that no amount of
economic benefit is worth the destruction of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. If increasing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">democratization</ENAMEX> is the test for access to the international-trading system,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has flunked. Yet, sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> are not in the cards.

            It is as
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> thinks that the end of every story is a signing ceremony on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> lawn: that the sole point is to sign documents and then
distribute the pens as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> favors. But useful, functioning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> are
not created by a single stroke of the pen.

            We remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marshall Plan</ENAMEX> today not because Secretary
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Marshall</ENAMEX> gave a great speech (he didn't) or because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> maneuvered the bill creating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> of the European
Recovery Administration through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. We remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marshall Plan</ENAMEX> because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> had follow-through: He knew that stories did not end with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>-lawn signing ceremony, and he fought for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> to breathe life
(and money) into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Marshall Plan</ENAMEX> so that it would make a difference.

            Will anyone remember the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>?

         
      
   
