
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve Flattened</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Murray</ENAMEX> is a
publicity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, and the publication of his and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Herrnstein</ENAMEX>'s book,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bell Curve: Intelligence and Class Structure in American Life</ENAMEX> , in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall of 1994</TIMEX> was his masterpiece.

            Virtually
all ambitious trade hardcover books are preceded by an edition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100 to 200</NUMEX>
flimsy "galley proofs." These are sent out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who might generate buzz
for the book: blurbists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bookers</ENAMEX> for television talk shows, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, and--most
important--book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. There is an ethos of letting the chips fall where they
may about the sending out of galleys: Now the book will begin to receive
uncontrolled reaction. (For example, back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> somehow got hold of
the galleys of my own last book, and wrote me heatedly denying that he was
working on a book about black genetic intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inferiority</ENAMEX>, as I had
asserted. I left the passage in, but softened it.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve</ENAMEX> was not circulated in galleys before
publication. The effect was, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, to increase the allure of the book (There
must be something really hot in there!), and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, to ensure that no one
inclined to be skeptical would be able to weigh in at the moment of
publication. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had galley proofs were handpicked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>. The ordinary routine of neutral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> having a month or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to
go over the book with care did not occur. Another handpicked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was flown to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> at the expense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise Institute</ENAMEX> and given a
weekend-long personal briefing on the book's contents by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> himself
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> had died very recently), just before publication. The result was
what you'd expect: The first wave of publicity was either credulous or angry,
but short on evidence, because nobody had had time to digest and evaluate the
book carefully.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve</ENAMEX> isn't a
typical work of trade nonfiction. It is gotten up as a work of original
scholarly research. Most works containing fresh regression analysis and
historical argument from primary sources would be published in academic
quarterlies that send manuscripts out for elaborate, lengthy evaluation before
deciding whether to publish them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> didn't do this, so it
wasn't until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full year</TIMEX> or more after <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> was published that
the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> on its subject had a chance to go through the underlying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX> with care. Therefore, as time went on, the knowledgeability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>
Curve discussion grew, but the attention paid to that discussion inevitably
shrank.

            The debate
on publication day was conducted in the mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with no
independent ability to assess the book. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>
took some pretty good shots at it in smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> like the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> . It wasn't until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1995</TIMEX>
that the most damaging criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> began to appear, in
tiny academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. What follows is a brief summary of that last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of
work. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve</ENAMEX> , it turns out, is full of mistakes ranging from
sloppy reasoning to mis-citations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to outright mathematical errors.
Unsurprisingly, all the mistakes are in the direction of supporting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' thesis.

            
First, a quick précis of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> .
IQ tests, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrnstein</ENAMEX>, measure an essential human
quality, general intelligence. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half of the 20</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, this quality has risen to supreme importance, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> has
become increasingly complex. The intelligent have therefore gone through an
"invisible migration," from points of origin all over the class system to a
concentration at the top of business, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and the professions. They are
likely to become ever more dominant and prosperous. The unintelligent are
falling further and further behind. Because intelligence is substantially
inherited, nothing is likely to reverse this process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> are
overrepresented among the unintelligent. Any efforts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> might make to
improve the economic opportunities of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, especially poor black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, are likely to fail, because their poverty is so much the result of
inherited low intelligence. About the best that can be done for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is
an effort to create a world of simple, decent, honorable toil for them.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> begin by telling us that the liberal position on
IQ--namely, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intelligence</ENAMEX> is a bankrupt concept"--has been discredited, and
that "a scholarly consensus has been reached" around their position. This
consensus is "beyond significant technical dispute." Thus, by the end of their
introduction, they have arranged matters so that if intelligence has any
meaning at all, the idiotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> stand discredited; and meanwhile,
extremely broad claims for intelligence have the cover of "consensus."

            The notion that IQ tests are completely useless never
prevailed in liberal academia to nearly the extent that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Murray</ENAMEX>
say. A more accurate rendering of the liberal position would be that rather
than a single "general intelligence," there are a handful of crucial--and
separate--mental abilities; that none of these abilities is important enough to
obviate the role of family background and education; and that native ability
(and economic success independent of native ability) can be enhanced by
improving education, training, and public health. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve</ENAMEX> refers
in passing to some of these points, but on the whole it sets up a cartoon-left
position as its (easy) target. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychometricians</ENAMEX> who dominate the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">footnotes of The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hunter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Jensen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Ree</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Schmidt</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are well known within the field as representing
its right wing, not a mainstream consensus.

            The next
problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> 's thesis is in the idea of the rise to
dominance of the cognitive elite. To the book's initial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leaguers</ENAMEX>, this idea seemed valid on its face. Everybody knows that the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>
used to be run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preppies</ENAMEX> whose main virtue was fortunate birth, and are now
open to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and all on the basis of merit.

            
But the larger premise--that intelligent people
used to be scattered throughout the class structure, and are now concentrated
at the top--is almost impossible to prove, simply because the mass
administration of mental tests is such a recent phenomenon. High scorers on
mental tests do "bunch up" (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> put it) in
elite-university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student bodies</ENAMEX>. But this is tautological: Any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> selected
on the basis of scores on mental tests will be composed disproportionately of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who score high on mental tests. Proving <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> 's thesis
would require proving that success increasingly correlates with IQ in areas of
life where mental tests are not the explicit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gatekeepers</ENAMEX>. To see how
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve</ENAMEX> tries and fails to get around these inherent problems,
see and .

            Having
conditioned its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> to view IQ as all-important, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX>
then manipulates statistics in a way that makes IQ look bigger, and everything
else smaller, in determining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' life-chances.

            The basic tool of statistical social science in general,
and of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> in particular, is regression analysis, a technique
used to assign weights to various factors (called "independent variables") in
determining a final outcome (called the "dependent variable"). The original
statistical work in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> consists of regression analyses on a
database called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Longitudinal Study of Youth</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> claim to
demonstrate that high IQ is more predictive of economic success than any other
factor, and that low IQ is more predictive of poverty and social breakdown.
Virtually all the early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> were unable to
assess the merits of the regression analysis. "I am not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>. I know
nothing about psychometrics," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Wieseltier</ENAMEX> (who was otherwise quite
critical) in a typical disclaimer.

            But by now the statistics
have been gone over by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>, who have come up with different results.
The key points of their critique of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> are as follows:

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Murray</ENAMEX>
used to measure IQ is actually a measure of education as well as intelligence.
All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tracked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Longitudinal Study of Youth</ENAMEX> took the
Armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Forces Qualifying Test</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> treat as a good
measure of intelligence. Because the material covered in the test includes
subjects like trigonometry, many academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> have
objected to its use as a measure only of IQ and not at all of academic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> concede in the footnotes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scores</ENAMEX> tend to
rise with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>' education--but they seriously underestimate the
magnitude of this rise, as shows. And they resist the obvious inference that
the test scores are measuring something other than intelligence.

            Most of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curve</ENAMEX> 's analysis is devoted to proving that IQ has more predictive power
than parental "socio-economic status." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s method of
figuring socioeconomic status seems designed to low-ball its influence, as
explains.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> begin
their discussion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Longitudinal Study of Youth</ENAMEX> data by announcing
that they aren't going to analyze the effect of education, because education is
too much a result of IQ. It's not an independent variable. (Of course,
according to their theory, socioeconomic status is also a result of IQ, but
somehow, that doesn't stop them.) Therefore, what you'd most want to know from
a policy standpoint--how much education can increase opportunity--isn't dealt
with in the book, except in two obscure footnotes. Both would seem to support
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberal</ENAMEX>, pro-education position that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> say is futile.
One footnote shows education increasing IQ year by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. The other shows a
higher correlation between college degree and family income than between IQ and
family income.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curve</ENAMEX> 's theoretical linchpins is the high heritability of IQ. Herrnstein
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, sounding like the souls of caution, write that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX> of
work, now amounting to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of empirical and theoretical studies, permits a
broad conclusion that the genetic component of IQ is unlikely to be smaller
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 per cent</NUMEX> or higher than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 per cent</NUMEX>. ... For purposes of this
discussion, we will adopt a middling estimate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 per cent</NUMEX> heritability."
This now looks seriously overstated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Daniels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie Devlin</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Roeder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Mellon University</ENAMEX> took the same studies on which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> based their estimate, and subjected them to a computer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">meta</ENAMEX>-analysis ("a powerful method of statistical analysis"-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>
Curve ). Their paper, which has not yet been published, says: "In brief,
studies of IQ, and our reanalyses of them, suggest a narrow-sense heritability
of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 per cent</NUMEX> and a broad-sense heritability of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46 per cent</NUMEX>. [The difference
between broad and narrow is too technical to explain in this limited space.]
This is a far cry from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s maximum value of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 per cent</NUMEX> or
their middling value of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 per cent</NUMEX>. Consequently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> give
the impression that IQ is highly 'heritable,' but it is not."

            If the purpose of the whole
exercise is to figure out what our social policies should be, then, "Which is
more predictive, IQ or socioeconomic status?" isn't the essential question
anyway. Making it the essential question avoids the issue of whether IQ is
really so massively predictive that it drowns out everything else. (Herrnstein
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> mostly leave the evidence for this, their central contention, to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">footnotes</ENAMEX>. The figures they offer are far from dispositive.)

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">chapter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> on policies that might be able to overcome the
fate of a low IQ focuses mainly on whether early-childhood programs like Head
Start (most of which aren't run with raising IQ as their primary goal) can
raise IQ significantly over the long term, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sorrowfully</ENAMEX> concludes that they
can't. What the book doesn't discuss is whether public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>--by far the
biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> social program--can raise IQ, or earnings after you control
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Political Economy</ENAMEX> , " Evidence of a genetic component to skills has no
bearing on the efficacy of any social policy. ... The relevant issue is the
cost effectiveness of the intervention." (As an example of where the kind of
analysis <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> didn't do can lead, a new study by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Girotto</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Peterson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who raise their grades and
take harder <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> can increase their IQ scores by an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> points
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three years</TIMEX> of high school.)

            
At the beginning of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> declare that "the concept of intelligence has taken on a
much higher place in the pantheon of human virtues than it deserves." And they
claim that their view of IQ tests is "squarely in the middle of the scientific
road." They end by expressing the hope that we can "be a society that makes
good on the fundamental promise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tradition: the opportunity for
everyone, not just the lucky ones, to live a satisfying life." Throughout,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> consistently present themselves as fair- (or even
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">liberal-</ENAMEX>) minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> who have, with great caution, followed the
evidence where it leads--which, unfortunately, is to a few unassailable if
unpleasant scientific truths that it is their reluctant duty to report.

            In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell</ENAMEX>
Curve is a relentless brief for the conservative position in psychometrics
and social policy. For all its talk of reflecting a consensus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> it
draws upon are heavily skewed to the right. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> used
quasi-nutty studies that support their position (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Lane</ENAMEX> demonstrated
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> ), and ignore mainstream studies that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contradict it (</ENAMEX>as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nisbett</ENAMEX> showed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ). The data
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell Curve</ENAMEX> are consistently massaged to produce conservative
conclusions; not once is a finding that contradicts the main thesis reported in
the text. ( shows how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> have made the convergence in
black-white IQ scores, which they claim to find "encouraging," look smaller
than it actually is.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Curve</ENAMEX> 's air of strict scientism doesn't
preclude the use of lightly sourced or unsourced assertions, such as the
statement that the median IQ of all black <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>, or that
"intermarriage among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the top few percentiles of intelligence may be
increasing far more rapidly than suspected" (no footnote). Though they piously
claim not to be doing so, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with the distinct
impression that IQ is the cause of economic success and failure, and that
genetic difference explains the black-white IQ gap.

            In the
most famous passage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">The Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plato</ENAMEX> describes an underground cave
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are held <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>, unable to see anything but the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shadows</ENAMEX> cast by figures passing outside; they mistake the shadows for reality.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX> is probably the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place in history where an idea like
that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrnstein</ENAMEX>'s cognitive elite appears. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato</ENAMEX> believed that
through education, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could leave the cave and be able to see the truth
instead of the shadows, thus fitting themselves to become the wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>. But he was quick to insert a cautionary note: Those who have left the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cave</ENAMEX> might be tempted to think they can see perfectly clearly, while actually
they would be "dazzled by excess of light." The image applies to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell</ENAMEX>
Curve : Presented as an exact representation of reality, in opposition to
the shadows of political correctness, it actually reflects the blinkered vision
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. It constantly tells these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they
are naturally superior, and offers lurid descriptions of aspects of national
life that they know about only by rumor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Readers</ENAMEX> who accept <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Bell</ENAMEX>
Curve as tough-minded and realistic, and who assume that all criticism of
it is ignorant and ideologically motivated, are not as far removed from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cave</ENAMEX> as they might think.

            : Dumb
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Students</ENAMEX>

            : Smart
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich People</ENAMEX>

            : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX>
and IQ

            :
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socioeconomic Status</ENAMEX>

            : Black-White
Convergence

         
      
   
