
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Against the Case Against Microsoft</ENAMEX>

            
               (Note: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> made
the case against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following</TIMEX> article, hotlinks
lead to more detailed discussion.)
            

            It is no crime for a company
to be successful. The are designed to complement, not displace, market forces.
The laws do not prevent market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> from enjoying the fruits of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> or protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX> from the consequences of their failure.

            What the
antitrust laws do condemn is anti-competitive conduct--truly exclusionary or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">predatory</ENAMEX> acts--by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that have ""--the power to raise prices or exclude
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> from the market. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have never established that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and its conduct satisfy either element of the law.

            In most discussions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, it is just assumed that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has monopoly power. However, no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> has ever reached that
conclusion. Even though <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 80 percent</NUMEX> of the personal computers in the
world use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s operating system, it is far from clear that an antitrust
court could be persuaded that personal computer operating systems constitute a
separate market. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> claim that browsers in the near
future will (or perhaps already do) .

            Even
assuming for the sake of argument that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> does have monopoly power, the
question still is whether truly anti-competitive behavior accounts for its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>. We don't need to speculate about the answer, because government
antitrust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enforcers</ENAMEX> have spent the better part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> putting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s competitive behavior under a microscope.

            
Almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Trade</ENAMEX>
Commission set out to determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> had monopolized personal
computer operating systems. After one of the most extensive antitrust
investigations in history (completed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX>
failed to issue a complaint), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> found only a single, rather
picayune <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX>--the so-called "per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">processor</ENAMEX>" license--worthy of challenge.
According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> itself, that practice did not account for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s competitive success. Rather than suffer the cost and hassle of
litigation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> agreed to a ending the practice.

            For
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, acceding to the consent decree was just the beginning. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>
couldn't blow his nose without starting a new investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> stopped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> from acquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intuit</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quicken</ENAMEX>
personal-finance software. It threatened to block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s introduction of
Windows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">95</TIMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> included the .

            Now comes the charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> has by including its
Internet browsing software, Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Windows 95</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
points to a that was negotiated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> for the specific purpose of
allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX>.

            It is
telling that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> chose not to attack the "bundling" of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> with
Windows as an actual antitrust violation--merely as a violation of the consent
decree. Whatever the technical merits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s interpretation of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">decree</ENAMEX>, you have to wonder what important public interest will be served if the
government's case succeeds. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> browser to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> who buy
new personal computers with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Windows 95</ENAMEX> installed. And more convenient, seamless
access to the Internet from the desktop will . It is hard to see any
anti-competitive danger that justifies denying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> these benefits.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s inclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows</ENAMEX> does
not prevent computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> from installing competing browsers or
putting those browsers on the desktop. Indeed, the computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that
wanted to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> off their desktops (the behavior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> wants to prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> from forbidding) probably intended to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape Navigator</ENAMEX> an
exclusive position on the desktop. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> did not demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netscape</ENAMEX> be
removed, only that IE be there as well. This may be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that the
government has gone against a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with a smaller share of sales in order to
protect the ability of its dominant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> to secure an exclusive.

            So after
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> spent investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, the
government seems to have found virtually no anti-competitive acts to account
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s success. Is this because all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>,
licensees, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> are too scared to tell the government what they know?
Unlikely. Has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> not tried hard enough? Hardly. All the incentives
for antitrust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enforcers</ENAMEX>--media adulation, professional recognition, and
congressional budgetary rewards--push the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> toward "bagging the
biggest game." We <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> are employing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> who
spend their every waking moment--and probably a few in dreamland--thinking of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. They are the best in the business, and their efforts
have turned up precious little.

            The ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> scrutiny itself may help to explain
the absence of verifiable episodes of anti-competitive behavior by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. A
swarm of government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enforcers</ENAMEX> peering over a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s shoulder is a strong
incentive for it to behave. More fundamentally, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s success is
not a mystery requiring any criminal explanation. The real and obvious source
is the good fortune of being the pre-eminent operating system on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> PCs. This
is not an antitrust violation.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s position is a reflection of an economic phenomenon often referred
to as "network externalities" (a k a "positive economic feedback" or
"increasing returns to scale"). In the market for personal computers, the value
of a machine is directly proportional to the number of applications that run on
it. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> will gravitate toward , regardless of whether
it is technically the best. Once such a standard becomes predominant, it will
be very difficult to displace--at least until the next "paradigm shift" comes
along.

            
Being the operating system on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> PCs, which
set the standard for personal computing, meant that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> became the
standard personal computer operating system. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> won that
round is no guarantee it will emerge the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of the next paradigm shift. In
the browser wars, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> faces a formidable array of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX>, to name just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>--and, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, it still lags behind Netscape
even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX> generally gets better reviews than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Navigator</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>,
however, want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to put some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s saddlebags.
However frightening <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> may seem or however unfair and imperfect the
market phenomenon of network externalities may appear, do we really want
antitrust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> determining Internet standards? It's difficult
to believe the answer is "yes."

         
      
   
