
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quote Doctor</ENAMEX>

            
               Locked in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>'s new memoir of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his years</TIMEX> as labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, is an engaging policy memoir: insightful, often witty
and, what's most unusual for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wonk kiss</ENAMEX> and tells, easy to read, partly because
it's told in long stretches of well-written dialogue that add up to scores of
novelistic scenes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> at work. The book reads like good fiction.
Unfortunately, some of it is.

            Call me old-fashioned, but
I've always believed that there is something special about quotation marks.
Whatever is between them, in nonfiction, is supposed to reflect accurately
words that some real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> actually said. Now, "accurately" leaves room for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quibbling</ENAMEX>, and a memoir will be understood by most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to be offered on an
"as remembered" basis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> says, in his prefatory note, that he jotted notes
to himself, "usually <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX>," and then consolidated them to make the
book. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, and will adjust their
expectations accordingly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> enough. Maybe he has a good memory.

            Certainly
from a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, however, one would expect, if not word-for-word
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accuracy</ENAMEX>, at least some checking of his memory, especially when public
documents are available. Suspicions mount as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> spins out page after page of
crisp conversation, especially when the same remark issues from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different
mouths--as happens on pages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">122 and 129</NUMEX>.

            Again and again, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> offers zippy dramatic dialogues
culminating in pithy and revealing quotes. For instance, he has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Michel</ENAMEX>,
R-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ill.</ENAMEX>, who was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> at the time, telling him this about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>: "They talk as if they're interested in ideas, in what's
good for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. But don't be fooled. They're out to destroy. They'll try to
destroy anything that gets in their way, using whatever tactics are available."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> may believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel</ENAMEX> said this, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel</ENAMEX> says he knows otherwise. "That's
not my quote, no," he says. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel</ENAMEX> says he probably complained about the
decline of comity and bipartisanship. But "I would never say that--that they're
out to destroy. I'd never say anything like it."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> says that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 18</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Olav Sabo</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Budget Committee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, told him this about congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>: "We're owned by them.
Business. That's where the campaign money comes from now." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabo</ENAMEX> says that
he could not have spoken with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 18</TIMEX> (they did talk on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2</TIMEX>) and
that, in any case, he neither said nor believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are owned by
business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich "</ENAMEX>certainly does not capture the substance of any conversation I
ever had with him," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabo</ENAMEX> wrote to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Tribune</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reich</ENAMEX>
also reports a conversation in which he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Obey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wis.</ENAMEX>, his
theory about blue-collar hostility toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The vignette ends with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obey</ENAMEX>
saying: "You're either a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> or you're nuts. If I were you, I wouldn't share
that theory with anyone else." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Obey</ENAMEX> says, through an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, that he's sure he
never said that, since he was talking up a similar theory himself--though he
says the rest of the conversation seems accurate. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lane Kirkland</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unsympathetically</ENAMEX> in several private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dialogues</ENAMEX>, protested in a recent letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>: "I did not, in fact, utter
the words that you attribute to me in various places, in direct quotation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marks</ENAMEX>, as though you were repeating my words verbatim."

            Asked
about these denials, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> said, "Our recollections differ." And it's certainly
true that, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, quote-denying is endemic. But some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s
dialogues are checkable, and turn out, when checked, to be inaccurate in ways
that serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s rhetorical ends.

            
At a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> press conference, just after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> have failed to settle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the baseball</TIMEX> strike, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>
has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> asking the following questions: "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>, why did you
invite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place?"
"If you can't even get these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> to agree, what hope do you have in
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bosnia?</ENAMEX>" "Does this mark the nadir of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s influence?" "First
it was the minimum wage and now it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>. Why do you and your labor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> should be involved in every employment issue in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>?"

            Those questions certainly
help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> paint a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">piranha</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> intent on humiliating the
administration. But none of the questions, nor any like them, was ever asked.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>' focus was on major-league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, not on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
and their tone was puzzled rather than angry.

            Here are
all the real questions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> asked: "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>, you've met now
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>. In your opinion, who is more to blame for this
impasse? And why won't they simply accept voluntarily binding arbitration?"
"Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>, what gave rise to the optimism you felt during the course of
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> that a settlement might be possible?" "How do you compare this, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, to, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> acting on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steel</ENAMEX> prices and former uses of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> for labor disputes?" There was a question about
legislation. And (most scathingly), "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>, if the season begins with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement players</ENAMEX>, would you throw out the first ball?"

            Life, unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s book, is not a series of morality
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fables</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 22, 1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> testified on the minimum wage before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint</ENAMEX>
Economic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>. That much his memoir gets right. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> attack
machine is gearing up," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> writes, "and I'm one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>." Then he
paints a scene in which committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Saxton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, interrupts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s initial testimony and lights into him savagely, starting with, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where</ENAMEX>
did you learn economics , Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>?" and then jumping up and down in
his chair and crying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evidence</ENAMEX>! Evidence! " while pointing to a chart.
"There was a time not long ago when congressional hearings were designed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">elicit</ENAMEX> information for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> in order to help them draft legislation,"
recalls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> ruefully. "Now they're attack ads."

            When I
checked the transcript, I was flabbergasted; so I checked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> tapes, and
they leave no doubt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> appears to have fabricated much of this episode for
dramatic effect. Saxton was, in fact, decorous and polite. He did not jump up
and down; he did not impugn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s education; he did not shout "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evidence</ENAMEX>!
Evidence!" The chart to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> refers was actually presented during
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saxton</ENAMEX>'s opening statement, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> testified, and did not look as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> claims it did. Worst of all, most of the lines that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> attributes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saxton</ENAMEX>--starting with "where did you learn economics , Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>?"--appear never to have been said at all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> has replaced a dull,
earnestly wonkish hearing with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> script in which a mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
hammers a decent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>. Don't take my word for it. I invite you to compare
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s account with reality by clicking .

            
Or, perhaps most striking of all, consider a
He describes himself as being ambushed by cigar-chomping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX> who hiss
at him so loudly that he has to yell to be heard. "They plan to carve me up
into small pieces," he writes. "There isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, in
dark suits. They've finished lunch. Some are smoking cigars. Others are quietly
smirking, ready for the kill." His speech over, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> is lambasted by a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>,"
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s answer elicits an eruption of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wrong!"</ENAMEX> "Bullshit!" and "Go back to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>!" As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> speaks, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> hisses so loudly "that I'm not sure
anyone can hear me." The cigar smoke, he says, "is making my eyes <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. I feel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dizzy</ENAMEX>." He says, "We're in a boxing arena, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>'s the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> is
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">loving every minute</TIMEX>." Finally, the meeting over, he races "out the back exit
before they can pummel me."

            As it
happens, the meeting was a breakfast, not a lunch. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAM</ENAMEX> says the attendance
list shows that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> or more of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> present were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (including the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> with whom I spoke). If anyone actually was inclined to light
up a cigar after breakfast, he would have been breaking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAM</ENAMEX>'s no-smoking
rule, according to an association <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> (who, like another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> I
talked to, saw no cigars). Most important, a transcript of the meeting shows a
respectful Q and A session, in which none of the comments attributed to
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John"</ENAMEX>--nor any like them--were actually made.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would hardly expect a roomful of corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reps</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hiss</ENAMEX>, boo, and shout "bullshit" at a sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>. Sure enough,
the transcript shows nothing nastier than sprinkled applause and laughter. I
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Boyd</ENAMEX>, the professional court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who transcribed the
session, whether his transcript might have omitted hisses, boos, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imprecations</ENAMEX>. "I never witnessed anything like that with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> or
anybody else at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAM</ENAMEX> meeting," he said. "I'm absolutely certain I would
remember it." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich portrays</ENAMEX> himself as the little guy standing up to a roomful
of abusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX>--pure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>. Again, don't take my word for it; click
.

            I asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> what was going on in each of these cases. In reply, he pointed to his
Note to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader</ENAMEX>: "I claim no higher truth than my own perceptions. This is
how I lived it." He said that his notes accurately reflected how he felt and
what he perceived. In the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> cases cited above, he felt varying degrees of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hostility</ENAMEX>. "I am not representing the book to be anything other than it is,
which is my account of my experiences, my perceptions, what I saw and heard
around me," he said. "That's all I can say."

            
In effect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX> is saying that he's not
writing journalism or history. He's writing ... well, what? He elides the very
distinction between history and myth, memoir and novel, reality and perception.
The problem is that those are real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he misquotes, real history he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rewrites</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
Wasserman, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> who now edits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> , points out an irony: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Books</ENAMEX> are often viewed as better sources
for history than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, which are generally much more
careful than the average publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> about such niceties as checking
quotes, are often the more reliable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reich</ENAMEX>'s memoir, if that's the
proper word for it, is now ensconced between hard covers and will be read for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come as part of the historical record. That is a shame. Quote me.

            Following
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of this article, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX> asked for a chance to respond.
Click here to see
what he has to say, and here to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rauch</ENAMEX>'s rejoinder.

             

         
      
   
