
   
   
      
         
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> in economics
was recently awarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myron Scholes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Merton</ENAMEX>. Their work has had
tremendous practical impact on the world of finance. Yet their own lives call
into question a key assumption of economic theory.

            The issue is simple. One day
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> hard-working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate professors</ENAMEX> of finance scribbled down a
few equations on a blackboard, and eureka! They had discovered a method for
pricing options. (The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fischer Black</ENAMEX>, died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.) What did they do
with this extremely valuable information? They gave it to the rest of us for
free. That is the problem.

            The
assumption that appears to be in jeopardy is profit maximization. In markets,
particularly financial markets, when profit opportunities arise, it is assumed
that savvy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> will take advantage of them in order to capture profits.
Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> describe it this way: No one leaves <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> bills lying on the
street. Indeed in finance theory--including the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> prize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>' own
formula--the profit motive is the engine that moves financial markets from one
equilibrium to another. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Equilibrium</ENAMEX> being the place where nothing really
happens.)

            Modern financial theory is highly dependent on such strange
theoretical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">greedy fortunetellers</ENAMEX> who can compute the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> derivative
of their utility function. For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creatures</ENAMEX> assumed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Asset Pricing Model</ENAMEX>, the keystone of most academic finance, are assumed to care
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about</NUMEX> risk and return. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trapped in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAPM</ENAMEX> are assumed to apply
the equations provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharpe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lintner</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Treynor</ENAMEX> (for which only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharpe</ENAMEX>
won a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>) to pounce on the slightest deviation from equilibrium in order to
get more . This greed is their most important trait. If they aren't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">greedy</ENAMEX>, the theory falls apart, as would most other economic theories.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scholes</ENAMEX> have undoubtedly assumed unbridled greed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>
of times in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX>, academic conferences, and cocktail parties. The
question at hand is whether our generous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> were greedy enough to be
consistent with their own assumptions.

            On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day in 1970</TIMEX>, they
surely knew that they had discovered something of great value. Why didn't they
take their solution and their measly academic salaries and start trading
options? With the formula programmed into only their calculators, they
could have ruled the emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Board of Options Exchange</ENAMEX>, taking the
money of the hapless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> who were still pricing based on history, rules of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thumb</ENAMEX>, or their guts (a potentially substantial source of wisdom here in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>). There is no way to know how much money they would have made, but it
surely would dwarf the million bucks they scored for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>. They had the
key equation that now drives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundreds of billions</NUMEX>, if not <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillions, of dollars</NUMEX>
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> trading volume in stock options, futures options, mortgages,
over-the-counter currency options, and most of the derivatives industry.

            To be
sure, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have made a lot of money working for Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. They surely have been adequately greedy in the rest of their
careers to satisfy their own assumptions. But their youthful charitable lapse
must still be explained.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possible explanation is that if they had
kept the formula to themselves, the budding options market would have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stunted</ENAMEX>. They would have quickly taken all the money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX> trading
against them, and no one would have been foolish enough to take them on.
Perhaps they actually have maximized their income by settling for a tiny piece
of the huge pie that their formula created? This explanation ignores the
underlying premise of the financial markets: There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> born every
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>. The market might not have grown as big if they had hoarded their
secret, but they would have been able to dominate it.

            Another explanation is that
they may have feared some other finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> would ruin their monopoly.
There usually is a pathetic close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> for any theoretical breakthrough in
academia. That's the nature of the idea market. Someone else eventually would
have stumbled onto the same formula. In which case they would have had to cut
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spoiler</ENAMEX> in for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. Or even worse, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">spoiler</ENAMEX> might have given the
formula away, leaving our laureates with neither fame nor fortune. Any claims
that they actually discovered it <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, but kept it to themselves, would have
been met with skepticism at the faculty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">club</ENAMEX>.

             

            This leads us to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> possibility: They couldn't trust
each other. Perhaps The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Treasure</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra Madre</ENAMEX> was showing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> and each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> realized that he would always have to
worry about the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>. As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any 10-year-old</TIMEX> knows (and game theorists
can now elaborately prove), <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-person secrets are particularly troublesome
in this regard, because nobody can ever pinpoint which of the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> might
have cheated. Thus, they may have opted for full, public disclosure because
they knew that that was the only way to ensure that they shared equally in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spoils</ENAMEX>. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, they didn't share equally, though. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scholes</ENAMEX> got his name on
the formula and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX> only got his name on the formula, and Merton
only got the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX>.)

            Here's a
thought: Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scholes</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merton</ENAMEX> were interested in serving the public
good, and the giveaway was strictly for the betterment of humanity! Before the
guffaws start, we should at least consider this alternative. The formula was
most directly a gift to the options <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> around the world, which is not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> that usually inspires charitable acts. So these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> weren't in the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">league</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Teresa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scholes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merton</ENAMEX> reportedly are applauded when
they appear on the floor of the options exchange, which shows that options
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> are at least appreciative, if not deserving, of the rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> that
they receive. However, the benefits of this formula do extend beyond the pits.
The efficient and accurate pricing of options has helped to make the economy
more efficient. So we all have benefited indirectly.

            
Another alternative is that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> were
pursuing the noble goal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> everywhere--tenure. Certainly tenure was
in the bag for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> after coming up with the formula, though it
probably was likely for them anyway. Or, if not tenure, their goal might have
been the eternal fame associated with having your name on an important piece of
human wisdom. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Economists</ENAMEX> are as guilty of this hubris as are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of any
discipline: There's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischer</ENAMEX> Effect, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharpe Ratio</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>-Modigliani
Theorem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tobin</ENAMEX>'s Q, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laffer Curve</ENAMEX> (the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in which the name helps
characterize the discovery), and the greatest of them all, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pareto Optimality</ENAMEX>.
Of these <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX> of academic immortality, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black-Scholes</ENAMEX> is probably the most
widely used by nonacademics, so they have made a good buy on the formula's fame
value.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> explanations
all rely on various forms of greed or other base human motivations that are
close enough to greed to be easily worked into economic theory. The last three
motives--public good, tenure, and fame--don't fit as well with the basic
assumptions of economics. It is possible to fit them in by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX>'s
magic trick of defining any behavior as maximizing something called "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX>,"
utility being defined as whatever you choose to maximize. But plain old greed
should be adequate to explain nearly everything in finance, because finance is
about making money. If the behavior of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are in the profession of
making money isn't well explained by the motivation of making money, then it
seems a real stretch to apply it elsewhere--for example, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX>.

            For straight cash greed, our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX> laureates fall woefully short of their own standard. Someday a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX> may
go to theoreticians in behavioral finance who will be able to build a model
that explains their own behavior as well as it does that of others.

         
      
   
