
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX> has
been devoted to Causes all her adult life. Apart from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, improving the
world (by her lights) is what she is about. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, Causes were
more than a royal-lifestyle accessory but less than a lifelong passion. Each
woman married into a huge opportunity to advance her Causes. And yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>,
the born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Causenik</ENAMEX>, has been far less successful--both for her Causes and for
herself.

            As the
official <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>'s funeral, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> must
have wondered why a small fraction of the outpouring of affection for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>'s
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous woman</ENAMEX> couldn't attach itself to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of dollars and pounds pour in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, prepares to co-chair a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conference on Child Care</ENAMEX>--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prospect</ENAMEX> that must make her feel at least a small fraction as weary as everyone
else.

            It is hard to remember while in the grip of posthumous
amnesia, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s press was often as lousy as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s. The media mocked
her outsized clothes budget, her downsized tank tops, her affairs, her various
dysfunctions, her penchant for New Age cures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX>
pulled its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Di Was Sex Mad</ENAMEX>" cover off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX> as soon as it could after the
fatal crash. Even the nontabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Sunday Times</ENAMEX> had the headline
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diana on the Couch"</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">above</NUMEX> a story questioning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>'s mental
stability--in the edition that hit <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> doorsteps (too late to stop) a few
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> after her death.

            Both women
suffered the indignity of a press obsession with their thighs. Photos from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX> vacation featured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> in a bathing suit
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">close</NUMEX>-ups of her legs. You would think that the thighs of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> would yield little in the way of news. But her gym sold photos of
her gams to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fleet Street</ENAMEX>. Her dimpled cellulite was blown up to ghastly
proportions and plastered on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX>.

            
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> was wiser about how to transcend her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tormenters</ENAMEX>. First, she knew not to trouble her pretty little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> about matters
of institutional power. It could only slow her down. When she successfully put
land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> on the world's agenda, she didn't do it by going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing St.</ENAMEX>, but to the places where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> had done their
ghastly damage. She posed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>, uttered some clichés, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> her glamour. But it worked.

            By
contrast, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> believed that this feminine approach was old-fashioned,
and went after executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. She got bogged down in
leading a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX>-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care Task Force</ENAMEX> and fighting with subcommittee
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairmen</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>. And it's not a question of physical beauty: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> also took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> approach and got results. When she wanted
something to be done about conditions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>, she went to (and posed at)
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>, not to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Mines</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> lesson for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is the one she delivered
to the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flex</ENAMEX> that upper lip. There was a great deal more sympathy
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s frailties, once she admitted to them, than the press--bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> of
how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will process embarrassing revelations--predicted. At a particularly
low point after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Squidgy</ENAMEX> tapes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> went on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX>
interview. Her private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> was so appalled over it that he quit, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX>'s assessment was summed up in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Has She Gone Mad?</ENAMEX>"
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> in trouble should pore over that tape for guidance in spin
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. With that unfiltered performance, her triumph over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windsor</ENAMEX> was ensured.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
once made a similar appearance, one that has become known as the "press
conference in pink." During the simultaneous controversies over the health care
task <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, her killing in cattle futures, and her alleged meddling in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, she invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Room</ENAMEX> to hear her
explain herself. But by giving absolutely no ground, she gained no sympathy:
Everyone thought she was smart, but no one was reminded she was human. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has admitted to causing "pain in my marriage," but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has never
given the slightest indication she feels any.

            
Of course, there's the fear that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--even
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whose public role derives entirely from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>--won't be taken
seriously if her portfolio is more princess than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>
was more fame than substance, she accomplished a lot with her <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 minutes</TIMEX> once
she had it. Land <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> made it onto the world's agenda because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> put them
there, using only the cameras and good will at her disposal. Meanwhile, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, there are still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with no health insurance.

         
      
   
