
   
   
      
         
            <I><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cogito Auto Sum</ENAMEX></I>

            By Karenna
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>

            Summary is the crux of
civilization. Long before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Age</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> struggled to digest the
mounds of words contained in his religious, cultural, and legal canons. Fame
and fortune awaited those who could reduce windy texts to bite-sized portions.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the all-time master summarizers was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, who, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cliff</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Notes</ENAMEX>, condensed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">592,439</NUMEX> words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old Testament</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">nuggets</ENAMEX>. "On
these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> commandments hang all the law and the prophets," he announced. "Thou
shalt love the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord thy</ENAMEX> God with all thy heart, and with all thy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, and with
all thy mind," and, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thou</ENAMEX> shalt love thy neighbour as thyself."

            Or at least, that is
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX> might have been summarizing, too.

            Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>' excellent example, wordiness not only
persists but multiplies as new volumes enter the marketplace of ideas. Besieged
with information and short on time, what is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to do? Luckily, whole
industries exist to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> nutshells and breviloquence: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nexis</ENAMEX>, Web
search engines, executive summaries, cheat sheets, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digest</ENAMEX> .

            To that list of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lifesavers</ENAMEX>, add an upstart, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX>," a new function in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Word 97</ENAMEX> word
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">processor</ENAMEX> (which is made by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that brings you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Caruso</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX> a "stunning"
technological achievement. It is not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s function to tout <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
products, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX> piqued our curiosity.

            
How does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX> work? According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
Fein of the Word <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX> cuts wordy copy to the bone by counting
words and ranking sentences. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX> identifies the most common
words in the document (barring "a" and "the" and the like) and assigns a
"score" to each word--the more frequently a word is used, the higher the score.
Then, it "averages" each sentence by adding the scores of its words and
dividing the sum by the number of words in the sentence--the higher the
average, the higher the rank of the sentence. "It's like the ratio of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> to
chaff," explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fein</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX> can summarize
texts to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> sentences, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX> sentences, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> words, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> words, or various
percentages of the original copy.

            Inspired by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caruso</ENAMEX>'s
example, we turned the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">powers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AutoSummarize</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> basic documents of
Western Civilization and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> contemporary texts:

            

            

         
      
   
