
   
   
      
         
            So Sorry

            "Accept
my confessions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O Lord</ENAMEX>. They are a sacrifice offered by my tongue, for Yours
was the hand that formed it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yours</ENAMEX> was the spirit that stirred it to confess
to Your Name. Heal all my bones; let them say, 'Lord, who is like you?' "

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Augustine</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Confessions</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Book 5, Chapter 1</ENAMEX>
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>,

            No doubt you're still
reeling from my searing confessional in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> , in
which I, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>, apologized for having lighted the mighty blaze now
consuming the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency. It told the riveting story of how I--"perhaps
the only self-proclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative journalist</ENAMEX> devoted to digging up stories
rather than writing editorials," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of a best-selling attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX>,
and "the star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> at the [ <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX>"-- came
to break the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troopergate</ENAMEX> story, and how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Troopergate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">begat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>, and how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> begat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            Actually,
this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time I've apologized for having broken the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troopergate</ENAMEX> story. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX>, in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>-and-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nipple</NUMEX>-baring
Esquire piece "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Confessions of a Right-Wing Hit Man</ENAMEX>." But I didn't
question the veracity of my reporting until my most recent confession, in which
I write on my "pangs of doubt: Is it possible [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troopers</ENAMEX>] took me for a
ride, embellishing their account for fame and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">fortune?</ENAMEX>"

            Now I realize my newest confession (on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX> now!)
isn't sufficient.

            I must
apologize for my apology. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> issued a statement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> saying
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "appreciates and accepts Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brock</ENAMEX>'s apology." Will this embolden
him to embark on sexual adventures? I must also apologize for all that nasty
stuff I wrote in my most recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> piece about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R.</ENAMEX> Emmett Tyrrell
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Isikoff</ENAMEX>, who, as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , pursued the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex scandals so aggressively. I portrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyrrell</ENAMEX> as a venal checkbook
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who was ready to pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troopers</ENAMEX> for their story. "How
much do they want?" I quoted him as saying. This was the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whom I had
described in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX> piece as "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> bright spot in an otherwise
bleak conservative landscape." That was while I was still on his payroll. Now
that I'm off it, I rat him out. Sorry. And then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isikoff</ENAMEX>. Over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four Seasons Hotel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX>, he tried to help me by passing along
some sex allegations that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> wouldn't print. He had every reason
to believe that our conversation was off the record. Now I've ratted him out,
too. And I didn't even pick up the check! Sorry about that.

            
To <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Bellow</ENAMEX>, once my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Free</ENAMEX>
Press but now gone: I am soooo sorry I didn't deliver the sort of nasty goods
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> that I served up in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Real Anita Hill</ENAMEX> , and that
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seduction</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham</ENAMEX> flopped. I hope that the poor sales of
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seduction</ENAMEX> played no role in your departure from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Free Press</ENAMEX>. And
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>, I'm sorry I wrote that at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law School</ENAMEX> you wore the
"loose-fitting, flowing pants favored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viet Cong</ENAMEX>" and hung out with
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com-symps.</ENAMEX> And I'm also sorry I wrote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX> fondled you in public. Whoops, I didn't write that. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wattenberg</ENAMEX> did. Please forgive him.

            I
apologize for having been, until recently, a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> . I was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative</ENAMEX> in human history to perform
investigative journalism, yet I did not share the wealth with other
conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
Standard . From <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Buckley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>, I beg forgiveness.

            Before I came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spectator</ENAMEX> , I was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> , the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> controlled by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rev. Sun Myung Moon</ENAMEX>, who has cruelly deceived <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into thinking he's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">messiah</ENAMEX>. I am vexed by this connection now that I know the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">messiah</ENAMEX> is ...
well, never mind. All will be revealed in time.

            Before I
came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, I was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Californian</ENAMEX> , the student
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newspaper at Berkeley</ENAMEX>, where I was reviled for endorsing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> invasion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grenada</ENAMEX>. But what about the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Cal</ENAMEX> who couldn't
say they'd been martyred at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> once renowned for its leftism? They were
denied my entree into the world of conservative journalism. And what of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
who didn't get into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> because I got his place? Did he have to settle for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Cruz</ENAMEX> or, God forbid, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cal State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>?

            
Iam gay. This is not fair to womankind. My
unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will never appear on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> show.

            After much painful
introspection, I realize that all of creation would have been better off if I
had never been born. The classic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Capra</ENAMEX> film, It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful</ENAMEX>
Life , tells us that the lives of ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> benefit those of countless
others in ways of which they are hardly aware. But what of the lives of
Nietzschean supermen like me? I am well aware of my deplorable lack of
humility, generally considered a crucial component of any sincere apologia. I
apologize for my sin of pride.

            I would
like to apologize to the sperm that were unfairly defeated in the race to
penetrate my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s ovum. Sorry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellas</ENAMEX>.

            
Regretfully,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brock</ENAMEX>

            P.S.: Oh,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita</ENAMEX>, sorry about that book. Let's have lunch.

         
      
   
