
   
   
      
         
            The CPI Trap

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Wednesday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boskin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s economics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX>, unveiled his report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer</ENAMEX>
Price Index overestimates inflation by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 1 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. Stalwart
budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">balancers</ENAMEX> from both parties quickly embraced revision of the CPI. Even a
relatively small reduction could push the budget <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several hundred billion</NUMEX>
dollars closer to balance by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2002</TIMEX> and put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> on a sounder
footing for the long term. But <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance Committee</ENAMEX>, who
requested the study and stacked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boskin Commission</ENAMEX>, may have serious
regrets.

            After all, if you are one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionaries</ENAMEX>, an overestimated CPI is the practical equivalent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s tax cuts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>' tax reforms, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lugar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
abolition--with no messy votes and no responsibility.

            Since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, tax brackets have moved up in tandem with the CPI. (In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more recent years</TIMEX>
the personal exemption and standard deduction have been inflated along with the
index.) The CPI's overcounting of inflation during those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years</TIMEX> means that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s purchasing power is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20 percent</NUMEX> less than it
actually is. The resulting revenue loss compounds itself with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> of CPI
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overestimation</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> alone, the cumulative effect has cut the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' take by
at least <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90 billion</NUMEX>.

            Inflation exaggeration should have special appeal to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of a flat-rate income tax. As long as the tax code is overindexed,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s incomes have to outpace actual inflation substantially for them to
reach the income levels at which higher tax rates cut in. Already, most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> never pay an income-tax rate higher than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> (the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> median
household income was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34,076</NUMEX>--a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> would have to make more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,100</NUMEX> to hit the next tax bracket). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few more years</TIMEX> of CPI overestimation,
and tax brackets and indexed deductions will be pushed so out of whack with
reality that only a tiny percentage of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will ever encounter the
progressive-tax system.

            CPI
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overestimation</ENAMEX> also serves another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> interest: cutting federal programs. As
things stand, if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want to combat the steady erosion of the tax base
and the pressure it puts on their favorite programs, they'll have to vote
eventually to raise taxes and face the electoral consequences. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, by
contrast, can count on their program being implemented without ever putting
anything on the record.

            
The explicit adoption of such a strategy,
subversive as it may seem of both the democratic process and deficit reduction,
may strike <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> as irresponsible. But sober reflection should quiet
their qualms. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, after all, do not want to balance the budget just
because it will make their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant constituency</ENAMEX> happy--they want to balance
the budget because it is an excuse to cut the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, which, if you
are a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, is the definition of "responsible."

            Adopting
an adjustment to the CPI as the centerpiece of a balanced budget would be a
boon to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. If the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few</TIMEX> elections have shown anything, it is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> don't like cuts; if the deficit evaporates, the demand for
cuts--and reforms--evaporates with it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is the perfect example. Adopting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boskin</ENAMEX>'s
plan to adjust the index will push <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s financing problems another
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> or more into the murky future, upon which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> never
focus. That would surely be a disaster for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> dreams of privatizing all
or much of the program--a dream they have not so much because they're keen on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>, but because it would convert all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX>,
whether they liked it or not. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exxon</ENAMEX> and the lowliest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> have the same financial interest, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have it made.
If the CPI is corrected, the pressure to make more than token reforms will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">evaporate</ENAMEX>, and the whole deal may be off.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Strangely,</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> continue to make nice about the prospect of adjusting the CPI,
many natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of such a move are silent. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform</ENAMEX>, led
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Norquist</ENAMEX>, has said nothing. Neither has the
adjustment.)

            
Even liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> who are opposing the
CPI adjustment understand how good the status quo is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. "In the short
term, readjustment hits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EITC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIC</ENAMEX>, food stamps, and school
lunches," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Baker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Policy Institute</ENAMEX>, "but in the long
term, taxes will be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> [<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX>] or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> higher."

            Whether all that amounts to
a tax hike or not depends on whether you count not getting previously
guaranteed tax cuts as a tax increase . But there is a threat of a
real tax increase. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boskin</ENAMEX>'s report admits that much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1</NUMEX>
percent overestimation number is a guess. If they have overestimated how far
the CPI is off, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boskin</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> may institutionalize an
underestimated CPI--guaranteeing a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX>, stealth tax increase. It is
that prospect that may bring <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> together to defend a CPI everyone
knows is inaccurate.

         
      
   
