
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamburger Hyper</ENAMEX>

            As food scares go, it wasn't
even especially sickening. Fewer than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fell ill, and not one died. Yet
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson Foods</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> outbreak in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> was all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
headlines. The danger is not that the public has been needlessly alarmed, but
rather that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have focused
attention on the wrong threats.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
wake-up call for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>," is how one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX> described the event.
The only thing is, such outbreaks are not rare events. In fact, they are
relatively common, and have been happening at least a few times a year for more
than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> (the further back <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevention</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> go, the spottier they get). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only last Friday</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 400,000</NUMEX> pounds
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> were recalled from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated</ENAMEX>
Press reported another outbreak at an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> high school.

            Nor was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> incident of unusual
proportions. There have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> bigger ones in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 15 years</TIMEX>.

            So why the
big national spaz over a small example of a relatively common occurrence? Well,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> said this was a big deal because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hudson</ENAMEX> was "reworking" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past days</TIMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> into current production and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>'s record-keeping was so sloppy that
the contamination couldn't be traced back to the real source--one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dozen</ENAMEX> slaughterhouses.

            
But neither of those claims is the whole truth.
Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> was adding "rework" to its new production, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> knew and
approved of the practice. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rework</ENAMEX> is even part of the prototype state-of-the-art
food-safety program that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>-approved <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> must put into effect by early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. And yes, problems with paperwork made it difficult to trace the
contaminated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. But that was not because the paperwork was
shoddy. Rather, it was because the reworked, old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> was being added into new
product throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> instead of to a single easily traceable lot at the
beginning of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> knew of that practice, too, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>
inspectors supervised its implementation at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.

            But even
if everything the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> argued was strictly true, it didn't need to recall
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25-million pounds</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75 days</TIMEX>' production). Industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX> agree it
takes a certain level of contamination to pose a threat. Even if a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">whole day</TIMEX>'s
production were contaminated and a small amount of leftover contaminated beef
reworked into ensuing production, within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> (which is very
slow-growing in a nonconducive environment such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chilled beef</ENAMEX>) would be so
diluted that it wouldn't pose a threat to anyone. Even leaving wide margins for
safety, at most the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> should have recalled <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 8 million and 10 million</NUMEX>
pounds of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>, however, is not innocent in all this. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX> that caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> outbreak were practically designed to
prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> from cooking. When prepared as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> recommended, the size and
the shape of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burgers</ENAMEX> was such that the outside would have had to be burned
if the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> was to be cooked.

            But
whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> might have done to contribute to the national
ruckus was topped by the media coverage. "Can <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Meat Kill You?</ENAMEX>" screamed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's ridiculous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1</TIMEX> cover. The text within was no less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hysterical</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Coli</ENAMEX> affects <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> each
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> reported. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CDC</ENAMEX>'s latest numbers place the totals at
one-tenth that, though it is true that they may be "somewhat underreported." In
fact, you are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> times more likely to die of a newly contracted
infection when you spend a night in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> than you are when you eat a
hamburger.

            
But just because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> flew off the handle
and the press blew the story doesn't mean there's no story here. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX>
outbreaks are increasing and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> are growing more and more diverse,
ranging from swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> to salads. But all the smoke-blowing around meat
processors is obscuring the real problem.

            A serious effort to curb <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coli</ENAMEX> would focus on the cattle rather than on the processing of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>.
Each of their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> stomachs is a breeding ground for the virulent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>, which is estimated to infect <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between 2 percent and 4 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
livestock.

            In fact,
ground <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> isn't the fastest-growing source of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX>. Runoff from cattle
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pastures</ENAMEX> goes into lakes, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swimmers</ENAMEX> get infected. Cattle <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">manure</ENAMEX> is used to
fertilize fields, and the produce infects those who eat it.

            Cattle, however, enjoy the powerful protection in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranchers</ENAMEX>, who gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> in the last
election cycle. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranchers</ENAMEX> are mighty resistant to any changes that could
cost them money. Still, some changes could be made quite easily. Industry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.A. LaBudde</ENAMEX> argues that testing and exclusion of infected <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> possibility--we already do it for a number of cattle-borne infections like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brucellosis</ENAMEX>. Cattle could also be kept off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">feed</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 or more hours</TIMEX> before
they are slaughtered. This would make their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX>-bearing digestive system
less likely to rupture, thus making contamination less likely. (The problem
with this idea is that it violates the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Humane Slaughter Law</ENAMEX>. Cattle need
their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last meal</TIMEX>, after all.)

            Technology
may soon provide some solutions. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Doyle</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> applied for a patent on some nonvirulent strains of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> that wipe
out the nasty version when fed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> argues, however, that what is needed
is more enforcement power, and to that end, it is advancing a bill designed to
expand its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>. The bill is irrelevant, though. No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has refused to
recall <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> said needed recalling. And considering that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>, a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100-million</NUMEX>-a-year <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, was dismembered in the wake of its cooperation
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>, any new powers would pale compared with what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> has
already.

            If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> is interested in
taking a hard look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> industry, maybe it should look for inspiration
to the battle between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> and the tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. It is common practice to add fat back into hamburger to reach the
high levels that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> demand--just like cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> add nicotine. It
is a good bet that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> from the extra fat they consumed
in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burgers</ENAMEX> than will ever die from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
