
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kiddie</ENAMEX>-Cash Caper

            Recent campaign-finance
revelations have focused on the vast and unregulated sums of soft money that
flowed through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-96</TIMEX> campaigns. While much of this fund raising was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sleazy</ENAMEX>, most of it was legal. But there is another category of sleazy giving
where the law is not murky: "kiddie cash"--contributions made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in the
name of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            The law
here is simple. When it comes to hard-money donations, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> can give
only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $2,000</NUMEX> to a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> during an election cycle. But
increasingly, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who have "maxed out" seem to be using their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s names to give more. Unless it can be shown convincingly that a child
actually directed the gift and controls the money in question, such
contributions violate the law. Not only is giving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2,000</NUMEX> illegal, but
giving money in another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s name is also a violation. Fines range up to
twice the size of the gift. If a campaign could be shown to have orchestrated
such a "kiddie-cash" drive, the penalties are even more severe--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to five</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> fine for each count of "conspiracy to lie to the
government." A confidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic National Committee</ENAMEX> fund-raising memo
warned of the peril: "Reporting a contribution from someone in the name of
someone else is a very serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>--often resulting in criminal
liability."

            The law notwithstanding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> have
stepped up their kiddie-cash collections. Contributions of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1,000</NUMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> listed as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX> records have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than</NUMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1993-94</TIMEX> cycle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass.</ENAMEX>, set the record
for such collections: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX>. In the run-up to the last presidential election,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s campaign took in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $200,000</NUMEX> in kiddie cash, outscoring his
opponent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 6-to-1</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, who raised similar amounts of hard money,
raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $35,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gupta</ENAMEX>
family of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Neb.</ENAMEX>, is among the more generous sources of student cash.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vinod Gupta</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Business Information</ENAMEX>. Campaign
gifts totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$143,000</NUMEX> tied him at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 135</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> list of
top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jess</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 17</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14</NUMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>),
gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $12,000</NUMEX>. All this went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> campaigns--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Nelson</ENAMEX>'s--in which the senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gupta</ENAMEX> had reached his
maximum.

            
Jess, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philips Exeter Academy</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">freely</ENAMEX> admits he had nothing to do with the donations. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dad</ENAMEX> makes those
donations in my name," he says. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vinod Gupta</ENAMEX> insists his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was misquoted.

            In fact,
all the money came from trust funds set up in the names of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
according to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. This is a common practice among the kiddie-cash set.
Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> has ruled in the past that donations from a source over which the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">donor</ENAMEX> does not have sole control are illegal.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guptas</ENAMEX> are not alone in their familial largess.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> records, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 25</NUMEX> and perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">donors</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>) were joined by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandchildren</ENAMEX>, from preteens to grad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, in giving to their favorite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. These earned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> sleepovers, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
coffees, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> memberships to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team</ENAMEX> 100.

            Smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">givers</ENAMEX> are in good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as well. Among the somewhat less generous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>
of kiddie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erskine Bowles</ENAMEX>, the winemaking
Gallos, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sugar-cane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fanjuls</ENAMEX>, Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX>,
and former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>.

            Typical of
a large-scale kiddie-cash <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bransons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> (No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> list). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank L. IV</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX>,
were listed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> filings, donations that added
to their trial<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-lawyer parents</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$175,304</NUMEX>. All the money went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to
whom their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had already donated.

            
The take may be even larger than the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">donor</ENAMEX> tally indicates. A cross-check of names and addresses of known student
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who left the "occupation" spot in other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> filings blank
(or listed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> names/other employment) revealed another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800,000</NUMEX> in gifts
from the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jess Gupta</ENAMEX> (male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>), for example,
is listed as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX>" in another filing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> who
collectively gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> used different designations when
contributing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $100,000</NUMEX> to him and others.

            In fact,
there is no way to tell how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and how much money may be involved, since
many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> filings are incomplete. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> fully identified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 65</NUMEX>
percent of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> attract small numbers of student
contributions. But some campaigns seem to specialize in their receipt. More
than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,746</NUMEX> such contributions made in the last cycle (up from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 401</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979-80</TIMEX>) was received by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 14</NUMEX> candidates. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a rundown
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $20,000</NUMEX> from
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.")

            Did
campaigns orchestrate such donations? Some evidence from public records is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suggestive</ENAMEX>. In every case where I was able to establish a parent-child
relationship, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX> gave to exactly the same campaigns as their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>,
almost always on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX>. Many are strategically timed. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety percent</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> donations, for example, were raised during the primary,
when his need for hard money was greatest and his donor base was smallest.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> donations failed, when first disclosed to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX>, to reveal that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>.) In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s last campaign, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>
percent of student donations came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just one month</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1995</TIMEX>)--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> that
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two days</TIMEX>.

            
Many of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are longtime
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> who know the rules. Some were sophisticated campaign
fund-raisers themselves. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Grossman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grossman</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>), contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX>. When headed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senatorial Campaign Committee</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-94</TIMEX>, it raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 50</NUMEX> grand in kiddie
cash. (That election was a high-water mark for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> donations in a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nonpresidential year</TIMEX>--twice the level of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989-90</TIMEX> campaigns.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westbrook</ENAMEX> also
had some familial help: His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, now college-age, has given <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $25,000</NUMEX>
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>.

            Another
big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> money <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">raiser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Glicken</ENAMEX>, also was helped by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glicken</ENAMEX> is credited with having brought in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $2 million</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaigns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glicken</ENAMEX> came up with extra donations for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Harkin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lew Wasserman</ENAMEX>
raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 million</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>; his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> chipped in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schechter</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 million</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>; his offspring ponied up more
than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,000</NUMEX>.

            While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> won the kiddie-cash sweepstakes for the
cycle, the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> in the primary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cash-hungry
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX>, who raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>,
who raked in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$106,000</NUMEX> in student cash, mostly from home-state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwarts</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s own high-school-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> chipped in, as did the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX>'s finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairmen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>,
raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.

            Even so,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have dominated this field. On the list of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of
kiddie cash, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> outraised <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $100,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
Torricelli, recently chosen to head up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> campaign efforts, was a
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX>, taking in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $30,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> listed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> records.

            
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> obvious explanation for this dominance is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> advantages in fund raising drive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to reach deeper into the
pockets of their regulars. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' big TV buys also increased their
appetite for hard money: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> rules require that part of each issue ad be paid
for with hard money. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> Deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> noted in
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1996</TIMEX> memo, failure to raise enough hard money would mean that part of
the soft money the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> had amassed couldn't be spent.

            Another
spur to kiddie-cash <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX> is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> has never shown much interest in
pursuing the issue (though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult daughters</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simmons</ENAMEX>, recently sued their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> for dipping into their trust funds to make
contributions in their names). Just recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>, in negotiating a
settlement with the campaign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>, dropped the matter of
apparently illegal donations made in the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huntsman</ENAMEX> chemical company
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, one of whom was a severely retarded minor. (The contributions were
returned after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> opened its investigation.) In other cases, the FEC
accepted letters from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-olds</TIMEX> as sufficient proof that they controlled
donation money, without ever interviewing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. Even the lamest story does
not seem to stir the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s suspicion. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FEC</ENAMEX> that
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> earned the money for her <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> contribution from raising
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> (cucumbers and onions, specifically).

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Addendum</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5/23</NUMEX>): <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> drew attention to one
kiddie-cash case in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has apparently taken action. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Lum</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX>, have agreed to plead guilty to
felony charges that they arranged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> in illegal political contributions in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trisha</ENAMEX>, has also been charged with a misdemeanor for
acting as an illegal conduit for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> in contributions.

         
      
   
