
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teen-age Midol Junkies</ENAMEX>

            A 7-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boy</ENAMEX> is charged with sexual harassment and suspended from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade for
kissing a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a week</TIMEX>, his picture is on the front page of
the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
               Times . A similar incident involving a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolboy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> becomes a national scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX>
cluck delightedly over the latest little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">feminists</ENAMEX>-who-have-gone-too-far. "We are deep into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCarthyite</ENAMEX> phase" of
the campaign against sexual harassment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leo</ENAMEX> opines in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Report</ENAMEX>.
            

            
Meanwhile, the story of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> suspended from junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> for
trafficking in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midol</ENAMEX>, the well-known over-the-counter pain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, has
been slower to build, and has crested at a lower level of media frenzy. The
suspension occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 20</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> before the notorious episode in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>--but didn't gain real national attention until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past day</TIMEX> or so. Why
the difference? The story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> plays into easy alarums about
"political correctness." The story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> plays against an
unacknowledged form of political correctness: anti-drug hysteria. The excesses
of sexual-harassment regulations are popular targets for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of common
sense because feminism remains a target for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> on the right--and the
concept of harassment remains controversial. The idiocies of drug policies are
widely tolerated, or often celebrated.

            Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> would probably not consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Midol</ENAMEX> a gateway
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>. The experiences of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Taylor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly Smartt</ENAMEX> ought
to subject hysteria about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to a little reality testing. Their descent into
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> abuse began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly</ENAMEX>, suffering from menstrual cramps and a
slight fever, took a packet of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midol</ENAMEX> from the school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> without
permission. She shared the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Erica</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> made the
mistake of exchanging notes during this transaction that were later discovered
by school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. Both were charged with possession under a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>-tolerance
drug policy that does not distinguish between legal and illegal, prescription
and nonprescription <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. Erica was given a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-day</TIMEX> suspension, of which she
served <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine days</TIMEX> before agreeing to attend a drug-screening and education
program. School <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> dropped a recommendation for her expulsion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supplier</ENAMEX>, was expelled from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 days</TIMEX>. She got no opportunity to
mitigate her sentence.

            School
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were unrepentant, defending their policy as a part of an effort to
maintain "safe, drug-free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>"--until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly</ENAMEX> sued. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly</ENAMEX> is not
challenging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s anti-drug regulations. She is charging racial
discrimination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly</ENAMEX> is black, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erica</ENAMEX> is white. Because her case is now
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about</NUMEX> race and not <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly</ENAMEX> is back in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.

            
It seems unlikely, however, that this case will
incite the same challenges to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>-tolerance drug policies that were directed
toward sexual-harassment regulations after the cases of the kissing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7-year-olds</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly Smartt</ENAMEX> will probably not be defended as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthyism</ENAMEX>. Indeed, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton Daily News</ENAMEX> that she
"could understand" a suspension for dealing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Midol</ENAMEX>; it was the expulsion that
seemed too harsh.

            Yet,
anti-drug crusaders routinely lie to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, just as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> lie about their own past experiences. The campaign against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marijuana</ENAMEX> is particularly disingenuous. Drug-awareness programs teach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that
it is addictive and will lead them down the path to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>
dependencies, while many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who inhaled regularly throughout their college
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> remain uncomfortably silent. Meanwhile, the testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Molinari</ENAMEX> who confess their youthful "experimentation" with marijuana
contradicts rhetoric about its addictive qualities. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molinari</ENAMEX>, and millions
like her, pot was just a gateway to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republicanism</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Some 70 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>,
and probably a majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 16 and 45</TIMEX>, have smoked marijuana at
least once, according to drug-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Nadelmann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lindesmith Center</ENAMEX>.

            Penal laws regulating the possession and distribution of
marijuana are as difficult to justify as school policies expelling <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> for distributing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midol</ENAMEX>. For a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>, such as growing marijuana
at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, you may be sentenced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> under federal law.
Federal drug laws, in general, are excessively harsh, as the press occasionally
observes. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
               Times ran a story about a
hapless <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24-year-old</TIMEX> serving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> in federal prison for agreeing to help an
undercover <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> find someone selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSD</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grateful Dead</ENAMEX> concert.

            In fact,
the gross inequities and disastrous inefficiencies of imposing long, mandatory
minimum sentences on nonviolent, low-level drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> are acknowledged by
virtually everyone familiar with the criminal justice system who isn't running
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety percent</NUMEX> of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>,
consider mandatory minimums for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> offenses "a bad idea.") At the very least,
anti-drug laws misuse prison <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 60 percent</NUMEX> of all federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>
are serving time for drug-related offenses, some involving simple possession of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marijuana</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>.

            
Considering federal and state laws against drug
use, the actions of a few overzealous school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> intent on keeping their
hallways free of caffeine and acetaminophen, the ingredients of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midol</ENAMEX>, provide
comic relief. Although it is serious business to them, the case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly Smartt</ENAMEX> is the light side of the war on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, which has
been one of the biggest public-policy disasters of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 25 years</TIMEX>. Instead
of decreasing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use, it has increased the violence connected with illicit
drug trafficking, greatly exacerbating the problem of gun violence. The black
market in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> creates a need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and probably the cash with which to
purchase them. While we snicker at rules banning <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Midol</ENAMEX> from junior high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, we ignore the damage wrought by laws prohibiting selectively demonized
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>--notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marijuana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> (while allowing use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prozac</ENAMEX>).

            This is not an argument for
the legalization or decriminalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>; it is a plea for dispassionate
consideration of the respective costs and benefits. We don't have rational drug
policies in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> or public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> because we don't have rational
discussions about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. It is popularly considered a moral failing, not a
practical or medical problem for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The war against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is not a
war against crime; it's a crusade against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice</ENAMEX>. Former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Surgeon General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joycelyn</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elders</ENAMEX> discovered as much when she suggested that we might study the effects of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">legalization</ENAMEX>, which was a bit like her other absurdly controversial suggestion
that masturbation was normal. Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elders</ENAMEX> might have gleaned from the reaction
to her remarks that no one in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has ever masturbated or used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> will have a tough time living up to its standards.

         
      
   
