
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LBJ Sounds Off</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> had a problem: His pants didn't quite fit. That was by no means his only
problem. It was, after all, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1964</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Baines Johnson</ENAMEX> had been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX>. Already, he had signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Civil Rights Act</ENAMEX>,
accelerated the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and watched entire neighborhoods in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX> go
up in smoke. Now, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> telephoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Haggar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of a
clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>. "If you don't want me running around
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> naked," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haggar</ENAMEX>, "you better get me some
clothes."

            Then
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> described in detail how he wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haggar</ENAMEX> to make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> new pairs of
pants. "Now, another thing, the crotch, down where your nuts hang, it's always
a little too tight," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>. "So when you make them up, give me <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX>
where I can let it out there, because they cut me. They're just like riding a
wire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fence</ENAMEX>." The image of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> naked--or, as he
pronounced it, "nekkid"--is not one I am anxious to ponder. (Do your own
pondering; click for an audio excerpt.) Yet it floats up from the sea of
recently released recordings of conversations that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> taped secretly in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1964</TIMEX>. Most of us who were alive back then remember what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">public LBJ</ENAMEX> sounded like--ponderous, faux-sincere, amazingly awkward for a man
reputed to be one of the most persuasive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> of the age. The private
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LBJ</ENAMEX> revealed on the tapes may be no more lovable, but he is, at least, more
understandable.

            As I pursue my research on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in my
cagelike cubbyhole in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, I listen to his voice
and remember how it sounded when I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> growing up in a forlorn little
timber <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> seemed all-powerful, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jehovahlike</ENAMEX> in the
execution of his swift and terrible authority. Everything about him--his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>,
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincolns</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear hugs</ENAMEX>, but most of all, his voice--seemed
ridiculously out of proportion. Even at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>, I understood that when the rest of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s voice, it thought immediately and bitterly of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with the graceful voice, was
murdered. God, I used to think every time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> grabbed another microphone,
why does he have to sound like such a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hick</ENAMEX>?

            His was the unapologetic
voice of those who used to be called "yellow-dog <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>," country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
bragged that they would rather vote for old yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
is mostly urban now and the yellow-dog <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are all gone, doomed to
extinction--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> knew they would be--by the passage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Rights</ENAMEX>
Act in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, and it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX>, and for the most part, all its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk as if they grew up in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and are auditioning for the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> commercial. We aren't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hicks</ENAMEX> anymore.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
was the last of the really big hicks. Yet, as you eavesdrop on him in
recordings he left for posterity, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy peeking</ENAMEX> behind the screen at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wizard</ENAMEX>, you find not a giant but a fearful and uncertain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a very big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX>.

            
In a conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Moyers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 7</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> sounds like a tyrant <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one moment</TIMEX>, a confused child the next. "Don't
just lope off," says an exasperated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, speaking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyers</ENAMEX> as if he were a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>. "I want to know where I can reach you on a minute's notice." Then his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">voice</ENAMEX> drops an octave or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, and he becomes more subdued. He warns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyers</ENAMEX> not
to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty</ENAMEX> go too far, and to keep it out of the hands of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Eventually <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> would go on to surpass <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early New Deal</TIMEX>,
but at this moment, he didn't know how to proceed.

            What he
wanted, he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyers</ENAMEX>, was a poverty program that would hire high-school
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who were about to drop out, and put them to work picking rocks off
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> or sweeping the floors of government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. "Now I never heard of
any liberal outfits where you could subsidize anybody," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moyers</ENAMEX>.
"I'm against all that. If you want to do it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>, then that's
your private thing and it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>'; but my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> program, I'm against
subsidizing any private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>." Beneath the bellow (click ), you can
tell how baffled he is by the enormity of what he had earlier promised the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>--"an end to poverty and racial injustice in our time"--and picture the
deep furrows of anxiety on his brow.

            Or listen to him talk with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kennedy</ENAMEX>, whose family
still holds the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in thrall. The conversation took place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4, 1964</TIMEX>. It
was a courtesy call, but tensions between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> were at an
all-time high. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> was still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> but was pressing to be named
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s running mate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, however, wanted nothing more than
to dump <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby</ENAMEX>. He placed the call from his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranch</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson City</ENAMEX>.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> says, straining to be polite. "How's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Texas?</ENAMEX>" asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>,
his accent as thick as his barely concealed resentment toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Briefly,</ENAMEX>
he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> that he believes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>,
had agreed to follow the law and desegregate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>; but he doesn't really
seem too interested in the problem. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The following year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> would become
more committed to civil rights, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>, he was still equivocal, partly
because he was worried about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> had infiltrated the civil
rights movement. On this particular day, he just sounds tired, all worn out.
"Do you want to talk to one of your girlfriends?" he asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, trying to
get rid of him.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A few seconds</TIMEX> later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Kennedy</ENAMEX> comes on
the line. As absurd as it may seem, she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> sound like a couple of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suitors</ENAMEX> (click to listen in on the courtship). "Did you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX>?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> asks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>, who coos that her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> was just fine. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> then tells
her he has been on his new ski <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and has become a little sunburned.
"You'll look marvelous with a sunburn," she tells him, sounding all airy and
breathless. It is a mesmerizing moment, one that shattered my childhood
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">illusions</ENAMEX>. Clearly the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys loathed Johnson</ENAMEX>, but they were as hypocritical
as he was.

            
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty-five days</TIMEX> after that conversation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> to the Oval
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> and told him face to face that he didn't want him as a running mate. In
late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> announced for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate</ENAMEX> race in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, but not
before he had had a conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> in which he admitted his own
insecurities about making the race. "I think it's damn tough," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> told
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>, sounding whiny. "I'd like to run. If I lose, then it's a reflection on
the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> to run and promised to do
whatever he could to help him. "I'm prepared to say what is desirable," he
tells him. "I have said that I highly regard you and that you have a bright
future, and that the things about our relationship were without foundation. You
know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> better than I do. It might be desirable for me to say nothing."
This was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> at his most evocative, trying to ease <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> out of his way
while sucking up to him. It is the side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> that we are most familiar
with, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> as the brilliant conniver, trying so diligently and without
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> to free himself from the spell of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>.

            He
couldn't free himself, of course, not from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>, not from anyone. Here
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who whispered terrible, dark things about himself under his
breath.

            
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25</TIMEX>, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> convention had
opened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56 years old</TIMEX>, threatened in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
recorded conversations to withdraw from the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> actually
drafted a withdrawal statement and read it to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reedy</ENAMEX>. (To hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> read a statement he never gave, click .)

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was overcome with doubts, which he expressed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later that day</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX>, a quiet, gentle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who served in effect as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>. "I
don't think a white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Southerner</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to unite this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this hour</TIMEX>,"
he told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX>. "I don't know who is, and I don't even want that
responsibility. ... I've had doubts about whether a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> born where I was born,
raised like I was raised, could ever satisfy the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern Jews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX>, and
union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>." He worried that he might be going crazy, and fretted over
running against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Goldwater</ENAMEX>. "I really, I do not believe, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>, that I
can physically and mentally ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX>'s had a couple of nervous breakdowns,
and I don't want to be in this place ... and I don't, I do not believe I can
physically and mentally carry the responsibilities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, and the world,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigras</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, and so on and so forth." (To hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> whine,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">click</ENAMEX> . To hear him whine some more, click .)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> does not really mean what he is saying, of course.
If he had withdrawn from the race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Kennedy</ENAMEX> would have run, something
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s pride could not have tolerated. What he wants from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> is pity.
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Five minutes</TIMEX> later, in another conversation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> can be heard giving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> instructions on how he wants <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hubert Humphrey</ENAMEX> to work the floor of the
convention. Yet, in this conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX>, it is possible to perceive
the depth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s despair.

            "I don't see any reason I
ought to seek the right to endure the anguish of being here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tearfully</ENAMEX>. "They think I want great power. What I want is great solace and a
little love, that's all I want." He presses down hard on the word "love," too
hard, and it comes out in an apoplexy of twang. "Luv," he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX>, "a
little luv."

            "You have a lot of that, Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> tells him softly.

         
      
   
