
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Choice</ENAMEX>

            Who in their right mind
would bite off a chunk of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s ear? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent van Gogh</ENAMEX> is famous for
slicing off his own. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van Gogh</ENAMEX> was not in his "right mind." He suffered from
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">manic-depressive illness</ENAMEX>. It's likely, from past revelations, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX>
may be similarly afflicted. This creates an interesting moral dilemma for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>, boxing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, and the public.

            A
connection between mania and artistic achievement has been known since ancient
times. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psychologist Kay Redfield Jamison</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Touched With Fire:</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manic-Depressive Illness and the Artistic Temperament</ENAMEX> , maintains that mania
is an essential driving force for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>. "The fiery aspects of thought
and feeling that initially compel the artistic voyage--fierce energy, high
mood, and quick intelligence; a sense of the visionary and the grand; a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">restless</ENAMEX> and feverish temperament--commonly carry with them the capacity for
vastly darker moods, grimmer energies, and, occasionally, bouts of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'madness</NUMEX>.' "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Woolf</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Rothko</ENAMEX> all suffered from manic
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>. The disease fueled their artistic achievements even as it led to
their suicides.

            There may well be a similar relationship, for similar
reasons, between <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">manic depression</ENAMEX> and sporting achievement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Golfer Bert Yancey</ENAMEX>
was the only well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> to publicly acknowledge this affliction. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Mets</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Harnisch</ENAMEX> made headlines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> when he became
disabled because of unspecified depression. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Wyatt</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> who has worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>, says there are many other cases.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> told an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that he had had a psychiatric illness all his life, that
he'd discussed manic depression with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX>, and that this illness
caused him to do things he would normally never do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Givens</ENAMEX>, said point-blank in the same joint interview, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> is a
manic-depressive."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>'s
well-publicized actions over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> are consistent with a manic-depressive
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> confessed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Remnick</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , "There's no
doubt about it; I'm a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>." According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remnick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>'s former trainer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Atlas</ENAMEX> says, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>'s] like a double feature now, like you're getting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> at the same time."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Manic depression</ENAMEX> is not rooted in a Freudian
childhood trauma. It's a genetically determined, chronic, and incurable disease
that affects <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 1 percent</NUMEX> of the adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>--striking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hardest
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their 30s</TIMEX>. The symptoms often can be contained by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>. Without
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">manic depression</ENAMEX> face poor outcomes. Some
studies report that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of untreated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sufferers</ENAMEX> commit suicide, making
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">untreated manic depression</ENAMEX> as lethal as many forms of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX>.
The disease also worsens over time, with both mania and depression becoming
more pronounced and less responsive to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX> are especially prone
to drug and alcohol abuse, with all the attendant complications.

            Would it
make a difference if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> were not just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chump</ENAMEX> who chomped on the ear of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">champ</ENAMEX>, but were suffering from an often fatal disease that can be effectively
treated? It would.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> faces a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hobson</ENAMEX>'s choice: he could seek treatment that
could diminish his boxing skills or avoid treatment and become sicker.
Treatment requires daily doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lithium</ENAMEX> (or other mood-stabilizing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>).
The effect on his athletic performance might be severe. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX>--by
design--diminishes many of the qualities that helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> to reach the top of
his game, including feelings of increased energy, invulnerability, elation,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exhilaration</ENAMEX>, inflated self-esteem, hostility, and violence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> acknowledged
the risk in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> when he said, "I'm not taking any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> because I feel
medicine's going to change me."

            For some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lithium</ENAMEX>
also has undesirable side effects. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyatt</ENAMEX> found that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> experienced
tremors and reacted more slowly physically and mentally, while others improved
their performance under <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> maintenance. Going off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lithium</ENAMEX> to prepare for a
bout is not a way out of this dilemma, since in many cases <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lithium</ENAMEX> is not as
effective the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time around.

            All
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> are required to pass physicals to ensure that they do not place
themselves or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> at risk. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boxer</ENAMEX> cannot fight with a heart
condition or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">dementia</ENAMEX>. So why should a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boxer</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">manic-depressive illness</ENAMEX>--and
a history of egregious conduct consistent with the disease--be licensed to
fight without medical clearance?

            
Then there's the public's infatuation with
train wrecks. We anticipate accidents at stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> races. We go to the "fights"
and a hockey game breaks out. We egg on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX>, watching him parade like
a peacock and break down in tears on national TV. We goad <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> player
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Belle</ENAMEX> so much that All-Star-game <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Torre</ENAMEX> must confine him to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dugout</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forward</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Scott</ENAMEX> makes headlines for uncharacteristic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rants</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> love it. Meanwhile, the adulation feeds a sense of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">invincibility</ENAMEX>--especially if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> already happens to suffer from manic
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>. After a crash, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>'s silence feeds an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, and despair.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>'s choice is whether to
save his life or save his career. The choice for others is whether to force him
to make the right choice, or to continue deriving profit and entertainment from
his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
