
   
   
      
         
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> of honor at the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX> party was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny Davis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> of damage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX>. The venue was the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Holeman Lounge</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Press Club</ENAMEX> in
downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> And the celebrants included--among
others--investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , all gathered for a final
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kiss</ENAMEX> of the master <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spinner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>.

            Why did
the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> make merry with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX> and pay tribute to him
with bawdy toasts? After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> had earned a reputation as one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s most egregious news twisters during <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">campaign-finance</ENAMEX> hearings, spinning any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who came near that the
hearings' findings were old news. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> eruption,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> provided the same obfuscating service.

            The truth is that we <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> love being
spun--or, to put it bluntly, love being lied to. The underlying reasons are
transparent. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and their mouthpieces gave it to us straight, we'd
have nothing to interpret and write. So we swoon when important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> return
our calls. (We've been asked to dance!) We thrill at the telephone game of
question and evasion, thinking our guile and cunning will ultimately yield
truth. We play the tortuous game of spin and leak because we must feed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deadline beast</ENAMEX>--that is, serve a new piece of the puzzle to our reading public
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>. So what if some of the pieces are ill-fitting and manufactured from
partial truths?

            There are
few new steps in this dance. In his book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Isaacson</ENAMEX>
recounts how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> would summon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> for supposedly intimate
discussions and solicit their opinions. Then he'd feed them junk, which they'd
publish. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Atwater</ENAMEX> was more cynical, deliberately telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> things
off the record, knowing that they'd view that information as more credible and
use it.

            
Technically, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> wasn't a
celebration; it was a roast. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Goldberg</ENAMEX> booked the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>,
purchased appetizers, and conjured the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. (At least it was a cash bar.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Simpson</ENAMEX>, an aggressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , agreed
to lend his name to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> to make it seem like a press-related event. The
invitations were faxed around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> as the RSVP contact. Joining
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> were a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two dozen</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Schmidt</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> (herself a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> spinning), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Galvin</ENAMEX> from the New York
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Lacey</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX>
declines to talk about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, citing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> policy. He was anything
but speechless at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> itself, serving as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of ceremonies and
delivering what many thought was a hilarious speech.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendee</ENAMEX> conceded that the appearances of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>
fete are all wrong. "We were treating it almost as a birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> said, asking for anonymity. "We all wrote a big card and signed it and
thanked him."

            "I wrote on this card if you
come across any news call me," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacey</ENAMEX>. He insisted that such socializing is
a cost of doing business in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>: "For me it was a sort of
source-development thing." But he added, "You wonder whether it just shows that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are too close."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacey</ENAMEX>'s anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>
spots a parable in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> prom: "In this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, you are judged by how well
you can get a story leaked to you, not how well you can develop a story on your
own and connect the dots," she said. "You get stuff leaked to you in the caste
system. You don't have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there filing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">FOIAs</ENAMEX> or figuring out
some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX> that hasn't been walked before."

            But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> don't need artful seducers like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> to make news. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> who worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> during
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX> says that getting your calls returned by official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>
is a false, overvalued currency. You claw your way into a position to get your
calls returned by actually breaking stories, but that reward is empty. It means
that you're the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> on the call list to be lied to, instead of
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 th</NUMEX> .

            
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> has officially retired from the
game, he's still mixing sense and nonsense for public consumption. Just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX>, I watched him on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rivera Live</ENAMEX> spin the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> on the subject
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s relationship.

            "She was not like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>
interns," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said. "She had come to know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> very well. She had
come to know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, through proximity and through being around that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, very well. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> had some concern about
her.

            "I know that most interns
don't get a chance to know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> and don't have the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> had with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. ... It certainly was a fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, by her own intentions, as a matter of public record, spent a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> getting to know [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>] and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>.

            "As a
matter of fact, I would agree that it is unusual to have that kind of access
and relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and the president
himself and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>. Yes, factually, it's unusual."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Icalled Davis</ENAMEX> to ask about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of his statements
and what he could add to them. Actually, you can't call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>. You page him and
he, joy of joys, returns your call.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> denied any firsthand
knowledge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> affair, claiming that he was merely spewing back what
he had read in published reports.

            "I was making a statistical
comment out of all the interns that work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>," he said. "I can't
characterize the relationship between her and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. ... I used the
word 'unusual' as a statistical comment."

            But you didn't qualify your
remarks on television, I said.

            "When you are on television,
you have to respond quickly," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> explained.

            Now I understood.

            "If you write anything, you
should know that I have no personal knowledge whatsoever about anything."

            Thanks, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lanny</ENAMEX>, here's to
you.

         
      
   
