
   
   
      
         
            I <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Have Seen the Future</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eurocrats</ENAMEX> were thinking
ahead when they made <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital of Europe</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> of the
emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>. Though practically unknown in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX> is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s biggest stories, an important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> trying to
establish itself as a sort of metagovernment for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>.
Entertainingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> is perhaps the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> left in the
world that admits that its goal is to expand. And what better place to locate
this new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>, which may be a living preview of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
to come: swathed in red tape and pomp, paralyzed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> politics,
declining at great cost. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> couldn't have picked a better
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Belgian</ENAMEX>
politics enjoy none of the rowdy intellectual contention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>,
none of the nuance-loving literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">polemics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, not even a strong
national identity. The primary issue in public debate is who gets what
benefits, and while commerce and money are gods, neither is served particularly
well. The national infrastructure is fraying, with little renewal: Belgians
have a high per-capita income and spend it generously on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and dining, but
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rousseau</ENAMEX> called the esprit social seems lacking. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Crumbling,</ENAMEX>
generic, enervated, debt-ridden, materialistic ... is this <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s future?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> is a place where you can take your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurant</ENAMEX>, but not your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Where a best-selling product, in an ostensibly
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Judas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>. (My proposed slogan: "Taste you can trust.")
Where there's no such thing as takeout <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> with lids. Anyone who wants
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> must sit languidly in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cafe</ENAMEX>, gradually feeling overcome with lethargy
and despair.

            Other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> atmospherics:
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lobster bisque</ENAMEX> for sale from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendors</ENAMEX>; excellent public transportation;
monumental traffic jams of expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> crowding small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>; bare breasts
common in advertisements and at beaches, miniskirts being considered acceptable
attire for professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> (when, oh when will these enlightened
attitudes reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>?); notably more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>; notably more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, running higher deficits; lots of
well-cared-for historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, such as the
built-in-the-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th -century</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> I attend with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>; prices far
too high, except for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, which are cheap (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European staples</ENAMEX>, you
know); large cemeteries, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> rest beneath uniform
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX> markers; and ubiquitous fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and great chocolates.

            Many
tongues are spoken here, but multilingualism serves mainly to delineate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituent groups</ENAMEX>, not to facilitate communication. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, called
Wallonia, is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>; the northern portion, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flanders</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX>. The civic sphere
is entirely bilingual, down to abbreviations: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buses</ENAMEX> and trams are brightly
labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIVB/STIB</ENAMEX>, the transit-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> acronyms in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flemish</ENAMEX>. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bilingualism</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to do much to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> together. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flemish</ENAMEX>
parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would rather hear <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, and in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sections</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flemish</ENAMEX> is rarely welcome. Until recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> politics
were dominated by an aging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Francophone</ENAMEX> aristocracy, whose wealth was secured by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wallonian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX>. But mining is a dying industry throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, and Wallonia
now produces <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 13 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>'s exports, vs. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flanders</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flemish</ENAMEX> have jumped into electronics, trading, and other growth sectors,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walloons</ENAMEX> have stagnated, devoting their energies to demanding more
benefits. Their economic power on the rise, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flemish</ENAMEX> have pressured for a
dominant position in politics. The result is an uneasy compromise giving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flanders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wallonia</ENAMEX> semiautonomy.

            
Public strikes, particularly ones blocking
traffic and commerce, are a regular event here, making it somewhat of a mystery
how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> maintains its high living standard. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX>, civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>, airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, and others have closed
off large sections of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> to chant for higher benefits. Ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabena</ENAMEX>, the national flag <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>, ran amok during a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> strike day at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">airport</ENAMEX>, smashing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminal</ENAMEX>'s glass walls and doing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of francs</NUMEX> worth
of damage, then demanding more money from the very <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that was going to
have to pay for the repairs.

            What are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>
striking about? Typical working conditions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> include retirement at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
or younger, full pay for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">32 hours</TIMEX> of work, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX>' paid vacation, and
essentially unlimited sick <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. Much more than high wages (which a profitable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enterprise</ENAMEX> can bear), such work rules are what stymie the continent's
economies, with overall <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western European</ENAMEX> unemployment now at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10.9 percent</NUMEX>,
double the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>.

            Yet,
sympathy is usually with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strikers</ENAMEX>, and cowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> give in to almost all
demands from almost all quarters. Polls repeatedly show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majorities</ENAMEX> think
government should give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> more, a legacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> class system.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is plagued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that have been filthy rich for generations--based
on no useful contribution to society. And a residue of estates reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>
of the landed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentry</ENAMEX>'s historic role as parasites. But the link between
government giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> more, and taxes and public debt rising, does not
seem to have sunk in on this side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>, except perhaps in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>, where, perhaps not coincidentally, unemployment is relatively low.

            As in most of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, state-sanctioned monopolies drag down
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> economic activity, and government barriers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> are much
worse than anywhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabena</ENAMEX> loses money even though it has
government-protected air routes, a high percentage of business flyers, and the
highest seat<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-mile</NUMEX> prices in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            The ossified state of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telecom monopolies</ENAMEX> would stun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Webheads</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> is
not a national obsession in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> (as, of course, it is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>)
is that Internet use remains a luxury here. The phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> have priced
out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> access. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belgacom</ENAMEX> charges <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 cents</NUMEX> per minute for connections to any
Internet service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX>, making the connection more expensive than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">provider</ENAMEX>'s service. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reich</ENAMEX>, having seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> Minitel
experiment, warned that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> would beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to the next
communication revolution--instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in the
dust. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">telecoms</ENAMEX> and communication <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> spend their energies
on blocking innovation and searching for ways to monopolize a new enterprise
whose entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> is decentralization.

            These
rapacious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> have given birth to independent call-back
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. Once registered, you dial a number in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, where a
computer with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX>-ID recognizes you after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>. You hang up to avoid a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belgacom</ENAMEX> charge, and the computer calls you back, providing you with a
stateside dial tone so you can dial as if you were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
Call-back services allow me to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">70 cents</NUMEX> a minute,
vs. the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.60</NUMEX>-per<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-minute</TIMEX> Belgacom charge, and make it cheaper to call
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Antwerp</ENAMEX>--just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 miles</NUMEX> away--via <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> than directly. Naturally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> want to tax call-back services out of existence. Supposedly, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European telecom</ENAMEX> market will deregulate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, and in anticipation of being
phaser-blasted by true competition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belgacom</ENAMEX> just sold <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX> of itself to
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ameritech</ENAMEX>. Foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> will now be blamed for cutting
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deadwood</ENAMEX>.

            
In a sense, all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angling</ENAMEX> to shift the blame for financial reality onto someone else via the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">euro</ENAMEX>. In theory, national currencies such as the pound, mark, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">lira</NUMEX> will all
disappear, replaced by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> universal tender. A unified currency makes economic
sense, but trade efficiency is only one motive for many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>.
Participation in the new currency requires <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> to cut their national debt
below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> of GDP. A dirty little secret of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX> is that it has
gone further into hock than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> public debt was down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.4</NUMEX>
percent of GDP in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, and may drop below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fiscal year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> all are running public debts at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> or more, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> is at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.4 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">national leaders</ENAMEX> know they've got to tackle
their deficits, but none of them wants the heat for cutting featherbedding or
generous social-payment systems. So the euro plan allows them to blame foreign
interests for required reductions.

            But will
the spooky level of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> corruption rub off on the euro? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observers</ENAMEX> consider
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-most corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, trailing only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary-general</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> had to quit over charges that his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Flemish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Party</ENAMEX> accepted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> in bribes from a defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> recently arrested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and raided the headquarters
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French Socialist Party</ENAMEX> in connection with bribes from another defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eurocrats</ENAMEX> have worthy ideas, such as
persuading the continent's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> to agree on harmonious environmental and
immigration policies. But the real overriding goal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> and its
executive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> (there's also a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Parliament</ENAMEX>
here, but we can skip that), is self-aggrandizement. In conversations,
Eurocrats are frank about their maneuvering for more money and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>: to wrest
"competence," or jurisdiction, away from national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and vest it in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> is the open objective.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">union</ENAMEX>'s command <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> is a cathedral to bureaucratic power, the only
diplomatic structure I've ever been in that actually looks the way <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
depicts diplomatic life. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Foggy Bottom</ENAMEX>,
paint is peeling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with titles like "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy director</ENAMEX>"
work in chintzy little <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dilbert</ENAMEX> cubicles. At the marble-clad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, even midlevel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eurocrats</ENAMEX> have large, plush <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">suites</ENAMEX> with leather
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">chairs</ENAMEX> and original artwork on the walls. Ranks of big black-glass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMWs</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">limos</ENAMEX> are parked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>'s circular drive, motors wastefully
idling. Landing a job in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brussels Eurocracy</ENAMEX> has become the career goal of
many of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>'s behavior synchs with its
opulent circumstances. Meetings are held in secret, and few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>-disclosure
regulations apply. This is the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>? Just how
competent the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> may be is on display at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berlaymont</ENAMEX>, the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. Forerunner of the current sumptuous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>,
this vast <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> now sits near the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> unoccupied, its
entire outer structure swathed in heavy tarpaulin. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berlaymont</ENAMEX> has been closed
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> after an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asbestos</ENAMEX> scare and a botched cleanup: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> have paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX> so far merely to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> closed, with
air pumps running around the clock to prevent any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> from wafting out. A
mountain of scientific studies has shown that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asbestos</ENAMEX> in walls is almost never
dangerous: The only dangerous thing is trying to rip it out because that causes
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fibers</ENAMEX> to become airborne--exactly what has happened at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berlaymont</ENAMEX>. And if the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> can't manage its continent any better than it manages its own
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> ...

            Fortunately, Berlaymont
isn't in my neighborhood, but a patisserie is. Bakeries are easier to find than
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>, and the neon bakery sign I can see from my office
window often calls out to me the way signs for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail lounges</ENAMEX> once called out
to earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. Think I'll answer now.

         
      
   
