
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New, Improved, Low Calorie Testament</ENAMEX>

            It shouldn't have been a
complete surprise when I walked into the elevator in my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> office
building and came upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> clutching a book by the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardinal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernardin</ENAMEX>. If you've been revealed as a moral degenerate, the natural course in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political life as it has evolved in our times is to come back as a
newly enlightened spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Augustine</ENAMEX> for the klieg light
age.

            Last
fall, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> gave an interview to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Door</ENAMEX> , the world's funniest
evangelical humor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, in which he traced the arc of this sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">spiritual/</ENAMEX>professional recovery. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>, the whole focus on career,
work, and money making has declined significantly as part of my life. They're
not the things that I think about constantly," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> said with beguiling
innocence. "At some point I would very much like to be able to have a national
talk radio show and a national television show and a national column to be able
to bring my views to those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who would care to hear them. I don't
believe that I should really do this until I am further along my own personal
growth and evolution."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, the wait is over. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> has emerged from his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long weeks</TIMEX> in the wilderness and come to
the point at which he can stop thinking about his career and start thinking
about getting a national radio show, TV show, and column. Rising above his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">careerist</ENAMEX> mentality, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> now spends more time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> of our
second-tier TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>. And it's working. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 13</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> is close to signing
a deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>. And he is writing a provocative column for the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>. He is succeeding as a
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundit</ENAMEX> in part because of his interesting vantage point--he hates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> but loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>--and in part because he is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Milken</ENAMEX> of the
attention economy. Everything he says--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s a lesbian, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
stages to the television age and he's got them all figured out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
are going to sweep the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> elections--is clever and provocative. Not all
these positions have great substantive thought behind them, but nobody gets
punished in the pundit games for being too ephemeral.

            The
great sorrow of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> life is that the corrupt world wants to drag him
back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> of politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' real focus, as he lets you know before
you have a chance to ask, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Realms</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> has been doing some
polling on spiritual issues, and he has discovered that morality is big. For
example, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX>, he had his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> read the following statement to
a survey <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>:

            Look into our own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bodies</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of cells which must work together or we die. When a cell
does its own thing, that's called <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. So it is with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>.
Unless we work for our planet, we will die of the global <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> of pollution,
war and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. He found <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> supported that statement,
and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 28 percent</NUMEX> opposed it (who the hell are they?). He concluded in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> column, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idealism</ENAMEX> is, I believe, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in our politics.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynicism</ENAMEX> is on its way out."

            
The odd thing is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> himself is not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cynical</ENAMEX>, at least not self-consciously so. He is genuinely excited about this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">new</ENAMEX> spiritual stuff he has discovered, and sincere--painfully sincere--when he
gives you his ideas about his plan to renew <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> morality. His tone at
these times is a mixture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>-omniscience and saintly humility--as if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> had become one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you hear on the management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> of the
airplane audio system. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> talks about his spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX>, his eyes
lower. He reiterates he is not qualified to speak on these issues. He is to
humility what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis XIV</ENAMEX> was to gilt-edged furniture. He has built a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> his own unworthiness, and if you talk to him, he takes you on an extended
tour to show off all his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>. But he can't not talk about these
things, he implies, because he has come up with a unique message that simply
must be heard.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>
calls his spiritual platform "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Transactionalism</ENAMEX>." It's not based on a specific
organized religion. "Those who fear hell are religious; those who've been there
are spiritual," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Door</ENAMEX> , echoing a sentiment he learned
from the addiction movement (he is a recovering sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX>). Transactionalism
is instead a series of policy ideas that would improve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s spiritual
indicators. As he talks about them, you realize that if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> followed his
advice, God's favorable/unfavorable ratings would go through the roof.

            
Some of the ideas are a little mushy, though
not entirely unworthy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> wants to set up a series of redemption centers
where ex-cons could get a certificate proving they are redeemed and therefore
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employable</ENAMEX>. He would like to see a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> create a certification
symbol that clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> could put on their labels to show the
products were made by well treated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. He says he has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of ideas like
these.

            If the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Almighty</ENAMEX> had properly focus-grouped the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Testament</ENAMEX>, it would be chock-full
of this stuff. There's lots of noble praise for the civil society movement
wrapped around a series of small, feel-good ideas that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">elicit</ENAMEX> warm and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">pleasant</ENAMEX>-feeling grunts of approval. If you remember the issues floated by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> re-election campaign--gun control for deadbeat dads, for example--the
tone will be familiar. What is striking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Transactionalism</ENAMEX>, and about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' whole approach to spirituality, is how much it is a continuation of his
political style. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is still manipulating images and spinning, but now he
is spinning for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>, not votes. He seems genuinely repentant of his personal
sins. But he evidently sees no contradiction between the amoral spinmeistering
of the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> and his new vocation. He recently recalled a
problem he faced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, when a congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> he was working
for was caught with a series of transsexual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitutes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> proudly noted
that he solved the problem and got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> elected. When asked if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was
guilty, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> seemed taken aback by the question. He said he guessed the guy
was guilty, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years later</TIMEX> he was caught again and had to resign in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disgrace</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has always had a spiritual self-help
literature that reconciles redemption with résumé-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man Nobody Knows</ENAMEX> , a best seller in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1925-26</TIMEX>, portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
as the ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>. "He picked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> from the bottom ranks of the
business and forged them into an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that conquered the world," reads
a typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> sentence. But in truth, the yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spiritualism</ENAMEX> of the moment
is the perfect breeding ground for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' style of rebirth. It takes religion,
removes all the dark images that drive up its negatives--like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment,</ENAMEX>
obligation, or anything that might not be career enhancing--and replaces them
with self-esteem and moral medals of honor. No wonder so many find this
market-tested spiritualism so cool. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Behind the Oval</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX> , ends with a conversation between him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> on why the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forgiving St. Patrick</ENAMEX> is better than the stern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Paul</ENAMEX>.

            I had another glimpse of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' oddly naive spiritual self-enhancement while working on this article.
After a meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>, I mentioned his new vocation to a

                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, who suggested I do a piece. I called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> to set
up an interview about his ideas and left a message. Then I ran into him at a
party. I had a pleasant conversation with him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> was excited
to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transactionalism</ENAMEX> and promised to call. He did, and we set up a
time to talk more. But then he called back and said that since he was now a
pundit, he should write the piece about his ideas, rather than have me write
about him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' ambitions are all on the surface, and you could see that he
wanted to crack into 
                  Slate
                and control the piece. I confess I've
never had the subject of a piece try to replace me as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, but I figured it
was up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>; so I gave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s number. But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX>
later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> called on his way to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> (it was Good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), sounding
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contrite</ENAMEX> and saying that he would "back off" and would call at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30</TIMEX> to talk. He
never called, and now he has stopped returning my messages. I figure he made
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> false promises to me during our preliminary conversations as he
tried to figure out how to play this to his advantage. None was serious,
obviously, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> suspects the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> wouldn't lie about a big thing. But
it is the web of easy evasions that is the essence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrisism</ENAMEX>, both in his
politico past and in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Augustinian</ENAMEX> present.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dostoyevsky</ENAMEX> wrote a book
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Idiot</ENAMEX> about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who is unprepossessing and naturally holy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX> is more of an idiot savant. He seems sincerely interested in
understanding holiness. But he can't stop spinning ideas, images, and sound
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bites</ENAMEX>, can't stop playing everything to his advantage. Watching him, you can
see why some of those monks felt it necessary to take vows of silence.

         
      
   
