
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skull Session</ENAMEX>

            I was expecting ... I don't
know what. Maybe some old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hatboxes</ENAMEX> labeled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Confidential: Vietnam</ENAMEX>" languishing
on a dusty shelf in a dusty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Sledzik</ENAMEX>, an earnest young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum of Health and Medicine</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>,
leads me into a large, spotless storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, unlocks File <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">24</TIMEX>, and
slides out the top drawer. There they are: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">skulls</ENAMEX>. Keepsakes from the
war that refuses to go away quietly. A cardboard divider, no different from
what's normally used to ship grapefruit, keeps the skulls from banging together
like marbles.

            "These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">favorites</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sledzik</ENAMEX> says. "I kind of go back and forth about which is the most
interesting."

            He points
out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> skulls that are indisputably the eye-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catchers</ENAMEX> of the bunch.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Interesting</ENAMEX>" is an understatement. These are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velvet Elvises</ENAMEX> of war booty.
The first skull (inventory No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1987.3017.13</NUMEX>) is slathered with graffiti. Above
the eye sockets someone scrawled "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chu Lai</ENAMEX> trip skull." The doodles include a
peace sign and a marijuana pipe. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuckie</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rich</ENAMEX>" are
among those who added their names, as if they were giddy college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX>
autographing a football after a big homecoming win.

            The skull is that of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-to-20-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>. It had
been confiscated from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Da Nang</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airfield</ENAMEX> in the fall of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>. They had inquired about the proper procedure for shipping their prize
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, apparently oblivious to the fact that body parts aren't considered
military surplus. "If you read the case file," notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sledzik</ENAMEX>, "it sounds as if
they thought there was nothing wrong with this."

            His other
favorite skull (No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1987.3017.23</NUMEX>) came from a slightly older <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authorities</ENAMEX> took it off the hands of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">GI</ENAMEX> stationed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pleiku</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. Somebody
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> was dabbling in morbid art therapy. An undercoat of shocking-blue
paint had been applied to the skull; red and yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day-Glo</ENAMEX> vertical stripes
were then added in the back. A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fat</ENAMEX>, black candle--melted firmly in place, wick
still intact--sits atop the skull amid a puddle of congealed wax. A drill hole
is visible in the cranium, evidence that this was once a hanging skull-candle.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> remaining skulls (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> belonging to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, all believed to
be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX>) also underwent what is euphemistically known as "post-mortem
decorative treatment." For example, the eye cavities of skull No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1987.3017.09</NUMEX>--found inside a footlocker at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Campbell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>--bear
the inscriptions "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimi Vivar</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70-71</NUMEX>" (left) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viet Nam</ENAMEX> que loco" (right).
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Things Go Better With Castro Coke" and "Stay High Stay Alive</ENAMEX>" adorn the top
and sides.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum of Health and Medicine</ENAMEX> is
located on the grounds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter Reed Army Medical Center</ENAMEX>. Its roots extend
back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>. Thus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> can find on display a swatch of diseased
colon removed from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> plagued by terminal diarrhea, and pieces of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wilkes Booth</ENAMEX>'s vertebrae, not to mention such miscellany as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siamese twins</ENAMEX>
in a jar and a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX> mummy. However, the oddest items in the oddball
collection--items that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> doesn't quite know what to do with--are
kept in permanent storage. Like the brain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Guiteau</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assassinated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garfield</ENAMEX>. Like the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> skulls.

            I'd visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>
several times, but learned about the skulls only recently from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. They
immediately ruined <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several nights</TIMEX>' sleep, prompting me to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Sledzik</NUMEX> a visit.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, after all, is my war. And I have the draft-lottery deferment to prove
it. The assumption, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sledzik</ENAMEX>, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grunts</ENAMEX> picked up the skulls
in their battlefield travels: souvenirs to someday show the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX>. But now
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> are busy re-establishing diplomatic
relations, now that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hanoi</ENAMEX> may be in the running for the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCBY</ENAMEX> yogurt
franchise, why not give 'em back? For the sake of symbolic closure. For sappy
sentimental reasons. By rights, it seems to me, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> ought to rest
in peace, if not near his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, then at least on the same continent.

            Shows
what I know.

            Trophies of war--from helmets, bayonets, and other
innocuous spoils to the grisly byproducts of dismemberment--have a long, if not
proud, history. In the latter category, the practice probably reached its nadir
with headshrinking. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sledzik</ENAMEX> walks across the storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and fetches another
rare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> piece: a perfectly preserved head no larger than a tennis ball.
It's the handiwork of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuar</ENAMEX>, a notoriously ferocious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX> that inhabits
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ecuador</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Peru</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shuar</ENAMEX>--who are to headshrinking what the
Amish are to quilting--were transforming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> into trinkets as recently as
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>.

            But such
macabre behavior transcends geographic bounds. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">medieval England</ENAMEX> the severed
heads of those who crossed the throne were regularly stuck on pikes and mounted
in public places, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> Bridge being a choice site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Cromwell</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decapitated</ENAMEX> after death and his head left on a pole in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster Hall</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Across the world, an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town of Nara</ENAMEX> once contained the ears of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> reportedly
moved on to bigger things in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. The archives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physicians of Philadelphia</ENAMEX> contain a note dictated by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> of the college
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX> that reads, "Recently a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> sent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">210</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> as trophies to be displayed. This number was exceeded by another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>
who sent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">220</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> was not the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> indulged in noggin nabbing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marines</ENAMEX> amassed piles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philippine Insurrection</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1899-1901</TIMEX>. Army records show that when the remains
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> killed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mariana Islands</ENAMEX> were repatriated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">some 60 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> were headless.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Alas,</ENAMEX>
there is a semi-underground market--collectively called "the bone trade"--that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trafficks</ENAMEX> in body parts imbued with historic significance or celebrity cachet.
What is reputed to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Custer</ENAMEX>'s left pinkie has, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>,
been traded for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and sold for its weight in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marquis de Sade</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> is known to be "above ground," as they say in the business. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Napoleon</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penis</ENAMEX>--lopped off during his autopsy--was purchased <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> urologist.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob White</ENAMEX>, a respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baltimore</ENAMEX> memorabilia <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the world's largest collection of shrunken heads (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> and
counting), says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> trophy skulls would find <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. "As sick as it
sounds," he says, "they would even be a good investment" (though not as good as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Monroe</ENAMEX>'s nipples--rumored to have been snipped off during her autopsy,
along with some locks of hair--which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> estimates "could bring well over
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX>").

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX> of shrunken
heads, who requested anonymity, has a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> photograph of a group of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> posing by a crude altar fashioned from skulls and bones,
reminiscent of the ghastly constructions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khmer Rouge</ENAMEX>. "They're
showing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Angel of Death</ENAMEX> that they're not afraid," he explains.

            
Desecration of the dead serves the dual purpose of steeling one's own courage
and intimidating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX> adds, "There is a difference
between taking a trophy and a souvenir."

            
The distinction seems irrelevant as I stand
inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Museum of Health and Medicine</ENAMEX> holding the bright blue
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skull</ENAMEX>-candle in cupped hands. Part of me is worried about dropping the damn
thing. Part of me feels obliged to smash it against the wall. I ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sledzik</ENAMEX> if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> might want custody of the skulls. "As far
as I know, they've never been offered," he replies. "We can't say for sure
they're even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">combatants</ENAMEX>."

            His
assistant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenore Barbian</ENAMEX>, cautions against practicing moral hegemony. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX>, she says, "are not very careful about the disposal of human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">remains</ENAMEX>.
It's not part of the culture. It's a different way of viewing death."

            She's right, of course. But forensic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> are
trained to view the world through dispassionate eyes. I'm unschooled. I'm also,
for better or worse, a creature of Western sensibilities, in which crude lines
are customarily drawn between the murderous imperatives of battle and the
wanton bloodlust of barbarism. Come <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Day</ENAMEX>--when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is absorbed
in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> rituals of war and remembrance, when flags bloom like
red-white-and-blue wildflowers on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of graves</NUMEX>--my thoughts will wander
to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rich" and "Chuckie</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimi Vivar</ENAMEX>." They are on the loose in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
Middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> now. How'd the readjustment to civilian life go? What gimmicks
are they employing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> to stave off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Angel of Death</ENAMEX>?

            Mostly, though, I will think
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six</NUMEX> lives and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> ignominious ends. Something tells me those hapless
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> skulls deserve a better resting place than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">File Cabinet</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>. Yet, I
can't say exactly why. I just feel it in my bones.

         
      
   
