
   
   
      
         
            Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> a Sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Addict</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, our most adept
practitioner of therapeutic politics, has always flirted with dysfunction. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, during his first successful presidential campaign, he discussed his
dysfunctional family history during a televised interview. He acknowledged that
growing up with an alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> may have made him particularly eager to
please and placate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Veterans</ENAMEX> of the recovery movement, which remained popular
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1990s</TIMEX>, would have instantly recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as an ACOA (adult
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of an alcoholic). Considering his abusive, alcoholic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stepfather</ENAMEX>, his
substance abusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, his mother's penchant for gambling, and his own
compulsive eating and alleged womanizing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> looked like a case
study in a codependency book.

            Whether you saw this as a
weakness or a strength depended on your relationship with the therapeutic
culture. "Real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> don't get on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , standing up for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tradition of
rugged individualism. But for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who considered
themselves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> of dysfunction and abuse and believed fervently in the
healing power of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> or their support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s implied awareness
of his "feeling reality" was much more appealing than any display of machismo.
Being "in recovery" is no weakness to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who consider being "in denial" the
only alternative.

            Besides,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> never actually presented himself as truly dysfunctional. (Who would
elect a dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?) Instead, his moments of apparent
introspection humanized him and made him seem approachable. They helped him
politically just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s bouts of bulimia helped transform her into
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s desire to please was a classic symptom of
codependency, but those who recognized it as such probably felt closer to him
when he acknowledged it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who were not conversant in the language of
recovery might see in his desire to please a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> for compromise--an
essential political art. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> deftly balanced hints of
codependency with the image of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in control of policy and the political
process. If he could not always control his appetites--for cheeseburgers and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doughnuts</ENAMEX>--he was someone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> could identify with. But his unmistakable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX>, his ability to master the details of complicated policy matters,
and his skills at communicating made him someone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> could also admire.

            The most powerful
charismatics are those who simultaneously invite identification and awe. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX>
even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> are awestruck by his seduction and survival skills.)
Charismatic personalities combine transcendent beauty, glamour, or talent with
accessibility, providing a way in for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> eager to identify with a higher
being. They seem both ineffable and utterly familiar.

            But this
delicate balance of minor, private, victimless dysfunction and the ability to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master public</ENAMEX> issues and events has been endangered by the current scandals.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s image as a "caring" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, one who will help us heal, has been badly
damaged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>'s story, which has put his very membership in the
therapeutic culture at risk. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who ran on a platform of compassion
allegedly acted cruelly to someone who came to him in need of it. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s
story is true, he didn't feel her pain. He used it.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> steeped in popular therapies seek
explanations. "Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> a sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX>?" some wondered when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
story broke. In the aftermath of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> interview, the
conversation has revived. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and
reputed former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolly Kyle Browning</ENAMEX> claims that, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, she confronted
him with her suspicions that he was a sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX>, "just like her." According to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> broke down and cried. Whether or
not this sensational story is true, it suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is in danger of being
defeated by the therapeutic culture that helped get him elected.

            The
recovery movement gave us the concept of sex addiction, which is a form of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">codependency</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, the movement popularized the notion that behaviors
could be as addictive as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substances</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>, and it founded
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-step programs for compulsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX>, sexaholics, and so on.
Recovery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> would probably be sympathetic to a sex-addicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
but might be unlikely to support him until he agreed to get help--which is hard
to imagine.

            To <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are most familiar with the term and most
likely to take it seriously, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX>, he is clearly not in
recovery. Therefore he is in denial. To recovery aficionados, that probably
means he is not sufficiently evolved, spiritually or psychically, to lead the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>. They would not expect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to be devoid of dysfunction, but
would expect him to have recognized and vanquished his own abusive behaviors.
To support him would be to support his denials, thereby making them
"enablers."

            There is
some symmetry in the diagnosis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, our therapeutic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> in addition to healer. The personal development tradition greatly
values the presumed authority of experience, and codependency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>--leaders
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Bradshaw</ENAMEX>--routinely confessed their own struggles with various
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">addictions</ENAMEX> in order to bolster their credibility. But they marketed themselves
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had been through the "process" of recovery, surrendered their
will to their higher powers, and freed themselves of addictive behaviors. From
this perspective, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has yet to get with the program.

            
For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are not immersed in recovery but
are receptive to the notion of sex addiction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s dysfunction
simply means that, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>, he is "out of control." Nobody wants an out
of control <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hostile to popular notions of addiction
will dismiss the characterization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as a sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX> as an evasion of
personal responsibility. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX>, indeed, some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> may prefer seeing
him as the victim of a disease rather than as an intentional sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">predator</ENAMEX>.)

            But let's get clinical: Does
the diagnosis of sex addiction make sense? Outside the world of pop psychology,
it is likely to engender skepticism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Psychiatric Association</ENAMEX> does
not formally recognize sex addiction as a mental disorder. Among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> who
treat and study compulsive behaviors and chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dependencies</ENAMEX>, there is
controversy over the meaning of the term "addiction" and the efficacy of the
disease model for a range of supposed addictions, from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX> to compulsive
gambling.

            Even if sex addiction
exists, and even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> qualifies, he is unlikely to claim the banner.
Politically, it's a loser. Or is it? It did work for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, Mayor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>, a self-professed sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX> who rehabilitated himself politically
after a drug conviction by declaring his powerlessness over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and sex,
repenting, and entering a program. "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are recovering from something,"
he explained to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> won back the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s office
by embracing his own dysfunctions--but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is a dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
