
   
   
      
         
            Can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Save Social Security</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>
has been gently tapping the "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> rail" of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
reform--to see if the electricity it generates is truly lethal. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> impressed a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Economic Forum</ENAMEX> in
Davos, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, with a disciplined description of his thoughts on the
subject. At the time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s remarks were "off the record." That he has
now agreed to let them be reported may be due in part to the cover provided by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kerrey</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, who have unveiled a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> plan that is, in certain ways,
more radical and less socially conscious than what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> seems to have in
mind.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s approach will not placate die-hard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> of the current system,
who are already up in arms about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> plan. Nor will it satisfy fire
breathing "privatizers" who would dump the whole thing and set every wage
earner free to make a killing on Wall Street. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerrey</ENAMEX>, would start to move some of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s current surpluses
into private sector investments. He would do it by setting up "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security-plus" accounts for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX>. These could be invested in a
"broad based" portfolio of private securities with low risk but a higher rate
of return than government bonds.

            The basic idea is not new. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, for example, all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Advisory Council</ENAMEX> agreed that some part of the
trust funds should be invested in the private market (though they didn't agree
on how). The reason is simple: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> system is missing out on its
own "golden <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>"--the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> period in the program's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> when it should be
possible both to keep paying benefits to current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> and to make prudent
provision for future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">claimants</ENAMEX>.

            That's
because, over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several years</TIMEX> and for several to come, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
payroll taxes have far exceeded, and will continue to far exceed, the benefits
paid out. Those surpluses, totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 trillion</NUMEX> by the end of this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>, are supposed to be "invested" against the rainy day when the baby
boomers retire. Instead, they are simply transferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> in
exchange for IOUs (plus IOUs for interest on past loans). The money is then
used to help cover the costs of everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Black Hawk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopters</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> spinners. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is thus doing the rest of the budget--and --a
huge favor since, without its loans, the much touted budget surplus would be a
triple-digit deficit.

            
This is like replacing the money you'd been
saving for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' college tuition with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IO</ENAMEX>-me note, buying a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, and
then congratulating yourself on your financial prudence. But in the case of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> there's an added problem: A payroll tax is a lousy way to pay
for most of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> buys. It's fair enough to use such a tax to pay for
a social insurance program that provides coverage in rough proportion to
contributions. This is especially so since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s retirement and
disability benefit formulas are heavily weighted to favor low earners. But
there's no justification for paying for defense or environmental protection or
the weather <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> with a regressive tax that hits only the lower part of
earnings and hits investment income not at all. (Well, there is one
justification: Otherwise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would have to cut
spending, raise taxes, or just admit they can't come close to balancing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>.)

            In their
plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerrey</ENAMEX> would address this inequity by cutting payroll taxes
by some <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>, thus eliminating the trust fund
surplus. To keep the deficit in the rest of the budget from being laid bare for
all to ogle, they propose both tax hikes and benefit cuts. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> for a
summary.) Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings</ENAMEX> would come from higher income and payroll taxes,
especially on well-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX>. (Expect a hue and cry to be raised
among tax cut <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> against the plan's provisions calling for smaller
inflation adjustments in the income tax code.) But much would come in the form
of reduced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> benefits, notably accelerated increases in the
retirement age and a one-percentage-point cut in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> cost-of-living benefit
adjustments. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> do agree that the Consumer Price Index
significantly overstates inflation, and the system currently adjusts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX>'
initial benefits for real economic growth as well as for inflation. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>' cut is toward the high end of the consensus, especially if sustained
long into the future.

            How plausible are these proposals? A truly honest reform
would force the general budget to pay for itself and let <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
reserve its past as well as its future surpluses for the system's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next-century</TIMEX>
needs. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> would soften the benefit cuts by offering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> a
shot at higher private sector returns. Beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> could take
the full two-percentage-point cut in payroll taxes they propose, including the
employer share, and invest the money in personal savings accounts. (Otherwise
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> can pocket their own half of the payroll tax cut.) That would make
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> look much like the current government employee retirement
plan--and many private sector plans--in which a fixed benefit pension is
supplemented by a savings plan in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> contributions are matched by
employer contributions up to certain limits.

            The
trouble with this, as former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Ball</ENAMEX> points
out, is that making the savings accounts voluntary means that many lower-wage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> will surely choose not to participate. Moreover, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are allowed
a wide range of investment choices, then administrative costs, error rates--and
risk--will soar. And even if investments are limited to a relatively small menu
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>-supervised options, the timing of their contributions or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retirement</ENAMEX> will disadvantage some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. In case you've forgotten, the stock
market doesn't always go up.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, however, addresses these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>, if
only in general terms. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davos</ENAMEX> he said he didn't even want to use the loaded
term "privatization." A basic social insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> is a hallmark of a
civilized society, he said, and it must be government-run and mandatory.
Otherwise, for reasons laudable or frivolous, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won't save the money
needed to provide for their old age or unexpected disability, and society will
end up paying to keep them on welfare. Nor should any current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> fear for
their benefits, especially at a time when the system is generating huge
surpluses that ought to be reserved for the system's future needs. "No one has
to worry. No one should get scared."

            Still, as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalists</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ball</ENAMEX> acknowledge, private investments--even the
broad-based, relatively conservative portfolios selected by insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>--do offer significantly better returns than government bonds. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Bureau of Economic Research</ENAMEX> estimates that stocks outpace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
securities by a range of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent to 13 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. Even the lower limit
of that differential compounds to a hefty sum over time. Moreover, redirecting
trust fund surpluses into the private market (which is what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan-Kerrey</ENAMEX>
plan essentially does) has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> large potential advantage--when the time comes
to redeem the securities, the money should really be there.

            And that's the key point. The incremental reforms that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalists</ENAMEX> favor to put the system's books in long-term balance all assume
that the current trust fund balances, held in the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> bonds, are
really being compounded and preserved. But when the time comes to redeem the
bonds (or even when the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> payroll tax surpluses begin to taper off several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years from now</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will be forced to choose among ugly
alternatives. It will have to cut other spending, raise other taxes or, more
likely, sell other bonds to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>--that is, run a big budget deficit.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> itself wouldn't go bankrupt. As long as there are still U.S.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> paying payroll taxes (and if there aren't, we'll have many far bigger
problems), these can cover at least partial benefits. But the pressure to cut
benefits or sharply raise payroll taxes would be enormous.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Moynihan</ENAMEX>
has long been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwart advocate</ENAMEX> of traditional social insurance. By his
abrupt switch to the side of relatively radical reform, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> has opened
up a gap in the middle of the debate. In a further role reversal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> may
have positioned himself to fill it.

            
               If you missed our previous
links to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s vacuous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> promise and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) a
summary of the very real tax hikes and benefit cuts proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Kerrey,</ENAMEX> click and .
            

         
      
   
