
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood Party</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for the Golden
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX> was high up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>. I had been invited by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who
has lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost 20 years</TIMEX> and is now a noted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anthropologist</ENAMEX>. As we rounded a turn, a pair of big metal gates appeared before
us. Behind them, set on the crest of a hill, was a large white <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in the
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian</ENAMEX> style. In front of the gates, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen or so</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>
stood around in dark uniforms.

            I thought
for a moment that they were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brass band</ENAMEX>, but they turned out to be the valet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parkers</ENAMEX>. I was just realizing why the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian</ENAMEX> unemployment rate is so low
when a dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windstar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">minivan</ENAMEX> pulled up next to us. We climbed in and were
driven approximately <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30 yards</NUMEX> to the steps of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, where we got out
again. The front door was opened by yet more valets, and we were bidden
inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>, veteran studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Medavoy</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irina</ENAMEX>, were there to greet us. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>, a black V-neck <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumper</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">open-necked</ENAMEX> shirt covering his ample torso, looked like he had just stepped off
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> green. Irina, it must be said, didn't. A striking blonde,
she was wearing high heels, velvet trousers, and a black cardigan that my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort helpfully</ENAMEX> described as a "peekaboo top." As I struggled manfully to
avoid staring at her cleavage, she explained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> had been built <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, and that she had redecorated it throughout.

            What she
didn't say, understandably, was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> had been built for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s
previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Duff</ENAMEX>, who had used it to throw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raisers</ENAMEX> for her
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. Then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> and took up
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Perelman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-leaning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX>. At about the same time
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>, he also lost his job as head of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TriStar Pictures</ENAMEX>. Even
here, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> are used to ups and downs of a personal and business
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nature</ENAMEX>, that was considered quite a twofer.

            
According to my date, the real purpose of the
party was to mark <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medavoy</ENAMEX>'s return to the big leagues. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suitably</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix Pictures</ENAMEX>, he is once more making films, including one
that might win an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar, The People</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> . And in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irina</ENAMEX>, he
has a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who, while she might not have his ex's political clout, has just
as much glamour and sex appeal.

            If
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prestige</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is measured in pulling power, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medavoy</ENAMEX> is definitely
back on top. Looking around, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> I saw was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Penn</ENAMEX>. He was
standing alone in a corner, clad in black jeans, black T-shirt, and black
leather jacket. I was thinking what a good job he was doing of playing up to
his image as a brooding misfit when a bathroom door opened next to him and a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> walked out and jumped into his arms. He smiled broadly, mumbled
fatherly nothings into his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s ear, and carried her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s gone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>," my date whispered.

            Moving further into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, I felt the same sense of
surprise that I always feel in the presence of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX>: surprise that
they look so familiar. Here was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Woods</ENAMEX>, talking <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a million miles</NUMEX> a minute
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Minghella</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The English Patient</ENAMEX> , and appearing
for all the world like he was playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Boyle</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador</ENAMEX> . There was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Byrne</ENAMEX>, nursing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heineken</ENAMEX>, every inch the
handsome villain of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Usual Suspects</ENAMEX> . And here was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Goldblum</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">angular</ENAMEX> and geeky, looking like he had just stepped out of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jurassic Park</ENAMEX> . He was just back from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, where he had been filming
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost World</ENAMEX> , the sequel to that monster smash.

            "What's the plot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>?" I
asked, casually, as if I had known him all my life.

            "It's a big secret," he
replied.

            "Oh, come on," my date
insisted.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, they tempt me to go
back to an island where there are more <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX>."

            "What sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX>?"

            
"Stegosaurs--the fat ones with ripples on their back."

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medavoys</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is beautiful, with large,
airy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and white walls covered with modern art. On virtually every surface
are photographs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medavoys</ENAMEX> with famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbra Streisand</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Kissinger</ENAMEX>. The
only notable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">absentee</ENAMEX> was his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>.

            In the drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, we ran
into another tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cromwell</ENAMEX>, who recently appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The People</ENAMEX>
vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> . When he heard I was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cromwell</ENAMEX> told me that he had
just finished writing a novel.

            "What's it about?" I
asked.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contact</ENAMEX>," he replied.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pardon</ENAMEX>."

            "Contact ... the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX> ...
what separates us from our destiny."

            " 'Contact.' You mean 'alien
contact'<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            He nodded.

            "The spaceship in the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> desert and all that? You think we have been contacted by life from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">planets?</ENAMEX>"

            He nodded again and
said:

            "Yes.
Regularly. Ever since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX>. You just have to look on the Internet. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> sightings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>."

            Iwent outside for a drink. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stone</ENAMEX>-flagged veranda was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> the size of a baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">diamond</ENAMEX>, and it seemed to overlook the whole of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, which was a mosaic of orange and white lights. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, I found
myself next to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> nondescript <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youths</ENAMEX> who were chugging down a couple of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beers</ENAMEX>.

            "You're really popular in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," one said to the other.

            "Yeah, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> and French
really like me."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, too."

            "Yeah, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> too. I'm a big
star in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. I've won lots of awards and shit over there. It's really
weird."

            My eavesdropping was
interrupted by a loud cry from inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. When I got there, I found
myself next to the hostess.

            "What happened?" she
asked.

            "Somebody ran down the stairs
on their hands," came the answer from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>.

            "My God,
somebody ran down the stairs on their hands in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>," she shrieked, clearly
delighted.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> was now in full swing. Belatedly, I
realized that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>. My date explained
that this is always the case at awards parties <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. She said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> have largely given up producing serious movies, so they have
to rely on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> and antipodeans to make films that won't embarrass the
industry when the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oscars</ENAMEX> come around. Unfortunately, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">academy</ENAMEX> have never heard of a lot of these foreign movies, so there is an event
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every January</TIMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Globe Awards</ENAMEX> to tell them what films to watch
before they vote.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Hicks</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shine</ENAMEX> , is one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of this shift. Having just got off a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16-hour</TIMEX> flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Adelaide</ENAMEX>, the longhaired <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Aussie</ENAMEX> seemed somewhat bemused by
all the fuss. "I'm trying to figure out what it is about Shine that
appeals to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so much," he told me. "I really don't know." I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hicks</ENAMEX>
whether he was planning to move to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, but he said he was wary of
repeating the experiences of other young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign directors</ENAMEX> who have tried it,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Figgis</ENAMEX>. "They tend to have a huge cock-up and
leave," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hicks</ENAMEX> said. For now, he added, he was "determined to enjoy the
moment."

            So were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Parker</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evita</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leigh</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secrets</ENAMEX> and
Lies . When I ran across the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX>, they were knocking back the white
wine and discussing that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> of subjects: the class system. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh</ENAMEX> are both self-made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Labor Party</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX> has worked primarily in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost two decades</TIMEX>, whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh</ENAMEX>
stayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to make his low-budget films. Although they admire each
other's work, this was clearly a point of some tension between them.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leigh</ENAMEX> knows sod-all
about the working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> said to me, apropos of nothing.

            Fortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh</ENAMEX> didn't
hear that slur. I asked him how much money it took to produce Secrets and
Lies .

            "Three
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million quid</NUMEX>," he said proudly.

            By this stage, the belle of the ball had finally arrived:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Love</ENAMEX>, who stars in The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> vs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> . At least, I think
it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Love</ENAMEX>. To be honest, she didn't look anything like the grunge
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">singer</ENAMEX> I remembered from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>. She was thinner, some of her facial features
appeared to have changed shape, her blond hair was curled, and she was wearing
a beautiful white maxi with a flowered pattern on it. I vaguely recalled
something about her appearing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vogue</ENAMEX> recently, but this was less a
fashion makeover and more a transmogrification.

            I was too frightened to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">approach Courtney</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leigh</ENAMEX> wasn't. He walked around in a circle,
inspecting her as if she were a prize steed.

            "What's this?" he asked,
pointing to a dramatic red-and-black tattoo that covered most of her right
shoulder.

            "Oh, it's from my death-rock
phase," she replied.

            The rest
of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> is something of a blur to me. At some point, my date appeared
and said it was time to go. It was almost <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>, which is considered late in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. On the way out, we passed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Medavoy</ENAMEX>. He was sitting on the
staircase with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irina</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of him and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Ormond</ENAMEX>, the beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">actress</ENAMEX>, on the other. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX> to go, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
