
   
   
      
         
            So Are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX> Still <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>?

            You read the press reports
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> about the DNA of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX>, and you quickly grasped how the new
findings suggest that this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of humanoids is much more distantly related
to modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Homo sapiens</ENAMEX> than you may have believed--they are not even direct
human ancestors. Now you must apply these findings, and examine their
implications for the world around you. Specifically, you must weigh their
effect on certain theories in circulation, among them that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX> still
walk--or lumber--among us, and indeed that they have maintained their cohesion
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX> and still constitute a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> apart. And, most importantly,
that this group of living, lumbering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>.

            You
laugh? That may be a mistake. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> working separately have
concluded precisely this: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX>. Laughing at such
ideas suggests you believe them to be absurd. But the validity of such
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theorizing</ENAMEX> is beside the point. What matters is the existence of such a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">premise</ENAMEX>, because it validates the question it seeks to answer: What explains
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>? That <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> require a meta-explanation is the problematic premise, one
that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philo-Semites</ENAMEX> have sometimes fallen for. Anyway, if you laugh at the
idea that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX>, what will you do when you learn, as you
shortly will, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are really <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> from outer space?

            Along and extraordinary history of speculation concerns the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ultimate</ENAMEX> identity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. In its course, learned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX> have repeatedly
announced they have stumbled on a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Secret</ENAMEX>, a hidden truth that explains
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> survival, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, behavior, and even the historical antipathy toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> by others. That <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Secret</ENAMEX> has often been that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are not what they seem
to be: This line of thought provides for a certain macabre entertainment, but
it is also a lesson in how the most inane ideas can have the most appalling
consequences. Here is a whirlwind tour of the field, in approximately
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chronological</ENAMEX> order.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are a Race of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lepers</ENAMEX>. An ancient argument in circulation in the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>. We know of it because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flavius Josephus</ENAMEX>, the traitorous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> general
who joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romans</ENAMEX>, bothers to refute it in his surviving writings. Josephus
attributes the argument to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manetho</ENAMEX> who, in a counter-version
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book of Exodus</ENAMEX>, asserted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hebrews</ENAMEX> weren't led out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
bondage by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>. Instead, they were an outcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of lepers, forced to
settle together, who were eventually chased out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> by patriots. The
existence of such a story is not necessarily evidence of general antipathy
toward <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>; it is a likely reflection of the long struggle between Hellenism
and the only <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mediterranean</ENAMEX> culture of consequence that held out against it,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>. The idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> lineage is impure or malevolent reappears in
Visigothic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> in the early medieval period, and most notoriously in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are a Race of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devils</ENAMEX>.
References to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of the devil or as constituting a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Synagogue of Satan</ENAMEX>" appear in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Testament</ENAMEX>, implying that they are in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">league</ENAMEX> with the devil. That they are themselves actually devils, complete with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">horns</ENAMEX>, is a folk belief that arises in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crusades</ENAMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Jewry</ENAMEX>'s problems begin in earnest. The survival of such beliefs
into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-20 th century</TIMEX> is illustrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlo Levi</ENAMEX>, an
anti-fascist <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian Jew</ENAMEX> sent into internal exile among dirt-poor southern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peasants</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. His memoir of exile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ Stopped</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eboli</ENAMEX> ,
describes an encounter with a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who refuses to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX> can
be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> because he seems to be a person much like herself. Arguments that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are a race of nefarious devils are still being published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East</ENAMEX>, and have been exhibited at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX>'s book fair.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Separate Creation</ENAMEX>. "Polygenism," the theory that God created
different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> in different acts of creation, blossomed during the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enlightenment</ENAMEX>. It was in part a "solution" to the "mystery" of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, whose startling existence seemed to require some explanation, and
whose status as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> awaited papal resolution. It was also an attempt by
early humanists to challenge clerical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>. They pointed to ambiguous
passages in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genesis</ENAMEX> that might suggest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> . Some prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of
the period saw the hope of popular redemption by supporting such notions.
However, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>-haters also saw value in the idea, because it allowed them to
regard the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> as an entirely separate species. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Poliakov</ENAMEX>
argues that the pseudoscientific foundations of racism were laid in this
debate.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inferior Race</ENAMEX>. A
still-familiar concept that arose in the wake of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">emancipation</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">19 th -century Europe</ENAMEX>, it argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> constitute a separate
racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> anthropologically inferior to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The thesis
attempted to provide a "scientific" rationale for hatred at a time when legal
restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were disappearing. A great deal of detail was presented in
support of the thesis, from relatively tiny cranial capacity to the idea of
peculiar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> feet and a peculiar <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> smell.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khazars</ENAMEX>. An idea put into circulation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Koestler</ENAMEX> in his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> work, The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thirteenth Tribe</ENAMEX> , it is now widely disseminated among
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>-haters and anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zionists</ENAMEX>. The argument is that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> have
no connection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, but are all descended from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khazars</ENAMEX>,
a once-powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turkic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who lived near the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian Sea</ENAMEX> and who are known
to have converted to Judaism in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the eighth century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koestler</ENAMEX> argued from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">circumstance</ENAMEX>, asserting that it is unclear where all the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>
came from, that the fate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khazars</ENAMEX> is unknown, and that the solution to
both problems is the same. Among the scant evidence he offered--in all
seriousness--was a chart of noses. The appeal of the argument is apparent: It
enables anti-Semites to embrace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripture</ENAMEX> and hate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> without .

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Africans</ENAMEX>. A thesis advanced
by a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, most notably, perhaps, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yosef ben-Jochannan</ENAMEX>. His
emotional book, We the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Black Jews</ENAMEX> , is printed largely in uppercase. The
central idea is that white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are all impostors, that the real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> of the
Bible exist, and that they are . Adherents of the idea draw on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> for
support, including the often-cited "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Jesus</ENAMEX>" passage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Revelations</ENAMEX>.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space Aliens</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> argued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Dem</ENAMEX> in
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Les Juifs de L'espace</ENAMEX> , this thesis holds that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are ultimately
space <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, and that that explains their, um, difficult history. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dem</ENAMEX>'s book
was part of the flood of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ancient Astronaut</ENAMEX> books inspired by the huge success
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich von Daniken</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chariots of the Gods</ENAMEX>? , and appeared here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Von Daniken</ENAMEX>, like many of his imitators, sought evidence for ancient
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visitations</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, especially in such passages as the description of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ezekial</ENAMEX>'s flying chariot. Deducing that the whole of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Testament</ENAMEX> was the
work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> is, therefore, perfectly logical.

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX>. Advanced in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX> by heretic anthropologist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Gooch</ENAMEX>, who has also argued that the
original, full-blooded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX> were telepathic. The thesis was taken up
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bradley</ENAMEX> in his incoherent book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chosen People</ENAMEX>
From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucasus</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> is known for a book-length rant titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iceman Inheritance</ENAMEX> , which identifies the origins of white racial evil in
prehistoric psychosexual tensions of some sort. Chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> is an
extension of his ideas: Biblical evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX> includes
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esau</ENAMEX> incident (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esau</ENAMEX> is hairy, remember?). The reason <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> have an
injunction against portraying God is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX> cannot draw. However,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> adduces evidence that they were quite good with numbers and were overly
sentimental about their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>. Interestingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> also believes that
modern <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khazars</ENAMEX>, which means he must argue not only that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biblical Hebrews</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX>, but that so were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khazars</ENAMEX>. He actually does
so. News that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX> have little in common with modern humankind should
be welcome to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">admirers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>'s work. Among his blurbists, by the way, is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Jeffries</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City College</ENAMEX>.

            "It is not my intention to
give anti-Semitism any support whatever," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Dem</ENAMEX>, as he argued that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> were from outer space. Certainly not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Koestler</ENAMEX> wrote the same thing
in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thirteenth Tribe</ENAMEX> , stating that if most of the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> come
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Volga</ENAMEX> region, then "anti-Semitism will become void of meaning." Sure.
We're all out here just looking for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX>. And no matter where we look for
it, over our shoulders among the hominids of prehistory, or out on the
interplanetary horizon, we can find whatever Truths we're looking for: Those
that set us free, and those that prove us mad, too.

         
      
   
