
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sore Loser</ENAMEX>

            As we all know, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> chess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. So where did he get this uncanny ability to
whine exactly like an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro athlete</ENAMEX> after an unexpected drubbing?

            "The machine's win has not
proved anything. It's not yet ready, in my opinion, to win a big contest."

            That's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX>, explaining how <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blue</ENAMEX>'s resounding victory did not really
constitute a "big" win. The rangy, big-shouldered computer prevailed in the
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous man</ENAMEX> vs. machine chess match in history--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 1/2</NUMEX> points to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 1/2</NUMEX>
points--capped by a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX>-move butt kicking that inspired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> grandmaster to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">observe</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX> got wiped off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX> reacted by reaching deep
into the sports-cliché moan bag, maintaining that he had been cheated by some
kind of backdoor playmaking help from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, that the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX> hadn't shown up at the match ("I was not in a fighting mood"), and
that his coaching had been bad ("my biggest mistake was following the advice of
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> who recommended I play this way").

            
What way? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Losingly</ENAMEX>?

            In addition, he talked about
himself in the annoying "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">third</NUMEX>-person <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX>," whimpered about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Blue</ENAMEX>'s
superior firepower (news flash, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry</ENAMEX>: the other side usually
demonstrates that when it beats you), and grumbled his way through a trash-talk
version of "wait till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>." "It [had] nothing to do [with] science," he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">whined</ENAMEX>. "It was one zeal to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Kasparov</ENAMEX>. And when a big corporation
with unlimited resources would like to do so, there are many ways to achieve
the result."

            And: "I
personally guarantee if the machine plays me again, I would tear it to
pieces."

            
As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chung-Jen Tan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep</ENAMEX>
Blue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, recognized with his overwrought For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Ages</TIMEX> rhetoric ("historically
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>, this is like landing on the moon"), the match will go down in the
permanent record of human-computer relations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX> made us all look
churlish, bratty, and just plain bad. We <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> deserved a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> at
this epochal point in our ongoing voyage of humility; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half century from now</TIMEX>,
surly, street-tough androids will routinely start bar brawls over the bitchy
tone of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX>'s remarks. Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX> had to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on the front
line--after all, he's the best human chess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> of all time. Still, he left
much to be desired in what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Deford</ENAMEX> would call "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and grace
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>."

            How
much nicer it would have been if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX> had accepted his defeat with a few
tactful words like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You de man</ENAMEX>!" or, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You de machine</ENAMEX>!"

            
If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasparov</ENAMEX> does get back onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> with
Deep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX>, he really must get it together deportmentwise. May I suggest that he
seek role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> in the world of checkers, a supremely challenging game (there
are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">500 billion billion</NUMEX> possible positions on the checkerboard) that doesn't
get the respect it deserves?

            Checkers
masters stared down their Armageddon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, when a powerful computer
program named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chinook</ENAMEX> forged a tie with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-best checkers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the
world, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Lafferty</ENAMEX>. A weaker version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinook</ENAMEX> had previously lost to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">legendary Marion Tinsley</ENAMEX>, a retired university math <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> considered the
greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">checkers player</ENAMEX> of all time, who had to withdraw from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> rematch
because of the pancreatic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> that eventually killed him. Lafferty bravely
stepped in and duked out a record of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1-1-18</ENAMEX>. No clear decision.

            
What really matters, though, is that neither
man resorted to in-your-face woo-woos or bitching, though in this case, sassy
talk from the other side probably warranted retaliation. ("The computer
gets smarter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Schaeffer</ENAMEX>, who led the team
that programmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chinook</ENAMEX>, "and human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinsley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lafferty</ENAMEX> just
get older.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinsley</ENAMEX> credited God for his abilities, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lafferty</ENAMEX> reacted to
the tie with the same sort of aplomb that, it's safe to say, he would have
displayed if he'd lost.

            "It put a lot of strain on
me," he admitted, making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinook</ENAMEX> sound not like a machine but like a grizzled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> who deserved respect, even affection. "It's nearly got human
capabilities now. ... But I like this machine. I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and computers are
compatible."

         
      
   
