
   
   
      
         
            I Was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teen-Ager</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>

            There is a gruesome <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> story, called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Survivor Type</ENAMEX>," in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>-addicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> marooned
on a desert island successively amputates each of his limbs in order to
survive. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horrid</ENAMEX> last line: "tastes like ladyfingers ...") This story always
reminds me of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX>. Ever since she turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>
has been selling off tiny portions of her life, and successfully enough to make
many of us envious. Her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> coup was perhaps her greatest: the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1972 New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> Magazine cover story that set a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>'s teeth on edge,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Looking Back: An Eighteen Year Old Reflects on Life</ENAMEX>." (Horrid topic sentence:
"My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> is special because of what we missed rather than what we got,
because in a certain sense we are the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and the last.")

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> unpacked what would prove to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>'s life baggage: a chirpy,
articulate writing style; a weather eye for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> shifts; and a
narcissistic obsession with herself. Enthralled by celebrity culture, enthroned
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , for the past quarter-century she has worked "as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> on my life's beat." From "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Embarrassment of Virginity</ENAMEX>"
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mademoiselle</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>) to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Changing My Breast Size ... Again</ENAMEX>"
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), she has hacked her way through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three decades</TIMEX> wrapped in a
delusion torn from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Sacks</ENAMEX> casebook: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Woman Who Mistook Herself for</ENAMEX>
Someone Interesting. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Millennium and Me</ENAMEX>"? I'm sure the rough draft is
sitting in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>'s laptop.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> recently announced that she will be looking back
again, this time at her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine-month</TIMEX> love affair with reclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">writer J.D. Salinger</ENAMEX>. Her announcement, prompted by the untimely leak of her
book proposal, came as a surprise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> story was always <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>'s
literary high ground, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> piece of integrity not included in the ongoing
fire sale of her life experiences. It was a story she had promised repeatedly
not to tell. "I will always respect his privacy," she told an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. "I made that promise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX>." When a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> biographer
approached her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, she hung up on him.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> story resembles the "ladyfingers" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> tale. It was the
last item on the shelf. Everything else has already been shipped out. The late
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> went to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Looking Back</ENAMEX>," which was expanded into a book. She told the
story of the halcyon years of her marriage in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s books and in a
syndicated newspaper column. Her divorce, which was not amicable, proved to be
edgy fodder for copy. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> canceled her column, which later
morphed into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>-only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX> called Domestic

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX> . "It's a publication unlike any other I've seen," says ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX>, "full of very honest writing by me and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
subscribe, who send me extraordinarily moving letters about their own
lives."

            
After her marriage folded, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> started
merchandising ghoulish, oddball dating stories, some of them prompted by this
personal ad she placed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>: "The truth is I'm gorgeous,
slender, talented, and passionate. My academic credentials and creative
achievements are impeccable." There's some fiction here: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> dropped out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> before collecting her impeccable academic credentials. But also some
truth: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> was an extraordinarily attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Before the breast
implants, that is.

            

               Now we're talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>. In a desperate commingling of
self-abasement and self-interest rivaled only by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathryn Harrison</ENAMEX>'s memoir of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>-licking her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> sold the story of her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> breast-augmentation
surgery to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. Well, OK. The problem was, the new boobs were
too big: "My breasts were a size <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>, D cup," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> wrote. They "stood out like
a pair of headlights." So what does a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl journalist</ENAMEX> do? Whip out the
notebook! Declaring herself to be a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> investigating the world of
big-breasted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> belched forth a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,500</NUMEX>-word screed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Self</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>, reporting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">implants</ENAMEX>' removal . Someone floated the
notion that post-op <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> might pose topless for the photo spread. Instead, she
is seen grasping the silicone sacs in two separate full-page photos, one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">captioned</ENAMEX>, "The nostalgic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> holds on to her old implants."

            Oddly, none of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">adventures crops</ENAMEX> up in the recent
advertising campaign for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Scholastic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, which features <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> as a
poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> for youth literacy. Nor are they to be found on her astonishing
Calling-All-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lonelyhearts</ENAMEX> Web site (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">joycemaynard</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>), where one can buy
past books, a package of the famous divorce columns and, of course, subscribe
to the Domestic 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX> newsletter. Lately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> has been
posting tales of her recent move to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay Area</ENAMEX> and commenting upon the dating
habits of the few other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Type A</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> in laid-back <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Marin County</ENAMEX>.

            It was on
the Web site that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> first informed her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> that she would "tell a story
I've never told before"--about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cynic</ENAMEX> might suggest that by
heretofore honoring the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>'s privacy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> has shrewdly
protected her investment. The literary marketplace has assigned a huge premium
to true-life tales of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Pynchon</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>
who quit the publicity mainstream <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who has seen her book
proposal reports that it is classic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>: gossipy, un-prudish, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-indulgent</ENAMEX>, with very little information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>'s literary
pursuits. (But we do learn that he is into homeopathy.) Small matter that one
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> has branded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>'s project "unconscionable." The wheels
of commerce--sorry, literature--are a-turning.

            
With Joycean aplomb, my former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> is
looking to score a twofer. Not only will her book generate interest among lit
types, but she is also aiming for the vast, self-regarding "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.
That's right--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> now sees herself as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>'s romantic
intrigue. Sparring with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> at her Web site, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce styled</ENAMEX> herself "a woman
sought out at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> 35 years her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senior</ENAMEX>, who promised to love her forever
and asked her to forswear all else to come and live with him," blah blah blah.
This represents a turnaround from previous characterizations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interlude</ENAMEX>: "After I left [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>], it seemed like I'd been in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">'Lost Horizon</ENAMEX>,'
" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. "There was no place on
earth for me to go."

            But contradictions abound in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>'s latest outing. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks ago</TIMEX>, she informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
that she decided to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> story now because her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> recently
turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. That was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>'s age when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D.</ENAMEX> summoned her to his <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">hilltop</ENAMEX> aerie in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.H.</ENAMEX> Yet when I sought her out for comment shortly before she
concocted her sob story for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> told me she whipped up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX> submission to fulfill a contractual obligation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin's</ENAMEX>. And
she complained about the size of the advance.

            Forced by a cruel publishing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> to give up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">her last</NUMEX>, cherished family jewel at a fire-sale price. Doesn't
that just say everything about the times we live in? I think there's a piece
there, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
