
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slates Man</ENAMEX>

            I was on the up escalator,
rising into the perfumed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">precincts</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordstrom</ENAMEX>
department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> City <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>, when a tall, shapely black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 39 years of age</TIMEX>, sashayed past and settled in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> steps above
me. From the heterosexual-male perspective, the view was outstanding: a fine
female rump in tight velvet pants, shifting around slightly somewhere north of
eye level.

            Until that moment, I had
been feeling like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> magazine kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. My pants were slate-colored, my
jacket a charcoal that certainly qualified as the same. I had absorbed the
wisdom of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dialogists</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Taylor Jr.</ENAMEX> on the
subtleties of contemporary sexual-harassment law. (Thus I chastely averted my
eyes from the behind ahead of me.) I had balanced my budget following the
recommendations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>. I had slaked my thirst for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> news by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reading Harry Shearer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gist</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX> was that I was above <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Fray</ENAMEX>. My
tabula was rasa .

            All I
needed to round out my sartorial and spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slateness</ENAMEX>, I knew, was a good
pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slates TM</ENAMEX> . The latter refers, of course, to a line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s
pants sold by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi Strauss</ENAMEX> to leading department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> everywhere.

            My search had begun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hecht's</ENAMEX> in downtown
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C. Navigating</ENAMEX> through brightly colored racks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX>
gear and a bold display of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Timberland boots</ENAMEX>, I had been distracted by a drab
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">blot</ENAMEX> to the right of the aisle. There stood a table covered with stacks of
folded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s slacks, uninspiring in color, dubious in cut. I slowed to browse:
first, a mound of sand-colored leggings and a veritable <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX> of dull
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forest</ENAMEX>-green numbers; nearby, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> racks of gray garments hanging limply beneath
a sign that said "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$58</NUMEX>." "Slates," the little promotional poster announced.
"These are those pants."

            This
stupid tautology bugged me immediately--but then stupid tautologies are the
hallmark of criminal regimes and successful ad campaigns everywhere ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> is
It," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>," etc.), so I checked my annoyance. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell Slates</ENAMEX> are so dumb and I'm so smart, how come I ain't rich like them? I
fingered the fabric and looked for a pair in my size (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> waist, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> inseam).
Some were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> worsted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX>--but who wants to wear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>? A
stack of gabardines would have made a fine cover for a motel love seat, but
they seemed out of place on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. And then there was the rack of bottoms
made of something billed as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Microfiber</ENAMEX>."

            
What is it about modern life (I wondered idly)
that makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> want to celebrate and sell its micro-ness? Especially
when the label in the waistband reveals that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Microfiber</ENAMEX>" is another way of
saying "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> Dacron."

            Then it dawned on me: What
if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slateness</ENAMEX>, as embodied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and the pants, wasn't as cool as I
was assuming? What if it wasn't cool at all? For all I knew, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slate</ENAMEX>" was
actually insider's lingo for a certain market niche--my market
niche!--comprising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who have gained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> pounds since high school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who
know their way around a search engine but, what with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and the child
support and the gas bills and all those <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, lack the loose
dollars and idle time that can buy true <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> style.

            Suddenly, I was face to face
with one of the recurring nightmares of bourgeois life. I was caught in one of
those waking dreams in which you understand full well that your individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tastes</ENAMEX>, carefully nurtured and developed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decades</TIMEX>, have in fact been
anticipated, designed, and shaped by others every step of the way. My search
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slates</ENAMEX>, apparently an act of free will, was but a pawn's move in the great
game of advertising played by casually superior types on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Avenue</ENAMEX> and in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> (and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wash.</ENAMEX>!) for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion-dollar</NUMEX> stakes in which I would
never share.

            Thus the
Slate mind pierces the false consciousness of late capitalism. Your vaunted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">individuality</ENAMEX> is exposed as nothing but a pixel in the big picture of the money
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>. But you do get a prize, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. You get to wear <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Dacron</ENAMEX>!

            Bitterly, I toted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pairs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slates</ENAMEX> to the dressing
room, vowing never again to subscribe to an online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, even one that
doesn't charge. There in the privacy of the changing room I understood that the
erotic subtext of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slates</ENAMEX>--the pants--was that there is no erotic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">subtext</ENAMEX>. While much of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s clothing is designed to send out a
complex code of sexual and social signals, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slates</ENAMEX>, true to their name, are
blank. You mean you want to slip into something that might attract the
attention and admiration of a fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mammal</ENAMEX>? These are not those
pants.

            The sole and grudging
concession that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slates</ENAMEX> make to male vanity is pleats. Now, I like pleats, and I
was consoled briefly in the changing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> by the thought that this subtlest of
fashion statements was all that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> needed. I tried on the gray
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microfiber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>, waist size <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX>. I checked the mirror: not bad. I emerged to
ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> if he thought the pleats were pulling too much. He was amused
by my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Slateness</ENAMEX>.

            "Try a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX>," he said.

            
The humiliation caused by his unkind smile
persisted for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours</TIMEX>. Not until that supremely attractive female butt crossed
my radar in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordstrom</ENAMEX> did I start to feel better. And no sooner had I begun to
enjoy my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slateness</ENAMEX> than glorious erotic opportunity went a-glimmering. At the
top of the escalator, the phat lady made a sharp left into a silky hedge of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Claiborne</ENAMEX> blouses to confer with a salesclerk. I wanted to follow her asking
playful questions. Instead I turned right, toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, still
searching for those pants.

            Truth be told, it was not
all that hard to come to terms with the unbearable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slateness</ENAMEX> of being. I had to
admit that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slates</ENAMEX>, although perhaps overpriced and ugly, were not altogether
inappropriate for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> like me. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pleats</ENAMEX> do pull. My prosperous ass is
too big for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dockers</ENAMEX> and too wise to try to fake the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">funk à la Tommy Hilfiger</ENAMEX>.
Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> too good for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dacron</ENAMEX>? Not at all. I marched up to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">salesgirl</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and inquired if she had any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slates</ENAMEX>.

            She looked at me--no other
word will do--blankly.

            "They're a line of pants
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Levis</ENAMEX>," I stammered.

            "Oh, we do not carry any
Levis," she said emphatically. "Never have." She smiled and produced a small
piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX>. "Want one?"

            I popped
that caramel <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">treat</ENAMEX> into my mouth and looked into her pretty eyes. Such
exquisitely miniaturized and stylized sexual situations (it occurred to me)
were the reward, the glory, of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. Thus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> mind grasps the
unfolding rationality of hedonistic capitalism: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Microfiber</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsex</ENAMEX>.

            The salesgirl directed me (still sucking gratefully on her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">micro</ENAMEX>-gift) onward to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macy's</ENAMEX> at the other end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX>. Here the lights
were brighter, the music a wee bit louder, and the tease of pleasurable
consumption a bit less subtle and a bit more fetishistic, though no less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pleasurable</ENAMEX>. The makeup counter was lined with female forms: an older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> painting the wide-open eyes of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX>; a white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and a pink <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and a brown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> crowding around the eyeliner counter,
avidly seeking their "one true color" amid the promiscuous riot of magenta,
peach, chartreuse, fuchsia, and mauve. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Undistracted</ENAMEX> in this brothel of platonic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indulgence</ENAMEX>, I went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and found another salesclerk. She
had a mustache, the cultural significance of which completely confounded the
Slate mind.

            "Do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slates?</ENAMEX>" I asked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weakly</ENAMEX>. "The pants."

            "Slates? No," she replied.
"We have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savanes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dockers</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Club Internationals</ENAMEX> on this side.
But no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slates</ENAMEX>. Maybe you should look down there." She helpfully pointed to a
corner lined with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s suits.

            There it
was again, an island of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slates</ENAMEX>, dull as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> but not as cheap: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pairs for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>. I quickly snatched up a bunch of size 40s before any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salespeople</ENAMEX>
could get close to me, and headed toward the changing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.

            
The fit was nice and loose, the way my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
likes it. The pleats were pleasing. Checking myself out in the dressing-room
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mirror</ENAMEX>, I realized that in these pants, I would never again be fearful of that
other nightmare of bourgeois life, the moment in which you sense that your
middle-class prosperity, your high-tech skills, your credit cards, and the
advertising industry all give you license to slough off your work ethic, relax
your discipline, and lower your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> knows the cultural
contradictions of capitalism. He lives them, wears them, and so is proofed
against the temptation to follow the (logical) sequel to bourgeois success--the
urge to abandon the self-denial that made it all possible, to mock your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and spurn your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>, to return no e-mail, to call in sick from the
beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, to drink <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>, to watch porno movies in
bed with ironic comp-lit graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, and to vanish for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> on end in
pursuit of un-bourgeois happiness.

            No, my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Slates</ENAMEX> reassured me.
I would do none of those things, and I would be no less delighted and content
for not doing them.

            The only problem was that my
pleats were still pulling. I noticed that I had brought in a size <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX>. I can't
be that big, I thought, picking up the pants. (Thus the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> corrects
the error of his ways.) I tried them on. Tucked in a wee bit at the waist, they
fit me perfectly.

         
      
   
