
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Temptation of Bob Dole</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is sorely tempted to
forget everything he knows about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> tax cuts. Here's a reminder.

            
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1648</NUMEX> words, plus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">links</ENAMEX>)
            

            
               By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie T.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
            

            All his career, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>
has stood for fiscal conservatism and balanced budgets. Most famously, he was
almost alone among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in his caustic skepticism about the
supply-side economics of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. Now, political and economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> are
urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> to take off his green eyeshade,
push aside that unappetizing bowl of budget cuts, and scarf down a tasty dose
of tax-cut rejuvenator. Just the tonic for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anemic</ENAMEX> poll numbers. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> is
tempted. He reportedly will endorse some kind of broad-based tax cut in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>.

            Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> know
better. But like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>, they are tempted, too. A persistent majority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> piously tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pollsters</ENAMEX> that budget-deficit reduction is more
important than tax cuts. "Yet," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosworth</ENAMEX>, "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> clearly believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are lying--and the
election results tend to support the fact that they are lying. When they
vote, they want a tax cut."

            Of course, nobody is out
there urging tax cuts instead of deficit reduction. And certainly no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enthusiast</ENAMEX> is presenting tax cuts as a deficit booster . On the other
hand, few (outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page) are still
brash enough to claim that tax cuts could actually raise tax revenues. Many
"old school" supply-side <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of</ENAMEX>
Economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advisers chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Feldstein</ENAMEX>, never did endorse the so-called
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laffer Curve</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocktail</ENAMEX>-napkin art purporting to show that big tax cuts
would soon pay for themselves. The "loose talk of the supply-side <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX>
gave fundamentally good policies a bad name," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldstein</ENAMEX> complained in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>.

            Now,
though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldstein</ENAMEX> is reported to be among a group of well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>
urging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> to adopt a so-called "pro-growth" tax strategy, meaning substantial
tax cuts. How they are to be paid for is unclear. The promise of painless
redemption is there--if not quite explicit. But, unlike the last time we had
this argument, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, there is the record of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> to show what happens
when the supply-siders get their way.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer Abraham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mich.</ENAMEX>, is an ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of a
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15-percent</NUMEX> across-the-board cut in tax rates. "Can we reconcile the seemingly
contradictory notions of cutting tax rates and balancing the budget?" he asked
in (where else?) a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>. "The answer
is yes," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> revealed, if only we ignore the claims of "conventional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thinkers</ENAMEX>" and focus instead on the fact that "from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982 to 1989</TIMEX>, federal
revenues, adjusted for inflation, expanded by an average of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.8 percent</NUMEX> per
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> despite a sharp reduction in tax rates."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham</ENAMEX> picked his years
with care. Shortly after passage of the supposedly rejuvenating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> tax cut
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy plunged into the deepest economic downturn since the
Great <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years 1982 through 1989</TIMEX> cover the recovery period from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pit</ENAMEX> of that recession to the beginning of the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. If you believe that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX> tax cut was responsible for all those growth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--that
otherwise we would have wallowed in stagnation for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX>'s
choice may be fair enough. If you doubt it, you might prefer the traditional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>' method of measuring long-term trends from equivalent places in the
business cycle.

            Even so, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX>'s
trough-to-peak comparison does not support his point. Official budget numbers
do show total federal revenue growing at an inflation-adjusted rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.1</NUMEX>
percent over the period, reasonably close to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.8</NUMEX>. But the components
of that growth tell the real story. Individual income taxes--which, by
supply-side theory, should have spurted since rates were cut--grew at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2.1-percent</NUMEX> rate. What boosted federal revenues most was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.3</NUMEX>-percent
average growth in payroll taxes. This was mainly the result of rate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hikes</ENAMEX>-- not cuts--legislated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security Reform</ENAMEX> act of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>.

            Corporate taxes also were
cut substantially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. Corporate-tax revenues took a nose dive in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, regained some ground with the economic recovery, but then surged
following passage of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> tax reform--which deliberately raised taxes on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> to pay for tax breaks for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.

            A
"conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>" might be forgiven for concluding from this record that
what raises revenues is raising taxes, not cutting them.

            The campaign to convert <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>, and to prepare the public
for his imminent conversion, is resurrecting many golden-oldie rhetorical
points from circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX> asserts that marginal tax rates
are what determine "whether a worker works <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overtime</TIMEX> or goes home for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
... whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> save and invest their income or spend it." No question,
taxes can affect behavior. Reducing very high tax rates can, at the very least,
encourage less tax evasion and avoidance. And restructuring taxes should, at
least in theory, encourage desirable types of economic behavior such as hard
work, saving, and investment.

            But cultural attitudes,
not taxes or other government policies, tend to swamp all other explanatory
variables in international comparisons of savings and investment. This is
especially so in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, where tax rates are low by international
standards. So how much do tax rates matter? Not a whole lot, if the Reagan-era
experience is any guide.

            Even by the supply-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siders</ENAMEX>'
own calculations, any offsetting behavioral response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> tax cuts was
swamped by the direct revenue loss to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>. For example, at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan Institute</ENAMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence B. Lindsey</ENAMEX>, a leading supply-side
flag-waver in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX> (now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve</ENAMEX>) whipped out a graph (see above/below) to show that tax revenues in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $13 billion</NUMEX> higher than would have been predicted by "static"
revenue models used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1981</TIMEX> tax-cut
debate. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Static</ENAMEX>" is the supply-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siders</ENAMEX>' pejorative term for thinking that
doesn't acknowledge sufficiently the explosive power of tax cuts.) What didn't
seem to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX>'s attention in his own graph was that actual revenues
were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $100 billion</NUMEX> lower in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> than they would have been if the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>
tax cut had not been passed. [NOTE: JODIE HAS SUPPLIED this graph]

            As for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working harder because of lower tax rates, the record of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> is
more complex than supply-side rhetoric predicted. Studying the effects of 1980s
tax policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosworth</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Burtless</ENAMEX> found that only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>--high-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--substantially increased their <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of work in
response to lower taxes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> whose work effort increased most
sharply was not the well-paid, whose tax rates declined most sharply. It was
the poorly paid, whose marginal tax rates, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> tax hikes,
actually went up. For these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, higher taxes prompted harder work to make
up for the lost income.

            Even more damaging to the supply-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siders</ENAMEX>' case was the
disappointing performance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s savings behavior. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> program
provided numerous inducements: not just marginal rate cuts on income but
capital-gains tax reductions, a variety of new tax-exempt investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX>,
vast new opportunities for tax sheltering--plus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX>'s tight
money policies which, along with financial deregulation, sent the interest
rates available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savers</ENAMEX> soaring. The more sober-minded supply<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-siders</ENAMEX> figured
that even if the tax cuts didn't pay for themselves, the increased savings they
generated would make the resulting deficits easy to finance. (Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldstein</ENAMEX> says he still believes that while it's a "tall order," the right tax
cuts can, "in some cases," raise saving by more than they raise the budget
deficit.)

            But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, savings
did not cooperate. The national savings rate, which ran at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">close to 12</NUMEX> percent
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 9 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX>, sank to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5.8 percent</NUMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>. The swelling government deficit, which amounts to national
dis saving, did much to drag down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> figure. But even private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> ran well below their 1970s level.

            Still more perverse was
the behavior of business investment. During the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> of the
business-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, business-equipment investment rose at
an inflation-adjusted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 4.4 percent</NUMEX> while corporate
before-tax profits grew at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.7 percent</NUMEX>. By contrast, during the presumably
hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, business investment has grown at an annual real rate of
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10.6 percent</NUMEX> while corporate pre-tax profits have climbed at a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13.2</NUMEX>-percent
rate.

            The
overall national economic growth rate has been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 0.8</NUMEX> percentage points
lower under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> than under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. But, amusingly, that difference is
totally accounted for by the shrinking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. While government spending
grew by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">an average 3.6 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, it has
shrunk at a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4.1-percent</NUMEX> rate under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The way national economic
growth is calculated, the expansion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> adds to his
growth total, while the contraction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> reduces his
growth total.

            In addition to supply-side arguments, there are the
traditional demand-side arguments that a tax cut stimulates the economy by
pouring more money into it. But this would be a very odd time for a demand-side
tax cut. As former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Reischauer</ENAMEX>
notes: With unemployment well below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> average and considerably lower
labor-force growth, the economy seems to be operating near capacity--"or, at
least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> thinks it is, which is what counts." Any
deficit-increasing tax cut would surely prompt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> to tighten the money
supply, curbing economic growth or even prompting a recession.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> could, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counsels</ENAMEX>, offset part of the costs of a tax-rate cut by dumping other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tax-reform</ENAMEX> plans--such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> tax credit, once a key feature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s
"pro-family" agenda. What would the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> think about that? Or,
he could propose to cut spending even more than his party has already
promised--but that sounds like spinach, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> seems to have lost its
appetite for even the healthy serving it has promised to serve up over the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>.

            Or, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>
could resist temptation. After all, he really does know better.

         
      
   
