
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiritual Opium</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. Did you know that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> leads the world in per capita consumption of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oranges</ENAMEX>? That it has the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s biggest neon sign, is home to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> of the world's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> busiest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>,
and boasts the world's highest number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolls-Royces</ENAMEX> relative to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>?

            If you
didn't, you will. Well in advance of the mobs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>, film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX>, radio disc <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jockeys</ENAMEX>, news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> now descending on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> to cover the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX> transfer of power--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,400</NUMEX> at last count--the
press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handlers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wisely assembled mounds of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prepackaged</ENAMEX> material. The result: a journalistic <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Gresham's law</ENAMEX>, whereby hard
news is driven out by the sheer volume of fluff and clichés. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , for
example, not only availed itself of much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> bumph in its
special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> issue, but also added fun facts of its own (e.g., "most
breathtaking bathroom view"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> trotted out not one but two
illustrations of old opium <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>. And TV-network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> have been parked
beside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>'s flagpoles, waiting to stock up on footage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
standard being lowered against a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk</TIMEX>-lit sky.

            Still, the arrival of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspeople</ENAMEX> has not been
without its headaches for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s business and political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishments</ENAMEX>.
They are now complaining about negative coverage that focuses on disputes over
the electoral arrangements for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> and the fate of civil
rights. That is only to be expected, inasmuch as most of the aforementioned
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> are interviewing the same <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--democrats
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Lee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Lau</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Loh</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s wheelers and dealers
should consider themselves fortunate. Because if the press ever did decide to
move seriously past politics, it would discover that the real threat to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX>'s future may have as much to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese-style</ENAMEX> capitalism as with
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese-style</ENAMEX> communism.

            That
threat arises from the blurring of lines between the kind of pro-business
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">regimes</ENAMEX> (with all the attendant corruption) that characterize the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asia</ENAMEX>
and the pro-market <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> that has distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> until now. When Gov.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Patten</ENAMEX>, who himself comes from the "wet" side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fence</ENAMEX>, sharply
increased social spending in his budgets, the business community thundered
(rightly, I happen to think) that the proposals had been introduced with scant
regard for long-term implications. Mainland <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were livid, seeing the
initiatives as a last-minute <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> effort to rob the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> of its riches
by saddling it with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> welfare system. "Spiritual opium," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>
called it.

            
Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champions</ENAMEX> of laissez faire and
low government spending have been curiously silent in response to the new
signals coming from the top. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just the other day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Executive-designate</ENAMEX> Tung
Chee-hwa--who will take over from <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Patten</ENAMEX> come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>--sent a very loud official
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> by declaring that "a noninterference policy would not meet the needs and
strengthen the competitiveness" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. The remarks echo a
similar speech <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tung</ENAMEX> made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>
in favor of a "new industrial direction" that would look more kindly upon state
subsidies for preferred businesses.

            In this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tung</ENAMEX> has been supported by a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX>, many of
whom oddly--and despite their success--see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> as a better model for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. Were the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legions</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to look as closely at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tung</ENAMEX>'s
business as they do his politics, moreover, they might discover that he is
closer to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> chaebol chieftain than to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>.
Not only does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tung</ENAMEX>'s container-shipping line operate within a cartel market
where routes and quotas are routinely carved out, but it was bailed out, as he
acknowledged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> when on the brink of
bankruptcy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tung</ENAMEX>'s fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessmen</ENAMEX> have not been shy about taking
him up on his new offer. Just recently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Herald Tribune</ENAMEX>
carried an alarming piece in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Tang</ENAMEX>, a prominent local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industrialist</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tung</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>, suggested tapping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s considerable
foreign exchange (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">some $69 billion</NUMEX> in reserves, plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">another $22 billion</NUMEX> in a
special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> from land sales) to develop southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. Given that there is no
genuine infrastructure need for which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> could not easily find private
sourcing--of which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> accounts for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>'s share--the suggestion by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> to raid the reserves is a virtual invitation for scam and graft.
"It's why I always told the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> to oppose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provident Fund</ENAMEX> [a
government pension scheme]," says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX>'s oldest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hongs</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> are still called here). "You put a pile of money out
there and there's every chance it will end up in some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam</ENAMEX>."

            And
raiding of the reserves is only one worry. Although hailed by no less than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX> as the world's most open economy, colonial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> has
retained many notable exceptions to the rule, exceptions that may prove more
costly after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>. The banking industry, for example, is run by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cartel</ENAMEX> that
until recently fixed interest rates every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. The same insulation from
market <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> prevails elsewhere in the non-traded sector. Even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>,
everything from legal and medical services to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utilities</ENAMEX> is almost
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">immune</ENAMEX> from market competition thought good for everyone else. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About a year</TIMEX> ago
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathay Pacific</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Sutch</ENAMEX>, defended such arrangements, saying
that "unfettered competition" would destroy the "stability" of the market.

            
Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years or so</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
interests have been buying into these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, usually at a substantial
discount to the market. This is not simply a matter of substituting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> for
British vested interests. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> vested interests didn't
also regulate their own industries, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> frequently do.
For another, mainland-connected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> generally are able to buy in at much
better terms than anyone else--certainly at terms better than their balance
sheets suggest they deserve. And so the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> we have on the eve of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">handover</ENAMEX> is one where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Lai</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next Group</ENAMEX>--the most popular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> media
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>--cannot find an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">underwriter</ENAMEX> to take it public. Yet when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beijing Enterprises</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with nothing to show but its connection as the
investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, made an initial public offering
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 1,300</NUMEX> applications for each available
share.

            None of this means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kong</ENAMEX> is about to go bust. So long as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> continues to develop, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> will
get a substantial chunk of that growth. But the market has clearly signaled a
future in which guanxi , or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX>, will count as much as
traditional pluck and enterprise. Such an outcome invites an irony that would
be appreciated as much by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX> as by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Smith</ENAMEX>: that the same businesses
whose investments have done so much to undermine communism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> may be
responsible for bringing down capitalism in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
