
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Suburbs Have Won</ENAMEX>

            The great movement of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20 th century</TIMEX> has been from the countryside and
small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> into big metropolitan areas. But within metropolitan areas the
movement has been outward, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> to the suburbs. The next census, in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, will show that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>-suburban: Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, that is, now live in metropolitan areas but outside the city
limits.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
is the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> by a wide margin, and it is the most urban
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--but don't let that deceive you. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seventy</TIMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>
live in the suburbs. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> has been majority-suburban for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, since
before there was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levittown</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> or Please Don't Eat the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daisies</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> suburbanite.

            The suburbs dominate popular culture. The default setting
for movies, television shows, and even rock music is the suburbs. Anything with
an urban or a rural setting is self-consciously played as "different." The
suburbs dominate politics, especially national politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> is the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. Every presidential campaign is now
conceived of by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> as a battle for the soul of the suburbs. (The
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>-suburban <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as a
whole did.) The dominant political machine in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is a suburban <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D'Amato</ENAMEX>'s.

            Forget every Sunday-newspaper
trend story you've ever read about gentrification, or about harried
metropolitans fleeing to small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, or about good-hearted buppies returning
to the 'hood. Those are statistical blips, or anecdotes, or fantasies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is still losing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural America</ENAMEX> is still losing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are suburbanizing faster than white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The suburbs are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unstoppable</ENAMEX>, inescapable.

            It is
still possible to hear the suburbs described, especially by professional city
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planners</ENAMEX> and other urbanologists, as a kind of temporary and revocable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aberration</ENAMEX>. You know the argument: They were subsidized by the federal
government through the interstate-highway program and cheap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans</ENAMEX>
Administration mortgages. They were forced upon <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> by a road-crazy,
mass-transit-hating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Moses</ENAMEX>. Their growth was a pure product of race
prejudice. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX>, are poised, ready,
waiting, eager to move back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, if only ... I'm sorry. Forget about
it. The main reason for the growth of the suburbs is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> like
suburbs. They like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. They like <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX>. They like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. Most low-income
city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would move to the suburbs if they could. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> commitment to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urbanism</ENAMEX> has never existed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>--even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, which seems
more urban than it really is because it annexed most of its suburbs (that is,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Staten Island</ENAMEX>) long ago. What's remarkable
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s suburbs is not their demographic success--that's a
characteristic of all suburbs--but their cultural failure. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> has the
most out-of-it, least happening suburbs of any big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.

            
Only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> has no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> with an essentially
yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>--by which I mean dotted with little strip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> containing,
perhaps, one or two casually chic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Starbucks</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Borders</ENAMEX>, an
upscale food market, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art gallery</ENAMEX>, a Merchant-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX>-type movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX>, and a
mildly stylish home-furnishings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shaker Heights</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX>, have far more of a patina of sophistication than any New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> also doesn't have a
full-blown suburban-nirvana "edge city" suburb, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tysons Corner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>--the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> that has shiny,
enormous <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> and "totally planned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>" with spindly little <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and
curving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and thatchy English names.

            
Meanwhile, a truly hip <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> (no, that's not oxymoronic--go visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Lake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hills</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Topanga</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>), where there would be leaflets
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stapled</ENAMEX> to the telephone poles and vegetarian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and rave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, is
completely out of the question in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where there
is still a total overlap between "downtown" and "bohemian." It's the only city
where the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is still the center not just of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">metropolis</ENAMEX>'s official
high culture but of its everyday culture too.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westchester County</ENAMEX>, where I live, is suburbia set in amber.
Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has barely fluctuated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>. You like
prewar <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>? Virtually the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westchester</ENAMEX> below <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interstate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">287</ENAMEX> is prewar <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>--it could be a movie set. There are very few <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>.
Superstores are just starting. There is ethnicity. There are <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">country clubs</ENAMEX>--the
old undemocratic kind, not the new kind that are essentially outdoor health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clubs</ENAMEX>. The expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> still serve "continental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cuisine</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> are all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> with sidewalked main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> containing rows of
brick <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>: just what brave suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sun Belt</ENAMEX> are
struggling desperately to coax into existence.

            Life
revolves around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. If you lead any kind of "alternative lifestyle," you
will be left <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">blessedly</ENAMEX> alone, rather than being ostracized, but you won't find
much in the way of an affinity culture. At dinner parties, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> argue whether
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who wrote "bitch" on a toilet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stall</ENAMEX> in the middle-school bathroom
should be expelled. My <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pelham</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Westchester</ENAMEX>'s alleged literary-media
colony, but I have never been to a single social event here where a hothouse
conversation about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry</ENAMEX> could be sustained for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than about half</NUMEX> an
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX> before it slowly flutters back to home ground: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
(Yes, this was the case even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pelhamite Joe Klein</ENAMEX> was unmasked as
the author of Primary 
               Colors .)

            
Virtually all the cultural imagery pertaining
to Westchester dates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man in the Gray Flannel Suit</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>, and is now out of date. But nothing has replaced it. Martinis, barbecues,
cigarettes, adultery--all are now vestigial, but where are the new suburban
symbolic hooks?

            Back in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1950s</NUMEX>, twin colossi sat astride the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>, figuratively glowering at each
other: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Friedan</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grandview</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX>, writing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Feminine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mystique</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cheever</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scarborough</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Bank</ENAMEX>, writing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wapshot</ENAMEX> books and the short stories. She, upset about the limited role accorded
educated upper-middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; he, upset about how little comfort the
unlimited role accorded upper-middle-class male <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Episcopalians</ENAMEX> seemed to bring.
Since then at least one monumental social change has swept across
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suburbia</ENAMEX>--namely the entry of married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX>--without
generating a literature. The best <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Westchester</ENAMEX> novel of the past
quarter-century, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.L. Doctorow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragtime</ENAMEX> , is set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>.

            When I moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kept pulling me
aside and saying, helpfully, that my life would be completely ruined if I chose
to live in the suburbs (or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>). All my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who had grown up in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organic New York</ENAMEX> suburbs had, at some point around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 14</TIMEX>, taken a blood oath
never ever to live in the suburbs as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who did move to the suburbs
had to obey an unwritten conversational rule that you had to justify it in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stagy</ENAMEX> and fake terms, either by exaggerating the hellishness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or by pretending that the suburbs were really not that far away and
had lots of great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> groceries. I felt as if I had wandered in in the
middle of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> act--why did it make such a big difference? What had
happened to all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> that was so horrifying?

            I now
realize that what all this was really about was, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, the extreme difference
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> between suburban and urban culture (which doesn't exist in most
other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> because they don't really have an urban culture for middle-class
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> any more); and, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, status. The status point is a tricky <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. In
the minor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX> of status, where most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> play, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is for the poor
and the suburbs are for the rich, so to move out to the suburbs is to move up
as well. But in the major leagues of status, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> outranks the suburbs. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is where the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> live. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is for the aristocracy, and the
suburbs are for the bourgeoisie.

            
In the major leagues, when you live in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suburbs</ENAMEX>, it means that you haven't made it enough to afford the basic setup of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co-op</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>-private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. Or it means that you're not New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX>-savvy enough to be able to arrange for yourself one of those special
little deals the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is full of, such as, mainly, a rent-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>.
Or it means that you're not artful enough to be able to live charmingly as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bohemian</ENAMEX>. If you have major-league aspirations and can't manage to live in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, you're better off moving out past the suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Zone of Shame</ENAMEX> and living
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full time</TIMEX> in the kind of lovely small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaguers</ENAMEX> spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX>. At least then you're plausibly rustic and creative.

            When I'm off the Eastern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seaboard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ask me where I'm from, I say "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>." When closer to
home I have to answer in apologetic question-language: "A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>?
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westchester County</ENAMEX>? Called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Pelham'?</ENAMEX>" Think of a real <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> big
shot--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felix</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>--and then try to picture that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> standing on a train <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> listening to a humanoid voice announce over
a microphone, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> -style, "Attention! The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:19</TIMEX> train to ... <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ...
will be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">13 minutes</TIMEX> late due to ... operating difficulties." It doesn't work,
does it?

            More than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Party, more than major-league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> system,
more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> salary structure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> suburbs need to be
reinvented. They need a real animating idea that isn't a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half-century old</TIMEX>. Or,
at the very least, a new set of clichés.

         
      
   
