
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX>Con

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> calls itself
"<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Biggest Bookstore</ENAMEX>," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, online and off, have accepted that
claim uncritically. "The toast of cyberspace" is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economist</ENAMEX> 's
accurate characterization of this Internet book-ordering service, which was
founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> rated <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> best Web sites of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> a "megawarehouse." The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yorker</ENAMEX> pointedly compared <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s claimed inventory of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1 million</NUMEX> books
with the mere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170,000</NUMEX> titles available at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Noble</ENAMEX> superstore.

            In fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s "megawarehouse" in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> contains <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 200</NUMEX> or so titles.
Any other book must be obtained from a wholesale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributor</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>.
This is exactly what any traditional bookstore does when it doesn't have a book
in stock. The difference is that traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> start out with a lot
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> titles in stock. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Biggest Bookstore"</ENAMEX>? More like "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s
Smallest."

            How does <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> get the books it doesn't have in its
warehouse? According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Cast</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> for marketing, it uses
several big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX>--including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingram Book Co.</ENAMEX>, one of the
largest--and sometimes, it calls the book's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> directly. She says that
in certain cases, it has even called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>. And how do less advanced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">booksellers</ENAMEX> do it? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">At</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Prose</ENAMEX>, a small local bookstore in northwest
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> told us, "We try <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ingram</ENAMEX> first, ... and then call
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>." At a northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> outlet of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borders Books</ENAMEX>, the superstore
chain, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> said: "It's no secret we try <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingram</ENAMEX>. ... If all that fails,
I guess we go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>."

            So why
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>? Cast gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> reasons: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One</ENAMEX>, we have a lower price. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>, we
have a better selection. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX>, we're probably much faster. And we're
definitely more convenient." We conducted an experiment to test these claims.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 16</TIMEX> we ordered the same <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Prose</ENAMEX>, and
Borders. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> were told to gift-wrap and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> each book as soon as
possible. One book was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Turow</ENAMEX>'s newest novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Laws of Our</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fathers</ENAMEX> , the kind of best seller that even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> actually has in stock.
The other was an obscure psychology text even Borders wouldn't carry, chosen
from the catalog of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University of New York Press</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Ego</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dynamic Ground</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transpersonal Theory of Human Development</ENAMEX> (second
edition), by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Washburn</ENAMEX>.

            
How did the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> booksellers compare by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s own standards?

            
               
                  Selection?
               
We've covered that. If you define "inventory" as any book a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> can
special-order for you, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> does, then the selection is identical at
almost every halfway-decent bookstore in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, you can browse
through all the titles and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>--and through some descriptive material--by
computer. At a conventional bookstore, you can pick up and leaf through actual
books, but fewer of them.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convenience</ENAMEX>?
               
For ordering, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Prose</ENAMEX> was by far the easiest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi</ENAMEX> answered the
phone on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ring. She was chatty, but professional. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> had "many,
many, many" copies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turow</ENAMEX> on hand, and she promised to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> out
"right away, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> at the very, very latest." When asked about the
psych text, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi apologized</ENAMEX> ("sorry, sorry") for not carrying it, and offered
to order it. Estimated time of arrival: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four weeks</TIMEX>. She took a name, address,
credit-card number. The entire phone call took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 minutes and 38 seconds</TIMEX>.

            Borders
was slightly less helpful. When asked to send the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turow, Drew</ENAMEX> groaned at our
lowbrow taste, but quickly said he'd send it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
selection's obscurity didn't cheer him up: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ugh</ENAMEX>, can't do you the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washburn</ENAMEX>
book." When pressed, he said it could be ordered, but would probably take two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. Borders' system is that when the book arrives, you are sent a postcard
asking you to come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and pick it up. Can't they just send the book?
"We prefer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do it this way," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew</ENAMEX> said, but then he gave in and agreed to
send it. Total phone time: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 minutes and 32 seconds</TIMEX>.

            After calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, we connected to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> using
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Netscape Navigator 3.0</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28,800</NUMEX>-baud modem. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> has a special page
dedicated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turow</ENAMEX> book, complete with a picture of the cover and some
unenlightening amateur commentaries from other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>. The psychology
text, not surprisingly, was listed with no description and no commentaries.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> said it would take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one to two weeks</TIMEX> to order.

            After clicking your purchases
into a "shopping cart," you are directed to a "secure Netscape server" that
will encrypt your credit-card information. After this is done, you are told:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Finalizing Your Order Is Easy</ENAMEX>." Nothing could be further from the truth. Lower
down in the verbiage, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> concedes, "Though we have tried hard to make this
form easy to use, we know that it can be quite confusing the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> have to page through screen after screen of details about shipping
charges, refund rules, and disclaimers about availability and pricing. Then you
are told to allow between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three and seven days</TIMEX> for delivery after your book
leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX>. "Upgrading to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next Day Air</ENAMEX> does NOT [their emphasis]
mean you'll get your order <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>."

            Total
online time from when we accessed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s home page to when we completed the
book order<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">: 37 minutes and 12 seconds</TIMEX>. It would be shorter once you got the
hang of it.

            

               Speed? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turow</ENAMEX>'s book arrived in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> from both <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Borders and Politics and Prose</ENAMEX>, in plenty of time before
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>. Politics and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prose</ENAMEX> wrapped the book perfectly. Borders wrapped it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attractively</ENAMEX>, but left the receipt inside. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turow</ENAMEX> didn't arrive from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 27</TIMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a week</TIMEX> after the conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, the
wrapping looked as if it had been done by a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX>. However, it came
bundled with the obscure psych book (which still hadn't arrived from the
conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year's Day</TIMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> for that one is pretty
good. As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turow</ENAMEX>, we had checked a box asking that each book be sent
separately, as soon as possible--so, either <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> ignored these instructions
or it really needed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the full 11 days</TIMEX> to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turow</ENAMEX> to us.

            By the way, let's not forget
that in a conventional bookstore, you can also--if you choose--acquire books in
zero <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, by "going to" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in the pre-Internet sense of actually going
there.

            

               
                  Price?
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> and Borders both offered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turow</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>
off the list price. Politics and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prose</ENAMEX> offered <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> off. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> wanted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> price for the psych book. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> charges <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">95 cents</NUMEX> per book for
standard shipping. Borders charged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> to ship the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turow</ENAMEX>, and Politics and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prose</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.50</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> charges <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> a book for gift-wrapping, which is free at the
other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> accidentally charged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $2</NUMEX> for wrapping both
books. Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> with local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> must charge sales tax on shipped
items; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> does not (unless you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>). In all, the Turow
cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23.72</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Borders</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26.30</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Prose</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> had sent
it separately as we had instructed, it would have cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24.82</NUMEX>. Gift-wrapped and
sent separately, the psych text would cost more at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> than at the other
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>; unwrapped and bundled, about the same.

            There is a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> category of books (besides those that
everyone has in stock and those that no one has in stock). These are books that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> doesn't have in stock, but a normal bookstore does. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170,000</NUMEX>-strong inventory, sniffed at by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , is a
good example.)

            This category is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s
greatest weakness. It includes hardly obscure current books that aren't best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sellers</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New Our Bodies, Ourselves</ENAMEX> , produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heath Book Collective</ENAMEX>. Borders' had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> copies on the premises.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> needs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to three days</TIMEX> to obtain this one, plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between three and seven</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> to send it to you. Likewise for a classic like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penguin</ENAMEX> paperback of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Dickens</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Tale of Two Cities</ENAMEX> , which any Borders or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noble</ENAMEX> will have on hand.

            Then there's a semiobscure
book such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Marr Wright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dodge City: The Cowboy Capital and the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Southwest</ENAMEX> . This hardcover book about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> is on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borders</ENAMEX>' shelves.
At <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> it is listed as a "special order," which means it might be available
to be shipped in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four to six weeks</TIMEX>, but, our computer informs us: "PLEASE NOTE
that it might not be available at all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publishers</ENAMEX> do not always notify the book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> about changes in the availability of their titles." Not
available? So much for the pretense that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>'s list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.1 million</NUMEX> books
makes it "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Earth's Biggest Bookstore</ENAMEX>" in even a metaphorical sense.

         
      
   
