
   
   
      
         
            Mind Over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>

            

               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie Allen</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate Editors</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: finding
new depths in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>

            a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> reports that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> here in town who is helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX>, auctioned off a dinner at
his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX> i think) recently. To
the surprise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>, present at the small gathering was no other than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> herself. She was, they reported, not only luscious but charming and
witty. Soon we can expect a raft of such reports in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> will slowly be
revealed as a renaissance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, whose deep knowledge of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> poetry is
matched only by her understanding of the historical tensions underlying the
current insurrections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> (she worries especially about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bulgarian</ENAMEX>
connection tho doubts that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX> are in fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>).

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Foer</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie Allen; Slate Editors</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
finding new depths in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>

            Funny you should mention
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. I ran into her <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayflower Hotel</ENAMEX> where she was
having <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cocktails</ENAMEX> with several middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in double breasted suits. She is
as perky and precocious as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Safire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> say. When I spoke with
her, she apologized for her slightly glazed eyes, having spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty-eight hours</TIMEX> teaching herself ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>. With all this time on her
hands, she has decided to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX> in the original. She also said she was at
work on a translation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vico</ENAMEX>. We engaged in a perfectly delightful
conversation about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-war strategy. The descriptions of her in
the press as "competent" hardly do her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>.

            

               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Foer</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie Allen; Slate Editors</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
finding new depths in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">monica</ENAMEX>'s in my painting
class. she's an amazing talent. perhaps a tad derivative of golub, but still an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> of far more restraint and maturity than one might expect of someone her
age.

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie Allen</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Foer</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
finding new depths in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>

            all the more remarkable
since she suffers, of course, from dyslexia (hence her failure on the writing
test at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> jordan sent her to). I understand she's been invited
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Quinn</ENAMEX> to speak at that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>.

            

               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus</ENAMEX> Krohn

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Allen</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Foer</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
finding new depths in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>

            What's truly astounding is
that I saw an application of hers for a job here at MS. She was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applying for a</ENAMEX>
development position with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 99</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. Her resume said she could
program c, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">c++</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DHTML</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VSS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STD</ENAMEX>. She claims <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STD</ENAMEX> was one of the
easier ones to acquire!

            
               From:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus Krohn; Jodie Allen</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Foer</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
finding new depths in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>

            It's funny that you guys
should be talking about this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> because I happened to run into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Wizards-Denver Nuggets</ENAMEX> game <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. She gave me a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15-minute</TIMEX>
disquisition on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>'s illegal defense rule: I've never heard it explained
so carefully. Turns out she's a big basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> too--she played a little for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis & Clark</ENAMEX> (shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>, natch), and was even drafted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WNBA</ENAMEX>. (I
guess that explains where she got those kneepads.)

            

               From: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>

            
               To:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus Krohn; Jodie Allen</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Foer</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>

            
               Subject: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>:
finding new depths in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>

            OK, get back to work and
stop picking on this sweet young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. You're all being sexist. If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had
done what she did, no one would ... wait a minute, that's not right. Well,
never mind, just get back to work.

         
      
   
