
   
   
      
         
            Wild and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woolly Sects</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leftists</ENAMEX> are enthusiastic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sectarians</ENAMEX>. The most brutal internecine spats took place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> of tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> sects vied to launch the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Revolution</ENAMEX>. Most of
these were personality cults, led by charismatic trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unionists</ENAMEX> and brainy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theorists</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fieldites, Lovestoneites, Weisbordites, Shermanites, Cochranites</ENAMEX>,
Schactmanites, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oehlerites</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX> for best sectarian of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX> may
go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trostkyite</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Mienov</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mienov</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> bolted from an
alliance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oehlerite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">faction</ENAMEX>, following a debate over which Leninist
strategy best suited the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proletariat</ENAMEX>. "We are proud to have split with
such a centrist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mienov</ENAMEX> proclaimed. But within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of forming his own
party, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workers League</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mienov</ENAMEX> purged all its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> for a lack of
revolutionary zeal. He flamed one poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mienovite</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>,
Spark : "We can gage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comrade Stanford</ENAMEX>'s sincerity, however, by the fact
that rather than give out leaflets for the revolution, he prefers to study for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exams at Brooklyn College</ENAMEX>." According to leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">apocrypha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Mienov</ENAMEX>, now
the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mienovite</ENAMEX>, developed multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> and split with
himself.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, at least,
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> of the right have generally eschewed minuscule <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and
bloody breaks. Recently, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have become enthusiastic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sectarians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX> wrote recently about the rumbling between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">libertarians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian conservatives</ENAMEX> over issues like the regulation of the
Internet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Republic</ENAMEX> carried a piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> about how
neoconservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> have also started to condemn the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX>-conservative rhetoric. But these are broad-brush disagreements. True
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sectarianism</ENAMEX> requires more esoteric disputes.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 20 years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> have come on
the scene promoting right-wing agendas. There's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Taxpayer Party</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Taxpayer Union</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Family Association</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Action Network</ENAMEX>, and so on.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Norquist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform</ENAMEX>, boasted in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Spectator</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that there are now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,000</NUMEX> state
and local property-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,500</NUMEX> taxpayer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>.

            Through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '70s</TIMEX>,
the right took a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular Front</ENAMEX> approach. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popular Front</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>'s attempt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1930s</TIMEX> to pool <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leftists</ENAMEX> into a grand
anti-fascist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Groups</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Birch Society</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Liberty Lobby</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Americans for Freedom</ENAMEX> similarly suppressed their differences in the
service of anti-communism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libertarians</ENAMEX>, evangelicals, segregationists, and
others put aside significant doctrinal disagreements.

            Most of the new conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, by contrast,
have particular ideological agendas. They fall into different camps. Some
examples: Buchananite populists (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">conservatives</ENAMEX> who are anti-tax and who are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traditionalists</ENAMEX>, but who are also economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nationalists</ENAMEX>) can join the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Taxpayer Party</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gun Owners of America</ENAMEX>. Less radical populists (like the
Buchananites, but more committed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> and without the
economic nationalism) fund interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">U.S. Term Limits Now</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Reform</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Libertarians</ENAMEX> have their
own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> promoting the rollback of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Separation of School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Alliance</ENAMEX>.

            And then there are the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian conservatives</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trotskyites</ENAMEX> of the right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trotskyites</ENAMEX> believe they
actually have an obligation to undermine other leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. They follow
their namesake's aphorism that revolutions are like birth: The forceps
shouldn't be applied too early. Only a vanguard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> (their own, of course),
using the correct tactics at the correct moment, can instigate a revolution.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian conservatives</ENAMEX> have a similar sort of fixation on the purity of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">movement</ENAMEX>'s strategy. Consequently, the religious right is riddled with tiny
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX>, their very own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mienovites</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oehlerites</ENAMEX>, who believe they each have a
monopoly on midwifery techniques for bringing a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> society into the
world.

            Reconstructionists, for instance, follow the teachings of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Schaeffer</ENAMEX>, an obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theologian</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, and argue for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theocracy</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judgment Day</ENAMEX>, they reckon, has come and gone--so we are
headed to perdition, unless a vanguard of radical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> reconstruct
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX> using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mosaic</ENAMEX> law as a blueprint. A truly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">polis</ENAMEX>, they believe,
would deny nonbelievers <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> and publicly stone or kill disobedient
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Though they can't claim much of a following, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coterie</ENAMEX> is well
organized and well positioned. Reconstructionists dominate the pro-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
Operation Rescue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Phillips</ENAMEX>, a well-known figure on the right and the
recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Taxpayer Party</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, belongs to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribe</ENAMEX>.

            Most other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservative groups</ENAMEX> don't
preach such an extreme vision for their ideal society, but they similarly abhor
compromise. Take <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Focus on the Family</ENAMEX>, a "parental rights" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist group</ENAMEX> with a
mailing list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.5 million</NUMEX> names, and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Research Council</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dobson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, sing the old
leftist tune "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Which Side Are You On?</ENAMEX>" Here, they describe their mission in
pretty stark terms: "Nothing short of a great <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> of Values rages today
throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> with vastly differing and incompatible
worldviews are locked in a bitter conflict." So if you give <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX> in battle,
you lose.

            There's a long list of
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> with a fairly similar take. Many claim to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Action Network</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Forum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concerned Women</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Traditional Values Coalition</ENAMEX>.

            These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> feel uncomfortable with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>, the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> on the right and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> most
committed to reviving the popular-front approach. Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX>
explained the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>'s strategy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX> in his manifesto,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Active Faith</ENAMEX> . He called the approach "surfing the mainstream." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>
argued that the religious right needs to retreat from the shrill language used
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>, and to abandon radical positions--such as their insistence
on a constitutional amendment banning abortion--in favor of more popular,
piecemeal solutions.

            But the popular-frontish approach doesn't attract
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauer</ENAMEX> crowd. They excoriate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> published Active
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> and said friendly things about pro-choicer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comrade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> wrote him a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-page letter condemning his soft politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> took to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> talking-head circuit, bad-mouthing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>
for backpedaling on abortion. And, more recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have blamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> for the debacle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX>, they
argue, quieted brawls between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian conservatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> that would have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">forced Dole</ENAMEX> to pay more attention to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> movement and its issues. In
their view, that would have helped.

            With all these new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">groups</ENAMEX> competing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and cash from the same pool of hard-core
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, tension is unavoidable. Movement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">old-timers</ENAMEX> resent having to
share the microphone and money with so many upstarts. For instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis</ENAMEX>
Schlafly, the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Forum</ENAMEX>, complains
incessantly about new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. In a series of letters, some of which were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">republished</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roll Call</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlafly</ENAMEX> blasted the populist group
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Term Limits Now for advocating a constitutional amendment. A
constitutional convention, she argues, would be required to enact an amendment,
and it would give pro-choicers the chance to push through their own amendment
protecting abortion. She has also jumped into the anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX> fray, criticizing
him for not being tough enough on the abortion issue.

            Or, there's the home-schooling movement, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> on the
right since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Groups</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Separation of School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Alliance</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home School Legal Defense Association</ENAMEX> hate the more recent conservative
obsession with vouchers. In its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education Liberator</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Separation of School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Alliance</ENAMEX> calls voucher <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> both
"fascists" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">socialists</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vouchers</ENAMEX>, they argue, are simply a guise for the
"edu-welfare system" to cast its net over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several million</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily Worker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Masses</ENAMEX> , socialist
papers from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, were peppered with citations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engels</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Liberator</ENAMEX> is peppered with references to their libertarian
equivalents--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedrich Hayek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ludwig von Mises</ENAMEX>.

            Debates like the home schoolers vs. the vouchers, or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX>, seem irrelevant or impenetrable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">onlookers</ENAMEX>, mere quibbles
over detail. But to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who believe the welfare state and abortion are
absolute evils, they are of the utmost importance. And, without the old
anti-communist battle and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> to suppress the differences,
differences have blossomed. It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldwater</ENAMEX> rallying cry, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Choice Not An</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Echo</ENAMEX>," taken to a new extreme. There's too much choice and not enough echo.

         
      
   
