
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">New Politics of the Drug War</ENAMEX>

            Did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX> mark the
beginning of the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Drugs</ENAMEX>? To some drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warriors</ENAMEX>, the reform
initiatives approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step
toward unilateral disarmament.

            "The implications of this
for the social norms that keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> away from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are very serious," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Dnistrian</ENAMEX>, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership</ENAMEX> for a Drug-Free
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. "There has been no greater fundamental challenge to the
drug-prevention field in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>."

            What is beyond dispute is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> of drug reform are enjoying unprecedented success in setting the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation's</ENAMEX> drug-policy agenda, at least for the moment. The "get-tough," "just
say no" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is on the defensive.

            Since the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> political system has responded to popular
concerns about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use by funding the steady expansion of federal and state
law-enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. With the advent of crack <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>,
the civic credos of "getting tough" and "just saying no" carried the weight of
common sense and enjoyed sway in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, print, and on the airwaves.

            Enter:
the marijuana problem. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1992 and 1996</TIMEX>, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> smoking
marijuana roughly doubled, a phenomenon that received wide attention during the
recent presidential campaign. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s harsh attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> for
allegedly condoning this development failed to excite <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. Given
the perception of a leadership vacuum around the time of the election, it's not
surprising that initiatives such as those in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
emerged.

            Though lumped together in articles like this, the two laws
are actually quite different. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona's</ENAMEX> is the more sweeping. It requires that
all nonviolent drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> be paroled (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> are
eligible to go free within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 90 days</TIMEX>); that the money saved in
jail-related costs go toward funding of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> on drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>; that all violent drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> do <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of their
sentence; and, almost as an afterthought, allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to prescribe
marijuana, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX>, or LSD. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> law, by contrast, shields from
prosecution <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who use marijuana under an oral or written "recommendation"
from a medical practitioner.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> law is an
implicit rejection of the drug war," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Vagenas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for pro-reform
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> was an explicit rejection."

            Is the
result a delegitimization of the drug war--a cultural surrender--an instance of
defining deviancy down, as cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> would have it? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> for
yourself.

            
On the Internet, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> entrepreneurial mind has
already set up a Web site offering <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">27 grams</NUMEX> of mail-order medical relief for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$270</NUMEX> ("taxes included") and handy guidelines for how to smoke it. The legality
is virtual: "All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> must send copy of medical report and birth
certificate." A return address in given. Is this a brazen hoax? Street dealing
on the information <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>? Proceed, with a caveat emptor, to:
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX>medical-marijuana.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com/.</ENAMEX>

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Therapy</ENAMEX>
Network chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, a posting on marijuana proved to be the most popular ever,
prompting a wide-ranging adult discussion of law, professional responsibility,
mental health, addiction, mind expansion, and above all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannabis Buyers Club</ENAMEX> had to take down its Web site, which had been
overwhelmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> hoping to score electronically. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Tuk</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> page, angrily yanked the site with this statement: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mail</ENAMEX> distribution
[of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marijuana</ENAMEX>] is an avenue of diversion for abuse!"

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital, the sound you hear is of paper
being shuffled. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry McCaffrey</ENAMEX>, has made it
clear he regards the two laws as the work of deceptive and mischievous drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legalizers</ENAMEX> who have snookered a lot of otherwise right-thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. But
what will federal drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> do? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCaffrey</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
that he would make his recommendations to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>.

            In the meantime, drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">warriors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> are on their own and not happy about it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Romley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maricopa County</ENAMEX> ( which includes
metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>), was perhaps the most incisive of those who testified
before a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> hearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early this month</TIMEX>. While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> criticized the duplicity of "pro-drug" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and the naiveté of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romley</ENAMEX> bluntly identified the central choices facing law enforcement:
go after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, federalize marijuana enforcement, go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and get a
strategy.

            The
options are not that attractive.

            
It's not clear that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> will prescribe
marijuana, but some surely will. Professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> reject the notion of medical marijuana, but caregiver
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of People</ENAMEX> With <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> support it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Walters</ENAMEX>, former
staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, want the feds to step in.

            "Nothing
in the law prevents <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX> from moving unilaterally against the small number of
pro-pot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> who would likely recommend marijuana for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> testified. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX>, he added, "should prepare to do so."

            That may sound like a good idea from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
policy-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> point of view. From the perspective of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> or state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX>
it sounds like a public-relations debacle: The sight of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> cuffing
some beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Welby</ENAMEX> for recommending a marijuana cigarette for kindly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Sebastian</ENAMEX> suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> will not go over well with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">federalization of state</ENAMEX> marijuana prohibitions would also impose some real
costs on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. The problem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, from the point of view of cops in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>, is that low-volume <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marijuana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX> are likely to
say in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> that they are handling medical marijuana. That would not be a
permissible defense in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, but federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> don't pursue
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX> unless they are handling substantial quantities. For example, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central District</ENAMEX>, the feds won't take a case that involves less
than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">200 kilograms</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">420 pounds</NUMEX>) or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dealers</ENAMEX> will be smart enough to
keep their operations under the federal threshold," observed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange County</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff Brad Gates</ENAMEX>.

            
Will the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District of California</ENAMEX> lower its threshold policy so as to discourage marijuana
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> posing as medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>? A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> declined
to discuss threshold policies and referred all questions to the still-silent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            The most forthright response
to the initiatives comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Lungren</ENAMEX>. He told
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX> cops in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have spoken," and counseled
grudging cooperation with the forces supporting medical marijuana. (Lungren
made national news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX>, when he authorized a police raid on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>" that was openly supplying marijuana to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>
and, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> charged, to many others who just wanted to get stoned. For his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vigilance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lungren</ENAMEX> was lampooned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Doonesbury</ENAMEX> .)

            "We must
realize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> meant that marijuana should be used only as an occasional
exception for someone who is seriously suffering and under the direct
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">supervision</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lungren</ENAMEX> said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> did not want to
start this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> down the slippery slope toward the legalization of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marijuana</ENAMEX>."

            But the "just say no" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> can't seem to get traction on
that slippery slope. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> now seems unswayed by its message. Leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prohibitionist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesmen</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCaffrey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lungren</ENAMEX> campaigned vigorously
against the propositions. Public opinion didn't change much.

            The drug
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enforcers</ENAMEX>' claim that the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> are some duplicitous, self-interested
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cabal</ENAMEX> is also growing less plausible. A civic cause that includes
self-described "limousine liberal" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX>, retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reaganite</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">statesman George Shultz</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Zappa</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of counterculture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>) is
not exactly narrow or shady sounding.

            
And the conclusion that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fools</ENAMEX>,
while always tempting to spurned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, is usually unwise. When <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Kyl</ENAMEX> recently said he was "embarrassed" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>' collective
decision, he promptly got roasted by most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>'s two top-rated
talk radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> and had to issue a clarification.

            On the other hand, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> have not shown that they can consistently win the confidence of the
public, which remains very wary of legalization of any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>--even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marijuana</ENAMEX>.

            "The reality is that we have
won a very small victory that is not readily convertible to any other area of
drug policy," concedes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fratello</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical</ENAMEX>
Rights, the umbrella <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that successfully promoted the medical-marijuana
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Kampia</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marijuana Policy Project</ENAMEX>, a pro-reform <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, says the legislative focus will remain on medical marijuana. He
claims to have pledges from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to introduce medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">marijuana</ENAMEX> bills in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. Meanwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Dnistrian</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partnership</ENAMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug-Free America</ENAMEX> says he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> will be contesting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>
everywhere and promises that next time, drug-prohibition forces will be "better
prepared and organized."

         
      
   
