
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diversionary Tactics</ENAMEX>

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine recently
took a job organizing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Employees International Union</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEIU</ENAMEX>,
you'll recall, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> that nurtured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sweeney</ENAMEX>, who
won office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half ago</TIMEX> on pledges to revitalize--or at least
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resuscitate</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> labor. There is good reason to take those pledges
seriously: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between 1980 and 1995</TIMEX>, a period when most of the labor movement was
submoribund, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEIU</ENAMEX> launched a series of clever and dogged organizing
campaigns, and nearly doubled its membership. But to reverse its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-decade
decline, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> will need to do more than adopt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEIU</ENAMEX>'s organizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wizardry</ENAMEX>: It must convince the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> at large that organized labor is not
simply a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, a New Deal relic, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">clubhouse</ENAMEX> full of gray-suited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

             

            Just after she was hired, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> attended a retreat of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEIU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> and rank-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filers</ENAMEX>. They spent
the weekend chewing over the tactical innovations that have made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>'s
reputation: "card check" campaigns that bypass the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Labor Relations</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX>'s sclerotic certification process; aggressive scrutiny of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>'
financial profiles; blitzkrieg drives that take on entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX> at once.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every evening</TIMEX>," she reports with a smile, "we all stood in a circle and sang
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'The Internationale</ENAMEX>.' "

            Now, the sight, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, of self-respecting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> trade
unionists singing a socialist anthem--in however jokey a spirit--would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">doubtless</ENAMEX> set off alarm bells. It's easy to imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nudging</ENAMEX> each other with told-you-so glee, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> averting their
eyes with a shudder. But you'll hear no complaints from me. Like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, I'm
somewhere to the left of paleoliberal; I believe that human civilization peaked
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. I hope my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have long and
honorable careers tightening labor markets and kicking the shit out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> or cheat their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.

            But I have
to confess: Something about that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEIU</ENAMEX> retreat sounds depressing. Imagine it: In
the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jesuitical</ENAMEX> preparations for long uphill organizing drives. And
then, for uplift and inspiration, a chance to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">sing "Solidarity Forever</ENAMEX>" and
other anthems that no normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 60</TIMEX> has ever heard. This
is, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX> in mind, one of the most vigorous and progressive corners of the labor
movement--and yet it somehow carries the odor of a fading religious sect.

            
This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sweeney</ENAMEX>'s burden. The American
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> is alone like no other in the advanced industrial world.
It operates in a crippling legal environment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Taft-Hartley Act of 1947</ENAMEX> and
its ensuing case law have erected absurd barriers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' freedom of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX>. For the price of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and a few gnat-size fines, nonunion
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> can comfortably fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> simply because they seek to organize.
(In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> whose economy is most similar to ours, organizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> are better protected from dismissal--and per capita <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> membership is
more than twice the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> level.)

            And where
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West European</ENAMEX> labor movements are well embedded within a broader left, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> left is populated by romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individualists</ENAMEX> whose pulses are not set
racing by the letters "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Bernard</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directs Harvard University</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Union Program</ENAMEX>, quips, "I sometimes think
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> will march in solidarity with any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s working
class except their own."

            The tactical savvy that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX> brings might help stanch
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>'s bleeding (it's been losing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200,000</NUMEX> members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>). But
tactics alone won't rescue labor from its peculiar weakness and insularity. To
break through that barrier, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> will need to convince a majority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>--or at least a muscular plurality--that solidarity is good for what
ails us. They need to sell the case that our colossal wage inequality is not a
fact of nature; that a progressive labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> can make our workplaces more
decent and more productive; and that strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> can leverage gains not only
for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> but for the broader society.

            Making
this case won't be easy, but it's unavoidable. Without such a framework, even
the cleverest organizing tactics will come to seem hollow. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard</ENAMEX> says,
"The labor movement is eternally in danger of becoming a Contracts 'R' Us
operation that only services its existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. You've got to look in the
mirror every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and ask yourself: 'What am I organizing for ?' "

            
If labor were less defensive and insular and
better embedded in a larger reform movement, it might be more motivated to
address its own shortcomings. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX>--ahem--there is the matter of housekeeping.
God bless <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when no one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Ed</ENAMEX> will be able to lean across the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thanksgiving</ENAMEX> table and say, "So I hear you're working for the labor movement.
Isn't that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s last bastion of mobsters, racists, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacks</ENAMEX>?"

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, a humbler labor
movement might be less likely to cut shortsighted political deals that undercut
its larger purpose. There was a pathetic scene <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to several respected labor-community initiatives. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alliances</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sweated blood</ENAMEX> in fights with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Riordan</ENAMEX> over public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX>, housing, and health care. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Labor Council</ENAMEX> voted to endorse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riordan</ENAMEX>'s re-election bid after he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dangled</ENAMEX> promises of an immense hotel-development project. (The endorsement
vote, which was narrow to begin with, was later rescinded after an outcry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riordan</ENAMEX> won anyway.)

            And
there's also a risk that tactical innovations like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEIU</ENAMEX>'s will come at the
expense of movement-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Several weeks ago</TIMEX> I spoke with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX>
about the disastrous newspaper strike in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumnus</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>'s much-praised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizing Institute</ENAMEX>, which trains both
rank-and-file <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and zealous college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the latest tactics. He
was full of scorn for labor's plans for a national march on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this June</TIMEX>.
"That's the lamest idea imaginable," he said. "Even if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> show up,
who's going to pay attention? If they want to win a decent contract in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>,
what they need is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">squad</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who will target the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of directors
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gannett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knight-Ridder</ENAMEX>. Find out where they live. Jam their fax machines.
Harass them when they go shopping. That's how you defeat corporate
power."

            This sort of strategy is very
much in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organizing Institute</ENAMEX>'s spirit. Its training materials stress
"finding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who can give you what you want" and making his or her life
hell. The ghost of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Weber</ENAMEX> might denounce these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">frat-boy</ENAMEX> tactics with a long
sermon about means and ends, but I'm a bit more tolerant. After all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>
routinely do things just as nasty. (Did you catch the story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX>
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> who was bribed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX> as part of
an effort to subvert an organizing drive?)

            But I'm still uncomfortable.
Isn't there something amiss when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> based on solidarity and cooperation
trains its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> to behave as if they were in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hobbesian</ENAMEX> world of all
against all? The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> is probably correct: The march on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>
won't do much to help win a contract. But without a steady drumbeat of public
engagement--through marches, debates, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX>, the works--the labor movement
will continue to smell of anachronism. So kudos to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweeney</ENAMEX> for toning labor's
muscles. Now let's work on the heart and the voice.

         
      
   
