
   
   
      
         
            Cracking God's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Code</ENAMEX>

            What would convince you that
God exists? A miraculous recovery from a fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>? Or would that prove
only the astonishing resilience of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>? An atheist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> struck by
lightning? Could be mere coincidence. But how about scientific
evidence--rigorously tested, peer-reviewed, unrefuted scientific evidence--that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> prophesies events that occurred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> after it was
written?

            This
sounds preposterous, of course, like some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late-night</TIMEX> spiritual infomercial. And
yet, such evidence may exist. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few years ago</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
conducted a computer experiment to test the existence of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>
codes"--sequences in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> that spell out hidden messages about future
events. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statisticians</ENAMEX> crunched their data, they reached an astonishing
conclusion: The hidden messages exist, and their presence "is not due to
chance." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, a distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Science</ENAMEX>
published their paper. Now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years later</TIMEX>, the results still stand,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undebunked</ENAMEX>. It's an unnerving prospect. If the study is true, science has
hinted at the existence of God, has suggested that God wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew Torah</ENAMEX>,
and has undermined our notion of free will. Either the experiment is flawed, or
the world has experienced a revelation.

            Back when the natural sciences, philosophy, and theology
were one great intellectual hodgepodge, proving the existence of God was a
relatively commonplace exercise. To the modern mind, however, science and
religion talk past each other. Except for the few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Biblical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">literalists</ENAMEX> who
spout drivel about "creation science," most of us now scoff at the notion of
using science to bolster religion.

            The search for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>
codes is rooted in the unfathomable theological premise that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>--itself
a set of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> books of limited length--contains literally all truth. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>, a k a the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five Books</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>," consists of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus</ENAMEX>,
Numbers, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deuteronomy</ENAMEX>.) This is not an overstatement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>, in other
words, is supposed to contain--somehow and somewhere--everything from your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> number to the names of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you've ever slept with,
as well as what you ate for breakfast <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX>.

            According
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi Daniel Mechanic</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on the codes, the belief that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>
contains encrypted messages dates to the medieval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> of the
Kabbalah, a form of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mysticism</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kabbalists</ENAMEX> believed that there were
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">84</NUMEX> coding schemes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them was equidistant letter sequences
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELSs</ENAMEX>). Choose every <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> letter from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hebrew T</ENAMEX> (called a
"Taf") in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Genesis</ENAMEX>, for example, and you'll find the word "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>." Do the same
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Exodus</ENAMEX>, and you'll find it again. (This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELS</ENAMEX> doesn't appear, however, in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>'s other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> books.) The current emphasis on ELSs stems from an
observation by a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> that pairs of conceptually
related words are bunched together in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELSs</ENAMEX>. True <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> have spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
counting out ciphers, then trying to puzzle out the significance of the
revealed codes.

            
Not that the codes ever attracted much of a
following. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> have never heard of them, and most of those who have
discount them as embarrassing numerological hogwash. Even many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jews</ENAMEX>
regard the codes as a kind of parlor trick that is irrelevant to the essence of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judaism</ENAMEX>. Besides, the codes claim is so fantastical that dismissing it as a
piece of intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knavery</ENAMEX> may just be the most reasonable--as well as the
most comfortable--solution. But what if they do exist?

            Of
course, any text of sufficient length is riddled with accidental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELSs</ENAMEX>. If you
look hard enough, you can "discover" all sorts of hidden messages. So Eliyahu
Rips of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>'s math <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, Doron
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witztum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoav Rosenberg</ENAMEX>, designed an elaborate experiment to test whether
there are real codes embedded in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>. They programmed computers to scour
Genesis for ELSs naming <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX> famous rabbis and their dates of birth or death. The
rabbis on the list were all born long after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genesis</ENAMEX> was written, so no human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> could have deliberately encoded them into the text. Moreover, the rabbis
were chosen according to an arbitrary criterion, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> were not
looking for names they already knew to be present. As a control, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
performed exactly the same experiment on a few scrambled versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genesis</ENAMEX>,
on the book of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isaiah</ENAMEX> (which, while biblical, is not a book of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>), and
on a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> translation of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> .

            If the phenomenon were due to chance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> reasoned,
they would be as likely to find an ELS naming <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rabbi X</ENAMEX> near one identifying the
birthday of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rabbi Y</ENAMEX> as they would be to find <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rabbi X</ENAMEX> near his own birthday.
And, indeed, this is what they found in the control texts. But it wasn't true
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genesis</ENAMEX>. Not only were most of the rabbis present in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELSs</ENAMEX>, but they
generally appeared closer to their own dates than to the dates of other rabbis.
When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> analyzed their data, they found a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-in-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> possibility
that such a coding scheme could have occurred as a result of chance.

            They sent their paper to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Science</ENAMEX> , where it was peer reviewed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> puzzled
over it, and finally, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, they published it. The article attracted
surprisingly little public attention, considering its potentially mammoth
significance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> ran a wire story and the magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> published a longer piece, and that was about it for media coverage.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> did not escape the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faithful</ENAMEX>. The Internet is
frothing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> bent on using the codes to woo unbelievers. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evangelical Christian</ENAMEX> site describes the codes as "unrefutable scientific
evidence the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> is God's word." Another site claims, somewhat more gently,
that the "mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hebrew</ENAMEX> codes" have identified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Messiah</ENAMEX>.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mechanic</ENAMEX>, the codes cannot be read as any sort of window on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>'s inner meaning: "They have nothing to do with the religion, nothing to
do with spirituality. All they can do is validate the hypothesis that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> is not human."

            
Acquaintances of mine have become <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> because of the codes. I also know of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who waited until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Science</ENAMEX> agreed to publish the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> before circumcising his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Statisticians</ENAMEX> continue to hope for a crack in
the experiment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kass</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Science</ENAMEX> ,
suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> may have subconsciously biased their results by
selectively reporting their findings. "Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statistician</ENAMEX> I know has reacted
that the most likely explanation is that some kind of selection or 'tuning' of
the method did take place, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> may not be conscious of it," he
says.

            But so
far, the only serious challenge to the published work comes from an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan McKay</ENAMEX>, who has replicated the experiment and claims
to have found defects. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay's</ENAMEX> draft report notes that the effect described in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genesis</ENAMEX> does not appear to exist in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other four</NUMEX> books of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>. He also
identifies a number of highly technical problems with the experiment that, he
says, render it meaningless.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay</ENAMEX>'s critique remains only a draft, however, and it has
not yet undergone the rigorous peer review that the original paper withstood.
Still, his report raises potent questions about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> codes methodology,
questions even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rips</ENAMEX> acknowledges to be "serious." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rips</ENAMEX> appears eager to
address the challenge. In a recent e-mail message to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKay</ENAMEX>, he welcomed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">critique</ENAMEX> and agreed that "more prosaic explanations" needed to be examined
before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> codes phenomenon could be ascribed to God.

            No matter how this discussion
shakes out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> codes paper seems fundamentally unlike any previous
attempt to use science to prove a metaphysical point. No similar claim has ever
withstood scientific examination as robustly as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX> codes have.

            What's more, until someone
publishes a peer-reviewed paper that demolishes them, at least a smidgen of
doubt remains, a floating question mark: What if God did write the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>? Then
what?

         
      
   
