
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molten Meltdown</ENAMEX>

            Investigative journalism
ain't what it should be. Too often it coughs up the long newspaper story that
the average intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>, having read it carefully, puts down and says,
"What the heck was that all about?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> produced such a story on Page
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 17</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,834</NUMEX>-word article was titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"A Lobbyist's Lucrative Ties</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ex-Aide Raised Funds From Client</ENAMEX>, Helped Its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Business</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read it.) The length, the placement, and the
authorship all suggest that this is a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX>--apparently an important new
revelation of some sort about the campaign-finance scandal. But for anyone but
the most ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX>-committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groupie</ENAMEX>, the piece is a massive,
unenlightening info-dump, containing paragraph after paragraph of brain-bending
detail that's barely placed within a conceptual framework.

            The story tracks the wheeling and dealing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Knight</ENAMEX>,
an influential corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> who used to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and is now a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prominent Gore</ENAMEX> fund-raiser. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knight</ENAMEX> lobbied for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molten Metal Technology</ENAMEX>, a
hazardous-waste <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that collected a large federal contract and whose chief
executive, coincidentally or not, was a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> to various <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> causes.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knight-Molten</ENAMEX> connection had already been reported. So what's the story?
There are perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> ways to tell it. One is chronologically--not a bad idea
when the plot is complicated. Another is "pyramid style"--the traditional
newspaper approach, with the nub of the story on top and an expanding base of
detail. Then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s way--a sort of postmodernist literary technique
in which time and space loop around and tie each other in knots. The piece is a
surprise coming from someone who has produced many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readable</ENAMEX> scoops.

            
"In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring of 1995</TIMEX>," the story begins (and
compressing it makes the story far more comprehensible than the full-blown
version), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molten</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> pledged to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX> sent them a thank-you note. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three weeks earlier</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> had
visited and praised one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molten</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knight</ENAMEX>
a thank-you note for arranging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> trip. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six weeks later</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> attended
a dinner for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>. Now government
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are looking into this. Into what, exactly? In the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX>
paragraph we learn that this is "a stark picture of how business and politics
often overlap, demonstrating the advantage of having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in high places."
Anyone previously unaware that business and politics "overlap" (whatever that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">means</ENAMEX>) and that it's good to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in high places has now had that
cleared up. But without any more guidance about why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who weren't born
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> should keep reading, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> resumes the narrative
carpet-bombing.

            We are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neck-deep</ENAMEX> in the morass when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> offers up something that smells like
news. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22, 1994</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molten Metal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> to help endow a
chair at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Tennessee</ENAMEX> to be named after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s deceased <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX> boosted an existing contract with the
company by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 million</NUMEX>. Even later in the piece, the most devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> is
rewarded with another significant item: On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s expanded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>
contract was announced, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Molten</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Knight</ENAMEX> was simultaneously a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and a fund-raiser
for both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign and the university chair. At that time, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX>
official involved in the contract was a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>.

            Believe me, you now have a better grasp of this story than
you could possibly have gained from reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s entire piece--once. You
also have maybe <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> of your life back. What you don't have is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s descriptions of various dinners attended by the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures</ENAMEX>.
(The choice is yours. Click here for another chance to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> story.)

            Another
traditional journalistic concept (like pyramid style) is that the news ought to
be new. Despite the front-page placement and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s brand-name <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">byline</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.17</TIMEX> story added little to a report posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days earlier</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Weisskopf</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s Web site. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to read it.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisskopf</ENAMEX> presented the story in a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hundred</ENAMEX> comprehensible words, reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molten</ENAMEX>'s federal contract was
expanded at the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> were making large,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>-brokered donations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>. (A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month earlier</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> made an elliptical reference to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molten</ENAMEX> case in his New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> column. Click here to read
the column.)

            
The traditional investigative story, at least
in the movies, works this way: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intrepid reporter</ENAMEX>, through gumption and
legwork, exposes the evildoer; then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> takes over to flesh out the
case and administer punishment. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, all too frequently, this chronology
runs backward. Specifically, the government process predates the journalistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">exposé</ENAMEX>--and in fact is its major source. Following what is by now standard
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> procedure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX>-committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> routinely shop stories
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. The pile of documents that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> relied on for his article
(and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisskopf</ENAMEX>, too) were, in all likelihood, provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, including me, make deals with congressional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> to get material by promising not to reveal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. Such deals
are sometimes necessary to get a good story. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> deserve to know that
some of the big, important stories thrust in front of them are actually the
product of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s political games.

            Actually, more than a year
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 18, 1996</TIMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Frisby</ENAMEX> wrote a
long story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Knight</ENAMEX> that disclosed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>'s connection to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molten</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Molten's</ENAMEX> donations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s success in obtaining
contracts from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. I don't know where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frisby</ENAMEX> got his
material, but he wrote the story before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> even existed.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read that story.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> did advance the story
by reporting on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> donation for the university chair honoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOE</ENAMEX> contract expansion. Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frisby</ENAMEX> did a better job than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> in offering meaning. He summed up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX> case rather well:

            "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>'s link to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> is now the power axis for a circle of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>,
all of whom benefit from the relationship. It works like this: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>, some of whom are old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and contributors to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, donate to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. In return, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> occasionally helps them.
Everybody wins. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rewards Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX> for his fund raising, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
lays the groundwork for his anticipated presidential bid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years from now</TIMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, by hiring Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knight</ENAMEX>, get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s ear."

            So that's what it's all
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. Now you know.

         
      
   
