
   
   
      
         
            Mourning Sickness

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Waldo Emerson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal</ENAMEX> contains this intriguing entry for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29, 1832</TIMEX>: "I visited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tomb</ENAMEX> and opened the coffin."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emerson</ENAMEX> was in his late 20s
at the time, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> still reeling from the loss of his young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
who had died of tuberculosis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 months earlier</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biographer Robert D. Richardson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> contends that by literally confronting death (ghoulish as it seems),
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emerson</ENAMEX> was able to pull out of his funk and get back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of
becoming a great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> philosopher.

            It is
inherently unfair to pass judgment on another's grief. Yet I must confess that,
just as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emerson</ENAMEX>'s behavior raised my eyebrows, so, too, of late has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman's</ENAMEX>. Where once I saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> struggling rather nobly with tragedy, I now
see someone trapped on the merry-go-round of notoriety. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years</TIMEX> after the
double murder of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, a part of me is weary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Goldman</ENAMEX> lapel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">button</ENAMEX>, of the habitual references to "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>," of the righteous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">indignation</ENAMEX>. More to the point, a part of me is wary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Goldman</ENAMEX>--a client
of a large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> public-relations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and a paid (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe Streets Coalition</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>--turning a
private ordeal into public policy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman</ENAMEX> now promotes the abolition of
unanimous-jury verdicts, the adoption of "judicial report cards," and an end to
the lifetime appointment of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>. "Being active is a way to focus
some of that frustration, anger, etc., into something positive," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last February</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Goldman</ENAMEX> and his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patti</ENAMEX>,
were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> for their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 th wedding anniversary</TIMEX>. They spent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> first promoting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">His Name Is Ron</ENAMEX> , in an
appearance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Press Club</ENAMEX>, and then touring the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust Museum</ENAMEX>.
"There's something like an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Testament</ENAMEX> prophet quality about [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>]," says a
court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who covered both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> trials.

            Indeed,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldmans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rabbi</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX> has become a
"moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>" for justice. "God is working through him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabbi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary E. Johnson</ENAMEX>.

            
God sometimes works in mysterious ways. So do
the media. Thus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldmans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX> were back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Correspondents' Dinner</ENAMEX>, a black-tie schmoozathon for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> writer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Hitchens</ENAMEX> notes that "it seemed rather creepy" to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Goldman</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton</ENAMEX> hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballroom</ENAMEX> along with such mainstream trophy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selleck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen DeGeneres</ENAMEX>. How do you make small talk about bloody gloves and
size <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruno Magli</ENAMEX> shoes?

            The
Goldmans were invited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> graciously
passed along to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s desire to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. During dinner, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX> decided to take matters into his own
hands, and marched up to the head table.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> intercepted him, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX> meeting
was arranged. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldmans</ENAMEX> later complained about getting only <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>
alone with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldmans</ENAMEX> didn't have
tickets to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> 's heavily guarded post-dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, but they
gate-crashed without a problem. "They assumed they'd get in based on this
macabre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>," says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who was there. "And they were right."

            
Considering all the misery the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldmans</ENAMEX> have been through, one can't begrudge
them a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and a little stargazing. What is cause for some
concern, though, is the peculiar public pedestal upon which they've been
placed, especially since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX> now is venturing into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> of
criminal-justice reform. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman</ENAMEX>'s voice is part of a rising chorus of
high-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>. The assemblage includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Klaas</ENAMEX>,
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polly</ENAMEX> was kidnapped and murdered; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Walsh</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
Most Wanted fame, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of another kidnap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> Rep.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn McCarthy</ENAMEX>, who launched a political career after her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was killed
by a crazed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX> commuter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>. Those voices deserve to be
heard, but the risk is that the national crime debate will be shrouded in the
emotional fog they produce.

            
If there is life after death, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Goldman</ENAMEX> will
probably chase <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnels</ENAMEX> of time. Perhaps rightfully so.
"Forgiving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who murdered my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is not something I'm able to do," he
said shortly before the civil trial commenced. "I think there's something
between vengeance and forgiveness."

            There is. It's called peace
of mind. I hope <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Goldman</ENAMEX> finds it. But he's looking in the wrong
places.

         
      
   
