
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax Shelters: The Video Game</ENAMEX>

             

            
               NOTE: This article
includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> live spreadsheets where you can plug in your own numbers. Click to
go directly to a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">or a</ENAMEX> .
            

            As part of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> Balanced
Budget Act, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cut the top tax rate on capital
gains to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>. Capital gains are profits on the sale of investments such
as stocks and real estate. Tax rates on ordinary income go up to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39.6 percent</NUMEX>.
Further reductions in the capital-gains rate are scheduled for future
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Enthusiasts</ENAMEX> of the
capital-gains tax break believe it will help the economy by stimulating savings
and investment. That is debatable. (See a 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> arguing
otherwise; also see this 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dialogue</ENAMEX>" on the
subject.) But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> form of investment this new law undoubtedly will stimulate is
tax <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX>. Shelters are financial arrangements designed primarily or
entirely to reduce taxes. They were largely eliminated by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> tax reform,
which ended the special break for capital gains. Now they are back, as the
following examples demonstrate.

            What is wrong with tax
shelters? Leave aside critical questions of fairness and revenue lost to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> (which must be made up by borrowing or by increasing taxes on other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>). Consider only the effect of tax shelters on the overall economy.
Shelters hurt the economy in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways. At best they waste resources on lawyers
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> designing complicated but economically meaningless
arrangements. At worst they redirect investment capital from uses that make
economic sense to those that don't. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>, for example, the tax
system made it profitable to build office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> even if you had no hope of
renting them out. The result was downtowns full of "see through" <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">towers</ENAMEX>, and a
real-estate glut from which some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are still recovering.

            How does a tax shelter work?
.

         
      
   
