
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX>

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s classic nuclear-apocalypse novel of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> awaits word that
nuclear war is imminent. He'll know that time is up when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, working
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and privy to top-secret information, sends him a telegram
with the words "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX>." The collapse of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> would not be quite as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">calamitous</ENAMEX> as a nuclear war. But, like many others who've gloried in owning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> stock, I would dearly love a signal if the moment to run for cover
arrived.

            I need a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> more than most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> do, perhaps. I joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
straight out of college in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> and left this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, taking a small but
healthy chunk of its stock with me. Now I have far more of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s savings
invested in a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, for which I no longer even work, than any sane
financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> would recommend. That's OK with me, because I still think
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is a great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with a great future. But nothing lasts forever. I
can't expect a telegram from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> saying "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX>." So here are the
signals that will warn me the unthinkable may be happening.

            Of course, any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> will tell you that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
strategic position at the center of the computer industry is paramount. Chances
are, if you're using a computer, you're running at least some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
software. In particular, there's a that you're running some variety of the
Windows operating system. The ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Java war</ENAMEX> (read about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Java in "Webhead</ENAMEX>" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Motley Fool"</ENAMEX>)
is a battle for this strategic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> doesn't scare me--yet.
There's so much software written for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Windows</ENAMEX>, and PCs running Windows are so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ubiquitous</ENAMEX>, that it's hard to see it being supplanted. But I'll know something
is wrong when someone I know buys a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Java</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> home computer . Not one of
my geeky computer-nerd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, either--they'll buy anything--I mean someone in
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, or any of my basically computer-illiterate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Unlike
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, which will occasionally throw money at bizarre nonstandard
computing solutions like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NeXT</ENAMEX>, OS<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Java</ENAMEX>, normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> only get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> shot
at it. So they are conservative. They ask around. They buy what their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
buy or (more likely) what their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> buy. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Java</ENAMEX> invades the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>,
I'll know the tide has turned.

            By then,
of course, it will be too late. I will have missed my chance. I believe the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> thing that can defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> (or, for that matter, at work)
is if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> fails to make computers easier to use . I spend far too
much of my life setting up computers for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and answering dumb
questions. But it's not really the questions that are dumb--it's the computers.
Software and hardware configuration is too error-prone; incompatibility remains
too common; and software is too difficult to use. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> aren't getting a
fraction of the productivity--or the fun--they could, and their computers soon
become merely expensive toys. Frustration is rampant. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> doesn't fix
this in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX>, someone else will.

            
A yardstick I watch on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis is the
stock price. But I'm not nervous about it dropping--I worry when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
stock stagnates, particularly when it stagnates at a high price . Now it
seems backward to judge a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s success directly by its stock price. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffettesque</ENAMEX> buy-and-hold strategy tells you to look at the
fundamentals. If they're strong, hold on to the stock. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifeblood</ENAMEX> is its employee stock-option program, and so the stock price is, in a
sense, one of the fundamentals. Options are how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> attracts and
retains smart young college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> with no money and (most important) no
lives. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> joining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> today right out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> will get a number
of options giving him or her the right to buy shares of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> at the lowest
closing price <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> after he or she joins. And most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> get more
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. In essence, options give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> any future increase in stock
price. If the price doesn't increase, the options are worthless.

            Options "vest" (take effect)
gradually over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>. At any time, therefore, valued <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> have a
sizable amount of money that's theirs--if they stay around long enough to get
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psychologically</ENAMEX>, it doesn't work to have the stock stay at the same price,
then shoot up after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. By that time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> is long gone, lost
to some little start-up about to have an initial public offering. It's worse if
the stock stays at a high price, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> knows (or at least
worries) that there isn't much upside. I don't mind a little volatility,
because this makes it more likely that a new employee's options will hit a
momentarily low price during that crucial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first month</TIMEX> (when new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>,
paradoxically, have an incentive to want the price to go down). And I don't
mind periodic declines, even steep ones, because it's a chance to scoop up some
more good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> at (to them) an attractively low price. Over the long term,
though, what I want to see is a steady upward progression.

            On a more personal basis, I
watch my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> slowly trickling out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, leaving because they've
made enough money, or because they've burnt out, or because they just want to
try something new. That, in and of itself, is not necessarily a warning
sign--old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX>, new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> comes in, and sometimes the old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> comes
back after a while. In any case, most of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> remain in the software
business. They love it, they live it, and they can't stop talking about it.
They talk about the important things: the key technologies, the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
the big deals. And they do it all the time: while feeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, hiking up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mountains</ENAMEX>, and even in nominally social situations. I'll know that the jig is
up, the end of the world has come, and it's time to sell my very last share of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSFT</ENAMEX> when conversations at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> no longer center on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
