
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kids as Status Symbols</ENAMEX>

            So, you've got the beach
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> compound on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nantucket</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">63-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hinckley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sailboat</ENAMEX>, the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>,
the nanny, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gardener</ENAMEX>; and your stay-at-home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> with the advanced
academic degree heads up the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> campaign. What other acquisition
might serve your high economic and social status? How about having some more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>?

            It has
long been a demographic truism that richer means fewer, not more, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. And as
far as it goes, census data seem to bear this out. As the average incomes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have increased, the smaller their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have become. Since the
height of the baby boom in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> born to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> has dropped from an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.76</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1.98</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. And this
phenomenon is not confined to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The average number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
born to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX> has fallen from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.5</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960 to 1.6 today</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> have lots of reasons for choosing to have fewer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, including the expansion of opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the workplace,
but it is an undeniable fact that rearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the modern world is an
expensive activity. Throughout most of history <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were net assets--they
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toiled</ENAMEX> in the fields, mucked out the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>, and cared for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in old
age. But modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't really expect much of a return from the resources
they spend on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> may mow the lawn and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny</ENAMEX> might run
the dishwasher, but in general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today do little to contribute directly to a
family's bottom line.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Census Bureau</ENAMEX>
confirms that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> with the lowest average annual incomes--those
under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>--have had the most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX> on average. By contrast,
upper-middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX>--those making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $75,000</NUMEX>--have an average
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 1.8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> interpretation of these numbers is that poor parents
still think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are a reasonable investment. In a poor rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> still do chores on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>. And before welfare reform, at least, an
additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> usually meant an increase in a poor urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s
benefits.

            Meanwhile,
for the upper-middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, providing for progeny is expensive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> try to
pay for private-school educations, soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and pool memberships, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, piano, and dance lessons. Of course, these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are spending this
money in an attempt to assure the future success of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. But even
with an income of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX> per year, they can afford only so much for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skip</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffy</ENAMEX>'s tutoring, so they limit their family size in order to bestow more on
fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.

            
But recently I have noticed that many of my
wealthier acquaintances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live in tonier suburbs like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potomac</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>,
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darien</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, are bucking the trend toward smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. Many have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Some intriguing, if sketchy, data suggest that at the
highest levels of wealth and income, the trend is toward larger, not smaller,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.

            For
example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mendelsohn Research</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that supplies consumer research to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>, advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, and publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--offers some
suggestive data. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mendelsohn</ENAMEX>'s most recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> survey shows that those
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> where the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> family income exceeds <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> are
blessed with an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> currently at home. That is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">0.5</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
more than the upper-middle-class average and the same number as the lowest
census income category. And because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mendelsohn</ENAMEX> data don't include <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who
have left home--while the census data do--the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> born in these
very wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> could be even higher.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> other interesting figure comes from the very tiptop of
the wealth scale. The households that compose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> richest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
average <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.88</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. That's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.08</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> more than the upper-middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> can
afford.

            These added <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> provide many
opportunities for status signaling. Wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> can talk endlessly at the
country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> about the costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> summer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, high-school semesters
abroad, little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>'s sailing trophies, and what hunt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX> rides with
regularly. And of course, there are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>. Did they prep at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Albans</ENAMEX> or Choate? How well are they doing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Middlebury</ENAMEX>?
Being able to provide lavishly for a large number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> shows that you've
really got it made.

            This is not to say that rich
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't love their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. Rather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today are not only little bundles of
joy but also are perhaps the ultimate symbols of worldly success and status.
Perhaps we are now seeing a new social phenomenon--trophy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
