
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ovitz</ENAMEX> Got <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Away With Murder</ENAMEX>

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney Co.</ENAMEX> and its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">short-time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX> announced they were parting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> a couple
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> may have been surprised by reports that I had been
involved in designing the contract that will reportedly give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> goodbye gift. After all, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, I set aside my highly successful
career as an executive-compensation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> and became a fierce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of
the size and manner in which many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> pay their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> and other
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>.

            My switch from henchman to
gadfly incensed many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>, some of whom called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">me a Judas</ENAMEX> and asked where they
should deliver the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>. In a sense, though, those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> and I
were operating on the same wavelength. They were quoting from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX>, while
I was beginning to think seriously about the need to save my immortal soul.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next six</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1995</TIMEX>--I stayed away from work with major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>. Then
the phone rang, and on the other end was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>, the by-then legendary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney Co.</ENAMEX> I had twice helped to design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisner</ENAMEX>'s own pay
contracts--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> and again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>--and I had long admired him
as one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> who take risks and play the pay game as it should be
played. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisner</ENAMEX> wanted me to suit up and help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s board compensation
committee forge a deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX> that would make him the No. 2
executive at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>.

            After some agonizing, I told
Eisner that I would help out as a personal favor to him, but that when
documents were released on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX>'s pay, I would review them as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>. If I
felt so inclined, I might well attack what I saw. His reply: "You would have
done that anyway. So I don't see that I'm losing anything." (As I've learned
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few days</TIMEX>, my boast of independence was an empty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. It's very
hard, in practice, to take money as a compensation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> and then be
openly critical of the outcome without either violating confidentiality or
inviting the inference that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> ignored your good advice--all of which
underscores my original notion that if you want to be a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, you
shouldn't get involved in corporate decisions, no matter how flattering the
invitation.)

            A lot of
my criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> pay is centered around the fact that there is no real
market operating out there. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> decide on what they perceive to be a fair
level of pay, add <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> to give themselves some maneuvering <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and
then present their outsized demands to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> that they
hand-picked. Typically, some <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> of other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and none has a known aversion to greed. "Whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lola Wants</ENAMEX>, Lola
Gets!" sings the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">devil</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Damn Yankees</ENAMEX> . Substitute a
different--and, almost invariably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>--name for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lola</ENAMEX>, and you'll get a good
picture of what ensues in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">boardroom</ENAMEX>.

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX> deal was of a different, better kind.
It met all the tests of a true free-market transaction.

            First, you had an informed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, the compensation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. Not only were
its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">members</ENAMEX> well versed in the arcana of executive compensation, but I was
along for the ride to point out the shortcuts and pitfalls. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, you had an
informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX>, who was also armed with his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisers</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX>, you had vigorous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>'s-length negotiations. Indeed, the
negotiations between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s compensation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> were so tough
that the deal almost collapsed several times (and, in light of more recent
events, one wishes it had).

            Finally,
though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> might have been hand-picked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>, it
certainly had not been hand-picked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX>. And it was certainly not
in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>'s interest to pay Ovitz any more than he had to. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisner</ENAMEX> is
himself a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> stock who, after clearing an ambitious hurdle
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> has to earn an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX> after-tax return on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>' equity),
also receives an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> bonus equal to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s above-hurdle
profits.

            
So I can't criticize the way in which the Ovitz
deal was reached. And, in fact, there was virtually no criticism at the time.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> the deal was announced, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s share price rose sharply,
suggesting that the investment community was well pleased that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> almost
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">universally</ENAMEX> acknowledged to be "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Most Powerful Man in Hollywood"</ENAMEX> had decided
to cast his lot with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>.

            Key
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> negotiating from outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> they are considering joining
usually have a great deal of leverage. After all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> wants them badly.
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ovitz</ENAMEX>'s case, the leverage was compounded, because he had been enjoying a
fabulously successful career as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>; rumor had it he was
pulling down <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $25 million and $35 million</NUMEX> per year. So it was
understandable that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ovitz</ENAMEX> wanted some assurance that he would have the
opportunity to earn a great deal of money at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> use a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goodies</ENAMEX> to lure a senior
executive from the outside. Often, they will give the executive a large
one-time front-end bonus when he signs his contract. In other cases, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> might give the executive an upfront--again, large--grant of free shares
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> stock. In still other cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> might guarantee that the
executive will receive big bonuses in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">future years</TIMEX>, poor profits
notwithstanding.

            The Ovitz
deal, however, contained none of these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goodies</ENAMEX>. They seemed too expensive. For
example, if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> deal was worth, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX>, and if the
compensation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> had added to that a front-end grant of free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
shares worth, say, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX>, then--assuming that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> finished his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> contract period--the cost to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150 million</NUMEX>.

            
Instead, to provide the comfort needed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">induce Ovitz</ENAMEX> to give up his marvelous career as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, the compensation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> offered him a severance agreement. This seemed a far cheaper--indeed
probably costless--alternative to a front-end bonus. Of course, the overall
costs of the package would go up sharply in the event of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX>'s termination
(and I wish now that I'd made a spreadsheet showing just what the deal would
total if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> had been fired at any time). But the probability of that
happening was deemed to be exceedingly low. After all, if you think the person
can't make it, why hire him in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place?

            But then the unthinkable
happened. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only 16 months</TIMEX> into his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> agreement, was out
in the cold. That brought to life those sleeper in his contract.

            Or have they come to life?
If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ovitz</ENAMEX> walked out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> under his own power, his contract guaranteed him
precisely nothing in the way of severance. Only if he were fired would the
severance provisions come into play. Given that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> have been
retailing the notion that he resigned, rather than being fired, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> might
not end up having to make good on the full value of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX>'s severance package.
Perhaps there was one final negotiation that reduced what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ovitz</ENAMEX> was to
receive.

            But if
Ovitz was truly fired, then his severance pay will be nothing short of awesome.
Different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> have placed values on his severance pay ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX>, and if he gets the full-bore severance package, I
wouldn't care to dispute those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>.

            Can you blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> for what happened? I don't
think so. They played by the current rules and, consistent with landing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Ovitz, behaved as prudently as they could.

            How about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Eisner</ENAMEX>? You might blame him to the extent that it was his idea to bring
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>. On the other hand, he is paid to make gutsy decisions, most of
which cost a lot of money, and some of which have the capacity to turn out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disastrously</ENAMEX>. And, viewed over his long tenure as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisner</ENAMEX> has
been an absolutely brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX>. With the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Goizueta</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>, there is, in my opinion, no other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> who has been as
successful in running a truly major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. So, though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisner</ENAMEX> is at fault, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> need to cut him some slack.

            
Can you blame the system? Absolutely. Large
severance packages are the dirty little secret of executive compensation, not
merely at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>, but at scores of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> talk with great bravado
about how their job is like crossing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niagara Falls</ENAMEX> on a high wire. But what
they don't tell you is that there is a safety net <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 inches</NUMEX> under that wire,
stocked with their favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverages</ENAMEX>.

            What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX>'s
unparalleled severance package (assuming it is paid in full) has done is to
shine a huge spotlight on that dirty little secret. Perhaps now, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> will toughen up: If you get fired, they'll tell their top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>,
you get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>' pay, or whatever else it is that we give to ordinary workers
who get fired.

            Of course, had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> taken that stance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX> would almost certainly have refused to
join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. And then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> might have had to entice him by offering a
huge--and very likely much more costly--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">front-end</NUMEX> bonus. Still, in the light of
the fury that has erupted over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ovitz</ENAMEX>'s severance package, that front-end bonus
would have had better optics. As my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue</ENAMEX> said: "A large front-end bonus is
for coming to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. That's something positive. But a huge severance
package is for failing. And that's incomprehensible." I couldn't have put it
better.

         
      
   
