
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> Figure

            "Isn't he a little old to
have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>?" That was the perplexed comment that greeted my first
halting efforts to explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 6 and 9</TIMEX>. I
promptly began quoting the profundity to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and reflecting indignantly,
along with the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, on what a poor role model the overgrown youth
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>. As the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> have passed, though, I've had
an unnerving revelation: The evasive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is a great role
model for us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX>
are under siege. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are literate but not large, and omnipresent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">X-rated</ENAMEX> news, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> have been in for a lot of lip-biting,
brow-furrowing, and earnest throat-clearing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willy-nilly</ENAMEX>, we all turn into
Slick <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willies</ENAMEX>. At least I did. Herewith the unsubpoenaed diary of an artful
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dodger</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1 Weak-Kneed Denial</ENAMEX>: For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first two days</TIMEX> after the
scandal breaks, I snatch up the newspaper hurriedly at breakfast. When the
older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> makes a grab for it, I say, a nervous twitch in my jaw and a
certain tightness in my voice, "There is no interesting news." I go to work
worrying what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will hear in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, whether I've been too evasive, how
much more I'm going to have to say.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> Weaseling Out of It: The question comes over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>. I emphasize the lying part, and search for the formulation that will
permit me to avoid anything that directly links the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to sex (a concept
I am not even sure my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is able to define). Hence my choice of the term
"a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>." I readily agree that he is "a little old"--if it's true--and
quickly steer the discussion in another direction. That's easy, since they find
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> with the secret tape recorder fascinating.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">3 Dramatic Denial</ENAMEX>: When pressed about my own opinion a
day or so later, I say firmly, without jaw-twitching, that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has
done what he is accused of, he should definitely step down. That seems to
satisfy them.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4 Well-Timed Distraction</ENAMEX>: It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, and when the
State of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> message comes on at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00 p.m.</TIMEX>, I eagerly give in when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> plead from their beds to be allowed to come out and watch a little. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wholesome</ENAMEX>, boring television--their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> doing what grown-ups are supposed
to do: talk and talk and talk about nothing interesting. I give a little civics
lesson, and go on about the beauties of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX>. Their eyes glaze
over, and they don't protest when they are sent back to bed.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">5 Hunkering</ENAMEX> Down: For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the week</TIMEX> I follow a
modified limited-hangout strategy, saying things like, we'll just have to wait
and see, the evidence isn't in yet, we just aren't in a position to explain
anything more. Luckily, it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX>, not one of my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, who asks his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> at bedtime, "What's oral sex?"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">6 Conspiracy Hysteria</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, it looks like it
might be safe to turn on the television, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s news has featured, of
all things, reticence. Information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has been barred in Paula
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' lawsuit, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to be offering as much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> as hoped.
Quickly discovering my mistake-- "It's OK to have sex, just not all the time,"
declares a talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>--I turn off the tube. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> object. I rant about nosy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> and a media conspiracy to drag out this unpleasant business for
much too long. It's like "indoor" and "outdoor" voices, I sputter: Some things
should not be endlessly discussed in public; they're private matters. I believe
my own outburst. I'm also hoping that by irately staking out the high ground, I
can distract the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from their many questions about you know what. They look
at me calmly and figure it's a good moment to bargain for another cookie.

            

               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX> Damage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Control</ENAMEX>: The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> weekend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arrives</ENAMEX>, and I conclude that it's time to deal with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> on a less ad
hoc basis. I call a couple of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to compare notes and confer about
strategy (it turns out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> fielded the dread question with the old
deafness routine). I want something more organized to rely on, some material at
the ready. At my out-of-date public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>, I peruse books on the beauties of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX>-making. At my up-to-date local bookstore, I peruse books about how
touching parts of "your changing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>" feels so good. I have no idea what to
buy and suppose the best course is probably to get a little bit of everything.
This is an issue that is not going away. I'm quite sure my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> know
they're not getting the full version of events. I have the feeling they're
going to let me get away with it, and I think, on balance, that is all for the
best. They are, after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
