
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> Endgame

            "We
should do everything we can to get this resolved and find a way to have [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>] removed from office one way or another."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss.</ENAMEX>)
            

            "I
venture, therefore, to propose that a small bell be procured, and attached by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ribbon</ENAMEX> round the neck of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX>."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aesop</ENAMEX>'s
Fables
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are behaving
very responsibly on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. From the start they have made it clear that the scent
of scandal wafting through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> will not for a
single moment distract them from fulsome support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX> as
he faces down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butcher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>. "In matters of international relations,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>, as he
spurned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>' questions on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">l</TIMEX>'affaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>.

            But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is not the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who should worry about the loyalty of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guard</ENAMEX>. For by stipulating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> is the
sole token of success, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has staked out a comfortable position from which
to criticize any <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> restricts
the bombing to "surgical" (i.e., relatively low civilian-casualty) strikes and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> escapes, as he did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> can charge him with timid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> (unsurprising from a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> who dodged the draft). And if he
commits the ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> probably needed to eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> and lots of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> start dying, they can attack him for recklessness with our
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>' lives (unsurprising from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others</ENAMEX> die for him in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>).

            Of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> hasten to make it clear that
they don't actually advocate murdering <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>. Heaven forfend. Why, that
would violate a presidential order dating back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>, a
well-known <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>. And they certainly wouldn't want to be responsible for
putting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> into bloody combat with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">household guard</ENAMEX>.
That could make for really lousy television. Having echoed the recommendations
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> leading foreign-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> who called for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s ouster, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> beat a rhetorical retreat at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of last week</TIMEX>. He still wouldn't
settle for a "halfway deal," clarified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX>, but "I'm willing to support the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in doing what has to be done, whatever that is."

            Well,
whatever is that? Writing in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook</ENAMEX>" section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>, leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Perle</ENAMEX> tried to explain.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>," he wrote, "should encourage, recognize, help finance, arm
and protect with air power a new provisional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> broadly representative
of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>." That's a happy thought. I wonder if anyone has
talked it over with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>? In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eliot A. Cohen</ENAMEX> counsels
making "ousting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> a top priority," and pursuing that objective with
airstrikes that "number in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>" and lasting over
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>." I wonder what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pope</ENAMEX> would say about that.

            
Sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might get lucky. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> is not,
after all, immortal. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has made clear that it's not above
bombing a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> or two no matter who's inside. And this time, it says, its
weapons really are "smart." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> also plans to target the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqi</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guards</ENAMEX>' favorite toys--<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">artillery weapons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>, and other heavy
weapons--as well as their hardened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bunkers</ENAMEX> and munitions <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX>, hoping that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s "elite" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> will finally decide the price of propping up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dictator</ENAMEX> has become too high. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> was not a lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>,
despite his self-inflicted wounds, surely is.

            More
likely, though, the limited warfare proposed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> will come to
a less than fully satisfying conclusion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> obviously cares nothing for the
suffering of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, except to display their torn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> on television as
evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> evil. The chemical and biological weapons that are
supposedly the main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> are easily moved and
hidden. Even our noble <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX> allies aren't willing to lend us their air <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> could emerge strengthened (and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> tarnished) in the eyes of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> world.

            How much better, then--so much cleaner and more
satisfying--is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> solution. Let's just get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>. Makes you
wonder why no one thought of it before. Perhaps they didn't, because they had
in mind the conclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aesop</ENAMEX>'s famous fable--the one about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> who
decided to protect themselves from their "sly and treacherous" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>,
by tying a bell around its neck.

            "This proposal," wrote the
fabulist, "met with general applause, until an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> got up and said: 'That
is all very well, but who is to bell the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cat</ENAMEX>?' The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> looked at one another
and nobody spoke. Then the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> said: 'It is easy to propose impossible
remedies.' "

         
      
   
