
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act II</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>)
            

            
               The living room of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>. A visibly distraught <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paces</ENAMEX>. She picks up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , which feature <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>
Willey on the cover, from a coffee table. She looks at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> for a
moment, then throws them to the floor with a shriek. She goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, puts
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cubes</ENAMEX> in a glass, pours a drink, lights a cigarette. She walks to the
window and pulls back the drawn curtain to peek out. The door opens, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> enters. He drops his briefcase and removes his coat,
exhausted.
            

            
               ML: Where've you
been? You've been gone all f**king day.

            
               WG: They wouldn't
let me leave. There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of them. The only call they let me make was to
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. She'll be here on the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>.

            
               ML: What's their
bottom line?

            
               WG: It's not
pretty. They say we have no choice--we either take a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> special and call
it a day, or they walk. No book tie-in, no movie of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, no cable, no
foreign rights.

            
               ML: No foreign?
Look, if you think I'm going to sit here while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX> f**<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willey</ENAMEX> walks
off with this scandal, you're mistaken. I made this thing. I wiggled my
buns for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to get those pizzas into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval</ENAMEX>, and she thinks she can waltz
in with this [mock whine] "He put my hand there " crap? Have you
seen how many times they've played that clip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? I told you we'd strung them
out too long. I want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Sawyer</ENAMEX> down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> . I want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted f**</ENAMEX>king
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koppel</ENAMEX> doing a town hall meeting with me on a stool. I'll let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie</ENAMEX> stay the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to do an exclusive on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>." No-- [she
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">smiles</ENAMEX>] --make that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Lauer</ENAMEX> ...

            
               WG: They don't
think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> will play. After the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willey</ENAMEX> thing, you're starting to look
like a rerun. Plus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rather</ENAMEX>'s already spreading the word that everybody gets
those presidential trinkets when he comes back from trips.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ML: Think</ENAMEX>. We've
got to think.

            
               WG: There is one
shot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryant</ENAMEX> said if we back off the affidavit he could see a series. Maybe.
You know, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37</NUMEX> Visits , or something. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One week</TIMEX>, you're the only one he can
turn to when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> shuts down the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>; the next, you're bucking him up
for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX>. If it hits, there's a big syndication upside.

            
               ML: What's the
downside?

            
               WG: Pretty serious
perjury time [looks at his watch]. Why don't you refresh your
recollection for a while, and we'll talk when I'm back.

            
               ML: Where are you
off to?

            
               WG: 
               [Putting his
coat on] I've got drinks with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>, and then dinner with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton</ENAMEX>'s. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> may stop by with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ailes</ENAMEX> wants to talk
about this idea for a legal show that ... [catches himself; she turns
away] . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, it's business. I left the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> menu on the counter.

            
               ML: I'm sick of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">f**</ENAMEX>king <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>.

            
               WG: Then go
out.

            
               ML: Are you
kidding? I'll be mobbed.

            
               WG: No you won't.
There's no one out there.

            
               ML: What do you
mean, there's no one out there?

            
               WG: They're all off
staking out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guccione</ENAMEX> just offered her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> mil for a
nude.

            
               ML: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> mil? I
thought he offered me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> mil.

            
               WG: Have you seen
her legs? For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">51</TIMEX>, they're pretty damned good. Not that my opinion is important
here. [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> flings herself on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>, bursts into tears.] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX>, I kissed those little polkas when you were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3 weeks old</TIMEX>. Let's face
it--they're not so little anymore. And the nets like the idea of a peer for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--it's safer, more like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX>, less like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lolita</ENAMEX> . What can I say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kiddo</ENAMEX>? Those are the breaks. But a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> special ain't bad for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who got
her start licking stamps in the mail <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> ...

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> heads toward
door, humming "I Got the World on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">String</ENAMEX>." He pauses to fix his bow tie in
the mirror. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> pulls out a gun from under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>.]
            

            
               ML: 
               [In a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trance</ENAMEX>] Where will I go? What will I do?

            
               WG: 
               [Over his
shoulder] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweetie</ENAMEX>, don't sweat it. You drop <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few pounds</NUMEX>, you're a shoe-in
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weight Watchers</ENAMEX> goes looking for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fergie</ENAMEX>. And aren't they bringing
back <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> 
               Squares ? [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> assumes the classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> firing
position.] Listen, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehrer</ENAMEX> calls, just tell him he can get me [he
turns to face her] ... on the cell phone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>!

            
               ML: Creep!

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Blackout</ENAMEX>]
            

            
               [<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Shot</ENAMEX> rings
out]
            

            
               [Curtain]
            

         
      
   
