
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sound of One Hand Talking</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hope</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>, the venerable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> and chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> on race, told reporters that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> would refuse to hear from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of affirmative action in higher education. This policy seems both
wrong in principle and politically foolish. Why on earth have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> dedicated
to racial reconciliation and exclude one of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> views that need to be
reconciled on the most divisive racial issue? What harm could come from letting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have their say, compared with the harm of seeming to censor them?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s only explanation was an imperious, "I'm not certain what [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
affirmative-action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ward</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connerly</ENAMEX> could contribute to this
discussion."

            A senior
official working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> is a bit less opaque. "The point of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> is to help formulate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> policy. So why should we appoint
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who disagree with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>? Why hear testimony from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
vehemently disagree with him?" Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> said, "This
is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerner Commission</ENAMEX>," referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> appointed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> after the urban riots of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>'s mission was to be "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> and unprecedented conversation about race." But apparently the main
purpose of convening the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> meetings is to provide an occasion
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to unveil installments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s Race
Initiative--a yearlong parade of minipolicies. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, for instance, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> announced that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> would be divided among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX> different
nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> so they can bring more housing-discrimination cases.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> concocts these policies, without say from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. Behind the
inflated rhetoric, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> has only a slim mandate and little power.
It is not legally allowed to meet in private and cannot even write its own
final report--prerequisites for any self-respecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>.

            
Another bit of the explanation concerns the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>. In theory, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hope Franklin</ENAMEX> is the perfect chair
for an anodyne exercise in racial reconciliation. His public image is that of
an avuncular <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> gentleman. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Robinson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>:
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black chair of an integrated history <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>. His most important books
rewrote 90 years of wrongheaded, often racist, historiography of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reconstruction</ENAMEX>. (The black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbaggers</ENAMEX>, who ruled parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
following <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the Civil War</ENAMEX>, were sincere <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX>, he proved, not venal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX>.)

            But over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s lectures and essays on race have acquired a
pessimistic, angry edge. He laments the permanence of racism, which he feels is
now deeply entrenched in almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> institution. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>, who
researched briefs for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Brown vs. Board</ENAMEX> and marched in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Selma</ENAMEX>, expected the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">civil-rights</ENAMEX> revolution to remake society. Instead of dramatic change, he sees
only marginal improvement and enduring black urban poverty, job discrimination,
and even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Crow</ENAMEX> attitudes. And he says those who ignore the extent of this
racism are not only mistaken but also racist. They "have no interest in
achieving a color-blind society and would be horrified if we even approached
it."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> is old. The real power in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> rests with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Edley Jr. Edley</ENAMEX> plans the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> strategy
and will write the final report on race relations. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> term, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edley</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
characteristically nuanced (or, if you prefer, mushy and having-it-both-ways)
"mend it, don't end it" policy for affirmative action. But since leaving the
government, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edley</ENAMEX> has become more shrill. In a round-table debate on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly</ENAMEX> 's Web site, he repeatedly calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of
affirmative action "counterrevolutionaries." He says, "Though their opposition
to these measures is framed as principle, certainly their real goal is to
protect the current distribution of privilege and opportunity that has produced
white-male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> in virtually every sector." Most recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edley</ENAMEX> has called
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White , Abigail</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephan Thernstrom</ENAMEX>'s
anti-affirmative-action tome, a "crime against humanity."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> are
entitled to their views, which may even be correct. But should <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with such
strident opinions be responsible for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> on racial reconciliation? It seems
especially stupid for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to spew platitudes about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> of healing if its intention was to push <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of a contentious
debate.

         
      
   
