
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fund-Raising Phone Tag</ENAMEX>

            Nothing exposes the sham at
the heart of the campaign-finance hearings like the obsession over what type of
phone was used to solicit contributions. The phone rule asks not how
much money was promised over the line. It asks what kind of phone
was used in the solicitation. Was a cellular phone used? That's kosher. Car
phone? That's OK, too. A phone in a rented <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> steps away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX>?
Still OK. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>? Off with your head and into the arms of an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>!

            Meanwhile, as the hearings
made headlines, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> delivered a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50-billion</NUMEX> tax break to the
tobacco industry, which just happened to have given the party <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.9 million</NUMEX>.
Don't expect congressional hearings on that giveaway while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have
phone calls to prosecute.

            This
current phone obsession illustrates our declining standard of behavior for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. We once imposed sanctions on them for their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">improprieties</ENAMEX>. Then we started punishing them for the appearance of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impropriety</ENAMEX>. Today, we'll tolerate almost any outrage as long as its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> maintain the appearance of propriety. Genuine propriety would
still be nicer. But in its absence, we settle for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> who abide by the
rules (like the phones rules), which are devised to cloak impropriety in
propriety.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Research Service</ENAMEX>
believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Pendleton Act</ENAMEX>--the law <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> believe prohibits
office-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX> from calling from federal property for donations--doesn't apply
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. What's more, the act, which was passed
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only a few years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Graham Bell</ENAMEX>'s invention, didn't really
envision phones. The legislation was designed to keep elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from
using the majesty of their surroundings to shake down <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> doesn't know if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> is calling from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>--and he doesn't much care. The ethics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> have spelled out very specific rules for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to
follow--one of which prohibits making or taking fund-raising calls. All this
excess of zeal in using the right phones at the right time lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> pretend they're cleaning up the system without actually stemming the
flow of money.

            This guile over what
constitutes a legal solicitation explains the existence of several hot-sheet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotels on Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> where some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> go to make--and take--all their
fund-raising calls. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About 100</NUMEX> steps from the portal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rayburn House Office</ENAMEX>
Building, on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> floor of the annex to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>, stands a maze of cubicles separated by padded teal-green
dividers of the type you see separating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> who take your call for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginsu</ENAMEX> knives. Between less pressing business--like running the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> hunch <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 3-foot</NUMEX> wide slabs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formica</ENAMEX>, working
up a sweat dialing as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> as they can. Like most of us, they rarely
reach their prey on the first try. If they're lucky, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moneybags</ENAMEX> returns the
call, but usually by that time the importuning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> is back in his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Does he put up his feet and take the call from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moneybags</ENAMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moneybags</ENAMEX> is ready to talk? Or does he race down the stairs and cross the
street to his padded cell and call his benefactor back? You be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>.

            It's
absurd to think everyone uses the setup for dialing--so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, so little
space--and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> fudge when asked point-blank. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Burton</ENAMEX>, chairing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> investigation into finance abuses, had to equivocate when asked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX> whether he hadn't indeed taken fund-raising calls in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. "I
can't say never ... many times they [potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>] will call back at your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and therein, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> said, 'lies the rub.' "

            
A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have admitted that they
take, and make, the calls from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX> (cash is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>) bragged in an interview about raising money from his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> using a credit card. When challenged on the legality of that, he pointed
out correctly that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> had never prosecuted anyone under the
law, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethics Committee</ENAMEX> stood down. There were calls to hold an inquiry at
the time but, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , the matter died
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch McConnell</ENAMEX> adamantly opposed opening an investigation because
so many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> were probably guilty of the same thing. A former staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al D'Amato</ENAMEX>'s says that when a donor called, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> used
to try to stretch the phone cord into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> trying to
keep his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> from overhearing his conversation. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
Nickles, the pit-bull <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">questioner</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX>'s hearing, says that he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">witnessed Nickles</ENAMEX> taking calls from potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> number on an answering-machine message, asking for a donation. When
it was reported, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> said it was a one-time mistake. Political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> said on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, "Would you like me to embarrass <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> of
my former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> by telling you when I sat in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>[s] and they made
fund-raising phone calls?"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
may have agreed that calls should be made from an annex, but the executive
branch never did. In the immortal words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, there is no
controlling legal authority that says elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> can't make calls from
federal property. Putting aside the fact that both he and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> live on
federal property, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Research Service</ENAMEX> and a host of other legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> said that the law does not apply to phoning from either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            Of course, officeholders shouldn't dial for dollars from
their official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">digs</ENAMEX>. Not because dialing is evil, but because they shouldn't be
hustling money at all. As long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> continue to divert
attention from the fact that money flows in at the same rate that favors flow
out, the televised "fight" over their fund-raising methodologies will allow
them to pretend they're reforming the system.

            Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> is up
for sale. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Operators</ENAMEX> are standing by.

         
      
   
