
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workplace-Romance Double Standard</ENAMEX>

            Army <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derrick Robertson</ENAMEX>
got sentenced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day to four months</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for having consensual sex
with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-old</TIMEX> (female) private. Meanwhile, the media buzz is about another
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">workplace</ENAMEX> romance: between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Westin</ENAMEX>, in the midst of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">divorce</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherrie Rollins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of perennially
embarrassed political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Rollins</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollins</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> until, in
the midst of all the rumors about their liaison, they both got promoted.

            Clearly,
on the subject of workplace romance, the media and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> operate by
different rules. And the rules in the (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> are different
and nearly inseparable from his former deputy, had that relationship hanging
over his head when he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to withdraw his nomination to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>. Other appointments are never proposed and political campaigns are never
launched (in addition to those that are famously derailed, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX>'s)
because of the threat that some sexual misadventure will become front-page
news.

            Would a bit of consistency be small-minded in this case? We
can scarcely avoid love at work: To paraphrase <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Sutton</ENAMEX>, that's where the
opposite sex is. There are good reasons for strict rules in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, where
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superior</ENAMEX> can send a subordinate into life-threatening battle. Still, if you
throw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> into close <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million or so</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>,
under immense stress combined with stretches of boredom and laced with
loneliness, some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacks</ENAMEX> are going to fall in love--or lust--with some of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jills</ENAMEX>. And a difference in rank is a permeable barrier.

            Abuse of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> must be punished. But for consensual sex, has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> ever considered a
policy of "ask and tell," with direct reports being reassigned and the others
being left alone?

            
At the other extreme, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> (which won't say
whether it has any rules at all) is off-base too. Corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> don't
risk their lives in battle, but there is career death--or enhancement--at
stake, as well as fairness. Since the classic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Agee</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Cunningham</ENAMEX>--he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bendix</ENAMEX>; he promoted her rapidly to vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>; they denied an affair; she was forced out; they married--many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have instituted the policy that when a subordinate and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> get
involved, at least one gets reassigned.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Koppel</ENAMEX> simply blew
off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westin</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollins</ENAMEX> affair to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , citing human
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">frailties</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> representative says the matter "doesn't deserve the
attention it's getting." Yet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, like all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, is quick to pounce
when the lifestyles of the rich and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, go astray.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> is proceeding against other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> under a draconian code that can
transform consensual sex into constructive rape, if it happens across ranks.
But there must be some middle way between that sad spectacle and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s
above-it-all double standard. In or out of uniform, we're all under the sway of
the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
