
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Ponzi Scheme to Shell Game</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Privatizing Social Security</ENAMEX>
is a solution in search of a problem. Oh, the problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is
real enough. But "privatization"--the hot policy idea of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>--simply
doesn't address the problem. It's as if you were crawling across the desert,
desperately thirsty, and you meet a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who says, "What you need is some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lemonade</ENAMEX>." You say <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> would suffice. He says, "Oh, but lemonade is much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nicer</ENAMEX>. Here"--handing you a packet of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lemonade powder</ENAMEX>--"just add <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and
stir."

            In this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s report by a government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, a majority
supported various forms of partial privatization. And lemonade (privatization)
is an appealing drink in many ways. But it's a testament to the agenda-setting
influence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> that, on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, we're debating
the merits of lemonade, when the real issue is: Where do you get the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> privatization was ably discussed several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX> in our "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee of Correspondence</ENAMEX>." But in this case, at least, that
discussion seems not to have provided the dialectical pathway toward ultimate
and inevitable truth that we had hoped for. So, let us try again. And--ladies
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gentlemen</ENAMEX>--I will now attempt to discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> with no numbers,
no graphs, and not a single use of the word "actuarial."

            According
to polls, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Generation X</ENAMEX> believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFOs</ENAMEX> than do in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX>. Of course, those who delight in this factoid never tell you how many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gen-Xers</ENAMEX> actually believe in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFOs</ENAMEX>--which might be the alarming bit. But,
because it serves their particular generational self-pity, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gen-Xers</ENAMEX> seem more
willing than older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> to grasp the essential truth about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>,
which is that it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ponzi</ENAMEX> scheme. Payments from later <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> finance
payouts to earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. The ratio of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> taking money out to workers
putting money in is rising, due to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> having fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living longer. This means the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ponzi</ENAMEX> scheme cannot go on. The famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>--an inspiration of our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Stein</ENAMEX>--holds, in brief, that what
cannot go on, won't. The issue is how exactly this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ponzi</ENAMEX> scheme will stop going
on.

            
Discussions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> "crisis"
often confuse <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different problems. First, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> in their peak
earning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> currently brings in more revenue than it pays
out in benefits. The surplus is invested in government bonds. These are special
government bonds. Statistics about the federal deficit--and both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>'
promises to balance the budget over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>--count the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
Security surplus as revenue, and don't count these bonds as debt. But within a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> surplus will evaporate, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> will
have to start drawing on this nest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">egg</ENAMEX>. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to honor these bonds
will require huge borrowing (essentially replacing these IOUs to itself with
real IOUs to private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>) or a huge tax increase.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> problem is that
even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> honors these bonds in full--principal and interest--a
point will be reached, well into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
"trust fund" is exhausted, and not enough money is coming in to pay the
currently promised benefits.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>
problem is that even if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s benefit promises can somehow be kept, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> represents a much worse return on "investment" (taxes paid in) for
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> than past and present <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> have enjoyed. This is partly
because some minor benefit reductions are scheduled already (raising the
retirement age slightly and gradually). It is mainly because younger people
will have paid much higher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> taxes throughout their working
lives. The average return on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gen-Xers' Social Security</ENAMEX> investments will almost
certainly be worse than they could have done by investing in the stock
market.

            Whether all this adds up to a crisis is a matter of
rhetorical taste. The fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gen-Xers</ENAMEX> will get a worse deal from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>--mainly because part of the money they put
into the system was, in effect, transferred to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>--doesn't seem
horribly tragic to me. Even after this transfer we will still, on average, be
better off than our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were. Where's the injustice? Problem <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> will run dry many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades from now</TIMEX>, depends on essentially impossible
predictions about the distant future and, in any case, can be solved by very
minor adjustments, if they're made pretty soon.

            No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is a real problem. It's
hard to imagine the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> actually reneging on its IOUs. But it's also
hard to see an easy way of avoiding that.

            For all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> problems there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX>: cut benefits, raise revenues, or
borrow. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Privatization</ENAMEX> is not a solution. Privatization means allowing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to invest for themselves all or part of what they and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> put into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>. Whatever the merits of this idea--and there
are some--it does not address the problem at hand. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is a Ponzi
scheme. Current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX>-in are financing current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX>-out, not their own
retirements. Privatization assumes an end to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ponzi</ENAMEX> scheme: Every generation
saves for its own retirement. But you can't get there from here without someone
paying twice--for the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> and the current one--or someone
getting less (or someone--i.e., the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>--borrowing a lot of money).

            
Privatization <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> sometimes admit to
this as a transitional problem. But it is not a transitional problem. It
is the entire problem. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Aaron</ENAMEX> pointed out in the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>" discussion, if you could pour in enough money to pay for the
"transition" to privatization, the system would no longer be out of balance.
The problem, or crisis, would be solved. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Privatization</ENAMEX> would not be needed.

            You have to watch closely as
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">privatizers</ENAMEX> describe their schemes. They play a shell game: Take this part
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> tax and convert it into a mandatory savings
contribution; take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s benefit and divide it into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts; give everybody
this new account and that minimum guarantee; take this shell and put it there
and bring that shell over here, and--hey presto! But no matter how you divvy it
up, the same money can't be used twice. That is the problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> now, and it is the problem with privatization. All you've said when
you endorse privatization is that if there were <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, it should be used
to make lemonade. Not obviously wrong, but not terribly helpful.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Privatization</ENAMEX> is a shell game in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> way. It is supposed to bring more
money into the system because returns on private securities are generally
higher than returns on government bonds. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the recent commission
who oppose full privatization supported investing part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s
accumulated surplus in the private marketplace. But (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> pointed out in
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>"), every dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> invests privately, instead of
lending to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> (as happens now), is an extra dollar the government
must borrow from private capital markets to finance the national debt. The net
effect on national savings, and therefore on overall economic growth, is zilch.
Every dollar more for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> is a dollar less for someone else.

            If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> manages to achieve a higher return, by
investing some or all of its assets privately, the rest of the economy will
achieve a lower return, by having more of its assets in government bonds. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essence</ENAMEX>, the gain to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> will be like a tax on private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>--an odd thing for conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">think tanks</ENAMEX> to be so enthusiastic
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX>. Also, the arrival of this huge pot of money looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> will
depress returns in the private economy, while the need to attract an equally
huge pot of money into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> to replace the lost revenue will increase
the returns on government bonds. Result? The diversion will be at least partly
self-defeating.

            The size and security of
future retirement benefits ultimately depend on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s general
prosperity at that time in the future. Checks to be cashed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2055</TIMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whoops</ENAMEX>! there's a number) will be issued in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2055</TIMEX>, whatever promises we make or
don't make <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The most direct way for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> to affect future
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosperity</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX> pointed out in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>") is to increase national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX>, of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> reserve is part, by trimming benefits
and/or increasing revenues. Since we have to do that anyway--even as a prelude
to privatization--why don't we do it first? Then we can argue about
privatization at our leisure.

         
      
   
