
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aborting Birth Control</ENAMEX>

            As a bill lifting an embargo
on money for international family-planning programs passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 25</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> congratulated themselves for their concern for poor women
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. They should hang their heads instead. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>, which passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>, authorizes far less than was
appropriated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, proving again that, on both sides of the debate,
support for family planning takes <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> place to the controversy over
abortion.

            This
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s congressional debate might seem like progress since both sides in the
abortion debate agreed on the fundamentals of family planning. Birth control
can improve health for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> worldwide. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> die each year
as the result of unsafe abortion, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have babies too close together
have a sharply increased chance of dying from postpartum hemorrhage. Babies
born too closely spaced or into large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are less likely to survive their
early childhood. In a report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> estimated
that with family planning, there will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3 billion</NUMEX> fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2050</TIMEX> than without it.

            Anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch McConnell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>) concluded that
everyone agrees about the importance of birth control for the well-being of
developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. Even in the sharper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> debate, there was no
substantial dispute that overpopulation strains natural resources, contributing
to environmental degradation, unemployment, and hunger. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shays</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>) said, "One mouth can eat, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> mouths can share, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> mouths
will sometimes go hungry, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> mouths starve."

            Even on the core issue of the
relationship of birth control to abortion, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>
sometimes found it hard to tell who was on which side. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chile</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and elsewhere, abortion rates have dropped sharply with the
increased availability of birth control. Since the illegal-abortion rate
remains high in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where abortion is outlawed, contraception may be the
only effective way to bring abortion rates down.

            "I think
our aim in humanitarian efforts ought to be to ... make the world
abortion-free," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Smith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>), who has devoted much of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to leading anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. But he added, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Family</ENAMEX>
planning certainly plays a part in that."

            
Yet, despite this apparent consensus, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
has cut birth-control funds deeply in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>. Abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>
insist on saddling family-planning appropriations with restrictions that deny
funding to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that perform abortions or give abortion counseling.
These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are already prohibited from spending <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> money on
abortion-related activities, but abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX> argue that giving them money for
birth control will let them divert other resources to providing abortions.
Abortion-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> argue that it would be inefficient to separate the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> activities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where abortions are legal. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
refused to accept such restrictions in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996 and 1997</TIMEX> budgets, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
leadership retaliated by threatening to slash and delay family-planning
appropriations. Rather than cave, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> took the cut.

            The standoff cost
international population programs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a third</NUMEX> of their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> funding
levels. Furthermore, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">both years</TIMEX>, funds were embargoed until late in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> leading family-planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> calculated that as a
result of the cuts, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4 million</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will have unwanted pregnancies, of
whom <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.6 million</NUMEX> will have abortions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eight thousand</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will die during
pregnancy and childbirth (in part from unsafe abortions), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">134,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>
will die.

            Yet,
despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' action to lift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s spending embargo, and the seeming
alignment of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> behind birth-control programs, these programs are
likely to be seized hostage again in the abortion battle, for neither side
seems prepared to compromise.

            Would <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> ever accept an unconditional release of money
for birth-control aid? The intensity of his floor remarks suggests not: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We</ENAMEX>
should not compartmentalize our view and say, 'If they do this with our money
that is OK, and who gives a darn what else they do with the rest of their
money.' Abortion is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse! It kills <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>!"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to
push a measure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> that would spend as much birth-control money as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> asked might seem like progress. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> respect his bill was more
generous than the alternative that passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, in that it would release
the embargoed funds at a faster rate. But his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> suspect that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s
was a cheap generosity, since he could count on the restrictions he demanded to
draw a presidential veto. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Wolfe</ENAMEX>, boasts that by
offering that bill, "We have called their bluff."

            For their
part, family-planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> seem equally
adamant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Cohen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan Guttmacher Institute</ENAMEX> explains that accepting
abortion restrictions would stymie efforts to set up effective family-planning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branches</ENAMEX> in the developing world. She says that in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> where birth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> has been unavailable, almost all indigenous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> they can work with
have some abortion ties. Furthermore, even if complying with abortion
restrictions were feasible, "You just can't compromise on a principle." Not
even if it means accepting funding cuts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guttmacher Institute</ENAMEX> concluded
would lead to an increase in unwanted pregnancies, maternal deaths, and infant
mortality. "It's a very steep price," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> concedes.

            
And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s votes are but a skirmish in
the crusades. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> promises, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]his will be the beginning of a long fight
with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">105</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Congress</ENAMEX> on this. ... We will be back on the
authorizing bills, we will be back on the appropriations bills when the fiscal
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 and 1999</TIMEX> funds come up, and again we are going to continue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this 1997</TIMEX>
effort as well."

            Anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Hall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>) points to the deep cuts in international family planning and
the angry battle going on around him and reflects, "In our effort to legislate
around here, sometimes we become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX>, and we hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we are trying
to help." We do indeed.

         
      
   
