
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Medici With Your Money</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James A. Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
of both the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX>, has become, at age
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">53</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medici</ENAMEX>. But even though he makes some <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> a year
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, he is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropist</ENAMEX> with his own money. The fount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">generosity</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>, funded out of its profits, which gives
away <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> and elsewhere.

            Of
course, it is common <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> for corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> to enjoy the perks, status,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gratitude</ENAMEX>, and frisson of generosity that comes from giving away the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>' money. What makes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX> special is that it is essentially
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' money that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> is giving away. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX> enjoys a massive
government subsidy, and its charitable contributions are part of a vital
corporate strategy to keep it that way.

            Indeed, preserving its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> subsidy is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">central</ENAMEX> mission, which helps to explain why a fellow like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Johnson</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of this <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$325 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> has only a modest business
background. A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX>, he was a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Mondale</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> and later <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mondale</ENAMEX> lost the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice presidency</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX>, founded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Strategies</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> that gave advice to business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX>. Later he
performed similar services for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearson Lehman</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mondale</ENAMEX> ran for president
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of his campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxine Isaacs</ENAMEX>, who later
became his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, was the campaign's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>. Considered likable and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">charming</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isaacs</ENAMEX> were, in a small way, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matalin</ENAMEX> of
that period: the hot political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> and
became its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>.

            
Established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> as a government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX> is a financial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">behemoth</ENAMEX>
with assets greater than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citibank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells Fargo</ENAMEX> combined. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, it became
a private, for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. Its stock is publicly traded; its Web site ends
in a ".<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>." Basically what it does is buy home mortgages from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and
package them into what are called "mortgage-backed securities," which it sells
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> then can use their own money for more mortgages. By
giving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> indirect access to the world's capital markets, this device
makes it easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. That is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>'s social
function. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, however, that function is served by many private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mortgage-backed</ENAMEX> securities are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a roaring</TIMEX> business.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>, though, has special privileges. Its
It is exempt from state and local taxes, so it escapes having to pay an
estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the parched</TIMEX> District <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">treasury</ENAMEX>. Most
important, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>'s securities come with an implicit guarantee that they
are backed by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. This allows it to raise money at an
interest rate that is lower than what a normal private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> has to
pay.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mae</ENAMEX> has it both ways about the federal guarantee. Its securities are required
to say in so many words that they are not backed by the full faith and
credit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. But nobody believes it. Why? As a
report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional Budget Office</ENAMEX> explains, "What the
government appears to withhold with one requirement, it provides with a host of
other legal provisions." The capital markets are persuaded that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>'s
bonds are backed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>, while denying the guarantee
exists, fights to preserve the arrangement that makes it possible.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> also notes that, since it has never missed a
payment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> have not yet had to shell out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a penny</NUMEX>. But that is like
saying that fire insurance is worthless if you've never had a fire. Just ask
other private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> if they would like to have a free federal guarantee of
their debts! The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, if it wanted to, could sell its backing to private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrowers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> points out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s guarantee of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>'s debt is just like a giveaway of federal land or hydroelectric
power. The fact that no money changes hands doesn't mean it has no cost.

            And what
is the cost? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> calculates that the federal guarantee saves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one-half</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> in interest. That was worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $4 billion</NUMEX> to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> (plus <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">another $2.6 billion</NUMEX> to a similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie Mac</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Home Mortgage Corp.</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> figures that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billion</NUMEX> of that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $4 billion</NUMEX> federal subsidy was passed along to
lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 billion</NUMEX> went into the pockets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> salaries resemble those
of a real private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of its size, even though its size is largely a
function of the federal guarantee and its business is not as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> as size
alone would suggest. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> are in many ways glorified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
makes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Raines</ENAMEX> made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">well over $2 million</NUMEX> in his last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> before he joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Management and Budget</ENAMEX>. Other politicos
feeding at the trough include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Affairs John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>, who was on leave <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>, and
Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Law Robert Zoellick</ENAMEX>, who was an aide
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Baker</ENAMEX>.

            Not
surprisingly, then, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>'s public-relations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> is unparalleled in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Its charitable contributions, through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae Foundation</ENAMEX>,
are a crucial part. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> sprinkles contributions on everything:
homeless shelters as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy Center</ENAMEX>, and powerful think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX> (which, to its credit, has issued reports
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">decrying Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>'s privileged status).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX> sports television ads depicting young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>,
plucky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>, and others being helped by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>. "Showing America a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Way Home</ENAMEX>" is the slogan. That is also the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s recent book--a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">175</NUMEX>-page tract that pleads for still more subsidies while cloaking itself in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">high-mindedness</ENAMEX>. The book is a parody of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett</ENAMEX>'s , serving up quotes
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jefferson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Rosenblatt</ENAMEX> with equal pomposity. The cover
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shows Johnson</ENAMEX>, a bland-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in full business attire, on the porch of an
all-American <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that looks a tad too small to be his. The flag is
conveniently draped in the background. The back jacket is crammed with
bipartisan blurbs--from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Feinstein</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ann</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of labor. Acknowledgments are offered to
any number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> big shots, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shrum</ENAMEX>, who is
thanked for his "considerable editing skills." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, the text could have done
with more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shrum</ENAMEX>, who, let's hope, did not pen the line, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> is about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">freedom</ENAMEX>."

            The book's subtitle is
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Expanding Opportunities for Home Ownership</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s idea of opportunity
ranges from the unobjectionable--like giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> better software for mortgage
applications--to a bunch of new subsidies, many of which, sadly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> may enact. The truth about government subsidies for
real estate--including the granddaddy: the home-mortgage-interest deduction--is
that they do very little to make housing more affordable. Part gets siphoned
off by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middlemen</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>. Most of the rest melts away into higher
real-estate prices. The main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX> of any subsidy for real estate is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who owns the property at the time the subsidy is instituted, not the
future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>, unfortunately,
has become a model. There is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddie Mac</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>'s smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> in the
housing market. And there is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sallie Mae</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Loan Marketing Association</ENAMEX>),
which creates a similar secondary market in subsidized student loans.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Organizations</ENAMEX> combining public and private functions appeal to the woolly ideal
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government-business partnership</ENAMEX>. They seem to represent a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> way, a
healthy distrust of government and the market, levelheadedness leavened by a
kind heart. More often, as with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fannie Mae</ENAMEX>, what you get is the worst excesses
of both.

         
      
   
