
   
   
      
         
            Selling <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seals of Approval</ENAMEX>

            Walk into any
home-improvement megastore, find their wall o' carbon-monoxide detectors, and
you'll notice that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> product carries the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lung Association</ENAMEX> seal
on its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Sensors</ENAMEX>. Does this mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Sensors' CO</ENAMEX> detectors are
the best? Better than those made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Alert, Nighthawk</ENAMEX>, or others? Not
exactly. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Sensors</ENAMEX> ranked <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> in tests conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consumer</ENAMEX>
Reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> were deemed "not acceptable" by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, thanks to a design flaw--since fixed--that could have short-circuited
the device.

            What the seal really tells
you is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> have found a new way to fatten their budgets--by
exclusive contracts with private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX>
recently sold its logo to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida Department of Citrus</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. It gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">another million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SmithKline Beecham</ENAMEX>, which puts the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> logo on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Nicoderm-</ENAMEX>brand nicotine patches. Not to be outdone, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">makers</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicotrol</ENAMEX>, a competing patch product, recently inked a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> deal with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALA</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 million</NUMEX>.

            The deals
are exclusive, but they're not endorsements. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> don't test the
products or ensure that the highest-quality ones get their logos.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Charities</ENAMEX> say they need the money. Competition from
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of other nonprofits makes fund raising difficult. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX> says its
surveys show that the public supports such contracts, so long as they raise
plenty of money for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> and don't conflict with its basic mission.

            But
getting in bed with corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> carries sizable risks. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Charities</ENAMEX> "selling
their halos"--as some have put it--risk damaging their reputations as sources
of independent information. And in some cases they seem to be skating close to
the edge of propriety, if not the law.

            
Take, for example, the sticky problem of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> benefiting from what appears to be false advertising. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX>
wouldn't pony up the bucks for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>'s logo if they didn't think it gave
them a competitive edge. Why would they think that it would? "Because at least
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> are going to be misled into thinking this is a special thing. I
think it's flat-out misleading," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Lawry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> deals have already
fallen through because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> concluded the same thing.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Heart</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> dropped its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HeartGuide Seal</ENAMEX> program in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, after federal
regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> complained it would mislead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. The program, started
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, endorsed, in exchange for a sizable fee, food products that met
certain standards. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> refused to let the AHA
put its seal on any products it regulated.

            Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McNeil Consumer Products</ENAMEX> agreed to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $2 million</NUMEX> to settle a
complaint filed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX> with regard to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthritis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>-brand <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX>. Ads for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> claimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> were somehow
"new"--although they were just plain old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX>. The ads said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthritis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> "helped create" the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>, though it didn't. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeil</ENAMEX> dropped the
product after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX> complained, even though a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> spokesman
says it "exited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> because it wasn't achieving its goals." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNeil</ENAMEX>, he
added, still donates <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AF</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Companies</ENAMEX> admit that the logos help sales, thanks to the
appearance of an endorsement where none exists. "It definitely helps us sell
our products," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Paris</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SmithKline Beecham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> of
Nicoderm, "because it provides the consumer with a more credible resource
behind this particular product." Well, not behind it per se. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> adds, "don't endorse the product at all."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sensors</ENAMEX> has seen its detector sales skyrocket from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">under $1 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> to
well over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALA</ENAMEX> logo help? "I certainly think it
helped sales of our detectors," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Lupynec</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>.

            
So how do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> respond? They say they
try to make clear on the label that it reflects a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>," not a product
endorsement. But they admit that at least some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> are being misled by
the logo.

            "Is there an implied
endorsement? The answer to that has to be 'yes.' There is no way around it,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Dickinson</ENAMEX>.

            "That's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gray</ENAMEX> area," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kirkwood</ENAMEX>, who is with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALA of Metropolitan Chicago</ENAMEX>.
"If you're standing there looking at the shelf, you might say, 'Hmm, maybe I'll
buy the product with the logo as opposed to the one that doesn't have any.'
That's a reality." Kirkwood was instrumental in putting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Sensors deal together. He later served on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Sensors</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, but insists
there was no quid pro quo.

            Another land mine: Can <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> that cut lucrative deals
with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> be counted on to provide accurate information about health
and safety issues related to those products? Heightened fear about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poisonings</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> might help sell detectors, but only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a year
die this way, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Safety Council</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nearly five</NUMEX> times as
many die of suffocation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> at home. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CO</ENAMEX> deaths were falling steadily
long before home detectors hit the market. Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ALA</ENAMEX> going to tell you about
that? Nicotine patches work <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 20 percent</NUMEX> of the time. True, they often
help hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> quit when other systems have failed. But the most
effective way to quit is to save your money and go cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX>. Are the health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> going to advertise this fact?

            Getting too cozy with
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> carries other risks as well.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lung Association</ENAMEX>, for instance, has been attacked in the past for at
least giving the appearance of lobbying on behalf of corporate interests that
have opened their checkbooks.

            
Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALA</ENAMEX> and some of its state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affiliates</ENAMEX> started bashing the cement-kiln industry, which was trying to get
permits to burn toxic waste. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALA</ENAMEX> complained that the practice was hazardous
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s health. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> enough. But it happens that at the same time, the
charity was getting grants totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $150,000</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Responsible Thermal Treatment</ENAMEX>, which represented the kiln industry's direct
competitor in the waste-incineration business.

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cement Kiln Recycling Coalition</ENAMEX> asked about this at a
meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said that state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, which are relatively
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">autonomous</ENAMEX>, ran the campaigns. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> added that the charity
would be happy to take money from the kiln industry, too, provided the grants
came with no strings attached. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1995</TIMEX>, the kiln industry filed a
complaint with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX>, charging that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALA</ENAMEX> was being
paid to lobby on behalf of a commercial interest, a violation of its nonprofit
tax status.

            And, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1994</TIMEX>, the national <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALA</ENAMEX> took out an ad in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pittsburgh Post-Gazette</ENAMEX> promoting a centralized auto-emissions test
program called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E-Check</ENAMEX>--which used testing equipment made by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Envirotest Systems Corp.</ENAMEX>--over another kind of testing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>. The
advertisement generated a flood of phone calls to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALA</ENAMEX>'s Western
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> from outraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, said the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX>'s executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>.

            It turns out that Envirotest
had also been a generous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> to the national <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ALA</ENAMEX>, giving a total of more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> to the charity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between '94 and '95</TIMEX>, according to tax filings.

            Given these risks, why pursue
these relationships? Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> plead poverty. "You've got something like
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18,000</NUMEX> new nonprofits in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 10 years</TIMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirkwood</ENAMEX>. "And
they're all competing for the same dollar." But budgets for the big charities
have seen healthy gains in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ALA</ENAMEX>'s national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> saw its
total revenues climb <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 30 percent</NUMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> before it signed its
deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Sensors</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>'s tax filings. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cancer</ENAMEX> Society revenues have climbed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 40 percent</NUMEX> so far in this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>.

            More likely, it's reluctance
on the part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to part with money without seeing any direct benefit.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nonprofits</ENAMEX> can't count on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> to give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> just
because they want to be good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, who once worked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALA.</ENAMEX>
"Now everything has to be linked to a stronger benefit."

         
      
   
