
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smokey</ENAMEX> and the Bandits

            The cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> have
become national pariahs, endlessly reviled as heartless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX> of death and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. But amid the chorus of demands for punishment of the industry, one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">profiteers</ENAMEX> continues to enjoy public sympathy and the favor of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>.

            You might
expect that any financial settlement would require compensation not only from
those who packaged and marketed cigarettes but also from those who made a
living growing and selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> to those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> have
succeeded in portraying themselves as innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> deserving to be made
whole by the settlement.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX> trooped to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> to request
continued indulgence. "I was born to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Kuegel</ENAMEX> of
Owensboro, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>, told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Agriculture Committee</ENAMEX>. "I do not like being
condemned because I was not born to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmer</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grower</ENAMEX>." Kuegel
and his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> would like not only to preserve the current
tobacco program, perhaps the most lucrative of federal agriculture subsidies,
but also to get a share of the loot from the proposed tobacco deal. "We deserve
to share equitably in any proceeds distributed as a result of a settlement,"
said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Carolina Farm Bureau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Jenkins</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> appear ready to accede to their demands. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Commerce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Bliley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, said financial arrangements would have
to be made to prevent hardship. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendell Ford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>, has made it known
that he will not go along with any deal that includes the dismantling of the
tobacco program. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco crusaders don't dare disparage tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX>. "There was never any intention to hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobacco-Free</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX>.

            
Among the changes demanded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
when he finally took a (vague) position on the proposed settlement was greater
protection for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>: "We have a responsibility to
these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. They haven't done anything wrong. They haven't done anything
illegal. They're good, hard-working, taxpaying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, and they have not
caused this problem." The proposals being discussed on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> include
paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> in aid to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX> switch to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> and compelling
cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> to use more domestic leaf in their products.

            The
existing tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX>, however, looks as though it will survive--which is
even more notable, considering that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> enacted legislation
putting most other farm subsidies on the path to extinction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobacco farmers</ENAMEX>
are especially loath to relinquish the embrace of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>
because they have been treated with unusual generosity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX> insist the
program shouldn't be called a subsidy because it costs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> virtually
nothing. But the only reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> get off easy is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> don't.
The program works by requiring either a federal acreage allotment to grow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tobacco</ENAMEX>, a marketing quota to sell it, or both. By thus restricting output, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> keeps prices artificially high. If the price drops
too low, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will effectively buy it at a floor price. To prevent
low-cost foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> from snatching away sales, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> also limits
imports. It all adds up to a very good deal.

            The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is often accused of gross hypocrisy
for discouraging smoking while rewarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> for growing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weed</ENAMEX>. In fact,
there is a weird and wholly accidental consistency in these policies. By
raising prices, the tobacco program reduces smoking, though to only a modest
extent. (The cigarette industry sells <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $50 billion</NUMEX> worth of cigarettes
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, but the tobacco in them costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only about $2 billion</NUMEX>.) But it
certainly encourages the growing of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glickman</ENAMEX> toured <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX> told him they
didn't want to have to raise other <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> because an acre of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> can yield a
bigger profit than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">50 acres</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Kentucky</ENAMEX> study estimated
the average net per<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-acre</NUMEX> profit on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $1,800</NUMEX>--compared with
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$73</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soybeans</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX>.

            So it's
easy to understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> want to maintain the status quo. The
question is why the rest of us should be prepared to give them what they want.
True, they are honest, hard-working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> who didn't break the law--but the
same thing could be said for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX> of the cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and no one has given any thought to
their bleak fortunes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glickman</ENAMEX> defended the program as a way to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> from
getting big and corporate. But that's been done only by rewarding inefficiency.
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Corn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> could make a living off <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">100-acre</NUMEX> spreads, too, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> was willing to tightly limit output and mandate high prices.
Besides, the specter of agribusiness <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> taking over <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> is largely a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fantasy</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 12 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> farmland is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, and
most of those are small, family-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>.

            
Nor can the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> be depicted as hapless
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bystanders</ENAMEX> blindsided by an unfair change in government policy. If the
cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> are guilty of an assault on public health, those who grew
tobacco certainly deserve to be charged as accomplices. Paying them a share of
any settlement to make up for the loss of sales due to expected reductions in
smoking borders on the absurd. When a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builder</ENAMEX> gets socked with a damage award
because one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> falls down, we don't allot a share of the money to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcontractors</ENAMEX> on the theory that they will lose work if business falls
off. Any help should come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> at large, not from the purported
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of smoking that the settlement is supposed to compensate. But the help
should be modest. Like everyone else, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> have known for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that
the future of the cigarette business was not bright. If they failed to prepare
for a decline in demand or the dismantling of the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX>, that's their
fault. The rest of us shouldn't feel the obligation to keep supporting them in
style.

            What they deserve is no more
nor less than they would deserve even if there were no cigarette deal (which
there may not be). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lugar</ENAMEX>, who chairs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture Committee</ENAMEX>,
proposes to buy them out over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> and then leave tobacco to the market.
His <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s farm bill, which phased out most other commodity
programs while providing transitional assistance during the changeover. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobacco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">growers</ENAMEX> managed to avoid that fate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. If they're not willing to settle
for it now, let them go cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
