
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh mostly we watch college basketball
 	
 	
 		oh do you
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh you know we're from uh originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville Kentucky</ENAMEX> and they've got a fairly decent ball club down there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		it's been around for a long time hadn't it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as long as i can remember
 	
 	
 		yeah who's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>'s name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny Crum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that sounds familiar
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny Crum</ENAMEX>'s pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he uh
 		i don't know he's got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollar</NUMEX> contract when he quits
 	
 	
 		and with pro ball you mean
 	
 	
 		uh no with uh uh when he quits they'll give him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		who will the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny Crum</ENAMEX> uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> gives him <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> when he quits
 	
 	
 		well why that doesn't make sense does it
 	
 	
 		because
 		because he's good
 		and it's giving him an incentitive to stay around and
 		uh he's been there for something twenty something years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i really don't know the uh full reason why they're doing it but they've got confidence in the man
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well to me i'd want to quit
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh he gets too much he gets you know he
 	
 	
 		oh that just shows how much he gets paid anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		he's got a TV show down there and everything
 	
 	
 		really
 		where are y'all living now
 	
 	
 		in Denison
 	
 	
 		Denison
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah do you ever watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not a lot uh i i don't really care for pro basketball i like college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and pro football
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but i do watch some uh pro football basketball mostly it's uh
 		i watch certain players
 	
 	
 		yeah like who
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Johnson</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah he's good too
 	
 	
 		and i can name a few more i just can't think of their names right off hand
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i used to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> in fact of of the pro sports i guess it's my favorite it's just that i haven't watched many sports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> or in the past several years
 	
 	
 		yeah well the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> double A tournament's going on right now
 		and uh
 		i haven't watched it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>'s out of it this year
 	
 	
 		how come
 	
 	
 		oh they just uh
 		they had three
 		tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who had uh didn't meet the requirements you know uh
 	
 	
 		the uh academic requirements uh-huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah academically they didn't meet the requirements so they couldn't play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> so <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of them they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s sitting here putting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> fingers in my face  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but they weren't very good but they was uh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> hurts
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> hurt
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		i think they got
 		i think that was almost everyone of them that he recruited uh recruited for this year
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		he didn't and none of them got to play
 	
 	
 		yeah well no wonder they're out of it
 	
 	
 		uh sorry
 	
 	
 		i said no wonder they're out of it
 	
 	
 		yeah well they put up a good show they did pretty good for uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know having all short <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh we only had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		one we only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> senior on the team
 	
 	
 		so they'll be back
 	
 	
 		so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> they'll be back and back with a vengeance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well do you agree with that requirement that they meet those uh academic
 	
 	
 		in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> yeah because it's reasonable now uh you know me with me being from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> i'm going to say at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> is unfair because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>'s got the highest uh
 		uh
 		the line the line the line drawn i don't know the correct word for it  but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>'s is higher than most other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i didn't realize it could vary from state to state or university
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they they vary from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> not just state to state university
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		if they'd been anywhere else i don't you know i don't care where it was anywhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> they could have played but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX> they was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> they couldn't play
 	
 	
 		how does that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> feel about that
 	
 	
 		oh he's highly upset he uh went on uh
 		he was on uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> i can't remember which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and got blasted uh you know they uh that's where it all came about because he said a few remarks of uh on that uh talk show or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		news show and then they uh next thing you know well they're in violation if they don't uh if they stop if they keep playing they're in violation
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny Crum</ENAMEX> ran his mouth a little bit too much
 	
 	
 		him
 		
 
 		on national TV
 	
 	
 		on national TV he messed up but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's all politics
 	
 	
 		probably that's probably what it mostly is i i can't say say that for sure but you know uh right now though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>'s just now getting off of a uh their
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		suspension from playing on uh TV and then games
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> they'll be uh playing and i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis State</ENAMEX> was even in a few of them where they got uh couldn't play
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		in uh games and stuff because of uh
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Dana Kirk</ENAMEX> that was their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> down there uh or over there
 		uh he
 		he was uh we was living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> for a while that's why i know about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh he was
 		selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> machines at the uh selling like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX> had given him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh for this little
 		uh this little uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">kid</ENAMEX>'s a a basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> that's what it is these little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would come here and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>
 		had sponsored the uh sodas you know just give them to him told him to give them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> well he sold them for something like fifty seventy <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cents</NUMEX> to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> when he's supposed to given them to them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh for heaven's sake what a cheapskate
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		yeah he was a he's uh we call him <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dana Jerk</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah and he blames all of his uh tax problems on his elementary school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		his elementary school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah she she never even got out of elementary school
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		well she might have been the cause of it
 	
 	
 		well no he was just a jerk he put uh he put the blame on everyone but himself he went out and you know bought uh bought recruits
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no i'm sure you know that's one thing you don't do
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he went out and did that and he got caught and then he got caught with the taxes and then he got caught with the sodas and that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> really went over on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> they really got hot about that
 	
 	
 		yeah i can imagine especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that were buying them
 	
 	
 		yeah these were young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> too they couldn't have been out of middle school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 		well that almighty dollar
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's uh yeah i'll agree there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		more powerful than you think
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 		well i think we met our time limit
 	
 	
 		yeah i think guess we did too all right well well you have a good day
 	
 	
 		so
 		uh-huh thank you very much
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	