
 
     		
 	
 		well the roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have certainly changed over the last uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade or two</TIMEX> and
 		i wonder if the the stresses that it puts on the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is uh all that good for her as it were had had there been enough adjustments in society
 		to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> cope with what she has to go through um
 		support group wise or or just all the different aspects that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have developed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> to handle what the world does to them uh how how is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s world coming along in that respect
 	
 	
 		i think it's come along very slowly i think that uh a lot of the stresses that you talk about have have
 		have taken a long time to become recognized but more strides are made toward addressing those stresses in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> than ever were in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and
 		i think that
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have had stress
 		you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two hundred years</TIMEX> but it's been a different kind of stress different kinds of situations because just being in the work place
 		is different from being at home but at home you still have work to do you still have things to take care of but you don't have the responsibilities and the pressures that you have in the work place
 		so a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have a little bit of trouble adjusting to that but i feel like the
 		in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of decades</TIMEX> the
 		the roles have almost come full circle because you know early on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were wanting to we were wanting to stay home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		and then they got into everybody has to have a career and it seems to be going back to
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> wanting to stay home with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> although i don't think it'll ever go back to the way it used to be there will still be many many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who seek careers uh before they seek family
 	
 	
 		do you think a matter of choice or economics both
 	
 	
 		both i think it's it's a matter of both um
 		economics economics has a lot to do with it unfortunately but uh i think a lot of choice
 		has gone into it lately and and most of them or or a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i know would rather
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um if they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they would rather stay home with them if if they if they possible can
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		you know that's an interesting point that you brought up about the the fact that they essentially always have been under stress uh i would say more
 		in the later latter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> even those who stayed home had stress but when you're
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> staying home on the block uh then the stresses that you do have uh the normal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> stresses caring for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or whatever is occurring
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you could go to at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> era you could go to the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> on the block or you could meet for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> or whatever and you had that stress relief uh built in
 	
 	
 		yeah your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		uh whereas now with it's a kind of fifty fifty split or leaning whatever percentage happens to be in your neighborhood like for our neighborhood we're looking at
 		<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> let's say uh there's no place for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to go when she has uh those kind of of stresses to be relieved
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right there's no one for her to go talk to and there's also no one to to kind of come in and take over for her and allow her some time to herself for even a day you know because there's fewer and fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> left or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that left at home to do that
 	
 	
 		so
 		that's right <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two months ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Omni Magazine</ENAMEX> which is a a science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> are you familiar with that read an article um really restating some conclusions of some some uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		programs or some investigations or research whatever you want to call it into the the actual physical differences between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and questioning whether those physical differences
 		uh accounted for some of the differences in ways <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> handled stress as opposed to men
 		and i guess to just barely summarize what the article said
 		was that in the the womb the differing levels of testosterone and estrogen across the lower part of the brain the base of the brain affected essentially how the brain was connected to the rest of the body
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> now how that has to deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> i'm not really sure since i thought most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stress</ENAMEX> had to do with you know from the from the eyes and the mental processes on up i don't know what it would have to do with the connectivity to the rest of the body
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it was an interesting uh uh line of reasoning where we've always thought or been told especially by the
 		for lack of a better term women's libber you know we're just the same as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> well maybe not and and maybe you shouldn't be exposed to the stress the same way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		have managed to do all these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and maybe it will take a lot longer before the physical physical evolution or for lack of a better term will occur to allow you to handle what we've put ourselves through
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree with that i it it's something that um
 		you know i guess science will eventually have all the answers to everything i don't know but it seems like it it would really be
 		it's it's really difficult to put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> a male and a female in the same role in the same circumstances
 		and have them react to have them and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> react to the same situation in similar similar ways i think
 		you know even between a same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sexes</ENAMEX> in a different in the same role there would there would be differences in the way one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> handled something over the way another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> would handle it so i i think when you put a male and a female in
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		in and when in comparison you know it would be uh completely different i mean just just totally different
 		and it you know goes a lot of it goes back to the way you were raised as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> are raised to believe this and be this way and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> are raised to believe something else and be this way
 		and uh
 		when when you're raised that way
 		you you kind of perpetuate that
 		oh
 		those ideals that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> upon you
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so you don't you're not able to well i i guess you are able to if you want to change them but you you stay in those roles
 		for so long that it's it's hard to to adjust and it would take a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX> long time for ethnic science to figure out you know what affects women
 		how and how the same thing affects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> i think it i just don't think it's any kind of study they can do in any even <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty year</TIMEX> period of time you know
 	
 	
 		yeah the subject would die before they had to run all the tests that they need  that's it would be an exhausted test uh how about the the area of role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> or roles as it were when you
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		
 
 		it would
 	
 	
 		you know teach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that uh he fixes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> fixes the meal uh
 		not not arguing that there should be a role for a sex but should there be
 		uh a set of not not a specific role let's say let's not say that only the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> should do the cooking but at any given generation or for any given
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh compatibility if you want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> to be together shouldn't they have uh defined roles as it were
 		uh certainly capable of sharing the other role for nothing more than empathy i mean it you know at least they understand what the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is going through
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh not being a tremendous cook i i know what the burden of preparing a meal but i don't know what  it would have taken to make that meal taste any better out on the budget i give her that kind of deal
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so i i wonder i don't have any argument or any problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> changing a given role as long as there's something on the other side let's say of of any relationship to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to match that i mean you don't want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing the same thing in the relationship
 	
 	
 		to pick up the slack yeah
 		that's right yeah yeah you have to it has to balance out
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		and i guess that's when you get into relationships and people
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are attracted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who compliment them most often i mean they say opposites attract and i'm not too sure i believe that very much but uh i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they get into relationships you know if there's somebody who
 		like like if you got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who hate to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> they're going to eat out all the time and that you know that's not that big a deal but you know if you get somebody who likes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and someone who doesn't like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who doesn't who doesn't like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> probably likes to do something else you know
 		so i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> end up i think that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are more diverse now than they ever were as far as what they have learned and what they're capable of and
 		and uh what they're willing to do and so i feel like it you know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have gotten to be that way too they've gotten a little bit more relaxed in their thinking about
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and you know what they expect of them so i think that you know it's a slow evolution but i think it's it's it's a good
 		process i think it's it's working you know
 		there are still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> should be home you know all day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and cooking dinner  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> cooking dinner saying right on right on
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		i i know one that's still that way but that's about it i'm down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that holds that position still i'm the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and i i have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> clamoring for my attention now so i understand what that's like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yes so i i you know think that there are very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who still feel that way and very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who will tolerate a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who feels that way
 	
 	
 		now that's an interesting point yeah i mean once the expectations are
 		
 		
 	