
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okeydoke
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		down here it's been it's everybody's got colds and everything because it's cold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and hot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		really oh that's the way it is up here like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it was fifty and raining and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days ago</TIMEX> it was snowing a blizzard up here so  it just it just likes kind of crazy all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		it's just
 		yep
 		yeah
 		well it is it's about
 		yeah it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about seventy five</TIMEX> here today
 	
 	
 		it's seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> down there yeah that's not too hard to take
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no but uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of days ago</TIMEX> it was in uh mid uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and only warmed up to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about forty five in the daytime</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh well it does that up here well we get a lot of weather that's that's uh controlled by the ocean we're so we're so close to the ocean here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> are you familiar with with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attleboro</ENAMEX> at all or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		not not uh no not the uh the area you know i am the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> as far as you know what they make and everything but the weather no
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New England</ENAMEX> is kind of kind of like uh pretty close sits right on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic Ocean</ENAMEX> and we get you know a lot of a lot of the weather is driven by the winds coming in off the ocean the northeast winds bring in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		all kind of weather from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic Ocean</ENAMEX> you know and that drives our weather nutsy sometimes we'll get the clouds and the wind coming the right way and the storms will just pour in moisture and pump anything from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> to rain depending on the temperature you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well down here they're normally <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> normally has pretty good weather but uh
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah it it's not bad uh i i was i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abilene</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> i worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abilene</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm kind of familiar with the weather out that way in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">west Texas</ENAMEX> but not in not in Lewisville
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh also the pollen down here has been terrible
 		if if you've got sinuses if you're bothered with ragweed and mountain cedar and all that other stuff that gets in the air <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> it's just been driving everybody crazy
 	
 	
 		is that right everybody everybody's sick down there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh either sinus problems or like i say colds or <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> or whatever
 		of course i don't know that that's really really weather related
 		i think you know we just have have every once in a while have epidemics of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of viruses going around
 		i know i had strep throat here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a week ago week</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i did too <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month ago</TIMEX> i had a a real severe cold but nothing that required you know um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s visit or anything like that i was just able to take some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aspirin</ENAMEX> and rest for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> but it just seemed like it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you're absolutely right you don't know how to dress you go out in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> with real heavy clothes on because it's real cold and by noontime you're taking everything off you know to to go walk around the site and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and it's unreal that uh uh you know by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> you can drop back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty</TIMEX> degrees it's just the weather changes so quick you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and if you don't have coats and sweaters with you of course by then you're all sweated up and warm and that's how i think a lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> carry
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'm a hot weather person i'm i can take the heat but i don't like the cold
 	
 	
 		yeah my the older i get the less i like the cold up here i'll tell you  i think that i think that uh you know it just takes it's toll and uh and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		when you get when you're young you kind of can tolerate a lot of a lot of cold weather and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> is pretty to look at but i i don't like to drive in it or or
 	
 	
 		you're right you're sure right it's it's nice to look at but the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of storms we've had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of snowstorms</TIMEX> we've had have really been good because they snowed and and like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">within a day</TIMEX> it's warmed right back up and melted the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and stuff so
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		we're able to get around pretty good and it didn't stay too long on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		i spent uh i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh i've
 		uh-huh i guess you've seen some pretty weather up there too
 	
 	
 		it was beautiful weather and it it was real strange it could snow
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and be sun shining
 		or right after it got through snowing you could go out in short sleeved shirt and it wasn't that uncomfortable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's the way i found  that's the way i found <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abilene</ENAMEX> in the winter
 	
 	
 		because of the
 		yeah it's a it's a dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> it's not a wet slushy snow it's packed
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah there's no see the humidity up here too is really bad in the summertime it's really bad it can be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seventy five eighty</TIMEX> outside but the humidity runs up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety ninety five</NUMEX> percent and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> your just like you're in an oven roasting i'll tell you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">West Texas</ENAMEX> now was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and ten</NUMEX> and i didn't mind that at all you know because it was so dry
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah
 		and i also spent uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> out in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ridgecrest California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		out in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mohave Desert</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's nice out through there i've got a
 	
 	
 		and i loved that
 	
 	
 		i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverside</ENAMEX> and i drove across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mohave Desert</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> i went from route <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and that was a pretty nice trip
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah but uh that was also a dry hot it wasn't a it wasn't a humidity hot
 		and uh i enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		i was surprised that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trip out there i'd never been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and i went through out to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Death Valley</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and twenty five</NUMEX> or something and it it didn't feel that hot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no huh-uh especially
 	
 	
 		it it like strange that it you're right in the middle of the mountains and it's so brown and dry but boy you just didn't feel
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it didn't feel that hot
 	
 	
 		especially if you can get find some shade
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah  that's the hard thing out that way but uh i liked Riverside though the weather in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverside</ENAMEX> was pretty good in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> was it was i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverside</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corona</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that was pretty good but the weather here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> like like they say if you don't like it too well well just stick around a little bit and  and it it will change up and give you something that you may like worse or like more it all depends on on Mother Nature's kind of fickle up this way i guess
 	
 	
 		
  
 		it will change
 		yeah
 		they had a they had a interesting show in uh public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on uh the uh ice flows and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ice age</TIMEX> and how the weather
 		effected the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> ages and everything and it's real interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that sounds like it yeah that sounds yeah i imagine it would that this
 		that's what we get real cold weather where the wind blows down out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> is called that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> ex press and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that winds comes down and it and it seems to make a big dip
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		sometimes it dips all the way down to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and then it roars back up the east coast here by the time we get it it is hauling some cold weather
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah in fact i think they showed on the they showed the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> map a shores of course <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> map and showed uh how far the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> had come down and during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last ice ice age</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think you all were <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a mile and a half</NUMEX> deep in ice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's unreal when you think about it you know that's that must be something uh to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well they say these big icebergs that you see floating out here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north Atlantic</ENAMEX> then you see the tip of them they look like small mountains and that's only like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one third</NUMEX> of the iceberg the rest of it submerged under the water
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that's been uh uh a problem you know to to the merchant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and stuff up here they run into that ice stuff in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> and it breaks away
 	
 	
 		how long have you been up there in uh Attleboro Attleboro
 	
 	
 		i've lived here all my life and i worked uh i've been with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh TI fifteen</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> of it in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> up here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i've lived up here all my life and i'm
 		fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years old</TIMEX> so i i could
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> spent some time up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right next door to us <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>'s not that far away did she like it up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah she liked it and she wants to go back up there and and uh
 		look around you know just sight see
 	
 	
 		it's nice the best time to come up here is like in in the fall in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late fall</TIMEX> and look at the leaves turn colors because that's that's something that you just can't paint a picture of or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the cold weather is starting to come in when the leaves start turning colors
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh that that's really nice to look at uh the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> are hot pardon me
 	
 	
 		what do you all have aspen
 		you all have mostly aspen or
 	
 	
 		no we have a lot of maple up here and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">oak mostly oak</ENAMEX> and maple is is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">and</ENAMEX> and pine of course evergreens up as you get up north into the northern part of the
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">maple</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corner</ENAMEX> here it's all pine <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i guess the hardwoods are probably
 		the biggest thing we have are our hard maple and hard oak and and the the evergreens
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		but that's scattered with birch <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and stuff and uh it's real pretty when the leaves all turn colors because you get a multiple array of colors and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come from all over the world come through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> only like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that  week or two</TIMEX> when the colors are the brightest you know
 	
 	
 		yeah a lot of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and things now are are starting to bud out i sure hope we i sure hope we don't get a hard freeze  to to kill everything now
 	
 	
 		oh sure because it's so warm
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		well uh yeah the it it's kind of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more week here i guess and we'll be into uh into the springtime i guess we got another week of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> here just about right we'll be out of the out of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> and into the springtime and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we might get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more little snowstorm in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> but i don't think it will amount to much
 	
 	
 		yeah usually down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our worst our worst month our coldest month</TIMEX> is usually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> but we didn't have have that much of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter this year</TIMEX> this
 	
 	
 		that's what i noticed when i was there was the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> storms you got around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February one time</TIMEX> i flew into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DFW</ENAMEX> and it was iced over  we had to go into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Love Field</ENAMEX> because we just couldn't get into DFW
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah usually
 		yeah
 		i'm i'm kind of sorry that we haven't had a real good hard a long hard freeze we've had a you know we've had a freeze but just maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		i think that that kills a lot of germs and stuff
 	
 	
 		it it kills a lot of the bugs and the
 	
 	
 		yep you're absolutely right i think it does it kills germs and bugs and the same thing up here if we get a hard hard freeze in the ground we get a lot of a lot of bugs and stuff in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX> that are no longer there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> but if we don't boy they just seem to jump right out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and i'm afraid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> is going to be bad as far as
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		bugs as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fleas ticks</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		how long have you been with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh you working in the in the military equipment equipment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh DSEG</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah D S defense systems equipment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> yeah yeah i was in that
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		
 		
 	