
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		back by that
 	
 	
 		the um
 		uh you know there are so many ramifications to this entire thing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have changed uh look at them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Indira Gandhi</ENAMEX> uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> so many uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of state
 		and i you know we we keep saying oh yes we feel someday a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> will be president
 		but i have some question whether or not they will ever really get around to that i think we'll have a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> before before we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> president
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't know that that's bad or good it's just a point that i have observed that we
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i i yeah i i i truly believe that that before that that we have to address the racial racial issues in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> before we can go anywhere
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right
 	
 	
 		um because it is so you know it  a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine went traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belize</ENAMEX>  and  and into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honduras</ENAMEX> hello
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh oh uh oh i think we're supposed we're supposed to hang up
 	
 	
 		yeah well it wasn't the matter of wealth it was the matter that they were not wealthy  that made them equal well i'll talk to you later okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 
 		alrighty thank you bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	