
 
		 		
 			
 				
 					 				
 				okay
 				
 					 				
 				well go ahead i'll let you start
 			
 			
 				uh i was thinking about whether or not we should have people
 				uh be required to do service public service for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX> and i was thinking that you needed to put some waivers in there for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped</ENAMEX> and also for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that had to stay home and maybe be wage earners for their family
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				or they had somebody at home that was ill that they had to tend to i mean you can't make it everybody
 			
 			
 				right yeah
 			
 			
 				but then you need to make it sure that the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't buy somebody off and and maybe send them in their place or or get out of it some other way
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 			
 			
 				too
 			
 			
 				um-hum or it could be like the draft where you know before they draft you they take 					you you get a physical anyway so when they send you a draft notice and then they give you a physical and if there's nothing physically wrong with you then you're drafted it doesn't matter how rich you are
 			
 			
 				and then we could maybe give physicals to the rest of the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> right
 			
 			
 				that would be good
 				what'd you say
 			
 			
 				give physicals to the rest of the family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and they all had to pass
 			
 			
 				oh yeah
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 				uh i thought it a good idea too though would be to extend this and make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are accepting public welfare have to do something along this line before they got any money
 			
 			
 				uh
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				and uh if they did this maybe help them out in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> cost and maybe they could pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for doing this at least something so they could could subsist
 			
 			
 				that's true
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 				well that's true the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s paying all this money to have other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> give uh aid to other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> so they could be paying their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and training their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the same time
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				because actually when you when you do uh service overseas you end up learning something usually that's that's really useful plumbing or farming or or something like that so you're really learning a skill
 			
 			
 				yeah and you know all these old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they would get out of this right all the ones that are already retired so what could we could do is take all the retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are going around in their big mobile homes
 				and they could do public service all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i'm just teasing
 			
 			
 				what'd you say
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 				
 					 				
 				yeah i i think well that's probably the idea i don't know whether their idea is to be within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or outside the country
 			
 			
 				well i thought it'd be a good idea if maybe you took the some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and had them go over to other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> came over to ours too
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 			
 			
 				a trade off
 			
 			
 				yeah that would be neat yeah sort of like an exchange program uh-huh
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				and other than that i can't think of any other ideas
 			
 			
 				yeah that'd be sort of neat
 				yeah well i like the idea of uh being uh a mandatory thing for welfare course that's what um that's sort of like what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX> had or or was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it Roosevelt</ENAMEX> i can't remember um with the big
 			
 			
 				oh with WPA
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 				getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or the work the work program and all the all the make work jobs that was sort of public service in a way all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> they started building
 			
 			
 				and we're still using those things too
 			
 			
 				what'd you say
 			
 			
 				we're still using those things
 			
 			
 				yeah that's true a lot of them still out there like all these wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> and no one knows why
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 				they built lodges before too like at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Caddo Lake</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">lake</ENAMEX> what
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caddo Lake</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Caddo Lake</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				it's between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				no never heard of it
 			
 			
 				it crosses into both of them well it's real pretty it's like a swamp you know with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moss</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> it's really it's eerie  					yeah
 			
 			
 				oh
 				
 					 				
 				oh okay real pretty like a swamp oh yeah yeah oh okay yeah i been uh i got uh talked to someone else before that was a uh
 				a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> but i guess that's uh that's what we're going to have this is uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> experiment to see how talk <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> talk to other people
 			
 			
 				i don't know where are you from
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Virginia</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> oh that's neat i talked to somebody from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX>
 			
 			
 				oh yeah it is neat to get other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> especially since you got other ideas about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> react to things and stuff
 				especially when it comes to um social services uh i'm 					i'm i'm glad they have a lot of uh um you know topics on social services because
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				like this thing this is a pretty good idea i didn't even know they were thinking about it i wonder if they thought about it themselves or whether someone somewhere is really uh thinking that uh it'd be a good idea to have everybody spend some time in public service
 			
 			
 				there is somebody and i read uh i can't remember who it is but there's a really famous
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 			
 			
 				of dang i can't remember his name yeah  that proposed it i read something in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> about it huh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Snider</ENAMEX> i don't know who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Snider</ENAMEX> is
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> is pushing it or uh
 				or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Snider</ENAMEX>
 				or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Snider</ENAMEX>
 				oh okay well see that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Snider</ENAMEX> is the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for the homeless
 				that uh he he said 					<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">said</ENAMEX> said it out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> but he started the um uh  the movement for creative nonviolence
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				yeah he started that and that that was basically a you know donate time and money to uh help the homeless but uh
 			
 			
 				so what have your other topics been
 			
 			
 				excuse uh the other topic was like i said uh  something about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> i can't remember exactly what it was it was a real general statement
 			
 			
 				i had one that i hated it was what meal would you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> for uh a special dinner  i mean how far can you go with that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right and another one though that was good was uh
 			
 			
 				gee whiz
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				what do you think about the social changes for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last ten twenty</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> and what do you think has caused some of the social problems
 				that have been it's probably the best one
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX>  that would be neat
 				i'd have to basically say my birth yeah
 			
 			
 				and we had to talk about air pollution too
 				what do you think's causing it and what should we do about it
 			
 			
 				um-hum well that would be sort of interesting because then you get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i mean other parts of the state you know of course <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> would say you know oh find the better cheaper ways of burning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> you know  yeah
 			
 			
 				uh-huh right
 			
 			
 				cleaner ways of burning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the south would say don't burn <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> you know
 			
 			
 				it's because we don't have much coal
 			
 			
 				oh we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX>  but uh it's uh it's a dirty <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> that's for sure
 			
 			
 				in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 				yeah
 				well how'd you get into this program
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 				excuse me
 			
 			
 				how'd you get into this program
 			
 			
 				how did i get into it oh i'm uh electrical enginee r uh here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 				
 					 				
 			
 			
 				for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				no
 			
 			
 				no
 			
 			
 				uh no they i'm in telecommunications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and they uh sent it out in our bulk mail so that if any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> want to participate you know
 			
 			
 				so does your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> have something to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				uh not really i mean no more than any other company you know we buy their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parts</ENAMEX> just as much as anybody else
 				but uh no no real association with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> other than being in the same industry
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				electronics industry
 				
 					 				
 				they just uh they just sent out a letter to everybody they does do business with saying that you know if you're interested we're doing a study and
 				and since
 			
 			
 				and do you know how much how long this is supposed to go on
 			
 			
 				i don't know no i don't
 			
 			
 				that's
 				i don't either i mean it says just keep on until and they'll notify you at first i was thinking it was just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> because that's all it shows
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 			
 			
 				you know on the schedule but then it seems like it might be longer than a week
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 				right
 			
 			
 				so what do you think we're going to get
 			
 			
 				what 					 what do you think what
 			
 			
 				what do you think we're going to get for this
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 				get
 			
 			
 				yeah money prizes
 			
 			
 				oh i don't know
 			
 			
 				do you know anybody that's ever done this
 			
 			
 				get your own
 				yeah get your own T I <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven four</NUMEX> L S <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two</TIMEX> or something what was it
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 				i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> gets prizes
 			
 			
 				a little chip
 				oh yeah i didn't hear about that probably for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> yeah
 			
 			
 				and i was led to believe that if you weren't <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> that you get money i'm not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				oh oh you're not you don't work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> oh okay
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 				let's see one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> that worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and she saw this on her computer and thought it might be neat so she ran off copies of the thing
 			
 			
 				oh
 				oh
 			
 			
 				and i just signed up for it
 			
 			
 				oh that's a neat idea uh-huh
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				yeah well he's gotten a good mix i i was saying because i've like i said i heard some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talking they've talked to different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and stuff
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				that's good especially since you call that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one eight hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> so so probably knock <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s profits margin way down
 			
 			
 				and it shouldn't be too good right now anyway because they've been laying off so many people
 			
 			
 				yeah right this is probably some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> study program
 			
 			
 				yeah really  so we're footing the bill on our taxes
 			
 			
 				okay
 				okay well i enjoyed talking with you
 			
 			
 				okay well thanks a bunch we'll talk to you later bye
 			
 			
 				i got to save my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> from a pile of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX> she's diving into
 			
 			
 				well i'm going to try to please clean up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> after my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX>  see if we can walk around okay bye
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 				okay we'll i'll talk to you bye-bye
 				
 					 				
 			
 			
 				
 					 				
 			
 		
 	