
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so what kind of eating out do you like
 	
 	
 		oh preferably <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> or seafood
 	
 	
 		yeah i i like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> or especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mongolian</ENAMEX> we've got a real nice little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mongolian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> here yeah i go out there probably once a week it's not bad you know
 	
 	
 		oh really hum
 		wow
 	
 	
 		you have to find out the right things to get so you get the most for your money but the the two meat the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> plates of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and one plate of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> is a pretty good deal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		oh yeah we uh
 		we haven't found a whole you know the are the best <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food we've found is back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		naturally
 	
 	
 		and uh same goes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seafood</ENAMEX> of course to there's not much smack right here out in the middle of nowhere
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no
 	
 	
 		but uh you know i think our luxury here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red Lobster</ENAMEX> and uh but back home there's you know different places  family owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seafood restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		do you do
 		yeah do you have a Steak do you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Steak and Ale</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		uh not close <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> away in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> there's the closest one
 	
 	
 		um
 		i haven't been to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Steak and Ale</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> but my favorite used to be their steak and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> crab oh that was good
 	
 	
 		yeah uh it's been a while since i've been there i was always jumped on the steak whenever i went there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		instead of the seafood
 	
 	
 		yeah they they had they had really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> crab of course it was expensive though dinner for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> was about fifty bucks
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and now that i'm full time poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> uh i got to watch the pennies  consequently that's why you go out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mongolian</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		so no i i pretty
 		you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> or or seafood pretty much
 		i could probably live on that
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't found a good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> around here anywhere i i'm at i usually do all my own <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food i my i'm partial to burritos and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tacos</ENAMEX> and i and i do them better than anywhere i've had out so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		there you go
 	
 	
 		and i can do them cheaper and i can do them my way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah right right well what do you like about your your <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food place there that makes you keep going back
 	
 	
 		and places place
 		uh basically the food and the price i it's sort it's set up on a sort of a buffet sort of thing you go up and pick your own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and all that fill up your own plate and then you drop it off at the uh grill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then go sit down and they they fry it out and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> it the way you want it seasoned and then they bring it out to you and the price is really reasonable the the drawback is that
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		all the uh all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> are uh are uh either <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Koreans</ENAMEX> or uh
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thais</ENAMEX> and they can't speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> very well so it gets a little bit difficult trying to explain uh some things to them but if you can get past that it's okay the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is really good
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i to me that's the thing that you got to have if the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is bad you're obviously not going to go back but if the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is good and the price is decent and the service is lousy i have a tough time going back again
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		course a yeah yeah i mean it's it's not worth the hassle just for the good food there's plenty of places that have good food
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		right
 		yeah um
 		there's there's a couple places around here that we'll go back to now and again um
 		
 
 		one being a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food place and and another one being another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food place and
 		and
 		it it just seems that
 		if the if the help is is good and they're like they're supposed to be that you know you're you're tempted to give the food a second try but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for some reason
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah yeah i i hardly ever give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a second try if if somebody's rude to me or
 		
 
 		excuse me somebody's rude or something like that i won't go back i don't care how good the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but generally i i the places i've been where i've had trouble with the help generally the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> hasn't been that good anyway which is sort of indicative of the whole problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well gosh now what  i guess it's been about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		now what
 		let's see how long do you eat do you go out once a week
 	
 	
 		i try to go out once a week sometimes more than that i about every other weekend i go down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and uh
 		see my my ex-college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> down there and uh we go out running around down there and there's some pretty good places down there to eat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but we've got a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there's a family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> here i don't know if they're over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> yet i know they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX>'s
 		um it's a it's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> they uh they have like a big food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and you can order from the menu or
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		uh just take the food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and the food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> usually has all kinds of entree items or salads and all that and they've just got tons of stuff and it's really cheap <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for about it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six</NUMEX> bucks and it's all you can eat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is good and of course you your service is pretty good because it's serve yourself can't complain too much they they they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come around and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah right so you can't complain about that really
 	
 	
 		deliver your your meal from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> if you ordered a steak or something and fill up your iced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> but other than that they don't they don't bother you
 		so it's a pretty good place i bet you don't have those over there
 	
 	
 		i don't think so i haven't heard of it
 	
 	
 		we have uh
 		there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and we've been to both of them and they're both terrible it was it was i was amazed because i've been in a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		and this is my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and they were terrible
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> here and i thought it was pretty bad until i had gone to those ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah we we figured this is probably the best <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but uh it's it's a pretty neat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> because they they don't take out loans for anything they
 	
 	
 		made you reconsider hm
 		oh
 	
 	
 		when they build a building they pay for it right then so that when they open the door they're making money immediately it's it's a smart operation
 	
 	
 		hum
 		right well that's a good way to go about it
 		yeah there's there's kind of a a little place set up like that i know that they've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and one in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> it's called You Are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cook</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and that's exactly what you are and it a it turned out it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle rancher</ENAMEX> who owns the restaurant and has his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> so it's an ongoing circle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and you uh you get your all your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> and everything for your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> is at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of the restaurant and then everything for a baked <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX> and everything you can imagine to put on it is another section and then right smack in the middle is these
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> huge grills
 		that they have set up for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p eople</ENAMEX> to use and you go in and you pick out your own selection of meat
 		that you want to to cook you know filet or T bone or whatever it is and they're just huge then there you know there the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> is just massive just massive i think the smallest the smallest they have is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i think a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nine ounce</NUMEX> filet i mean just we're taking taking doggy bags <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> every time we go and it's it's it's like twelve <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but you are you're getting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> meals out of it by the time you take it home
 	
 	
 		i would
 		yeah exactly and and you and you cook it yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah you take it up to the grill and you flip it or or they'll cook it they'll charge you an extra dollar to cook it for you
 	
 	
 		gosh that's half the fun cooking it yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really a lot of fun because they get up there and
 	
 	
 		well that's that's an interesting sounding place
 	
 	
 		yeah season it and throw it on the grill and
 		and you know sit around and and just talk while it's cooking and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go back and eat their salads and leave it there most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> stay up there so they get to
 		take their own steak back to their table but uh it's really neat i never thought it would go over much because nobody you know i don't want to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> my own dinner i want to go out and you know pay for it but it's really a it's really a neat phenomena how it all works out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah that sounds pretty neat it'd be worth giving a try
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah if you're ever in or around the area do give it a try because it's really good food
 	
 	
 		that's pretty interesting i've never heard of anything like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not sure where all you know he's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> bound obviously because i haven't heard him go any farther than those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> but that it's it's really neat too so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 		that's a unique idea i guess i guess that's part of the game nowadays in fast food you got to come up with some catchy idea
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah and it's it's and i and you know the fact that it's his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> it's just an ongoing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		he he surely doesn't have to worry about supply
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		that's a pretty good idea
 		huh
 		maybe i'll start a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah yeah you got all these tips
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't know if i trust these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> to cook anything though
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		probably burn the place down
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i bet you can't get find <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food over there i had always wondered what i'd do if i lived somewhere other than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well come to think i've never even seen a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> here
 		we got lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwaitis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX> but  gosh
 	
 	
 		oh well
 		hum
 	
 	
 		oh well
 		well i guess that about does it on the fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">circuit</ENAMEX> doesn't it
 	
 	
 		i guess so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		some of the subjects i tell you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well they've they've been a lot worse
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		it was good talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> you have a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night um bye</TIMEX>-bye
 	
 	
 		you too <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	