
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 		so huh what do you think should they uh should young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> be forced to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> of service
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't think they should be forced but i think they should be encouraged i guess encouraged to
 		to do some kind of public work i guess just to get them i guess involved with community maybe you know just community activity if nothing else see how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> works stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i think something like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> is a bit harsh
 	
 	
 		yeah i  i think so too i think that's a bit dramatic but but other than that i think it it's a good idea to get them involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and community activities and you know like the uh shelters and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know kids
 	
 	
 		uh that kind of thing helping out uh volunteering i guess if they can
 	
 	
 		move on
 		yeah i think it's a little harsh to say that they should have to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two and and</TIMEX> and force them i think that uh i think it'd be i think most i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> actually do a lot of work and no one just realizes it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you're right i do too i think they start out young like in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> doing stuff
 	
 	
 		right exactly i was a i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> and as part of being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> you had to do you know projects all throughout and then to become an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Scout</ENAMEX> you have to spend a do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year long</TIMEX> project for
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		right that's see that's what we did in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> and and that got you involved real good and it i think it starts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out on the right track and it lets them decide if that's what they enjoy doing something
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i i now i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> generally volunteer that that there's no problem with getting them to to do stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i do too i think i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> volunteer than than uh than we than get credit for it as you know like in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and uh and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 		and even if it is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the holidays</TIMEX> i mean at least they're getting out and doing it and  you know perhaps helping and helping out i think that's good and
 	
 	
 		well we have a funny commercial around here it says something like if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were to give <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five hours a week</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> of their salary we could they could solve all the world's problems or something
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so  i guess if we all give <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five hours a week</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> of our salary we could uh or just or just gave or or just or just forced our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just to force <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to serve for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i'll be
 		yeah  there you go that's
 	
 	
 		substitute my my yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'ll do uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five hours this week</TIMEX> for me no problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it sounds pretty good  that sounds good i've noticed a lot of uh  different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> uh
 		pick up like on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> and stuff and i think that's pretty neat they uh go along and have so many miles i guess of highway to take over and they clean it up
 	
 	
 		oh i
 		i've seen that yeah
 	
 	
 		and keep it clean i think that's a pretty good idea and i think you know again i've seen a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> doing that and i think it gets them prepared to
 		to learn how to volunteer as they get older i know i did you know in like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> and everything and after that in high school i would volunteer at a nursing home and stuff like that  so
 	
 	
 		they they just started trying to get them together like like like like that around here from for from the community because uh we had a big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> storm uh very very recently you don't sound like you're in the north you sound like you're in the south somewhere
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> where are you at
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i'm in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> upstate upstate upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> yeah and uh  long way uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 		oh gosh
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and we just had a really big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> storm and basically half the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in in in our city i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> which is uh right upstate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in the city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um are no good anymore and that's how bad it was everything is just down everywhere you know we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without power
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		oh
 		golly
 	
 	
 		you know it was and you know and and they and we didn't have power for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and there are still <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't have power it's it's oh yeah it's been over it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten days</TIMEX> already and there are still something like
 	
 	
 		are you serious
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without power and were officially yeah and we're officially in a state of emergency funny thing is the news the national news how they covered it um
 	
 	
 		oh my God how do they live
 		yeah i haven't heard a thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it made <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three minutes</TIMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the national news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> or something and and we've been in a state of emergency for over you know for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> you know we just got our phone back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord</ENAMEX>
 		God
 	
 	
 		and and they're you know putting out ads and now for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to come volunteer or to have their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> come volunteer to help clean up the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's good that's great
 	
 	
 		because we have you know everywhere everywhere that a tree is down <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need help and we're all all a lot of older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> need help getting their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yards</ENAMEX> cleaned out because they can't afford to pay anyone and they and and they certainly can't carry it themselves and so
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		right
 		right  that's one thing we do at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is um  we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hearts and Hammers</ENAMEX> and we go along and i'm really not sure how we find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> but we find older people
 		that cannot afford to fix up their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that need desperately need it and uh we go along with all the material and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> more or less go in and say roof paint fix whatever we can
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah and spend a day doing that's really neat i mean it's not a lot because you're just doing a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at a time but you know every little bit helps
 	
 	
 		and is that supported by all donation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and so forth or
 	
 	
 		uh yeah they uh  luckily we have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who owns a building company
 	
 	
 		oh so he
 	
 	
 		so he donates a lot not everything but a lot of the material then what he doesn't donate we just go out and buy
 	
 	
 		that's real nice
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's not you know we don't promote it a lot outside the community because we don't want recognition for it you know so much as we just want to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out so it's real neat it's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		that that that's real good and i and i bet it gives you a real good feeling to be doing that
 	
 	
 		yeah it's like i say it's not a lot but it helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple</TIMEX> we helped you know they were in their eighties and she was bedridden and i just you know it just tears your heart out to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to see this kind of thing and you know if you can do any any little bit it helps so
 	
 	
 		that's that's uh that's real good we had uh we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> like that in college you know we had a community service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in college that had all sorts of different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and some did like that some did elderly visits some did um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some did you know <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Brother Big Sister</ENAMEX> stuff like that and i'm convinced that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that that at least twenty five</TIMEX> percent of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> participated in some sort of uh
 		some sort of group you know activity activity like that you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> i don't know  <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> percent  yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was big in that  and she thinks yeah <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> percent it's it was a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>  but um
 	
 	
 		gosh that's great that's a lot
 		that's that's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> though
 		oh well still that's a lot you know that's a good chunk of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah but i mean a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would get involved and you know because there were all different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to do there was <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Big Brother Big</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> they had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> auction they had a dance marathon for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> or to to to support that group
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's neat
 	
 	
 		such that you know lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got involved that way
 	
 	
 		that's great that's great but uh like i'll agree with you though i don't think they should have to do a year
 	
 	
 		yeah

 		yeah no neither do i i think it should be completely optional and you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't think that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i don't think have uh a year in them to volunteer if you know what i mean they're not worth it
 	
 	
 		yeah they're not worth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> unfortunately just just can't even afford it you know or whatever i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> doesn't pay very well
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh yeah that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get shipped off and then you know and then and then their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i have a um a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> whose whose son is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guatemala</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guatemala</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		oh oh oh
 	
 	
 		and you know he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> just went off to visit her and you know i know i could never afford to go visit a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in Guatemala
 	
 	
 		i i couldn't either i couldn't either
 	
 	
 		you know so so i think you know and and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s certainly not making much money
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		so i can see where that that may be a problem
 	
 	
 		yeah i just know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> and  i mean she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and and just wanted to do it she'd been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> for a while just decided she wanted to do it so
 		i mean i'm grateful for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that but i don't see how they can just
 	
 	
 		
 
 		just take off a year
 	
 	
 		yeah just pick up and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on out i wish i could do something like that but
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i don't yeah well neither can i so i i i i i i did my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> before and i'll do my little community service throughout but never never for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> again
 	
 	
 		i can't so
 		right that's the way i am  i know the feeling
 	
 	
 		but so right so i guess our vote is no
 	
 	
 		that's right  we're against it
 	
 	
 		well it's been nice talking to you i guess
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		you too and i hope everything works out up there
 	
 	
 		well yeah we're we're slowly getting everything back together again you know it it's taking time but everything you know we got lucky we had no damage to our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or anything so the rest'll just have to come with time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		good good that's great
 		yeah well good luck
 	
 	
 		well good luck to you too  bye-bye
 	
 	
 		thanks bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	