
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		so what movies have you seen lately
 	
 	
 		i really haven't seen any movies lately i the only two movies i've seen were uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh King Ralph which</ENAMEX> really was depressing wasn't any any good
 	
 	
 		oh was bad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh that's disappointing i was thinking about going to see that
 	
 	
 		and
 		well it's not worth the whatever <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bucks or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four four</NUMEX> fifty whatever you pay for you know to get into the movie but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		wait for it to come out on videotape i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah or i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chima Para Diso uh Chima Para Diso</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what's the other one
 		oh say that again
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		it's a foreign film
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> film about uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who uh
 		who from when he was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinema Para De Simo</ENAMEX> oh okay because you're saying it with a you're saying it little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> oh are you Italian oh okay that's why go ahead
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">italian</ENAMEX> accent
 		yeah
 		yeah it's it's about a movie about you know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who was running a a movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> whatever he ran he ran a machine that was pretty good didn't you think so
 	
 	
 		yeah i saw it too
 		yeah it was i really liked it my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i loved it yeah
 	
 	
 		i thought yeah i thought that most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> might not like it because you know of it's it's not that good of a quality film but i mean it's the meaning behind it that i liked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> yep that's true yeah it had a really uh i thought the story was really nice and i thought uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that played the projectionist i just thought was superb you know he was great uh and the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> was good too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i i thought they did an excellent job of actually aging the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you know from when he was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> to little older to little older to except the last the very last you know the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> that played the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know when he had gray hair he didn't look anything like him but you know up until that point they did a really good job of keeping you know an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah they did well i think that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that uh it was like his story
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think he was like a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> or something like that and i think that was himself he was he that was his own story
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		on what's made him successful or whatever yeah so of course he picked probably all these really good looking young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know yeah yeah i liked that too yeah um we um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i are planning on trying to go see um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Silence of The Lambs</ENAMEX> tonight
 	
 	
 		yeah i hear that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a suspense well i guess it's ranked number one now it's supposed to be pretty good suspenseful yeah but are you good at do you like suspenseful movies like that yeah because see i i'm not really one that likes real suspense i like the nice lighthearted comedies most of the time
 	
 	
 		oh is it
 		yeah i do
 		well it depends on what mood you're in too you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true yeah but uh
 	
 	
 		like for example Tequila Sunrise i liked that
 	
 	
 		yeah well that well that was that's with uh who's what's his name's in it uh
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX>
 		and uh what's his yeah that was a good movie too that was good i
 	
 	
 		yeah is that supposed to be something like that one
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah something like that except it's it's supposed to be really you know suspenseful yeah so i guess but you know we're it's been rated pretty well and every all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> like it so and every word of mouth has been pretty good on it so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah we're we're going to go see that probably tonight
 	
 	
 		well what have you seen that that
 	
 	
 		uh actually let's see we we uh we've rented <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple</TIMEX> movies lately you know because you get them on videotape we rented uh just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> we watched um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX>'s uh movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blue Velvet</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which which is that it it sort of has some of the some of the music behind it did you ever watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i don't watch that show
 	
 	
 		yeah well that it has some of the music we've watched we watched <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> because uh uh a little bit so it have you know and i think she had seen part of it before
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of hers had rented it and she'd seen part of it but we thought we'd rent the whole thing and actually it's a pretty good movie but it's not great you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they said it's supposed to be really weird but because that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX> has like a weird style but i didn't think it was really weird you know not as weird as i don't know i we also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		maybe you expected too much out of it
 	
 	
 		yeah i think yeah that's probably true yeah we also saw <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild At Heart</ENAMEX> which is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX> movie that that that had been out now that was a weird movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild At Heart</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was yeah that was
 	
 	
 		about what
 	
 	
 		it was it was about uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Cage</ENAMEX> does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> like a like a pseudo <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> impersonation through the whole movie he's like a real violent uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty year old</TIMEX> and he uh he's in love with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that's about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> or seventeen and they leave he's involved with like a murder and then um
 		he they go to uh
 		they go to like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		and uh he get they get more he gets more involved with this robbery and whatever but it's sort of
 	
 	
 		so he just gets in trouble everywhere
 	
 	
 		yeah he gets in trouble everywhere he goes it's real violent
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know which is like what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX>'s other movies were about you know the so i don't know i just i didn't think it was that good my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> liked it a little bit more than i did she looks she looks at more some of the uh more creativeness behind it you know she likes the different type of movies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but i didn't think it was that good
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't like to look too deep into movies if it's good it's good if it's not it's not
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's sort of the way i feel too i don't know what else we just saw something recently
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		i want to go see The Doors that's what i want to go see
 	
 	
 		yeah they say that's pretty good well how old are you
 	
 	
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty one</NUMEX> oh see you're young so you you see i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty one so</TIMEX> you see this as like a mythical thing you know so you're like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right well i mean i i you know i'm pretty familiar with the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Morrison</ENAMEX> i mean i don't know everything about it but
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		yeah it's one of the things uh if you read in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and stuff he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> really like it or they really don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah so i think uh but i think it's supposed to be well done
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i heard i heard that it that what what is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siskel</ENAMEX> and Ebert someone told me that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siskel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebert</ENAMEX> said that
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> liked the whole movie but he doesn't like the ending so he wouldn't recommend the movie and he didn't like the ending because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Morrison</ENAMEX>'s life ended and it's like that's ridiculous i mean that's a true life story How can you not like something that really you know is if it happened it happened you're just telling a story
 	
 	
 		right yeah  yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's true yeah i guess i guess uh i well i was watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh Arsenio Hall</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> that plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Morrison</ENAMEX>'s one of the other uh
 	
 	
 		Val Kilmer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh not Val Kilmer</ENAMEX> the um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom McLaughlin</ENAMEX> who plays one of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in the band one of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> uh was on was on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arsenio</ENAMEX> and he was talking about it you know and uh he said that uh they tried to stick pretty much to you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the real story yeah
 	
 	
 		the real story and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and and for to</ENAMEX> for all of them to get an understanding of how their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> were they could they watched older videotapes you know of their them in interviews and things like that so they tried to make it pretty you know close to the line
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh they also said that whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that directed it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't  he uh he's very he really liked The Doors so it was very much his impression too you know so so if you have
 	
 	
 		right yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX> isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and he's a very strong willed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and his his ideas whatever came through you know with however so they said if if you um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but he's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> so i mean he should still be able to
 	
 	
 		yeah so so if you like his view and his direction in other words then you'll really like the movie you know so probably if you liked his other two movies uh those are like Wall Street and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Platoon</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i liked Platoon it was all right but i didn't see Wall Street
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah if you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Platoon</ENAMEX> yeah if you liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Platoon</ENAMEX> you'll probably really like this because it takes pretty much the same direction for the time you know uh i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's uh because he has a pretty strong will and he directs his own way so it should be you know pretty good
 	
 	
 		well i think i'll go see that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> or next weekend one or the other
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i really want to see it i wanted to see it uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks ago</TIMEX> when i had a chance to go see it but i i went home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> and they didn't have it playing home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">like spring</TIMEX> break and
 	
 	
 		yeah oh you in college
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm still in college
 	
 	
 		well why are you participating in this study
 	
 	
 		uh my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> took a voice over course
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		and they told him to sign up for this and he asked me if i wanted to do it and i said sure you know it's like just you know to help out whatever you know the the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> you have the bigger
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> the better it works out because i'm a voice researcher
 	
 	
 		uh you get a bigger pool of all the different regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">and</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		i guess they wouldn't be called dialects but they're pretty close sometimes
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what they're yeah that's what they're really looking for
 		i think just how we speak also looking where we pause and where we don't things like that yeah but that's pretty that's good um what do you get many movies on campus
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		well the the good thing about campus is that we have this uh system that uh
 		uh it's a it's called UAB uh university something or other i don't know and they give out like movies they show movies in the theatre for a dollar
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right yeah
 	
 	
 		and and so you know like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every other day</TIMEX> or or so they have like movies for a dollar Sometimes they're even free i think uh they showed uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chima Para Diso</ENAMEX> free
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but i missed it so i rented it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i saw it in the theatre we really liked it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i liked it but i didn't i didn't know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> would like it so much they might you know look into it and say uh this is low budget film and it's not really that good but i mean i like the story
 	
 	
 		yeah it was a great that's a i think that's that's one thing too um you know you can't get so much caught up in the expense
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		as as you do a good telling a good story and i thought that was that movie really told a good story
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and i think if you really like the story going along with it you don't notice that it's a little bit you know it might not have as many camera angles or it may not have
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know uh because the you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character actors</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> the community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were just great they just seem so real you know they came right off the screen
 	
 	
 		they were they were i mean i you know i i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every summer</TIMEX> except i missed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> but i mean it's like that you go into the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> especially you know like in where he was in Sicily
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the southern part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> everything is like that you know and no one has any money you know you just barely get by But everybody is like a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and it's like it's just like that so that's why i liked it i guess i'm a little biased but i i i i i thought
 	
 	
 		right
 		but see i really think yeah i i think those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> came right off the screen in that story you know it was really enjoyable and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> we thought the same thing we were so pleasantly surprised
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	