
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 		being a former <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whoa
 	
 	
 		i uh i'd i guess i have to say at this point that i do approve of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because i know
 		that uh
 		in using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i was not a good employee
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i can see from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s standpoint that there  uh whenever you are an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you are using it's assets
 		and uh
 		and but you're also under their liability under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workmen</ENAMEX>'s Comp
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh on my job we had a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workmen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comp</ENAMEX> cases and
 	
 	
 		where do you work
 	
 	
 		uh i work for a tire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Tire</ENAMEX> and uh it's also a retreading <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and that's where most of our uh injuries occur
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what we do is we'll have a drug test if if an if a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> uh has an accident then he's automatically uh given a drug trest
 	
 	
 		right do they do it like you know within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of
 		the accident or is it
 	
 	
 		yes when he goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so that kind of uh i don't know if it's been a deterrent or not because we have uh just started using it oh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past year</TIMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now we've let some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go uh that well it was found that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> were used in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> now i don't know how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TEC</ENAMEX> would handle it they haven't pursued it you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh if there's some uh problem i know there was one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that we tested for preemployment for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> who absolutely swore up and down that it showed that he was using amphetamines
 		and he went to a a separate drug testing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and they showed it negative
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think the tests themselves are not really that cut and dried you know
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 		yeah i think that's probably true too that's that's that's sort of scary
 	
 	
 		uh-huh really
 		and then i also had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who was uh just around some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> and he tested positive on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> now then you always wonder well is he just saying that you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah  yeah really really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's a bad situation i think that probably i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> now as far as entry you know exams require that i think they should
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> and and and uh i'm i'm really gung ho for it in fact
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i you know some of the places now um like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> don't allow even smoking you know in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> we we have designated smoking areas
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um i work in sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> that's that's not really it well it's on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> but it's a little bit you know separated we lease the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and it's mainly it's a factory environment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they they have designated smoking but it's just wide open it's not ventilated properly and i think that's bad but as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> you know being in the factory kind of environment that way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think it's a it's a definite i think it's essential
 	
 	
 		yeah because you're endangering everybody's lives if you've if it's something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		in fact we've had the policy on just the random testing now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i was giving my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> a hard time because i kept waiting for my name to came come up you know they never they never called me they never you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		then finally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> we declared war was my time
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 	
 	
 		no  and so and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> has has gone for about like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times i think and i told him he's obviously in a high risk group
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		right right and of course you know they they did specifically single them out when we started you know that they  were going to do all them first
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah wouldn't that be awful if you were
 	
 	
 		which i thought was interesting
 	
 	
 		if you were using and and oh lose your job and everything
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> yeah
 		ooh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i can't believe i'd was so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brazen</ENAMEX> before i'm like i say i'm a former <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> but uh i i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		i accepted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX> as my Lord and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savior</ENAMEX> and so i don't use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> any more
 	
 	
 		what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> did you use if you don't mind
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marijuana cocaine</ENAMEX> and amphetamines
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		um yes
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and all on the job too you know it had gotten that bad
 	
 	
 		really
 		well it's really lucky that you got away from that cause that's
 	
 	
 		really it's it's life is so much more enjoyable
 	
 	
 		really
 		downward spiral
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and i was losing jobs just from doing a poor job you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's that's it
 	
 	
 		i mean you know there's all kinds of drawbacks much less the drug testing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		just life in general
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'm well i'm definitely for it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		plus you know you you want to think that that you're working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are not only putting out their fair share
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		but that are not endangering your life in some cases like uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years back</TIMEX> worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they had you know i mean it was a chemical handling type
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean and they have they have some serious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> out there you know like they have emergency shower where you just run in there and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> off and dump water you know that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there using all sorts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> handling those chemicals
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		and that's really that's really frightening so i think some place you know places like that it should be like mandatory like you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		on on a on a greater frequency than maybe just you know the paper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pushers</ENAMEX> like like i am
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i would think they would be
 	
 	
 		well you well you'd think so but uh
 	
 	
 		but they weren't
 	
 	
 		i don't know if they do it until yet
 	
 	
 		isn't that awful
 	
 	
 		because when he was at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> now it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> now because it was before it was even before they had the the designated smoking type stuff you know at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i forgot what i guess it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> something like that and they at that time they had no testing whatsoever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so that's scary
 	
 	
 		yeah that's reminds me of uh i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who was telling me about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> who gets high all the time
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i have just casually asked her what he did for a living and she said oh he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> of this chemical land fill you know where they go and dump all this toxic stuff
 	
 	
 		oh Lord
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i just you know went oh where
 	
 	
 		yeah should we move
 	
 	
 		let me move as far away as possible
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's awful
 	
 	
 		but i'm proud though that that um you know i grew up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> and back then it was popular you know but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have really wisened you know become wise about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they really have a good campaign for the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know they know it's not smart so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i guess it was just a generational thing
 	
 	
 		yeah peer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is the other way now instead of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right and that's good that's the best way to stop it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's
 		yeah that it really is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think we did it
 	
 	
 		okay well i enjoyed tack talking to you Cathy bye-bye
 	
 	
 		it's good talking to you yeah bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	