
 
     		
 	
 		oh no i hadn't heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo Jackson</ENAMEX> though what happened
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo</ENAMEX> was uh playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> actually you know he plays both <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football and baseball and baseball</ENAMEX> and he was plays and during a tackle he ended up either damaging his hip or you know injuring his hip
 	
 	
 		yeah plays for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's been <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> and he's been out for a number of of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> games and it just as of announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansas City Royals</ENAMEX> put him up on waivers made him a free agent
 		so they're saying now that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo</ENAMEX> knows <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> and it could be actually a career ending injury
 	
 	
 		uh i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		so they had uh they're having actually a special on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and they were mentioning that and even though <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> may have dropped him some other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> may pick him up but the big thing was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>
 		uh the athletic shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is still going to keep him on as one of there cross trainer sponsors
 		and since that makes him more money anyhow
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah it does he has more money out of the uh ads than he does the game itself
 	
 	
 		yeah he does it it's pretty amazing though how much he can get for endorsements anymore
 	
 	
 		i well i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Montana</ENAMEX> got something like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> for saying i'm going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disneyland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't be surprised whatsoever
 		on the same program they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> they were saying that he gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about six million dollars</NUMEX> for playing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> about i think <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two million dollars</NUMEX> for endorsing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen million</NUMEX> dollars for his endorsements with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>
 		and then of course he's got uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheaties</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		outrageous prices
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and that's that's in a year
 		that's uh what would you do with all that money
 	
 	
 		uh i i wouldn't know what to do with it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we just discussing what we'd do with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i could make that go a lot of places
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's amazing anymore there's a also a program on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this evening</TIMEX> about the
 		a very sports intensive <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> it seems to be on TV about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of college athletics
 	
 	
 		uh the uh
 		achievement for the let's see how are they putting that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> let's see the academic report board review <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX>'s being it more involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i was watching that
 	
 	
 		yeah it it talked about all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX> and their the death penalty and how they're getting around all the regulations and rules and and things of that nature
 		i guess anymore it's just a big business
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh
 		some of for most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i guess it is for some of them though they do it just for the love of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i think it also probably also more is more as you get into the the big schools
 		the ones that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TVs</ENAMEX> are going to cover and things anyhow when you still have the the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> or the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> they're all doing it just for the for the love of the game because they're not getting the big revenues from anyone
 	
 	
 		well that's not necessarily true though you know uh
 		i'm an avid uh basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> there gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> when he quits
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or you know and so you know he's doing it because he wants to
 	
 	
 		they actually mentioned a little on the fact that he's started to instigate a program where he's actually uh not necessary they say he's getting around the rules somewhat but it's actually sounds like a pretty good idea where he goes out and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX> other
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who don't meet the minimum academic requirements to get into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and and then qualify for a student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> position
 		and he takes them and signs some contract or something with them but sends them then then to junior college
 	
 	
 		yeah i heard about that i haven't heard much about it though
 	
 	
 		so at least that's uh some way that they're
 		you know i i guess the best part about it you can't just drop off all scholarship scholarships because it does i would imagine at least in it's intentions help a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who couldn't afford to go to school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but that seemed like it was actually uh you know if there's a good way to get around a rule that sounded like it was a pretty smart way
 	
 	
 		you don't think yeah i don't know if it would be dishonest or honest though
 	
 	
 		well uh at least it's hopefully still helping the the student
 	
 	
 		yeah it's yeah it's helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're not uh going to graduate somebody who still can't read and write
 	
 	
 		uh it's happened too much
 	
 	
 		that's way too much yes it has
 	
 	
 		yeah well we veered from the subject
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah but that's quite all right i think they just want to have some kind of normal conversation
 	
 	
 		i hope so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's happened to me more than once
 	
 	
 		does it
 	
 	
 		yeah almost all the time
 	
 	
 		really well there's been uh actually some pretty interesting interesting topics that i've had i've had things from uh tax reform to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> to fishing those are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> i've participated in
 	
 	
 		i haven't had anything on fishing i've had uh
 		oh arts and crafts uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football basketball and baseball</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well heck you
 	
 	
 		child rearing or child day care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> other things i can't remember
 	
 	
 		wow sounds like you participated quite a bit
 	
 	
 		yeah well almost everyday the  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lines</ENAMEX> are open
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you normally receive the calls or is it pretty much split
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-and-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		is it well that's good
 	
 	
 		oh you know uh i had to start out doing it i done it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> times and then uh here lately they i've been letting them catch me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's good well it's been enjoyable speaking with you
 	
 	
 		all right well you take it easy bye
 	
 	
 		all righty good-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	