
 
     		
 	
 		okay so what do you think
 	
 	
 		well i believe in capital punishment um and i i think
 		the way that i understand the laws right now they are only for certain crimes um i'm not sure exactly what they are i think rape and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		capital murder
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> gets killed you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that would be a capital crime yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah something like that but my problem with capital murder capital punishment is they don't carry it out
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree they
 	
 	
 		so if they're going to have it to me they ought to do it
 	
 	
 		i agree they uh
 	
 	
 		you know they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> been sitting like they had on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20/20 or 48 Hours one</TIMEX> of them they had them on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> waiting on death row
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see that don't make no sense
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that we waste a lot of money keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in prison
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that uh is not necessary
 	
 	
 		and now i think they ought to increase it to all these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah have you ever been on a jury
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i haven't either but and i you know i i have real strong beliefs in capital punishment but when it comes right down to it
 		yeah i i'm wondering though
 	
 	
 		they're not going to do it
 		that's my biggest problem is even if you give them the death penalty they appeal it and appeal it and appeal it and there's you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		but what if they're not guilty
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 	
 	
 		what if they're not guilty
 	
 	
 		what do you mean what have been
 	
 	
 		what if they truly are not guilty and they're convicted anyway
 	
 	
 		that's the whole system though isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah see that's what
 	
 	
 		there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that aren't guilty that's in jail
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know
 		uh i i i don't know about if you if they was
 		like capital murder
 		and then if they were married then what would you do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't know you know like i said said i do believe in capital punishment but if i were sitting on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and had to make the decision  i wouldn't want to have to be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to make it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i do agree that they keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we spend too much money keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> are overcrowded if they're going to do well you know let's do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do it and get it over with
 	
 	
 		i don't know if i could i could probably it depends on the crime my problem would be that like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to me the like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child people</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that's killing kids
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the ones messing with old people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		those type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now i i have no pity for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but just like if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is fighting and he kills her that he shouldn't die because it might been accident or you never know what you know what what they done went through together should i say
 	
 	
 		yeah but i don't know if they if  they if uh the death penalty
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't think they give them the death penalty if given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i don't think they give it to just
 	
 	
 		i think they just put them in jail and let them think about it
 	
 	
 		yeah  for a long time
 	
 	
 		so i don't know
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i definitely think anyone that kills somebody should be in jail i don't think everybody that kills somebody should die
 	
 	
 		yes
 		die because it all depends
 	
 	
 		so under the circumstances
 	
 	
 		there's a lot of circumstance sometimes i even feel like and up in another state i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> where they don't have uh
 		self-defense laws and i think that's wrong
 	
 	
 		is it i i'm from i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and i didn't realize that
 	
 	
 		yeah they had them on the news this lady her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> i'll never forget it because she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> pregnant and he hit her in the stomach and then tried to cut her throat
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		well she shot him and she went to prison
 		she you know she killed him but she lost her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and then they sent her to jail so that's not right
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they she's nothing should have happened to her at all he shouldn't have hit her in the stomach i don't care
 	
 	
 		well see he shouldn't have been trying to slit her throat anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but he did both
 	
 	
 		yeah well i wonder why did they say why
 	
 	
 		well he was he he she was abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> he was he was a a what do you call it abuser he would he would beat his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		oh
 		so there was a history of that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so she's not going to get to have her baby
 	
 	
 		she no she lost the baby
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		he hit her in the stomach with the shovel
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's just you know things like that that you know i don't think those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or even a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman man</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> shot him but he didn't die
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they put her in jail now i don't think anything should happen to him but i think she should stay in there because really she just did it because she wanted to get out the marriage and she wanted all his property
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see i think that's wrong too
 		but i don't
 	
 	
 		cheaper than a divorce
 	
 	
 		no she she wouldn't have got no property see there was no grounds for divorce she was she wanted out cause she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> and it was weird but uh the capital punishment i don't know actually what they give the death penalty for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		the only thing i i know they give it for is shooting a killing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> or you know assassination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and and something big you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think capital crimes uh capital crimes and i want to say kidnap i don't know why kidnapping sticks in my mind but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they should give it to them but i don't think they should keep them waiting in jail and let having us pay for it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no if they going to give it to them i think they should go ahead you know okay maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or you know like that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> whatever but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ten years</TIMEX> on death to me that's worse for them too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they're not they don't know when they going to die they know they got the death penalty but that don't mean nothing not anymore
 	
 	
 		well i i assume that you live in do you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is very uh one of the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> i mean i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> executes more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than just about any other state
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't know
 		they don't they don't put it on the news or they don't broadcast it because you know the i guess they don't just don't
 	
 	
 		well they they they they don't sensationalize it anymore they used to make a big deal out of it every time it happened
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for right uh life or something
 	
 	
 		and i think now that it happens more frequently than we know that it's just not sensationalized as much at least in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> because i hear every once in a while i'll hear something on the news
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i
 	
 	
 		but i think they going to have to do something
 		to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wake up like on especially the drug dealers
 		you know the the not the little penny ante ones on the corner i don't think they ought to get in trouble
 		i mean i know they ought to get in trouble i'm not  they ought to get in trouble but not not death because see they you know we're to me what they ought to do if they can find the big man
 	
 	
 		but they ought to get yeah i was
 	
 	
 		because see that's where it's coming from to me it it's coming in here some kind of way i don't care what anybody tells me <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tell me i said if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> really want to i think it's all government something to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> i really do
 	
 	
 		they
 	
 	
 		because if you can stop uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> cigars from coming you can't buy anything <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> so why can't they stop anything illegal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know if they really wanted to i think they could they just don't want to put there's too much money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s been bought out you know and that's what's wrong with some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> on the street
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they you can't blame just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> says he can make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two five hundred dollars</NUMEX> a day
 		for just taking a bag somewhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is not getting that much money
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know if you think you think about all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the ghetto
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> would probably kill us but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh you know it's something that has to be done to me if they bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> into it because now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are killing and so they going to have to do something with the death penalty or to scare these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think that's the whole thing they're not scared they know they're not going anywhere
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well yeah i mean when when you think about it
 		yeah when you think about how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> die from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> you know ultimately
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh-huh innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not just the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'm talking about innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they have they little drive by shootings and and and see because i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		see originally i've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> twelve thirteen years
 		but originally in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> die all the time just from being in the way at the wrong place you know see you know but i think something should be done for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		but i don't know too much about the death penalty
 	
 	
 		i think that that they have much i like that they've changed it to lethal injection rather than you know the electric chair or gas
 	
 	
 		yeah but they don't use that no more
 	
 	
 		no they don't
 	
 	
 		they use the the injection thing or whatever it is
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's a lot more humane than uh than the electric chair than the than the gas or the gas
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's funny because i had listened to a comedian talk about the death penalty you know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying they they don't have nobody to do this and i said well if somebody killed my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> just because
 		i'll pull the switch
 		i'll even do you know to me if if that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can forgive them fine but what is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> going to do next is he going to go out and kill somebody else
 	
 	
 		kill  right
 	
 	
 		you know how many times is it going to take for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> before you kill him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now you know sometimes i can understand maybe if they robbed something they didn't mean to do it okay but how many times you going to go by that how many times you going to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> keep killing so i don't know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess if you stay out of trouble you don't have you worry about it but
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well it's like you said though sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just get caught up in it innocently but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so i think it just i think it depends on the circumstances and
 		how many times that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has been in trouble i mean really big trouble
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but that's all i got to say
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and it is nice talking to you all righty
 	
 	
 		well it's nice talking to you i'll have to start doing this again some more  i i don't know what i've tried it several times with
 	
 	
 		oh it's fun i call
 		
 		
 	