
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		well how do you feel about it
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		i don't have any strong convictions about it that's for sure um
 		i know i haven't done any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> service and
 		i don't know anybody in my immediate family that has or you know has ever even thought about it do you know uh do you know anybody that's been it
 	
 	
 		no the the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know that have done anything remotely like that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have gone to be missionaries
 		and that's only because i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX> and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX> go and and serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> during the summer
 		but i think i think that's a terrible idea that's like forcing someone to donate to a charity
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it it's nice to to try to teach young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> some
 		some uh
 		uh
 		civil uh consciousness
 		but forcing them to to donate basically their time and efforts
 	
 	
 		yeah it's definitely up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> uh so
 		i'd have to say that uh
 		it you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do it
 		well some feel it's rewarding i don't know you know
 		but uh
 		i don't know how we got the subject you know i have nothing to say about this
 	
 	
 		it it
 		i don't either
 		i don't either i was i almost hung up because i thought well gosh i don't i don't really have an opinion except for no i think that's dumb
 	
 	
 		um-hum well how long you been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		i've been here for um just uh almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> well no almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and i lived with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana</ENAMEX> in school
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		that's how we know each other
 	
 	
 		and uh you you were just up there then huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Six Flags Saturday</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah a good old time
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		well back to the topic at hand
 		what other types of community service would they be talking about i mean  the the recording mentioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it sounded like i mean this is like major long term commitment like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or six months</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you're looking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> or sabbatical maybe or you know i don't know i mean but uh
 	
 	
 		i mean i'm all for donating my time to worthy causes like i do some
 		volunteer work here and there and every once in a while i'll do uh a uh local <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Brother Big Sister thing</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or i'll go you know do a
 	
 	
 		but that that time is minuscule compared to what what it sound like they were referring to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah i i couldn't possibly commit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my life
 		to to go do something
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they couldn't cover my <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hourly</TIMEX> rate
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i couldn't afford it
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i have this thing against bugs too and seems to me like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> they send you someplace that there's a lot of bugs
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a lot of
 		yeah
 		have to live in a shack with no air conditioning and no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> and no anything i'd probably catch a terrible disease and die
 	
 	
 		yeah well i doubt that but you know i guess
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i i mean it would it would have to be tough going somewhere you don't know
 		the culture usually i guess i think that maybe that's why some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh to see the other cultures or you know and some of that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh to do that i don't know i'd have to be
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know either the other growing up all i knew was
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you go to high school you you know you work you go to college you get out of college and you get a good job and you work and and none of this you go spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> to expand to broaden your horizons
 	
 	
 		um-hum well you know uh i know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> i'm now i'm working at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> now and they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		after a certain amount of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of service these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> can take off
 		like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> or something for some type of sabbatical or some you know some something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		they're allowed to take that time off and then come back where they left off
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so it is something that i think
 		uh
 		you know even the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> will support uh
 		it's really it's really for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to give you know to to give back to the community type of thing
 	
 	
 		i'm for
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		pretty it's for yeah i think at the same time it's for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
 		you know help them grow in other areas
 	
 	
 		kind of like joining the military
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i mean in that respect a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> join the military to to grow up
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe
 	
 	
 		and to decide what they want to do and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> or something like that is probably useful as as that kind of a time
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe a little bit in that perspective but uh
 		i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have gone in the military i mean in you know when they're in the college
 		sometimes it's to support help support college you know the money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">others people</ENAMEX> don't know what they want to do
 		but as far as uh
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>
 		i guess i suppose there's a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have done it at that point in their lives
 		but i think a lot of it's you know when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get older they'll do something like that
 	
 	
 		i'd probably have a different perspective if i actually knew someone that had gone into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i don't
 	
 	
 		but i don't and none of my
 	
 	
 		didn't mean to cut you off there
 	
 	
 		oh that's okay none and none of my
 		really close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in college went off to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> or anything so i don't really know anyone first hand that's
 		that's committed committed a chunk of their life to do service work
 		everybody i know has been well i'm going to go get a job good job and make some money and buy a nice car
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i know
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		or try or  try to make a living
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah i i have no
 		i don't know anybody that's that done that either so
 		i it's it's interesting we got this topic because i i i don't know what i marked off to get this but
 	
 	
 		i certainly didn't mark off anything to get this one
 		i can't i can't imagine and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">switchboard</ENAMEX>'s been down for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> and the last time i called it before it went down
 		i had this topic and i didn't feel like talking about it so i hung up and i guess they they keep you on the same topic until you actually talk to somebody about it
 	
 	
 		so you had the same one huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh well well you you'll get it over with here
 	
 	
 		i know it
 	
 	
 		how many times have you talked
 	
 	
 		oh probably <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not a whole lot
 	
 	
 		oh i've done maybe <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four or five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana</ENAMEX> sign you up for this
 	
 	
 		well she just sent me the information out i
 		i got a hold of it you know i just sent it back in and
 	
 	
 		yeah that's she stuck my name on some list so they mailed me the information
 		that i filled out
 	
 	
 		what other topics have you had
 	
 	
 		well that's pretty
 		um i've talked about camping with someone i've talked about the weather
 	
 	
 		great great
 	
 	
 		that one was interesting because i talked to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 		and it was hot here and it was snowing there so that was pretty interesting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i talked to someone about the uh
 		the uh education system
 		i forget exactly what the focus was on that one but that was fairly interesting
 		and i've talked to somebody about credit card usage
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and i talked to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who
 		i gathered from speaking to her that that she and her family just didn't have much
 		and they didn't have much credit available to them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so she basically didn't use credit cards and didn't know very much about them and how they work and
 		and how you can use them to your advantage and and how you know you
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah i always
 	
 	
 		you can do certain things with them
 	
 	
 		i use everything with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> and i pay it all off so that's a good deal for me i get free money for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's the way i use them uh i try i try to make sure i don't get in debt so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well that's always a good plan
 		i can't think of anything else that i've talked about
 		all the the most most of the ones on the list i checked off stuff like <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football and</ENAMEX> and stuff that i can i i would enjoy talking about
 		and i haven't gotten a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them yet when i've called
 	
 	
 		i had uh let's see i've had fishing
 		and uh
 		i can't remember
 		me and
 		i think me and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana</ENAMEX> had football yeah we did
 	
 	
 		oh how funny
 	
 	
 		yeah uh we so we talked about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> a little bit and
 		i'm out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> so we talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix Cardinals</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so so that one was all right and then what else i had
 		i think i had some other uh
 		like staying in shape or working out this other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i got this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		i had to talk to someone about hobbies
 		and
 		the switchboard called me so i was caught a little off guard and i couldn't think of anything at all
 		so i started making stuff up
 		i told this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that my hobby was gardening
 		and i can't even i can't even grow an ivy my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> gave me a plant once that told and he told me when he gave it to me that it was impossible to kill you could freeze it you could
 	
 	
 		and you've probably never gardened in your life
 	
 	
 		you could dry it out no matter what you couldn't kill it well i killed it pretty quick
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i don't have too much of a green thumb either so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i do have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> here it's been hanging out for a while but i think it's one of your easiest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> i can't i don't know the name of it but
 		i'm not too much into
 		
 		
 	