
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay well i guess i can tell you that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy Brown</ENAMEX> that's the one i don't miss and i don't know if you've seen that that's with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candace Bergen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i've never seen that before
 		uh-huh i've heard about it but i've never watched in fact i don't usually watch TV on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> i guess i'm either just really tired from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> and i get home well uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i have aerobics on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> too i just didn't quite make it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> because i was caught up at work for too long but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh jeez
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah i i usually don't get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock</TIMEX> so that's another good reason but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i'd say that's the only one i don't miss or i try not to miss that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers on Thursdays</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh but those are probably about the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> that i that i usually  with any regularity
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		back when i had time to watch TV oh maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when i wasn't doing aerobics and work wasn't quite as busy as it's been lately um i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wonders Year's</ENAMEX> and uh
 		um
 		sometimes every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then i'll catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Doogie Howser</ENAMEX> because i think that comes on at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and that's about the time i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from aerobics and i turn on the TV as i sit down to eat dinner and i'll catch that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> watches that religiously we tape it for her because it comes on at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> here and she has to go to bed at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight thirty</TIMEX> and uh so that you know we watch it too while we're taping it we watch it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		oh no
 		yeah
 		yeah it's kind of cute um
 	
 	
 		yeah i like the lessons it's a good uh good it's got a lot of good morals to it so i enjoy that one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i like uh what is it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> oh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> is kind of funny on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> yes that's another one that i try not to miss although it use to be better i don't know it seems well
 	
 	
 		yeah i like that one um
 		i haven't seen it in a while
 	
 	
 		yeah i was going to say i haven't seen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple</TIMEX> episodes i think the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i really saw was when he broke up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was thinking well do i really want her to go back with such a jerk
 	
 	
 		i know  i know it's funny that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> even like that show because he really is he's such a jerk but then it's just kind of funny because you you can sit there and laugh and go yeah what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>  typical
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh  uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh that one's kind of cute i'm real bad i got hooked on a soap opera when i was in college <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		everybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dorm</ENAMEX> watched it i mean everybody you were an outcast if you didn't gather in the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two o'clock in the afternoon</TIMEX> to watch this soap i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> scheduled their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> around it and everything so i
 	
 	
 		really
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i started watching it and to this day i still watch it i just kind of got caught in that and then after i moved out of the dorm
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommates</ENAMEX> watched <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Hospital</ENAMEX> and they watched <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All My Children</ENAMEX> and some other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soaps</ENAMEX> and i was going i'm not even going to be near that TV when they have any other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX> on because i don't want to get stuck in another one one is bad enough no more but uh
 	
 	
 		i know excuse me just a minute i think Katy
 		get off the phone
 	
 	
 		oops  how old is she oh
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten</TIMEX>
 		
 
 		so she's been getting hearing about the the different calls and i've i've been in the middle of tests and stuff so i keep you saying oh press three
 	
 	
 		sorry mom
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so let's see i was trying to think of i don't think i've ever watched any soap operas i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> used to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Restless</ENAMEX> but i don't i don't watch them
 	
 	
 		yeah don't ever start  that's just the thing
 	
 	
 		no  well my my last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 		she oh gosh she would run the tape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the minute</TIMEX> she went to go do her aerobics and she used to do like um filing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think she did some work at a thrift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> so as long as she was gone for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about four hours</TIMEX> well maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> she would tape soap operas
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		and uh she would watch them at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> when she came home
 	
 	
 		i just couldn't watch that much TV
 	
 	
 		i know he was saying he was so sick of soap operas because i guess for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years</TIMEX> now she you know he'll come home from work and there she'll be watching soap operas yeah
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah
 		course see <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> of soap operas is really going to translate into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two hours</TIMEX> of TV watching time because they're really <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of it is just commercials they play more commercials in soap operas than anything i've ever seen in my life but still i just don't think i could sit down for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and especially <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> of soap operas i'd that'd be that might be a real good way just to break that habit is to have to watch them for that long i'd kind of be like uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this is enough  i can't take this any more  this is disgusting
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah well she's really she's really into it i guess but i never have gotten gotten used to well i just really never have been home i think during that time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i never had a chance and even when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of course i always had classes about that time so i never had a chance but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Hospital</ENAMEX> huh is one to get hooked on if you're going to get hooked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah i think so i mean i guess that's the only one i've ever watched and i just i refused to i mean i never watched <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Knots Landing</ENAMEX> or any of those things because it's like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no
 	
 	
 		i don't want to get hooked into one of these things that you have to watch it every week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean you can watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> from time to time and not have to you know not feel like oh wait i'm missing an episode and i won't know what's going on
 	
 	
 		right really
 	
 	
 		and so that's fine and i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX> too that's another one
 	
 	
 		and i've never watched that i going to have to watch that sometime
 	
 	
 		it is pretty good i've watched it maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six times</TIMEX> but it comes on kind of late on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and sometimes i'm trying to get things done and get in bed so i can go to work of of course for you it probably comes on really late on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> come to think of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah they everything starts at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and then it goes through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> and uh i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Carson</ENAMEX> comes on until like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		gosh
 		oh gosh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so everything really that's what's really cut into my TV watching is the time that everything comes on since it's all shifted back an hour i just i don't really have time to stay up late and since i have to get up so early to go to classes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		i can't stay up past <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten thirty</TIMEX> i'm falling asleep anyway  so i miss most everything anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh let's see
 	
 	
 		yeah i haven't watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Carson</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> i used to watch that and i used to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Letterman</ENAMEX> and things like that in college and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Love Connection</ENAMEX> that was one of my favorite ones in college because we'd get up in the in the apartment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">downstairs</ENAMEX> who by the wa y <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> upstairs and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> downstairs and they'd come upstairs and watch it with us and we'd all sit there and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know we'd be yelling and going pick this one pick this one and we just had it was just a fun you know fun thing to watch but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		i've never seen it what is it is it like a version of the dating game or huh
 	
 	
 		kind of yeah they have the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> choices on video and it's usually real funny because they'll usually get someone in there that half the time the dates didn't work out at all and they have to tell about their date and how it went and
 	
 	
 		oh God
 	
 	
 		half the time they'll say well when he showed up at the door he didn't really look quite like his video and i just wasn't real sometimes they really burn each other it's really kind of funny but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that is terrible and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has to hear it
 	
 	
 		yeah well then if the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> hears something like that they come back just as bad  and he'll say well she underestimated her weight by quite a bit  and they they just got you know they they go back and forth and it's kind of funny um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		uh-huh oh gosh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then you'll see the real funny looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> and it's it's it was just entertaining and of course that was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's been probably oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five six seven years ago</TIMEX> since
 	
 	
 		oh gosh i was going to say i never heard of that one <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Love Connection</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we used to do that but uh i don't know if it even still comes on but that was always fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah i hadn't heard that one let's see i can't oh gosh that that probably wipes out my whole inventory of TV shows other than um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		right now they've got that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Hepburn</ENAMEX> one where she's touring all the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">gardens of Europe</ENAMEX> i of course have missed the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> series of that but that's about the only thing that i really catch on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we used to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts and Entertainment</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and i we get a little bit of the good ones here but we used to try and catch uh some of the stuff they had on there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and like i said  i don't really watch TV too much any more uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sometimes i'll turn on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> or something like that in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> when i if i i get really sick of the radio in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> because they just they're so obnoxious
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i'll turn on the TV and just i can hear it back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and you know keep up kind of what's going on in the world so i'll do either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Morning America</ENAMEX> or something like that but from time to time
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well we used to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> because that was the only thing on really early that i could an update on all the news but with the war coverage i had had it with reporters
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the coverage and so after a while i just turned it off i said i can't take it any more i just can't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i haven't watched it since the war started i <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> though was it was a life saver for me back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> had sent me to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> actually they sent me to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> foreign countries <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> was right about in the middle and all they speak there is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and in my hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> there was nothing but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> programs on and they had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i just kept that thing on constantly because i was going <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> language this is wonderful and and they at least i kind of knew what was going on on the other side of the world and trying to keep up with
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay what's the weather been like and what's happening back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> because by then i'd been out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> already and i was i was you know wondering what's been happening lately but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i never knew that i never even thought that they would have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> on in Taiwan
 	
 	
 		yeah believe it or not
 	
 	
 		i guess that keeps anybody that's traveling that's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> over there you'd think that they'd put it on in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> or translate it in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Chinese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> they had it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> too in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> but they had they had they had <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Married With Children</ENAMEX> have you ever seen that before
 	
 	
 		huh
 		no i've heard about it i've seen a little bit of it it was kind of
 	
 	
 		they had that on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> i watched it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> i've seen it here before a few times it's a real sarcastic type show it's kind of funny
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		um i thought i can't believe they're playing that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over there must think we are horrible i mean some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> shows were some of the worst ones we have and that's what they're showing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> and i'm thinking
 	
 	
 		i know that i didn't much
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they must think <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are just really terrible  if they watch this
 	
 	
 		they probably do you know if that's all they see of us oh God what a thought so next time i think of that next time i meet somebody from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> they're going to think oh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Married With Children</ENAMEX> yeah that's what she's like
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		yeah
 		yeah it was pretty embarrassing
 		she's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peggy Bundy</ENAMEX> oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>  and he's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Bundy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh golly
 		yeah because i i can't remember where i've seen clips of that but they were showing highlights of it and stuff and i was thinking who'd think this is really up my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> you know if i'm going to spend my time but it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		um a lot of um borderline jokes yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 		
 	