
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay so have you seen any good movies lately
 	
 	
 		uh well let's see i think the best one i saw was probably <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping with the Enemy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i haven't seen that one yet
 	
 	
 		have you seen Silence of the Lambs
 	
 	
 		uh no i haven't seen that one yet either
 	
 	
 		oh well tell
 	
 	
 		how about uh Awakenings
 	
 	
 		no but i've heard it's really good
 	
 	
 		okay well have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LA Story</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't seen that did you
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i have
 	
 	
 		what did you think of it
 	
 	
 		uh well it was it was entertaining it was funny <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX> did a pretty good job
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it's uh they portray the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> lifestyle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's uh quite a lot uh crazier in the movie than it is in actuality i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and nothing's as crazy as what they how they uh uh describe it in the movie
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well i saw a few of the uh little coming attractions you know it looked really cute but
 	
 	
 		it's kind of fun if you've been there before you'll you'll be able to relate to uh to the humor that they have in the movie
 	
 	
 		yeah well i've never been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> but not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i thought it was interesting how they cast that movie with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Tennant</ENAMEX> as his uh love interest in the movie because she is his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in reality
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't even realize that that's interesting hum
 	
 	
 		so that added something to the movie
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess so did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Alone</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't seen that one yet either
 	
 	
 		oh well i was kind of disappointed in that one
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i've heard so much about it that you know it's such a great movie and you ought to go see it over and over again and
 		uh i thought it was just kind of like a spoiled brat staying at home and causing a lot of trouble
 	
 	
 		yeah i i heard that uh it was a little pretentious that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was very wealthy and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it just didn't uh appeal to uh to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as it as it could have
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i was kind of disappointed
 		but um  are you intending to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambs</ENAMEX> have you
 	
 	
 		yeah i've heard that's really really good uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine at work saw that
 	
 	
 		yeah it's pretty intriguing
 		yeah it's it's a very unusual movie
 		kind of keeps you well the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of it wasn't as
 		scary and intense as i thought it was going to be but toward the end it got got more that way
 	
 	
 		well i understand it has a real complicated plot
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it really does
 		the only way they can get any information is through someone who's so crazy and bizarre it's hard to tell what he's going to do next so yeah so it was a good movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping with the Enemy</ENAMEX> was even scarier but that's because it was about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> chasing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and that's my big fear so
 	
 	
 		okay yeah um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i was trying to think if i've seen any others lately but
 		that probably pretty much sums up i don't get to go to the movie too much
 	
 	
 		you seen uh Ghost
 	
 	
 		no i haven't as a matter of fact it's on at the dollar movie around here and i was wanting to go
 	
 	
 		yeah it's been out for quite a while already
 	
 	
 		yeah i heard it was really good
 	
 	
 		that is a is it is a very good movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Patrick Swayze</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demi Moore</ENAMEX> did a really good job very uh uh emotional put it that way uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum yeah
 		yeah that's the way i understand as a matter of fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> believes in uh ghosts and she said that she thinks that's a real uh true portrayal of what it would be like
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting the special effects were great i have to admit that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i i want to see that as a matter of fact i intended to go <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> and didn't get to so
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		hopefully we'll go soon
 	
 	
 		you seen uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Scissorhands</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		oh it's
 	
 	
 		as a matter of fact i don't know anything about that movie what it is is that  funny or
 	
 	
 		it's
 		uh yeah it's somewhat of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bittersweet</TIMEX> comedy
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		it stars uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's uh from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> Jump Street
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh he portrays uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Scissorhands</ENAMEX> this uh creation of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Price</ENAMEX> uh kind of a uh scientist
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		who uh creates a person uh out of uh
 		oh just uh spare parts and i guess uh cookie cutters or whatever
 	
 	
 		oh really huh
 	
 	
 		it it's kind of interesting he he doesn't complete the job though and his hands are are are not finished so he has scissors on the ends of his arms
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		oh huh
 	
 	
 		and uh is is found in this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">castle</ENAMEX> by uh
 		oh it's the local <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Avon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she takes him into her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh he learns
 		what life is like uh in a uh moderately normal suburb
 	
 	
 		oh well that is interesting
 	
 	
 		it's uh it it is entertaining it's kind of like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale
 	
 	
 		yeah huh
 	
 	
 		with a sad ending but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah oh
 	
 	
 		it's uh
 		uh it was different
 	
 	
 		yeah well that sounds pretty yeah  is it something uh that you could take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		a fun movie
 		oh yes certainly um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six and a half year old</TIMEX> that'd probably enjoy that
 	
 	
 		oh i think it'd be great for a for a a child
 	
 	
 		yeah huh
 	
 	
 		it does have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale like uh quality
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh well i'll have to
 	
 	
 		that
 	
 	
 		have to take her to see that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scenery</ENAMEX> is is very entertaining uh and what he does with the with the scissors and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh doing uh certain types of landscaping uh working with shrubberies
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		uh he uh carves out different figures in t he in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants plants shrubs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really huh
 		wow that sounds like that would have been a hard movie to make
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i they spent they evidently spent a lot of time on uh on the scenery for that the special effects
 	
 	
 		yeah i can imagine
 	
 	
 		have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Field</ENAMEX> over at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inwood</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		that's i thought that was an outstanding film
 	
 	
 		huh i don't know anything about that either
 	
 	
 		with
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Harris</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh he plays a uh kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> nineteen twenties <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's about a uh piece of land that he rents
 		uh he works uh a piece of land and rents it from uh an old <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> uh widow
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		but uh he
 		he has an obsession with this piece of land that he wants to own it and won't allow anyone else to uh to uh control that land
 		and when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> puts it up for uh for sale uh
 		he claims that it's his even though he cannot afford uh the price the price
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it uh goes to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American American</ENAMEX> uh who has uh ancestors from from the area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he's trying to uh
 		apparently trying to uh uh
 		gain some background on his his heritage from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> so he's buying this piece of land to try to introduce civilization to the area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and uh there are just a lot of uh interesting
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i have never been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inwood</ENAMEX> theatre
 	
 	
 		well they well they have more of of the artsy type of uh films a lot of foreign films there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah do you go there often
 	
 	
 		no not too often uh but uh this was a uh just a good opportunity to go see that movie it was uh
 	
 	
 		yeah hum
 	
 	
 		i really enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		yeah well it sounds interesting
 		well does this um
 		however this is set up tell you when you've talked for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		well they cut you off after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you oh really oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh okay well i didn't know this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> call that i've made so i wasn't real sure if you
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		if it tells you when you've talked long enough or
 		let me think if i have seen anything else that's interesting lately
 	
 	
 		well getting back to uh to that other uh film uh with uh which one was that with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh-huh yeah Silence of the Lambs um</ENAMEX>-hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Silence</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambs</ENAMEX> yeah i didn't really care for her her earlier films uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi Driver or The Accused</ENAMEX> and i was kind of wondering if this was uh a little different style
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i'm sure
 	
 	
 		departure from what she's done before
 	
 	
 		i haven't seen either one of the other films she was in but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> said that
 		he thought she was playing a real different role in in this show yeah
 	
 	
 		okay
 		see i never did care for her too much in the other films so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine at work says that this one is a lot different that uh she's really good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i one of the things that i was really impressed with uh she has to
 		have an accent that she does a real good job with i it sounds so real that she sounds like she's from that area of the country
 	
 	
 		all right that's interesting because i
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i think it's like in the i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama Georgia South Carolina</ENAMEX> area or something it's
 		and she does a real good job sounding like she's from that area
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but um i thought she did a really good job
 	
 	
 		well that's good i'll have to go see that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's been highly recommended
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that plays this bizarre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is really i don't know if i've ever seen him in a film before i don't even
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Perkins</ENAMEX> yeah
 		i didn't remember him from anything else i i'm sure i've seen him in other movies but he looked so his his face the entire movie just haunts you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he did a real good job
 	
 	
 		sounds like i'll have to go see that one soon
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah there was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> there i think it's uh definitely getting some good ratings
 	
 	
 		okay yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Enemy</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX> i haven't seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> yet uh have you seen that one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		because she was just on uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Choice Awards</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and won uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Choice Award</ENAMEX> for uh best uh female entertainer
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		as well as uh an award for this movie
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't realize that
 		well i thought it was i really enjoyed that movie i mean it scared me more than the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but it was real intense to me i enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		okay well i'll have to go see that one too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it was it has a real eerie beginning
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that she's married to is obviously crazy but at the first you don't really
 		know about that and it's real interesting the way it starts out
 		so uh i thought it was really interesting
 	
 	
 		sounds like another obsession type movie uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it is it's a lot like that
 		i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX> was a good movie did you like it
 	
 	
 		uh i thought that uh the movie the movie that it was based on was better
 	
 	
 		i didn't like the ending but
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		that was uh which one was that
 		with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Mills</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		it came out in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">nineteen seventy</ENAMEX> trying
 	
 	
 		i didn't know it was based on another film
 	
 	
 		oh it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Play Misty for Me</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i thought that was a very good film and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX> was on the same theme almost identical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but uh i didn't care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX> as much
 	
 	
 		huh well i liked it until toward the end i
 		i didn't care for it too much but
 	
 	
 		no it gets quite violent
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and it's kind of unbelievable too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> can live through everything she lived through
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i can't think of much else to talk about
 	
 	
 		okay well i think we're reaching our limit anyways so
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so well thanks for calling
 	
 	
 		all right i appreciate it thanks a lot bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh good-bye</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	