
 
     		
 	
 		well uh she said uh one was a total ban on gun control and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> was uh no control at all where do you fit in there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well i think you'd probably have to put me at the at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> area <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten or nine</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh is that right well we're probably not too far apart i'd probably fall in there at a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh i just you know it's it's you know weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> obviously do not kill it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that operate them and
 	
 	
 		well i pretty much agree with that that's uh
 	
 	
 		with with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred years</TIMEX> of uncontrolled gun control in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i mean it was founded on that it was one of the things that founded this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i can't imagine trying to to do that and if you pass laws you're gonna make a lot of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals criminals</ENAMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wouldn't register them i i i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and and we just had a a registration a law registration for automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they know that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of them out in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and less than about i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> registered them
 	
 	
 		is that right in the whole state
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah in the whole state
 	
 	
 		golly well the
 	
 	
 		so what is happened now is that those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that did not register them are um
 	
 	
 		they're now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> themselves yeah that's that's the crazy thing about it you're you're putting
 	
 	
 		they're now criminals
 	
 	
 		they're they're putting more laws and more restrictions and more burden on the honest citizen the one who doesn't give them a problem anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know and it's it's crazy they're just putting more
 		giving more paper work problems to the honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> and and you know because uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> whose gonna use a gun for a crime he's he's not too concerned with the crime of not registering his gun
 	
 	
 		no no no
 	
 	
 		that's
 	
 	
 		absolutely you know it's like it's i i i i don't really quite understand the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think that
 		i mean i i'm all for registration in the sense that uh a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a lawful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can go down and get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and and maybe you shouldn't be given <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one the day</TIMEX> that you go down they should be able to do a check i think possibly and
 	
 	
 		yeah i i would agree with that that you know well you know that's that's why i say i kind of fall into a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight</NUMEX> range there you know i i don't have a problem with registration
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh you know when it comes to restrictions and and
 	
 	
 		yeah and and just plain can't have guns
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it it is crazy because
 		like you say this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was founded uh and obviously had a uh had a big interest in in letting them their citizens <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> themselves
 		and which uh you know which maybe does cause some problems that maybe other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> with more restrictive laws don't have but it's one of the prices that you have to pay for for freedom i think
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely not only that but i think there's also a hidden a hidden wealth in in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> having firearms and that hidden wealth is is that i would really
 		i would really feel sorry for anybody for a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that that tried to physically invade this country
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		mean because you know it's it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where everybody has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and they're gonna have some trouble  i mean you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and pop little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and stuff they're gonna run into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		yeah they're
 	
 	
 		and and that that is sort of a hidden security factor i think for this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> you know i mean
 	
 	
 		oh yeah everybody who lives out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or or around around my area everybody who lives out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has a gun
 	
 	
 		sure
 		at least one
 	
 	
 		yeah you know and it's not for uh not for protection or hunting or or anything just you know for all those reasons just you know nobody thinks anything about having a gun it's no big deal
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's that's the way they just brought up well uh where're you from by the way
 	
 	
 		but but
 		yeah
 		i am in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trenton Texas</ENAMEX> did you yeah did you say you were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> right now i'm i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> though i
 	
 	
 		well i
 		well i didn't know this program reached out that far
 	
 	
 		hey it's reaching all over
 	
 	
 		all right well that's that's a neat deal
 	
 	
 		well listen you think they've earned their money we've earned our money tonight
 	
 	
 		oh i bet we have we gave them <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> worth
 	
 	
 		all right well listen you take care of yourself all right
 	
 	
 		all right you too good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> then bye bye
 	
 	
 		good night all right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 		
 	