
 
     		
 	
 		oh go ahead i i am glad to talk to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> i always wanted to know who an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		oh well i'm not an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> i just had a little i've i've seen a little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> in my time it's uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		the the chemicals we were dealing with were uh a Raid repellent and uh that was really quite dangerous i'm not certain that that was
 		that's that's really a pollution issue i think pollution issue is is uh
 		is is the argument over over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> catching uh things like uh respiratory disease
 	
 	
 		uh well there there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things uh
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i'm interested the most i guess myself uh
 		would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the Freons</ENAMEX> i mean for air conditioning the one i guess that's the one i'm most curious about is how they're going to replace the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freons</ENAMEX> in air-conditioning
 		that seemed to be the biggest surprise to me and whether when they replace it you know they're going to really come up with something that is not just as bad
 	
 	
 		well the you know that that's another arguable issue and i i've seen the uh uh uh assuming you can buy into global warming i
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i uh was uh you know where they were all concerned about that but that that it seems to be
 	
 	
 		well did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Sagan</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> on uh when he was talking about when if if the if the war started in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> and they'd set those uh all the
 	
 	
 		no i heard about it though
 	
 	
 		uh it was it was it was interesting but uh i'm just curious what he has to say now that they've got them all lit
 	
 	
 		was that before i didn't see it was that before they actually did that or it was what
 	
 	
 		yes and his argument was uh was that that you would see a uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> with no summer
 		which actually happened and it it actually yes it actually happened uh
 	
 	
 		because of that you know
 	
 	
 		it was a volcano erupted and it was high enough up but uh they had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the national meteorological <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> i think it was the  which is the national
 		anyway research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they said that the uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> would not go high enough
 		and it's it's going to be interesting to see if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Sagan</ENAMEX> and his billions and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> may have once made a mistake but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the the the</TIMEX>  the general the opinion among among the uh meteorologists at uh i'm uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Meteorological Society</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		are you don't you don't work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i do
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but i'm uh i only i do that in my formalize
 	
 	
 		where do you work in research or
 	
 	
 		no i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planner</ENAMEX> a production planner
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but i i i'm in the active reserves as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weatherman</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		no okay yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i i keep up from time to time but what the the argument is that uh that uh maybe there isn't global warming and maybe there is
 		but um if there is
 		uh we probably could do something about it now and if there isn't if there isn't and we do some the right things i think how do you feel about about all this smog and mess stuff on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh well i'm kind of a car buff myself i was going to ask you another question but uh
 		i i'll do that in a minute i i think that the changing you know from leaded fuel was a tremendous advantage
 	
 	
 		well do you have an older car
 	
 	
 		you know not not using
 		no no no
 	
 	
 		i i have been working on an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but it to yeah
 	
 	
 		really oh i'm a car buff too we ought to work talk about that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> uh
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well i'm restoring one
 	
 	
 		i think you can use the you can use high you know the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> percent uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> octane i don't think you'll have any trouble
 	
 	
 		i'm not having any problem it's a seventy
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		no i i think uh i uh work on my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and uh
 		i don't think that's a problem i thought i'm saying i was glad to get rid of leaded gasoline
 	
 	
 		but did you have another question you said you had another question
 	
 	
 		uh oh yeah i the same thing about the war uh or related to the war on i was watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and i cannot remember what <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> it was
 		what did you see the advertisements uh
 		when they talked about nuclear war what that would have been like in changing the atmosphere it is so scary that
 		i hope that every one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> saw that because it was just total disaster you know
 		did you see any of those uh i it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no i didn't see that that i know that the uh that's
 	
 	
 		it must have been channel thirteen i don't recall although i thought it was on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> oh i
 	
 	
 		well that they talked nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> and and i suppose that's that's the ultimate uh pollution problem
 	
 	
 		it was a somewhat of a commercial because it came i saw it regularly
 		and it showed that and it was really devastating and it would uh
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		how much ash would fall and and how it would essentially literally destroy the world you know
 	
 	
 		well it's interesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chernobyl</ENAMEX> accident uh actually um because the circulation budget as high as it went
 		um covered
 		a a fairly remarkable amount they did some tracers and they i i think it's drawn in uh i think
 		gets in there because i can't think of the other trace but i saw a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">a</NUMEX> presentation on on that and they it went quite a long ways but i i i guess
 		i can be a little sympathetic but you know there's some argument that in in in the blue grass of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Smoky Mountains</ENAMEX>
 		that that's the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">pine trees</ENAMEX> giving off <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh really yeah there there's probably a lot of natural things uh
 	
 	
 		but the but when you see when you get up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and and see all that haze from west <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is that is that pollution
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh it i guess it's got to be really i don't know i don't know if it's air pollution it's uh it's dust pollution whether it's natural or not i don't know
 	
 	
 		well it that's the thing is that i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> really does have a problem in this the idea if we could get some cleaner fuel
 		burning fuel the problem is is it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't want to use mass transit so
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah well i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> and there there there are no buses i mean there there is the only school bus the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> you see are school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		but who wants to who wants to um ride a bus
 	
 	
 		well i know it it's uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is we have this big romance with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are would be interested if you had one i mean
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> drives forty miles one way each day
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that works with me drives forty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> miles
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and they don't think it well i guess they do think something of it but
 		um not enough to
 		you know you consider how much um
 		but then you get into all these issues of of whether it it's the types of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> and what it's doing to your lungs and are we going to die of of respiratory so we all move out of the out of the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		out of downtown so we get away from the the smog my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> grew up in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and they moved out to the valley
 		before <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> uh when when the valley was clean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and now the valley is not and so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> move out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more valley and
 	
 	
 		well you said you were car buff uh i think that uh all of us could use one electric car right now i mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> because i think uh
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		you said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> drive forty miles and fifty whatever yeah when you go to trips and all you can have one gasoline <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but i think we all could in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> say
 		have an electric car where my one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> she could use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> now if they had one you know
 	
 	
 		well do you know
 	
 	
 		because they she don't even she doesn't put fifty miles a day on the car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> apparently has one that they're they're testing i think it's
 		no it's alcohol <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> that they're testing almost
 	
 	
 		no no you're right i i have seen them but uh they have a battery car
 	
 	
 		but they
 	
 	
 		uh i went to the auto show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past week</TIMEX> and they did not endorse now that i think of it
 	
 	
 		suppose
 	
 	
 		and i was so interested in the auto show i didn't think to ask anybody there were no electric <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i was surprised but now that you just mentioned that
 	
 	
 		huh well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road and Track</ENAMEX> was talking about that this apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> has some uh they apparently think they're close
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think uh there could be a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> close this is really we're
 		were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> away or less i guess from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX> and i think
 	
 	
 		well there there's still a lot of research i was over in in the research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> a couple i guess it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month ago</TIMEX> and saw this
 		there have been research it was a little light that says solar solar powered research
 	
 	
 		yeah they've got a they've got a area over in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SE</ENAMEX> building too which is uh but it's a solar
 		uh it's for uh they got got some money from a power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and it's probably more generating power for you know uh electricity <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty volt</TIMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah well do you work in that C building
 	
 	
 		no i'm actually in the south <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		oh well i'm at
 	
 	
 		i was uh i'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> so i've been in all most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		oh well i'm in i'm in the C building been there for all my life
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well the the solar area is right
 		right around from the auditorium now
 		and they they've got several different uh areas where they're called solar lab
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		it's right there on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> floor you ought to walk by there
 	
 	
 		well that's been a  i know the focal plain array is they were taking space to for a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah but the solar project you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s been into it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and i guess it's just not uh economical yet because of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well the problem is that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a dollar</NUMEX> a a gallon
 		you know
 		who wants to yeah i mean we want to not pollute but uh at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a dollar</NUMEX> a gallon uh it's hard to beat the amount of energy you get from
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i've seen some i think then again i'm surprised now i didn't think they'd asked anybody when i was in the auto show
 		there was nothing uh and there was no  place for
 		air <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollution</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or anyone there it was just pure automobiles
 	
 	
 		well i thought i saw an ad for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen</ENAMEX> that had an alcohol
 	
 	
 		there
 	
 	
 		they had one with spots on it and something i didn't go but it was it was showing they i mean uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 		i didn't see did you go
 	
 	
 		an article
 		no i didn't i didn't go so i wish
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i i was uh quite impressed with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> you know the engines are so much smaller now and everything and they're they all have brand new engines even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> uh
 		very few only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Caprice</ENAMEX> and them and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> uh the old V8s they're all brand new engines uh of course they're burning gasoline of course
 	
 	
 		they've done a lot
 	
 	
 		now and uh
 		whether you know that's one way you know uh
 		uh for on air pollution i i i don't know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> are the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX> or not really they've got catalytic converters everyone seem to have
 		gone to that whether they last uh and do a good job and now that they
 		the inspection systems are analyzing that uh well what do you think if you're in that you know if you're concerned about that i mean if you're you're you're knowledgeable on that
 	
 	
 		well there
 		well they uh it's interesting though because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are older and so i didn't have to if you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas County</ENAMEX>
 		you have to have your have to have it checked and it's great i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiero</ENAMEX> that uh they tried and tried and tried and had all kinds of terrible getting that pinned and so apparently
 		
 		
 	