
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right last thing i saw was um i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping With the Enemy</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i hadn't seen that but i've heard that it's real good
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> didn't like it that much i thought it was okay it was a little strange you know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> supposedly is um
 		being mentally abused by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> you know he keeps her pretty much terrorized to stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and she figures out this way to um
 		to leave him secretly you know she fakes her death kind of thing and he tracks her down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> scenes are are kind of suspenseful you know when she realizes he's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you know after her but uh
 		kind of had the feeling along that uh why didn't she just tell him to straighten up  you know why didn't she just tell him hey look bucko you don't get away with this nonsense
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but anyhow um what have you seen
 	
 	
 		well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> as a matter of fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> break and we went to two movies we went to see Awakenings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX> and we went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kindergarten Cop</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and i really liked both of them i really did Awakening
 		was it was kind of sad to me it really was and it would it would be to anyone because you know they really don't know that much about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so this is where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been kind of
 		well i don't a better word to say than like asleep or in a coma for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> let them come back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 		uh-huh but the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> didn't work for long and they started having real bad side effects
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and this is about nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty four</TIMEX> i believe or something like that and there still hasn't been any you know new development in
 		prescribed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> that can help it
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but yeah there you know it
 		it was a big breakthrough but in time you know the all the side effects started showing
 	
 	
 		well how bad were the side effects
 	
 	
 		bad
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah they was actually went back like they were you know
 	
 	
 		oh um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		all it was they wasn't mild you know they was just
 		bad side effects
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but i really enjoyed it though
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		well how about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kindergarten Cop</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  that's strictly for entertainment  that was just  it was
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> is getting to be uh a bit of a variety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> you know at first he was just a big muscle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> but he's kind of branching out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		he sure is he is as a matter of fact um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX> is that his name
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX> is that his name i really believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> is really going to be a variety variety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> more so than he is because he really played the part good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know he could be this rough tough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and then you know this substitute teacher
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		it was really good
 	
 	
 		well there was a movie out it's been on cable i get cable and there's this thing with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny De Vito</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i've seen that yes
 	
 	
 		i thought that was just great
 	
 	
 		it is it is isn't it yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i even like some i mean some of the original stuff like i like The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator</ENAMEX> at first you know it was kind of strange but i still like watching him in The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator</ENAMEX> and and some of the other things um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Total Recall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i thought was really good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		guess it didn't last too long at the box office but i thought it was pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah i did too i really did
 	
 	
 		and it was
 	
 	
 		i enjoy a lot of movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> as far as let's say heavy violence i can't handle
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i'm not into that
 		you know i just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rambo</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i that's just
 		something i just don't want to watch
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and i i have some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> at work i know gets really into those goofy horror flicks
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i just keep telling her how can you do that and i told her when she had her her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> i said now you better get out of the habit of watching those you shouldn't be watching them with your little girl
 		and she says her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s into it now
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and she watches she watches these really gross things you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Nightmare</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Elm Street</ENAMEX> and the you know that kind of junk i don't go for that at all
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh uh-huh
 		yeah
 		oh
 		i guess i'm a little too scary  for that
 	
 	
 		i remember when i was real little i we all went to some kind of scary movie and
 		it was like this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house big house</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> and there was all these weird things going on in the basement you know and i was scared to death of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> for years
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know and i got a lot of really weird ideas from that goofy movie
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know they tell you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> can you know be impressed by all that stuff and it's true i i had a lot of things that i i nobody told me that it was all fake i was just sitting there watching it going oh jeez
 	
 	
 		it is it really is yes
 		watching yeah
 		watching yes oh i don't want to go home yes yes  oh goodness
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it's funny get the same kind of fears like there's somebody under the bed
 	
 	
 		yes oh
 	
 	
 		where do we get that from
 	
 	
 		yes i know uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i really try to watch what they watch i really do because my youngest one he watches something you might as well just plan on staying up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> because you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he'll come in mama i think the ghost is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> mama i hear it
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		don't you
 	
 	
 		how old are they
 	
 	
 		they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so they're you know they hadn't really distinguished it's just a movie you know i try to say it's just a movie but no mama i've seen it
 	
 	
 		oh but i remember i was with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine had uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> must have been oh maybe about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> and we rented <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>'s Web okay
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and he just bawled at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> and just uh she's not going to die and we were trying to say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenny</ENAMEX> it's okay and he didn't want to listen to it
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		he just was beside himself you know this is supposed to be a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s movie <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>'s Web he just couldn't stand it that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> was going to die at the end
 	
 	
 		die oh  oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's funny how your little minds work isn't it oh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah she's so nice she can't die  oh it was just
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i guess that's why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and actresses make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> people like us you know
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 		well well i've enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		you too
 	
 	
 		and maybe we'll run across each other again
 	
 	
 		yeah this is kind of neat i haven't ever initiated a call i've just been called you know by the switchboard and uh well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first week</TIMEX> i think a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were doing it but i normally get a call like every other day
 	
 	
 		do you well as far as we could not call in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know from where i'm at
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we couldn't call in they said it would be up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday the March</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">fifteenth</ENAMEX> before it was prepared
 		so i missed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> because i was getting quite a few calls
 	
 	
 		um
 		how weird
 		i don't know and they they do have a variety of topics my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one was the toughest it was something like discuss pollution
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh uh-huh oh
 	
 	
 		it was discuss air pollution causes of it and cures i was going oh well
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh
 		
 
 		oh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> sometimes you know he'll receive a call and he's at work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if i you know if i know the topic i'll go ahead and accept it as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about</TIMEX> fishing and i thought oh my
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't know a thing about fishing so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm not even going to try
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because when they listened to that tape they would have really had a good time believe me
 	
 	
 		say well i know it takes a fishing pole and some bait and some water
 	
 	
 		but i'm really not for sure though if  well i'll let you go and we'll talk to you later okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		alrighty bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	