
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay what do you think about the idea of uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		kids having to do public service work for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> do you think it's a
 	
 	
 		well i i think it's a pretty good deal i think they should either do that or or or afford some time to the military or or helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX> i
 	
 	
 		yes yes definitely
 	
 	
 		i i'd you know i think that we have a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly folks</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that could use some help and i think that before we expend all our young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> overseas and
 		and helping other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> we ought to perhaps give a little bit of our help to our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at home and
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure that that's not a bad idear and or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX> wouldn't be bad for i think it teaches <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> how to grow how about yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh i agree with you um um what i'm thinking about is back oh when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and much earlier than that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were kind of
 		you know the parents kind of pushed them to join like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> and they did do do do a lot of public service
 		activities but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> they're not um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents parents</ENAMEX> aren't encouraging their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to do things like that because when i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> we did a lot of public service things
 		because that's just part of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of the scouting and you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i that's really great i i really think that both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> is a excellent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they are but parents
 	
 	
 		but you know they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> seem like when they get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> they fall out of that and and they don't follow it at all you know there're very few scouts go on and become <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Scouts</ENAMEX> and and i don't know what the high rank is for the gals but
 	
 	
 		yeah they do
 		oh no
 		i i a senior
 	
 	
 		ah senior okay so there's not uh
 	
 	
 		oh they're just not um once they get into junior high they just not done anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah they they lose interest and then when they young young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> there's even less interest they're they're more for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess uh not not yeah i mean me yeah  you're absolutely right  i think it's a really a good thing i i like to see
 	
 	
 		me  grab grab grab walk
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of course there's you know <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that can use all kind of help
 	
 	
 		yeah but there's a lot that can be done right here in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		but i think we ought to start right here at home i'm  you know
 	
 	
 		yeah um i'm not i'm not so sure that overseas help helping overseas would be such a hot idea for some for uh a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> people
 	
 	
 		no it it
 	
 	
 		but uh since there is much that needs to be done here
 	
 	
 		i think that yeah i think that we need to really address what we've done here and and then perhaps even a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six month</TIMEX> tour overseas that gives a much broader outlook
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it's been really good we talked about this for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> and uh hopefully we'll have another good topic maybe another call someday but i i don't really have too much more to say on this topic i guess
 	
 	
 		no uh i agree with you
 	
 	
 		we i guess we both agree that it's a good thing that they should do sometime well you take care and and enjoy the day thank you ma'am bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay you too
 		you too  bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	