
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		we've my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s retired and we vacationed a lot and i think i've had a lot in the meantime i'm not sure i would have picked that one either  shall we have a go at it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay trial by jury
 	
 	
 		um
 		i think one of the facets of living in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is that often times
 		you are uh sitting in on a jury trial where you might be acquainted with at least maybe not that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but part of their family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so that might lead you to a biased uh decision perhaps if you were uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i would think so
 	
 	
 		on the other hand um i don't know if course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> as all the expertise in that field and he's trained for that and and i'm sure there are certain
 		rules that are set down that he goes by uh along the way to make a decision
 		but
 		perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> can um
 		give their uh input as to what they think need to be done and then maybe he can go from there
 		uh have you ever sat on a jury trial
 	
 	
 		yes i have
 	
 	
 		yeah i have too and i found it real interesting but
 	
 	
 		i did to yes
 	
 	
 		but we weren't given any opportunity to make a decision as to what would happen we just said whether or not we thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> was guilty
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and he took it from there
 	
 	
 		uh the last trial i sat on
 		at the end of the session the prosecuting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> called us into a private room
 		and more or less instructed us to find her not guilty because even though they knew
 		and they proved that she had set fire to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in order to collect the insurance money that would we find her guilty she would simply flee the state and avoid any prosecution of any kind whatsoever
 		which we did find her guilty against his instruction and she did flee the state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but she was guilty and
 		we just didn't understand why he was doing that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that would merely make for some
 		odd behavior on the on their part
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> sat in on a jury trial a murder trial that lasted for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that left him uh i mean in the very beginning he was convinced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was not guilty and at the end of their deliberations he finally voted uh
 		guilty uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which surprised me that that uh through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> discussion they were able to convince him
 		against his original opinion so maybe that speaks well for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i remember the one that i sat in on we had quite a problem coming to a conclusion and and we came back with so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> this way and so many that way and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> told us we couldn't leave until we
 		came to a decision and we just could not we were split and he kept us there one <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and everyone wanted to go home and so they were willing some of them were willing to change their uh decision just to get out of uh out of the jury room
 	
 	
 		that doesn't seem fair does it
 	
 	
 		no and i i couldn't believe they would do that so maybe in a way it should be left up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> because uh maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> isn't
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> going to give them an honest decision
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i i don't know i guess if if we had more power
 		we're just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> so to speak and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we don't have the the uh background to maybe make that decision
 	
 	
 		the only thing that frightens me about that is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Graylord</ENAMEX> cases in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> where so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> were
 		guilty of so much misjustice from the bench
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that after all they're
 		only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too in that
 		they're subject to corruption just like any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> and they do have a lot of power
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it seems uh sometimes it seems uh rather
 		i guess rather uh odd that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would have that deciding factor
 		he would be the sole factor uh determining a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s outcome i guess though but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> still has their input and maybe he goes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> has a lot to decide has to decide a lot from what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> has input to the case too
 	
 	
 		maybe we both agree then that we need to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i think so
 	
 	
 		i think so
 	
 	
 		we could go on
 	
 	
 		i think we've reached a decision  nice visiting with you bye
 	
 	
 		i think we have
 		thank you bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	