
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		where to start
 	
 	
 		well i think
 		uh i haven't had that much of course i just heard but i haven't had that much time to think about it either
 		i guess the
 		um
 		biggest thing i find
 		find find is the
 		financial
 		aspects uh particularly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the ability of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to access
 		you know your financial records or for example your credit rating uh rating
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		almost at will
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		i didn't think about that
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		of course
 		flying uh using your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> number of course permits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and almost anything you do now
 		uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> number is required
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		of course there's another aspect of this too uh in terms of invasion of privacy i just thought about it being a professional and of course you probably belong to
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and that is that
 		some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> sell their mailing lists
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which i think is a is an invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes i get some of these things in the mail that i wonder where in the world did they get my address or where did they get my name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in fact some of these things i get some of these questionnaires it's funny because i'm i was in the process of filling one out when i decided i would make this phone call but um
 		i haven't got to the end of it yet where it asks all that salary information and everything but when you have to send that back in the mail with your name on it your salary information i i just have a real hard time doing that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and they ask you what type of household items do you own like stereos and TV's and VCR's and
 		and you hate to send something off with your name and address and what types of things do you own and what kind of money do you make and you wonder
 		well who's going to get ahold of this and think um that's a nice place to go rob
 	
 	
 		and not only that it it opens you to
 		phone solicitations
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i
 		i've noticed more and more i would say over the last
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i am getting more
 		at home phone solicitations
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for a variety of things from
 	
 	
 		i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight about six</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> when i sat down to eat dinner
 		carpet cleaning
 	
 	
 		i've had them for carpet cleaning i've had them for of course for you know real estate investments know you get uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		please send in your uh you know this particular card and you get uh
 		a free trip or something along those lines
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so that uh that bothers me because i
 		of course i enjoy being at home and
 		i do not enjoy
 		getting called by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh particularly solicit you know soliciting
 		so
 		having your and i know that a lot of these of course are random phone calls they just you know start going through the phone book or going through a series of numbers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but some of them are sold and i know you talking about mailing lists
 		the i there is one particular
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> to which i belong and for some the reason they have three
 		different
 		names
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		for me now the address is the same you know my my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> address
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they have one under you know my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
 		they have one under my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name and initial middle initial then they have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third one</NUMEX> under my just my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> initials
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		i get mail
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		here at home
 		under each of those names
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		so i know that they have sold their mailing list
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i think those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things bother me more than anything else as far as an invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i can't really think of anything else offhand that uh
 	
 	
 		i think i dislike the phone number part the worst i mean it's it's one thing to get junk mail because you can you can just put it right in the trash but it's the phone calls and
 		you know usually when they call you it's going to be when you sit right when you sit down to dinner because they know
 		they pretty much know that you're at work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and they call you right when when you've just gotten home from work the last thing you want is a phone call unless it's you know something halfway enjoyable but if it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesperson</ENAMEX> it's just something you don't want to have to mess with and
 		and i've gotten a lot of them lately or i'll sometimes i come home from work and there's a lot of hang ups on my answering machine and i'm just assuming it's probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> that called during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and
 		i wasn't home and they'll probably call me up and you know call me back and bother me when i sit down to dinner later on but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i find that very annoying the uh mail stuff yeah you know it's kind of irritating but it's not nearly as obnoxious as the phone calls
 	
 	
 		i think you i think you mentioning the phone calls during dinner
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know when i sit down with the family
 		and want to have the opportunity you know to talk
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and see what's going on and all those things
 		even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> call
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it irritates me so i try to i actually during that period of time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		from you know usually from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six o'clock</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six thirty</TIMEX> whenever i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or so</TIMEX> i will
 		shut off the phone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> gets irate when i when i do that because you know she's a teenager
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		uh oh
 	
 	
 		so she'll you know why are you cutting off the phone i might get an important phone call so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		so those i guess those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things are the uh
 		um
 		most irritating to me
 	
 	
 		um-hum i agree with the phone too in that i'm single but
 		when i come home from work there's times i need to pay bills i need to balance my checking account i need to do all kinds of different things like that and
 		even though it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> calling sometimes you just feel like this is my quiet time i need to get things done and the phone ringing bothers me but that's
 		that's where answering machines are nice because if it's really important they'll leave a message and i can call them back but uh at work i have so many phone calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> calling in sometimes it is just
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		i just want to get away from the phone ringing because it it really does annoy me and uh if i've had a lot of phone calls during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> when occasionally we have uh like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past week</TIMEX> we have to do a lot of troubleshooting when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">programmers</ENAMEX> have installed a new system
 		and uh phone rings like crazy and you come home and the last thing you want to do is have to answer the phone and if it's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> that just makes it even that much worse
 		and uh it just i get to where i i turn the answering machine on
 		and just let it pick up the phone but now with this thing i'm participating in i kind of have to answer it because you never know if it's the switchboard or if it's uh you know somebody calling that you really don't want to talk on the phone
 	
 	
 		well i have you know we have a you know voice mail system at uh at the office
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now what i have done is
 		i have forwarded my home phone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to the answering service at the office
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that i do not have to have a um a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> at all
 		oh huh that's an idea
 	
 	
 		if i if i want to do that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh or i will just
 		let the phone ring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> times and know that it will forward to uh to the office
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so it's you know it makes it convenient but at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> when i you know we can uh on our system and i imagine on most systems
 		you can just
 		route it directly to the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">answering</ENAMEX> service
 	
 	
 		yeah ours is that way too
 	
 	
 		and when i when i want to be you know not bothered during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> that's exactly what i do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so uh
 	
 	
 		well yours is probably the same as ours it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tigon</ENAMEX> isn't Tigon uh part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX> or vice versa or something like that
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		seems i read
 	
 	
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tigon</ENAMEX> is part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay okay that's it that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX> had purchased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tigon</ENAMEX> and yeah that's what we have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		except we call it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aspen</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		Aspen hum
 	
 	
 		yes
 		and uh
 		we
 	
 	
 		i couldn't remember in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tigon</ENAMEX> had purchased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>'s phone mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> or if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX> had purchased <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tigon i</ENAMEX> knew there was some type of a tie in there i remember reading in the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> back but
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX> purchased Tigon
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and so
 		we
 		have have been using a the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aspen</ENAMEX> service before they purchased Tigon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i imagine we will be
 		uh shifting over to that service
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh for a while or if in a while
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as soon as we determine what we're going to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contel</ENAMEX> after we bought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana</ENAMEX> i think we have probably conversed long enough well all right
 	
 	
 		i think we did that's good
 		i didn't think we could go too far on this privacy thing but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess it's close enough
 	
 	
 		all right well thank you for calling i had i i enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		sure good talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
 		all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		take care
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	