
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		so where have you been where have you been camping before
 	
 	
 		well i've been camping a number of uh of state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> as it were and one of the
 		the first ones that i ever went out with was with another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there were some uh college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> uh
 		uh out on a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out and there were probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or fifteen little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents strung</ENAMEX> in a row on a little peninsula sticking out into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> Texoma
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and the wind started blowing and it was one of my earlier trips to be really out in the middle of
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no where as far as wind breaks go and and we had secured tents real well even if we had done it in the dark at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock at night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh oh i guess <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> into my
 		somewhat sleep a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> woke me up and uh said you'd better get out of the the tent they're they're liable to come down several of the others had already come down blown down they hadn't blown away but they had flattened
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i said okay i didn't you know was kind of groggy didn't know what was going on and crawled out of that tent and uh sure enough uh shortly after that they blew down so we're out here in the pitch dark in this wind and it starts to rain
 	
 	
 		
 
 		naturally
 	
 	
 		and we managed to uh fortunately the rain didn't last long but we managed to get them all back up and uh got some sleep in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> and
 		after we got uh
 		back from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> we checked with one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the other college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they were a little concerned they had heard on the radio that the winds on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam</ENAMEX> there anyway had gotten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to ninety</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven miles an hour</NUMEX> straight winds and
 	
 	
 		good grief
 	
 	
 		and we could believe that we were out in that at that time and it uh it can be quite a horror story i guess and i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that was a bad a bad place to be especially right there on the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> especially if it i mean if it were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> you're all right because it probably wasn't too cold but uh probably the worst one that ever happened to me was in when i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		right it was summer
 	
 	
 		um i was stationed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellsworth</ENAMEX> there at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapid City</ENAMEX>
 		and it's right there at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Hills</ENAMEX> and i just absolutely love the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Hills</ENAMEX> it's the greatest place in the world to go camping you throw a pack on your back and get up in the mountains
 		and you can understand how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> got real religious up there because it's just it's just awesome up there
 		so quiet and peaceful and the wind blowing through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and all that i had a favorite little camping spot i used to go to it was uh right next to a stream and all the streams of of course are mountain fed melted snow
 		so it's nice and ice cold a good place to keep your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> and stuff and this little place was uh it was a perfect a perfect circle of trees
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		it was almost like they were intentionally planted that way and i would camp right in the middle of this thing and it provided shelter and everything else it was just absolutely terrific well
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winters</TIMEX> are pretty tough up there and right around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> i start get cabin fever
 		and i say oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i got to go camping so throw all the stuff in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and of course being the careful camper that i am i carried my uh propane heater with me and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple</NUMEX> bottles of propane
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so i get my tent up and i get my fire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> built and all that and i'm just having a good time and uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>
 		it got down to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seventeen degrees</NUMEX> below <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> and snowed
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and i'm sitting in this tent in my sleeping bag freezing
 		so i said oh time to get this heater cranked up so i cranked up the heater and this things going of course i got it going full bore
 		i run out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">propane</ENAMEX> so here it is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> and i've got to hike back to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to get more propane
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well across the stream there's a fallen log that you have to walk across to get into this little place
 		and i'm crossing over the top of this thing it's snowing the thing is slippery and of course i slipped and fell in
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> i'm up to my neck in freezing ice cold <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and i can just feel my heart just you know scrunch right up the size of a pecan
 		so i finally drug myself out of that i just got in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and drove home i left everything sitting there i just got just got in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> went home got uh got a nice hot shower uh i got some dry clothes on and then went back
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		that was probably the worst thing that ever happened
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i hope to never venture into something that drastic
 	
 	
 		it's fun though that that was i just absolutely loved it up there that whole part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was great went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Glacier National Park</ENAMEX> a couple of times and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yellowstone Yellowstone</ENAMEX> is just too crowded though it's not a lot of fun with a whole bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX> bears i mean they're almost tame they come up begging for hand outs you know course i'm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of you know being around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> there's nothing left of them as far as wildness goes
 	
 	
 		well that's true and and it's sad because now they they're so used to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they're going into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and raiding garbage cans and stuff and that presents a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living there and now they're having to shoot them
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you know i mean it's sad because those those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bears</ENAMEX> were doing fine until we got there you know and now they're now we're killing them because of something that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> that we created
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i don't know it upsets me a little bit i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bears</ENAMEX> they're pretty they're pretty cool
 	
 	
 		yeah that's it's a shame to change a whole area so much like that
 	
 	
 		yeah and to me <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> was just too uh commercialized
 		i mean it it's it's got some areas that are really nice but i mean you get up there and everything is just you know you know souvenirs and all this kind of junk
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and i i sort of i like the really raw land you know go out and where no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has gone before and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh uh i've been mainly with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh sometimes with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> here and there a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> get together but mainly it college age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 		uh on this one weekend where the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> blew down <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that same weekend</TIMEX> we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that yeah he thought he wanted to come and then when he got there it was a little more boring and you know that place doesn't have a whole lot to do up there
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh he sat in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> most of the time and and uh listened to his tapes and fortunately he didn't keep them crank them up too loud but he uh he stayed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and did what he could have done at home as it were
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it was no surprise when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> rolls around and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> won't start and then you listened to tapes all weekend you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right there goes his battery
 	
 	
 		it doesn't take much but uh we got him all back going and
 		packed up and came on back uh let's see i i had another another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out that wasn't uh near as bad in fact it had some really good good points to it i'm trying to think of exactly where we were
 		uh we were on another lake i don't remember the the name of it but we were right up at the shore and the way it was layed out the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> grounds were
 		uh it was another state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campgrounds</ENAMEX> had railroad ties blocking off a sandy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pit</ENAMEX> and that made for a fairly level place to put the tent
 		but to get down to the beach you had to walk down a real steep embankment i mean it was so steep they had put railroad ties as stair steps every once in a while mainly for the erosion and that became a path as it were
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the beach was beautiful we managed to comb out some of the broken glass and the like but the actual sand was a real good quality and real deep and we set up the old volleyball net and you know just a typical
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty or thirty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> playing volleyball on the beach and this this cove this beach was a bit of a cove
 		and it was surrounded oh i'd say <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple of hundred yards</NUMEX> by uh this hill this mountainous uh rock terrain and only that little bitty section of it was actually beach the rest of it was water right up against the rock
 		so you pretty well had the whole area to yourself there were enough of us where we filled the whole peninsula as far as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the camping</TIMEX> on both sides so we did we all had to walk down to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area to go down to the bea ch and it was pretty much the whole area to ourself
 		beautiful weekend however at that time at that stage in our life our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were
 		were uh real young and one of them managed to catch diarrhea while we were there so we'd have to run him up the the hill and you know the little portable toilet was up there and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it was a little bit to bulky to bring all the way down to the to the beach with us and we probably should have found some way to do that or
 		but uh and it was hot and we had a little trouble keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> it didn't last as long as we had planned so we had to buy that a little more often but uh the beach just couldn't uh couldn't have been any better a good place to dive for balls
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh yeah i uh i used to uh when i was over in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam i</ENAMEX> used to go out and just spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> on the beach and go scuba go scuba diving at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and
 		looking around
 		it was a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah you have to get pretty far out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area to uh be able to see the stars and uh we do that on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> outs
 	
 	
 		yeah all the all the  all the light pollution
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that was one good thing about the hills you could get up there and it was just it was crystal clear it was just beautiful you saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> you never saw before great place i'd love to go back up there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		maybe i'll get back up there one of these days
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of course i'm in i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and</TIMEX> and uh the mountains here are pretty nice i haven't been i just got here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last September</TIMEX> but i'm planning to
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		do a little camping trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>
 		get up there in the mountains and have a look we used to uh when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> as a boy uh we used to have our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> retreats in uh
 		
 		
 	