
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		all right
 		uh
 		i i would like to talk about just briefly  what happened over there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> in the political context
 		i think it's uh refreshing to see
 		the uh the support
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> got from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
 	
 	
 		yeah it we i i read an interesting article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that discussed uh
 		that uh
 		seemed that every other time a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> tried to get support for an action like uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> and his thing with the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostage</ENAMEX> crisis and he always did it through rhetoric
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and this time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did it through action and he he drove policy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		by
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> he took and almost forced public support or uh i mean he left almost no alternative
 	
 	
 		yes
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and and it was very interesting how he did it and uh i mean i'm i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> so it uh it was interesting for me uh you know i'd certainly
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really
 	
 	
 		uh i i mean i think it's great that all the support i have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> i'm i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolm Laboratory</ENAMEX> but other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers guys</ENAMEX> here on base this is a B fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">base</ENAMEX> where i work so
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gone from the base that went over there and they're getting a tremendous amount of support out of it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's great um if if you remember the vote in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to authorize war if necessary was actually pretty close
 	
 	
 		yes it was
 	
 	
 		and if if my memory serves me right i believe a majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> may even have opposed it
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i don't know the exact figure but i i would imagine that because of the
 	
 	
 		it it was
 	
 	
 		how close the the vote was i'm uh i mean almost certainly would have to be Just based on the sheer numbers of uh
 		the disparity of  excuse me <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> he'd think that it would have to have been
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and uh i i gosh this uh this whole thing now with all the uh
 		all the political cartoons on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and how they're
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		uh uh
 		they're in in a sad way for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> now in terms of the presidential election anyway
 	
 	
 		especially the ones that came out and said oh come on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> let's talk about this little while longer
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> are we going to wait and what what do you do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are over there in the mean time
 	
 	
 		right right i think that was all those
 		factors played a part in you know uh the everyone was
 	
 	
 		no doubt
 	
 	
 		discussing whether we should uh wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer</TIMEX> but i i i know that
 		there's a
 		lot of reasons to wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">longer</TIMEX> but i think we were genuinely concerned about how their military capability and we uh i think we over estimated it but still we were really
 	
 	
 		i think so too
 	
 	
 		highly concerned about it and that we were worried that they were getting dug in and uh
 	
 	
 		well they were and in fact they were so well dug in that uh when we sent our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> around behind them they couldn't get turned around in time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right they couldn't yeah they couldn't yeah it's true they
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> thought he had the whole thing uh figured out to to which way we were coming and which what what our doctrine was that uh
 	
 	
 		well had had we done a frontal assault it probably would have worked more to his favor
 	
 	
 		that's right that's true
 		that's interesting i think uh
 		this political situation over there now is uh
 		uh it'll be interesting to see what comes out of it whether the this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX> will
 		uh uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turks</ENAMEX> uh agreed to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> which is something they've never done before and uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 		interesting
 	
 	
 		and uh this and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> uh and not the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> all of a sudden are uh
 		are cheering for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> on his drive for
 		to reconcile relations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> so it's like
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> is is really
 		not very much pro <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		and did you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sununu</ENAMEX> is uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no uh i i think i did hear that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX> because i used to live in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right in fact when he was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> i believe okay
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i believe he was the only one of fifty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>
 		that voted against some kind of resolution of support for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		and uh now he is a conservative but he is not a conservative that favors <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and that that concerns me greatly
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well
 		i don't
 		yeah i'd certainly uh support <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> in in their their policy that in defending themselves and in uh in their handling of their foreign policy i think
 		i think the stand they have or or the way the command respect i i support that i think that is a a positive thing for them after um
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they have to uh
 		they had i think they in when they became became a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> they more than or more or less decided they weren't going to take it anymore and uh
 	
 	
 		well they didn't have much choice they could either fight or die
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		exactly exactly and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um so gee i lost my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> of thought here but uh
 		um
 		so okay so i can't say whether that that i'm pro <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> or anti <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> i mean i'd like to see them resolve something in that situation and get some stability
 		in the region and looks uh that the joining of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> for this uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Desert Shield</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> thing ended up being a positive thing
 	
 	
 		it is a positive thing um
 		however uh every time an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> says well we'll see if we can work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel</ENAMEX>
 		then uh they get embarrassed some <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every few months</TIMEX> by documents that reveal that their ultimate purpose is to totally eliminate them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so you you basically have
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh mutually exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is going to occupy the area or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> are going to occupy the area and i'm just not sure that that there's going to be any easy permanent solution
 	
 	
 		yeah somebody's going to and i think that's the problem the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">P L O</ENAMEX> has is that when they
 		whenever
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of them decides that they're going to negotiate or they're going to do something
 		they're going to try to make some peace but uh
 		the end result is that they there so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> of them and uh some more violent than others some with a certain agenda different than the others or
 		they split they end up being becoming divisive themselves
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		uh i
 		it's interesting i i'm i'm looking forward to seeing what happens over there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple of months</TIMEX> but uh that's
 	
 	
 		it is
 		yeah i i commend <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> for their restraint in not responding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scud</ENAMEX> attacks
 	
 	
 		yeah i know that that is almost i mean that's absolutely unprecedented that was an an incredible foreign policy
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		coup on the part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Departme</ENAMEX> nt and that i mean that's never happened before
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly
 		no
 	
 	
 		and i don't know if it will e ver happen again but
 	
 	
 		may not well it's been fun i enjoyed enjoyed talking with you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay
 		uh i guess uh well maybe the computer will pair us up together another time
 	
 	
 		you never know
 	
 	
 		all right bye bye
 	
 	
 		bye bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	