
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what would you do about this pressing problem
 	
 	
 		well i can relate to uh when i decided to choose a college
 		uh it really had very little to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i i stayed at a i went to a local uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> that was close to home it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about sixty miles</NUMEX> away went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh besides it being uh close and being a uh major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> in the big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> a prestigious conference i joined the marching band
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh that really was uh a good deal of the motivation for going to that uh college
 	
 	
 		so with the band
 	
 	
 		yeah something to do extracurricular activity
 	
 	
 		what do you play
 	
 	
 		i play the trumpet
 	
 	
 		my uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> played music he was involved in music all of his life and went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX> where he decided he was going to have a good time
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and never  and then  never went into the scholastic bands he went into uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		bands on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> and he played music but i i just can't believe that  he didn't can play in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX>  when he was good enough to do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he went the other route i think uh i think the advise i'd give to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would be to start when they're like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years old</TIMEX> today
 	
 	
 		at least start saving
 	
 	
 		yeah at least start saving and and start routing them to where at least they'll have a chance to get ahead
 	
 	
 		well i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when they are in high school are very undecided about what course of study they want to take
 		and they really don't have the foggiest idea of what kind of career they want to get into at least until at least until they've been in college for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 		it's um
 		i wish i had known more when i was uh
 		choosing a college i i kind of did or i'd i went off to i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and i went off to
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Utah</ENAMEX> and didn't find the atmosphere there what i quite expected so i came back and went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cal State</ENAMEX> and so i kind of do what you did only by route of another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wish i had known more about what a school meant
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i started uh studying mathematics basically because i was really good at that in high school
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh by the time i was a sophomore i decided that mathematics was really not the thing to be into to find a good job they weren't hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematicians</ENAMEX> at the time
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i started taking computer science <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and uh that become my major course of study uh i finished a major in mathematics also i had a double major but uh computer science is what got me a job
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it was very uh very much in demand for a career
 	
 	
 		well it still is
 	
 	
 		uh still is that's true it's uh very good choice
 	
 	
 		i was just looking at a job sheet that's about all that's in there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so but i know many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have changed majors several times in uh college uh in fact very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> finish in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		do you think it do you think it's well worth going to uh uh bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or more well-known school
 	
 	
 		uh i really don't think it makes that much difference what size of the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> or university <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chooses as long as they have a decent program and they're uh
 		uh
 		well known throughout the country
 	
 	
 		right right the reputation that they have a good reputation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um some of these i didn't the college i went to was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but i was an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> major and it the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> major is very small so i had the
 		benefit of being able to talk to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> and hangout with them you know and i really appreciated that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that does make a difference uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> had a very good reputation in uh computer science and engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and i'm sure that helped uh helped me get job offers
 		uh if you choose a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that's not well known or it does not have a very good curriculum in uh in the in those areas uh it could be difficult to uh make a career out of it
 	
 	
 		right
 		i think that's what i would tell parents
 		
 
 	
 	
 		kind of like uh going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX> they have a reputation as being a party school
 		and uh
 		i just
 		
 
 		i have to question how worthwhile it is to go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that uh really isn't uh that well known for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hey i'm headed there
 	
 	
 		i took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of semesters</TIMEX> of graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> there myself
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of liberal arts there and so i thought i would go and do that
 	
 	
 		right
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it's the closest thing to a humanities degree that they let you do at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's not the i i'm not into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bohemian</ENAMEX> thing you know were i <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at night</TIMEX> and go to school during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah  i was just making making a point that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> develop certain reputations and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i i agree  but but it's like oh you offer this degree okay i'll go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i've always wanted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> degree but to get one in in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> or anything other than an MBA it's really difficult to do at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's true uh
 		i i took uh like i said i took uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of semesters</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX> and it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX> in uh engineering courses
 		but uh it really did conflict too much with uh with my work it's very difficult uh to maintain a full-time job and try to take uh courses uh in off hours
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		it's true
 	
 	
 		so i quit doing that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and just lived the easy life
 	
 	
 		well yeah somewhat  i wouldn't mind going back to school again if i thought it i wasn't going to get in trouble again with the with the work it just takes too much time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		going back full-time i think is is the way to go
 	
 	
 		oh it it would be wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah if one can afford to do that that's back to the reason why why i joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> that was my entertainment while i was in school
 	
 	
 		i know the little dreams
 		right
 	
 	
 		going to all the football games and hockey and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> games
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because when you're a poor starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> you don't have the uh cash flow to uh entertain yourself  you have to find whatever means you can
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's true yeah
 	
 	
 		those events were always free
 	
 	
 		i i uh i picked up sweats for the track team i was the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track track</ENAMEX> team <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> we got i got to ride the bus all over the state  i got to see everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that sounds exciting
 	
 	
 		so it was fun it was little i did that for a long time it was a lot of fun so i understand that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i'd recommend that if if someone was trying to choose a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that they they get uh as much information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> as they can as far as what curriculums they offer and uh how reputable they are and what kind of reputation they have in the country
 		and uh go from there
 		the rest of it's just personal preference whether you like the mascot or not or whether it's close by
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		i mean uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> was only up uh sixty mile bus ride away from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> house so it only took an hour to get back on uh oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weekends a semester</TIMEX>
 		it was very convenient
 		not to mention being a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> it was the tuition was uh much less expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah that was a good thing to look out for
 	
 	
 		i looked into going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marquette</ENAMEX> also and had a chance to get a scholarship there but it would have only covered uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a quarter</NUMEX> of the cost of the first uh year which uh wasn't enough of a motivation to uh to go there to commit to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">to four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well we're still writing checks for the loans for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i'm sure that that's uh it's not uh cheap either
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but he's really happy he went there
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 		i i got uh by with the minimal amount of financial aid and was able to pay it all off within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of graduation
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so i was very pleased with that of course i lived like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pauper</ENAMEX> too during that time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that did most couldn't afford to to go to a movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was uh really living on a budget
 		forced you to learn a few things that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but we had fun
 	
 	
 		tried to have fun being in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> was about the only entertainment i had
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i really i miss college i had a good time
 	
 	
 		that was fun uh lived on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tombstone</ENAMEX> pizzas and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it was fun
 		well i'll just wrap this up
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		now that we've done our conversation for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well wonder if if this advice was uh worth following for uh choosing a school
 	
 	
 		
 
 		hopefully i i guess i don't know what they're doing with the conversations
 	
 	
 		they're being recorded and uh oh put in uh i guess in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> somewhere for reference for speech projects
 	
 	
 		aren't aren't they like put taking the words and and listening to the dialect and yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that is true based on where where you come from and all
 	
 	
 		that's funny
 	
 	
 		where you're educated in the first uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		that would be interesting well it was good talking to you
 	
 	
 		okay i appreciate it enjoyed it all right bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> thanks a lot bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	