
 
     		
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> do you have a favorite team
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh the of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i live live and die with them
 	
 	
 		okay well they're rebuilding right now yet i think it's going to take them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple more years</TIMEX> before they can be a really good team
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah uh of course
 		i guess really the reason i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> is because
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX> was my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> uh college  pardon me college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and of course they started out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Meredith</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so that that tie there between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> have shown a lot of improvement this uh past year
 	
 	
 		yeah uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Johnson</ENAMEX> surprised me
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i didn't think he was going to do very good because i thought he was a college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> and not a professional coach
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay yeah i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had that impression that uh that he ought he should have stayed in the college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranks</ENAMEX> but uh looks like they're going to do all right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah course he he came after a legend too <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Landry</ENAMEX> so he had some uh tough row to hoe there
 	
 	
 		my
 		yeah big shoes to follow  well my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is a is a sentimental favorite uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Bay Packers</ENAMEX> i grew up in that area and have been following them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 
 		pardon my for coughing i've been coming down with a cold
 	
 	
 		been following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Packers</ENAMEX> ever since uh they won the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowls</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		they used to have some uh
 		bang up fights and dig in the trenches with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ice Bowl</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah they sure did i remember those
 	
 	
 		the other uh
 		games that they would play for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowls</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i actually know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ice Bowl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		at uh
 		they had they had some good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		they could have had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good year this year</TIMEX> uh unfortunately the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> uh controversy they had where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don McCowskey</ENAMEX> got hurt and couldn't play most <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they spent an awful lot of money on him too <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million and a half</NUMEX> dollars for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> contract
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know if he's going to be in shape to
 	
 	
 		and course they were they were kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> in that after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lombardi</ENAMEX> who could fill his shoes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		who did you root for in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i didn't really have a favorite in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> i just wanted to see a good game
 	
 	
 		yeah both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i was tired of blow outs
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well that turned out to be a good game
 	
 	
 		and it it was it was good to see a good good uh championship game
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> is an up an coming team they're going to they're showing some real promise for the next uh few years
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> are always uh always there perennially a good team
 	
 	
 		yeah well their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> has a lot to do with that i think
 	
 	
 		i think they had a lot of luck there too with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> getting hurt in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i think if if he was uh healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> would have stomped those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> it wouldn't have been much of a contest
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		but uh there's a lot of parity now compared to what it used to be
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's getting better more competitive
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh we see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> getting in the play-offs every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> with uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> records or a little below even
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFC Central</ENAMEX> is a lot like that with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh Cincinnati Cleveland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> nobody really dominated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah another one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> was in the old uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL</ENAMEX> or the uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Football League</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> when they started
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		in fact they were they out drew the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> there for quite a while
 	
 	
 		okay i wasn't living here then so i can't talk much about that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but uh but some of these some of the uh i get a little disappointed sometime with with uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now days</TIMEX> compared with the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> it seems like most the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		are playing for the money rather than the the uh
 		fun and for the uh competition that used to be in the older days
 	
 	
 		well there's no doubt about that the money's there and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> are willing to pay if unfortunately uh and you get star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> like uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Montana</ENAMEX> making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four million dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and everybody else wants to match that type of salary now
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> end up paying for it are the fans
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it's no wonder ticket prices are so high
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't go to games myself uh uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i can't afford to go to them
 	
 	
 		no you you really can't not when it costs twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six dollars</NUMEX> a ticket and uh so much for parking
 	
 	
 		nah you you take
 		yeah you take just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> by the time you pay the tickets
 		the parking
 		uh any kind of refreshments or anything there you can spend a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> right quick
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can afford to spend a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> have somewhat lost sight on that because uh they are all wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh the expect that uh the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> is going to be able to to go to a game and uh pay for that type of entertainment
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		and also i don't like the deal uh with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> stadium
 		where that you to get a decent seat you have to buy a season ticket
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		the only seats they have available are in the end zone
 	
 	
 		yeah it looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Jones</ENAMEX> is trying to make as much money as he can out of this deal uh he's got his own TV show and he opened the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cowboy Corral</ENAMEX> out in in the parking lot there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh every every opportunity there is to make a dollar he seems to be exploiting that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but that's that's true just about every
 	
 	
 		i think there's still a lot of distrust for uh for an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to come here and own uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't think that's going to die very quickly he is getting some support there were a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are uh that were skeptical and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> are coming back and they have a pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Aikman</ENAMEX> looks like to be looks like he's got the star qualities for a quarterback
 	
 	
 		hum yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah if they'll just give him some protection and don't kill him before h e
 	
 	
 		yeah well i was surprised at the the way they drafted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> they didn't really didn't go for the uh big offensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lineman</ENAMEX> or the defensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lineman</ENAMEX> they're going for the skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> they really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		really didn't need that type of uh player
 	
 	
 		yeah and i you know i think defense really is what wins
 		wins uh in the long run you can have the best <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> back there is or the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> but if they don't have any blocking maybe they can't do anything
 	
 	
 		yeah they've got an awful lot of good draft picks coming up it's going to be interesting to see what they do with them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so hopefully we'll see some more improvement
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFC East</ENAMEX> uh they're they're getting uh older uh they're going to have to like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> Redskins uh that that's an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and they're going to have to start rebuilding pretty soon too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		looks like we'll reach a point of uh parity there where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> may start being a little more competitive with the rest of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah what
 	
 	
 		i don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>'s going to do without <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy Ryan</ENAMEX> it might be interesting to see
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't know i i have mixed emotions about him
 		uh sometimes i like him but at the same times i love to see somebody beat him
 	
 	
 		yeah he's uh one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you love to hate
 	
 	
 		because he's got a mouth on him
 	
 	
 		kind of like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Glanville</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> you love to hate
 	
 	
 		yeah they they do pick up the image of a team though uh and they create a lot of excitement locally so i think they're good for the game just because they are diverse and they bring a different attitude
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		but um
 		but he yeah to me he's just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> you just
 	
 	
 		but uh they're not my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		you love to see someone beat him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		they do have a good team
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy</ENAMEX> will probably get another job
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think old uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham</ENAMEX> is an excellent quarterback
 	
 	
 		oh he's great i saw him play when he as at uh UNLV he was not only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> but the punter and he can punt the ball sixty yards no problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah i imaging he could play just about any position on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> except maybe a defensive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lineman</ENAMEX> but he's a very excellent athlete
 	
 	
 		he's a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> that is true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> expected to do a little better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX> unfortunately they uh they got cut a little short
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i don't they uh the games they lost lost i don't think they lost by any blowout i think they were all close games
 	
 	
 		no
 		i like the team i really really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> a lot but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddy Ryan</ENAMEX>  is not one of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so i wasn't too disappointed to see them lose
 	
 	
 		no
 		i i'm wondering where he's going to wind up
 	
 	
 		i don't think he's going to get a head coaching job this next year
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		he'd be lucky if he can get an assistant uh job someplace
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um he's just one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> he's created such a controversy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> nobody wants to touch him right now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but uh he'll he'll wind somewhere
 	
 	
 		i'm sure he will he's not going to have problems there if not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> then in one of the other leagues
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm kind of interested how this new uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>'s going to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> league's going to fare
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide Area Football League WWAFL</ENAMEX> or whatever they call it WWAFL
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Football League</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> is going to use that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> as uh
 		uh kind of like as a minor league to recruit players
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about uh there's not that it won't be as good as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> because uh there's not that many good or quality <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> i can't believe that
 	
 	
 		not only that but they don't pay the money either
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh
 	
 	
 		uh it's very low uh scale compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i still think there's plenty of good <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> around that just
 		were not able to get on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> were just full
 	
 	
 		right well some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'm sure the the more talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> are going to try to uh impress <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scouts</ENAMEX> with their play in that league
 	
 	
 		yeah but yeah and wind up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		possibly but that's that's uh one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX> shot if they have the talent to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> they're going to get drafted and make a pro <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> there aren't going to be too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that'll make uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> out of uh WWALF
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it will be like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> with the uh with with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> can come back and play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> but most of them don't really don't have the physical skills or the talent
 	
 	
 		right
 		but uh
 		i'm i'm looking forward to the season i think it's going to be fun yeah
 	
 	
 		i think it will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> are showing constant
 		
 		
 	