
 
     		
 	
 		did they say anything
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i guess we got <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> or something like that i don't know
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so what do you think
 	
 	
 		um i think they should do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i do because um with all all the sports you know and everything they're doing there
 		and also because whenever you're dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> like if you if you are on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> then that affects the way you work and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i agree but i think they're slow  in testing  you know i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> yours but <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mines</ENAMEX> they so slow they tested some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> twice <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> haven't been tested at all
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well see um and i worked for a steel mill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two summers</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i had to go through you know a physical and everything and before they even told you you were hired like they just called me in for an interview
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i went in for my interview and then right there he said okay go down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company hospital</ENAMEX> and you'll go through a physical so you know i mean it was really good that way because they they tested everyone right away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you didn't you didn't have any notice you know so like if you were doing drugs then like you didn't have a way you know to stop i mean it was still in your body
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i like that i know when i i was in that like  in the service and we didn't have we used to have to go every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other month</TIMEX> or whenever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to uh just do do we called it the golden flow but  and they did random drug testing
 		just because
 		
 
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uncle Sam</ENAMEX> but i've always thought that they were slow  as far as outside of the government you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		because i've always i'm i'm use to it
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's no big deal
 	
 	
 		yeah well see you know i well
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i guess if you're not doing anything it's no big deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> call it invasion of privacy not to me it's not because <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all if you're not doing anything they're not invading anything
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and if you're taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> that's no big deal either
 	
 	
 		yeah because like what
 	
 	
 		because then they'll or you have a prescription
 	
 	
 		yeah you know what too whenever they did that for me like you know we had to take they did it blood and urine
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and um they they gave you a paper right there and they said if you were out drinking or if you went out for a good time last night go ahead and write down that you did have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> or you did have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> or if you are on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> go ahead and write down what medicine you are on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay but i you know so they allotted for you know things like that like you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't know they were being tested well you might have had a drink <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> you know and that would show up too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well see they don't do a blood test to us
 		
 
 		they just do a urine test which i think they should do a a blood test because then that tells them that you know they testing for  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> but i think
 		it's like i tell and then you know they have all this smoking stuff why don't they just test for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> because that's between <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> that's it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> there is i think they should do both of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know because then that that way they'll they'll get rid of they can help the alkies and then they can help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that's on drugs
 	
 	
 		yeah and then uh it got you know it got backfired on a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> too because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um like you know like somehow they missed the physical or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and they wrote down that they uh weren't but then they went back and they checked them like maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> after they were working and if they had <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in their body i mean they were fired on the spot there was no ifs ands or buts about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum i that's all right
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think this way too because in that steel mill i mean someone
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and see some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> always talk about the kind of job you do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it would that wouldn't be fair if they tested just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with strenuous jobs
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because you know you you got your your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and your your air traffic controllers your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i would want all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> checked but then you got your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> are checked because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> drives a truck they he has to pass a physical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know but i think why don't they and and to me it's wrong to check just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you think are affecting the public
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		why not just check everybody so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah see they checked everyone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> too and then that was hard because you know someone would come in and they had a problem well then if i like some of the jobs i was doing was very dangerous you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we were working with that steel that's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of degrees</NUMEX> hot and i would have to cover for him you know like i would have to do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jobs for someone just because they they think they're being smart or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and i mean they even had um the the higher up management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would even come in periodically and have unexpected checks you know
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		so it was really good you know they were checking you know visually and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and the urine tests
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's all right
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought it was really good
 	
 	
 		because they check our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> and everything and i think that's the way it should be if they going to check you know that way you can't stay well they didn't check my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>
 		you know yeah they checked him too  so everybody's getting checked it's not like it's just little peons it's everybody
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah yes
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that that's the way i think they should do it that way it is random you know it's random because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is already gone <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two three</NUMEX> times and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> ain't went at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and they just when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> comes up your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> comes up
 	
 	
 		yeah right and then uh they checked us like once during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the summer</TIMEX> also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know like it's not like they just like well then the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time when i got hired i knew what was coming you know so then they checked us again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i thought that was really good too
 		i don't i
 	
 	
 		well i think if you're doing something really bad  it's going to show up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't think you can hide
 		
 
 		certain drugs
 	
 	
 		no i think it what is it like
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know even even like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> well how long does it take for marijuana to get out of your body
 	
 	
 		that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		see so there still
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they said it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX> but
 		on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my our our thing is they said that you'd have to the way the test is you'd have to really be smoking for it to show up and i don't think that's right
 	
 	
 		oh really i thought it would show up with no matter what amount we
 	
 	
 		that's what he told
 		that's what they tell you but i think it is i think it'd show up no matter what if you doing it then it's going to show up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> i mean that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> that's a lot longer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that takes a lot longer to get out of your body
 	
 	
 		i think they should check everybody everywhere that's working because see they got this and that's just like even all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> yeah i think they ought to check them because you get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> looking up to them and here they are strung out on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> what good is that you know that's not good
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah
 		and even and even uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know sometimes i think they should even check the the music you know the entertainment
 	
 	
 		oh yeah because the the
 	
 	
 		with with uh the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		because they get strung out too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they're no different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i guess you know that's they contract they don't
 	
 	
 		and they're out winning awards you know and then and then the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> think they're great and everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but yet
 		and then they're strung out on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> secretly
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		you know they go off because they have a drug problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh-uh  that's not right
 	
 	
 		yeah you know what i think's i bunch of bull too is whenever um they um really you know like nationwide or you know popular people
 		they do have a problem and they come out and they say they're having the problem so then they get more publicity because they admitted they have a problem and they're trying to fix it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well what about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Shmoe</ENAMEX> who's an alcoholic and he's trying to fix it you know but he's not getting any
 	
 	
 		he they're not testing him because they only testing for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think they should test for alcohol
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because we have some alkies too boy you can smell it on they breath
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know it's bad when you can smell <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> on somebody but there's nothing you can do because they not drunk
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but you know they drink constantly  to get that breath smell
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 		but i said no they they getting on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> and stuff but i think i because like i told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> don't kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a wreck from being smoking
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you know drunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from being drunk
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		i never thought of it that way but that's true
 	
 	
 		so why are you know why don't they just to me they ought to just do the blood test for alcohol
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i said they'll have more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> then
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh definitely
 	
 	
 		i mean you know i can understand like on a Monday
 	
 	
 		yeah but then you can look at it there too well alcohol's legal
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah but so is cigarettes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know so why charge me more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is not is is is not legal
 		
 
 		some of them are
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are addicted to prescription drugs
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah
 	
 	
 		and so what's the difference
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they still got a drug habit but they're legal
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		they got a drug problem but it's legal you know it's like huh-uh huh-uh no they need they need some help too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they check those and i know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she was on some kind of medication
 		
 
 		but see they didn't bother her because she had a prescription
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i mean what if she was hooked on them you know
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		how they going to know just because she has a prescription
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how are you going to tell if she's hooked on them you'd have to take her off them you know some people
 		i mean that's they they they go off them and they they're going to die
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		so you need to to me if they going do a
 		they need to keep checking like if somebody's got some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in they system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and it's all prescription it's fine but what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is it
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and then how long are they supposed to take it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have prescriptions for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valium</ENAMEX> but they're not supposed to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valium</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours</TIMEX> a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> you know all the time that's for if they have a problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and then see that way you'll find out if they have a problem because if they keep taking it they have a problem
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or they wouldn't keep taking them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and then also after you know they can find out whenever their prescription ends and then find out you know how long it will take for that to be out of their system and then test them again
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and test them again and see if they have it again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum because you know they don't give you a whole bunch of them pills
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because they gave my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> some
 		when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> passed but that was for like to calm him down
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know but see now they're gone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think they gave him like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pills
 		no and then that was it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but see now they they would be out of his system but if he was to be tested
 		
 		
 	