
 
     		
 	
 		okay well my favorite probably all time TV show is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX>
 		and i would  like that i i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the idea that that we would survive long enough to get to that point and be able to do these fantastic things in space
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i like the they have a new one now the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek the Next Generation</ENAMEX> which it's an all new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> but kind of the same idea going out to new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> and and doing new things and
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		finding out about different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i've i've always liked that show probably the very best
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i think i've actually seen a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Treks</ENAMEX> one way or another over the years
 		uh although i never watched it regularly i'm certainly acquainted with the character the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and then i've seen some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah those the movies are good too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i i guess all the most the shows i like are are kind of along the same line because they're all adventures
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when i when i started thinking about this that those are some of my favorite shows McGyver
 		because it's it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> there more than uh you know instead of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but he's always going out and inventing new things out of scrap and grabbing what he can and you know pieces of baling wire and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a few tires and all of a sudden he's got a hang glider and
 	
 	
 		i don't think i i've even heard of that show it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">McGyver</ENAMEX> and what is what is he
 	
 	
 		you haven't
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		he's like a semi government type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> who goes out then to uh works for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phoenix Foundation</ENAMEX> supposedly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh his his big thing is that he can take pieces of
 		little bits and pieces of string and baling wire and turn them into fantastic different things he took a car battery and some wire and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> washers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and made a welder
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so he  he does all kinds of strange things like that
 	
 	
 		oh great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> ought to hire him and give him a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">junkyard</ENAMEX> and see if he could build a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">747</NUMEX> out of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		see what we can come up with do you like the uh news shows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> those kind of things
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh i used to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact and uh and i used to like the show very much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but unfortunately i find getting rid of your TV set you do throw out some some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> with the bath water
 	
 	
 		some of the little things yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i just decided i had to do that i think in part because it was easy for me to become addicted to it i mean i could just sit mindlessly in front of a TV set for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and i just realized i was sort of like an alcoholic if i didn't get the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i was going to drink
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i guess i haven't ever had any trouble with that i have more or less i have my favorite shows and i usually make time in my day or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my week</TIMEX> you know to watch those
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but for the most part i try i have small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i try and keep it on just
 		a minimum amount of time really when they're up
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		because they're i guess that that that falls in and one of my other favorite shows is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		i like that real well
 	
 	
 		right well when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were little i did have a TV set and i did watch a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Company</ENAMEX> as well
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i don't think they have that on anymore
 	
 	
 		oh that would be a shame
 	
 	
 		i haven't seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Company</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> i i remember it when i was younger of you know catching it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> but uh i don't think they show it must be in maybe it's in if it was in repeats but they're not making new ones
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i haven't seen it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> is still really good
 	
 	
 		yeah how about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Rogers</ENAMEX> is he still around
 	
 	
 		yes yeah they still show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Rogers</ENAMEX> i don't think he's making new ones but they repeat all the old ones
 	
 	
 		i see i see
 	
 	
 		so that's still a real good show too i that one tends to come on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the day</TIMEX> than i want to turn the TV on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Sesame Street comes on from like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> which is a good time and everybody is up and had breakfast and dressed and ready to go so it's the timing of of it is good besides the amount what's on
 	
 	
 		right i figure your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are preschool
 	
 	
 		yes i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little ones
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so they like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i seem to remember those shows being on in the afternoon
 	
 	
 		they come on both they come on like from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> and then from uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five to six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh okay</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they just repeat
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		over again which is also that's another thing that's  good about it when it comes on right in the dinner hour i feel can feel like i can let them sit in front of the TV and watch
 		and they're watching something worthwhile while i can make dinner and do things i need to do without them under foot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah little with little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> the TV set really is a
 		i mean i used it as a pacifier i'm not sure it was that great for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but they turned out okay so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh it didn't hurt them any
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some shows are good for i think some shows some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek i</ENAMEX> for the imagination of it all
 		the idea i i think that's one of the things i like about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> and is is the even in for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> watching it some of it can be a little violent sometimes and stuff i don't let my little ones watch it but the imagination of look what we can do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know in the future this is perhaps this will be possible
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay well i think we've covered most of my favorite TV shows
 	
 	
 		well i'm trying to think if i ever even had a favorite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		let's see how about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man From Uncle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do seem to remember is that the one where they uh he always got this this tape recording that self-destructed
 	
 	
 		that's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mission</ENAMEX> Impossible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Mission</ENAMEX> that's right Mission Impossible yeah i used to watch that in fact i can still remember a couple of those they were i thought those were very good
 	
 	
 		yeah they always have i've i've seen some of them on repeats
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that uh they always had a good plot
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		it kind of kept you guessing on on uh what was going to happen next
 	
 	
 		right right you
 	
 	
 		how they're going get out of their latest scrape
 	
 	
 		yeah i do remember that and uh i remember as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Sullivan</ENAMEX> Show that was really the big deal in our household
 		was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Sullivan</ENAMEX> Show yeah i guess i guess it was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and i went to see the movie The Doors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days ago</TIMEX> and they had this scene
 	
 	
 		oh yeah every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that portraying portraying The Doors appearance on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Sullivan</ENAMEX> Show
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		they even had somebody portraying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Sullivan</ENAMEX> and it was very very funny i think it was the funniest part of the of that movie
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um
 	
 	
 		well i don't know was there any i remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Milton Berle Show</ENAMEX> even i was
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not old enough to recall that one
 	
 	
 		i was well i guess i have to admit that i am
 	
 	
 		my TV viewing started sort of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid sixties</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> didn't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> i'm not even sure if we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> when i was really little that may be why but they probably didn't have a TV until i got to be
 		you know grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the shows that i like now they wouldn't let me watch i had to catch them all on repeats like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> they thought that was much too violent for small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i i i i ended up watching a lot of these things on you know repeats in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's interesting uh i think it's interesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> think that their small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> learn violence from TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were just as violent before TV was invented maybe even more so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i guess that's that's a different topic isn't it
 	
 	
 		probably so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i think that's about uh
 		that's about covered it for me so i think i'll say good-bye and we'll
 	
 	
 		yeah well it was nice talking to you tell me tell me where you're calling from
 	
 	
 		talk another time perhaps
 		i'm calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland Texas</ENAMEX> all right i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North</ENAMEX> i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		where were you from
 		oh my goodness i didn't know they did it long distance
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they're doing it trying to do it or i hope they're trying to do it all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> because they need to collect all kinds of different
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		different dialects
 	
 	
 		well it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		same here bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	