
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello hello</ENAMEX> did i reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 		you sure did to to whom am i speaking
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what
 		my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hi Fernando</ENAMEX> i'm Bill
 	
 	
 		hey how's it going do you work for TP
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah where you calling from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Carolina State University</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh for goodness sakes that's great great you a student there
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		how what do you do
 	
 	
 		i'm getting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master's</ENAMEX> in computer science and computer engineering
 	
 	
 		uh that's great how did you get introduced to this program
 	
 	
 		um i took a voice IO course
 	
 	
 		oh okay i just saw there was an advertisement within <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> to sign up for it and i just i just uh signed up for it
 	
 	
 		well uh one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> went to a to this conference up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so he saw it there and he just said you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> want to make some money and talk <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes a day</TIMEX> here you go so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando</ENAMEX> uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando</ENAMEX> are you from  excuse me you from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		uh not originally
 	
 	
 		oh where are you from originally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> oh my goodness how do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh well i used to live up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and i uh i like i like bigger cities i like i like more populated areas because i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buenos Aires</ENAMEX> but they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten million</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh this area is nice it looks like it's got a lot of uh job opportunities especially at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Triangle Park</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so it looks it looks well it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> largest growing area in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for businesses
 	
 	
 		yeah i like the pine trees
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've been over there from time to time uh you're you're at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh oh North okay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC State</ENAMEX> the wildcats
 	
 	
 		yeah no the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Pack</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Pack</ENAMEX> okay the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah no we're we're not we're not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tar Heels</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i knew you weren't the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tar Heels</ENAMEX> uh no somebody gave me a pair of running shorts and with the logo on it and i thought it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wildcat</ENAMEX> but it was a wolf yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N C State</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf Pack</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		why why do you run
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm a runner
 	
 	
 		oh okay my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> is too
 	
 	
 		in fact i went up there visiting i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davidson</ENAMEX> one time and i went up there visiting him and and he took me out running through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> in the piney woods up there and i just loved it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's nice
 	
 	
 		so  well what are we supposed to i i was kind of fumbling this was the first i haven't been home other <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> when they've called so this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've participated
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh uh and i i was fumbling for my uh pin number uh when she was talking about what to talk about and what are we supposed to discuss
 	
 	
 		it's it's clothing
 	
 	
 		yeah uh how you dress to go to work or something like that
 	
 	
 		right how you how you dress to go to work and how it changes from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> to day
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well i'm ready any time you are sir
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay ready i'm going to press the one
 	
 	
 		hey uh how does this work <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando</ENAMEX> do we talk for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> and does somebody cut us off or
 	
 	
 		no then then we say bye and uh i i probably
 	
 	
 		uh how do we know how do we know when the time's up
 	
 	
 		well i i got a stopwatch here
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so i'll probably say you know it's like well we've been talking for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five six minutes</TIMEX> so okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay you want to go <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or me
 	
 	
 		well uh we'll just open it okay i'll press the one ready
 	
 	
 		okay
 		ready one
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay so well you see since i don't work i just go you know to class it all depends because i like to wear like sweat pants
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because it's more comfortable for me but you know it's like when you're in school you either wear sweatpants or jeans
 	
 	
 		yeah uh you know i i i can remember back to my college days
 		and uh it was uh T-shirts and jeans in the warm weather and jackets and jeans in the short weather uh the thing is here i'm i'm supposed to be an executive you you can uh uh take that or or not depends on where you're looking from
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and however and you normally think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our position wear shirts and ties well many do but i am absolutely not comfortable with a necktie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i carry <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in my briefcase and i wear it i wear it when the occasion demands if somebody important is coming to visit well i take it out and put it on
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh i</ENAMEX> wear a sport jacket sometimes and i wear uh well reasonably not not real dressy dressy pants but but reasonably decent reasonably decent pants
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh comfortable comfortable that way and a good loose fitting pair of shoes that i take off under tables when i'm in a conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> because i can't stand having anything on my feet
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh say i like my shirt and short i wear short sleeved shirts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> round i just
 	
 	
 		okay are they like T-shirts or are they like do they have
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah no short sleeved sort of semi dress shirt
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but i i i absolutely cannot stand anything down over my elbows and when i'm working and and i mean that's even in the winter time
 	
 	
 		well
 		because how how hot i mean like like in the coldest that it gets in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> down there how much is it
 	
 	
 		well we'll have a day or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that it'll be down near <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> as it has been the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years</TIMEX> just before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 		but at uh uh normally it'll be in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> and forties on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coldest days</TIMEX> and we've experienced some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seventies</ENAMEX> here uh to eighties recently
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's
 	
 	
 		but i i don't ever feel the need to dress that warmly i i don't have to travel that far to work uh what what what what about uh your clothes in the winter time up there
 	
 	
 		well it's basically you know it's like i got like a leather jacket or a you know so i just put on a T-shirt and a leather jacket and i usually stay in class that way and if not i would wear a sweatshirt underneath it
 		and then you know you'd but what happens is uh what i've seen here on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> it's very strange because a lot of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here they wear like dress pants and dress shirts to go everywhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		my goodness i i've not see that at all
 	
 	
 		okay
 		and they wear either that or they wear dress pants and b lack turtlenecks or white turtlenecks
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so the thing is you know is like i asked a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you know why why do you wear that he goes well it costs me the same amount which is true because some dress pants you know cost me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five</TIMEX> dollars which is the same as jeans
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um but basically all over here everywhere everybody  wears jeans and if not  what the  what the thing is that they're wear <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">ing</ENAMEX> now is sometimes you wear like shorts with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biker</ENAMEX> pants underneath it
 		which is
 	
 	
 		okay  that that sounds pretty good uh it sounds like it's a very relaxed atmosphere on campus you know i've uh i've uh always <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is a very informal company
 		uh i i think the thing that i've noticed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more recent years</TIMEX> there's more ties and jackets and shirts as the younger the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> seems to want to dress those of us i've been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX> those of us been here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> don't care to dress up
 		but when we came to work i was told that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> set the standard of dress and he's he dressed like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX> so we all we all did
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and the feeling has always been that without the shirts and ties and suit coats that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were in a more relaxed atmosphere and you could have a freer exchange of information
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i've seen this  actually i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> overseas with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and while i was gone
 	
 	
 		where at
 		where at
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Malaysia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and and while i was gone this change to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wearing ties and jackets came about because when i came back i saw ties and jackets in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what was interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> is a tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> just uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two degrees</NUMEX> above the equator
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and when i went over there i packed a lot of clothes and i packed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sport jackets and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ties and the ties got lost and never got there and i was there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years or four years</TIMEX> rather and never missed them
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i absolutely never wore anything out in the tropics like a necktie
 	
 	
 		but the thing is when you started with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> was it as big a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as it is now
 	
 	
 		oh no no uh i think it was something i started in nineteen fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> we're talking about at the most <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> world wide and at that time the whole world was right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> was concerned
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah which is which is basic i mean when hello
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is that uh i'm sorry that's
 	
 	
 		you probably got wait calling
 	
 	
 		yeah i got a wait call hang on a second
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i guess i'm supposed to talk alone while he's on the wait call about clothing right
 		so i don't know what to say i don't wear any clothing
 		we're at nudist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> we don't wear any clothes here
 	
 	
 		you still there <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando</ENAMEX> sorry uh
 	
 	
 		yeah oh that's okay
 	
 	
 		and anyway uh where uh oh we're talking about the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> yeah it was uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when i got here it has in the past gotten <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to eighty six thousand</NUMEX> we're not we're that high right now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh in in many many many many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		was that in the seventies
 	
 	
 		uh no i started in nineteen fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> i
 	
 	
 		no no but uh when it it had gone up
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah yeah it peaked out in the seventies yes yeah i've i've i've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX> in
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i remember
 		i i quit i sort of remember that i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only twenty two</TIMEX> but in the seventies i heard you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> was even making uh those little watches you know those those uh LED watches that you couldn't see in the sun
 	
 	
 		okay
 		right
 		right right we made those
 		yeah yeah yeah i used to referee soccer games and uh uh i would use those watches to time the games and i'd be out on the field middle of the field at high <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and have to cup my hand over it and peek down there with my eye to see what time it was
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh yeah we were about the first ones to make those and went out of that business in nineteen eighty one
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh back to uh uh back to clothes i don't really i don't really have what you'd you'd think was an expensive wardrobe i mean some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very very very clothes conscious uh
 	
 	
 		well they said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> like the the you know executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that work whatever they spend uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> on clothes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> so but but for me
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i wouldn't i i would think they'd spend at least that as the at the cost of clothes
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> go all i mean what i've seen like you know they like to wear something different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and for me it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know how i dress and we we have you know like the gym here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they give you shirts right which which you use and then you take back they give you a clean one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so sometimes you wear you know the shirts from from the gym <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">everyday of the week</TIMEX> the only thing is that you can tell them apart because they have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that they were bought in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i mean you don't feel as bad because it's like they they give you different year sometimes you know so you're wearing you know sometimes you're wearing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nine</NUMEX> the other times sometimes you're wearing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety one</NUMEX> the other times you're wearing you know eighty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> so it's okay you know
 	
 	
 		is that for like gym classes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> classes and things like that
 	
 	
 		right see when we take PE you have to dress in the in PE clothes but it is it's issued to any one that wants one that's in the university
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		right right right how many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> are you taking
 	
 	
 		well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> since i'm graduating i'm only
 		
 		
 	