
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes i saw Home Alone with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple days ago</TIMEX> i wanted to see it uh because it was uh
 		much recommended
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and it was a a genre that i wasn't in the least bit interested in and i usually when i hear about a movie that's supposed to be very good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even if it's in a genre i don't like i figure well i should go see it because if this is you know the best of the genre and i should know about it or something like that and i usually come away thinking no i really don't like this show
 	
 	
 		yeah right uh-huh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh i i i feel that way when movies are like blown up out of proportion you know usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tell you how good they are and you always
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know end up with expectations too high or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well the the problem i had with the movie was the problem i've had with a lot of uh i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movies which is you know it's a formula movie and they're making the movie according to a certain formula that's a good formula but they seem to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		fall short of
 		of being really creative with a lot of things i mean here's the situation of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> at home you know it's a classic slapstick situation with these bungling burglars trying to get in
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		right
 	
 	
 		and yeah he did some clever things but given the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and how clever the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> was it seems to me they could have done a lot more
 		i mean you know basically basically stepping on things and yelling in pain and it seems to me they could have been a lot more creative stuff used
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i was very surprised that did do a slapstick movie because that's uh not really the way comedies are right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know a lot of the comedies are more like jokes and you know gags and stuff like that there's not as much slapstick anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i guess it was a uh a very successful movie financially so we may say more slapstick
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that well that's true it's very cheap to make a slapstick movie
 	
 	
 		yeah it is it is and i guess you don't have to but you know if you look at
 		oh have you ever seen any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Teti Teti</ENAMEX> movies the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> movies uh Teti it it
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 		no not really the last movie i saw i guess uh was uh
 		uh the one about the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> and comes back and he's someone different um
 		he's uh uh well it's about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> uh
 		that uh leaves his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and comes back to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s all excited but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that comes back is not her original <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but um
 		Gear um i'm sure you've heard of it it was a very famous uh popular movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Gray Norman Gear</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		no i'm not with you so far
 	
 	
 		oh shoot i'm going to hit myself after i hang up i'll remember the name
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh anyway that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> movie it was um that was the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i saw downtown but i i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> actually <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Falls Church Virginia</ENAMEX> outside the city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ha ha</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so a lot of times they the the the international films downtown
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh so this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> i guess are into the slapstick i guess so they would like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lewis</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		they have they have a long  yes they like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Lewis</ENAMEX> much to the chagrin of sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> quote unquote sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> but they have this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques Teti</ENAMEX> that does slapstick comedy and there's something about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's so innovative you know he'll have trouble picking up his hat or catching his umbrella blowing in the wind or something but there's something about it that just it isn't just slapstick there's something about the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in it
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and that's what i find lacking in a lot of you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Alone</ENAMEX>
 		there was a lot of the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> when he was home alone and he was trying to be tough and they s had a lot of human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> there but when it was the real slapstick moments him versus the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> kind of thing it just sort of lost the human element became purely a caricature
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		does does that make since to you
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i see what you're saying there is less character development rather just the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the funniness</TIMEX> of the gag rather than
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah did you go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		and how it fits with the character right
 	
 	
 		did you go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		did you take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> along
 	
 	
 		no we went uh without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it's was a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a night</TIMEX> out
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i would have liked to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> with me i think preferably someone <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> just just to get a sense for you know how how it affected them
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		especially to come home and you know   if he didn't knock real loudly and clearly i would have gotten in trouble <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> i'm sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that that's true i i was thinking about that too i saw that um
 		that's why i watched another silly movie um  um with my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> was uh uh the one about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um the turtles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles</ENAMEX> huh um-hum
 	
 	
 		right yeah i saw that with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> just to see what you know what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are into
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that is yeah he's a little yeah he's anyway and that was just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		excessively violent i was worried it's like golly if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> start imitating that
 	
 	
 		yeah wasn't it amazing
 	
 	
 		they'll knock each others blocks off
 	
 	
 		yeah those
 		yeah it was all bloodless and the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> can get hit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long and they have to shake it off they don't they don't you know get  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">epileptic</ENAMEX> fits or anything from getting hit on the head
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah it it's a little disturbing
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the violence in these films partly it mean it's supposed to be a little bit more okay because it's comic book but on the other hand it makes it seem like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i read an article <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time talking about even the quote unquote realistic movies don't have very realistic effects of the violence the violence can seem very realistic but the aftermath is usually not there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are severely injured it's
 		very very badly they lose control of body functions they thrash around they scream you know uh it's just a very very bad thing and they never present that even the movies that want to show violence as real they don't really show you what happens with that real violence
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm not really sure how i feel about that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh on the one hand i'd like it to be a warning on the other hand i wouldn't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who currently get sort of enjoy their violence fixes from these movies to start thinking gee now we want to see the aftermath all the time either
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's true
 	
 	
 		but yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teenage Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles</ENAMEX> is sort of the same way they i guess they figured i mean they know what they're doing and they make the movies good enough i guess i'm a bit of a snob they make the movies good enough to be successful
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then they don't and they but they could make them better you know they could try to make i mean as far as i was concerned <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles</ENAMEX> could have been a classic of world theater
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really
 	
 	
 		it could have been you know it was it was innovative uh a completely new approach to making a movie in a lot of ways and yet it ended up not being anything particularly memorable
 		cause the the story was stupid and and then things like that and uh they built up i remember feeling annoyed
 		again i didn't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> with me
 		and i remember feeling annoyed that they had this whole thing about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> and the passing of wisdom the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from older</TIMEX> to younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> it was it was a classic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> you know it's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> mess going back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three thousand years</TIMEX> that they're playing with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and he had to past and he told them remember  remember you
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">united</ENAMEX> you can succeed individually you will fail and then there was a big climactic fight scene and they didn't remember that
 	
 	
 		yeah right oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they didn't fight together they fought individually and they failed individually and then that was it then they had to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> beat him
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> should according to the classic myth the sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Campbell</ENAMEX> type myth
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> should have died at the end because the the lesson was passed to the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> and the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> is not needed and is reborn to the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> and on and on and on and all this wonderful myth
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it still would have been every bit as accessible a movie for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		if they had included all this stuff that
 		i anyway as an as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual adult</ENAMEX> would appreciate it wouldn't have hurt the movie to do that and it would have make it uh
 		broadened the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that it could have been targeted for i thought
 		but i um i'm i'm clearly enough you know i'm i'm clearly an intellectual snob to be going to these kinds of movies i realize that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean to go to these movies and expect them to be you know other than just just good entertainment kind of thing
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's true
 		yeah there's not too many that are uh that are good just on their you know that that you wouldn't want to change something and there's always something that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i i i i'm very i'm very critical  i i i'm actually originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> and then then then and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> works in films and such and i tend to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		tend to be hypercritical of these things and then perhaps perhaps it's unfair because i i i must admit i enjoy these movies um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		and that that's what they're for
 		but i don't don't remember them
 		and i think it's i think i can think of movies i have less fun during and then after the movie's over i remember it so terribly well because it it had some some meaning to me or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		exactly yeah there there there are a couple movies that hit home like that most of the ones i always remember are the the older ones
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i always like the musicals and uh those ones uh those stick in your head
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they leave the
 		yeah they leave they leave some songs with you they leave i don't know what it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it just
 		i mean i don't know if this is old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fart</ENAMEX> talking here or something because i'm not that old  i look you know those old movies seemed to have had something that uh that was memorable somehow i don't know what it was
 	
 	
 		no it could be
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		okay well i guess i got to get going got to go take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well um  thanks for hearing me ramp i guess  all right nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah nice talking with you are you calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> by the way
 	
 	
 		okay
 		no i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i've talked to outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they're paying the phone bill
 		yeah there must be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as near as i can tell no okay i'm from the other coast all right bye bye
 	
 	
 		yeah okay well thank you very much bye bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	