
 
     		
 	
 		nope
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one i've had from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and where are you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i guess the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've talked to before were from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah mine me too and i had
 	
 	
 		i was beginning to think that was the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the network
 	
 	
 		yeah they all work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well what do you uh what are your favorite television shows
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and  foremost it's got to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX> yeah that's a very popular one around my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> but i've never seen it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		never
 	
 	
 		never have seen it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		my goodness it's hard to believe i didn't think there was anybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> who hadn't seen that one
 	
 	
 		i
 		well i can go even better than that i've never seen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		
 
 		never
 	
 	
 		never once
 	
 	
 		gosh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i admit that i used to be hooked on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but back way long time ago when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jock</ENAMEX> died i gave up watching it it just got too funny
 	
 	
 		well i think i just sort of uh
 		didn't start watching it and then felt like i would have been way too late getting in on the action to figure out what was going on so i never did get involved in it
 	
 	
 		well i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> had the same problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i mean they they went for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an entire season</TIMEX> with this
 		and i'm sure you heard about it all these things
 	
 	
 		oh who killed JR
 	
 	
 		all these things going on no this was i think it was before or after that
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but they went for this whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and they had all these situations
 		and then to end the season come to find out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam</ENAMEX> it was all a dream
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes i remember reading about that thinking uh i would have just strangled them
 	
 	
 		you remember that i mean an
 		and then oh i i tell you that just did it for me right there i said you've put me through an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">entire season</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam</ENAMEX> dreaming
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> are coming you know you're having a hard time here
 	
 	
 		i think that's right i think they just lost their uh inspiration for a while
 	
 	
 		well i understand that this is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX> for it
 	
 	
 		yeah somebody said that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JR</ENAMEX> is going to die and that will be end of the season forever i mean the end of the show forever
 	
 	
 		uh i i read something in the paper
 		yeah that's
 		yeah they uh i read something in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> today talking about or it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parade</ENAMEX> magazine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and they said you know when's the last episode and what's going to happen and they say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JR</ENAMEX> is going to get knocked off
 	
 	
 		well it's about time huh
 	
 	
 		good
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		too bad they didn't kill him the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		yeah too bad they didn't get away with it shoot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well anyway what's your favorites
 	
 	
 		oh well i mostly watch public television so yeah i'm one of those i uh
 	
 	
 		no i i that's what i spend most of my time watching that uh
 	
 	
 		well i love <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masterpiece Theatre</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and i love the mystery series
 	
 	
 		yeah mystery especially uh Miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marple</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes oh
 	
 	
 		i i've i've got all the videos that i can get my hands on of of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss</ENAMEX> Marple
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah i love those i used to i i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years</TIMEX> so it really brings back
 	
 	
 		oh we
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some memories
 	
 	
 		we have uh uh a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> uh on our cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> here that uh is showing all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miss Marples</ENAMEX> over again so we got to repeat them
 	
 	
 		it must be either uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A&E</ENAMEX> or um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Discovery Discovery</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i
 		i think it is A&E
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A&E</ENAMEX> runs quite a lot of them
 		um i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery Channel</ENAMEX> too i like they have lots of wildlife shows and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh they do have some absolutely gorgeous things so uh but they uh the one we just watched that we had videotaped from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gardens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> did you see that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		hum-um no i missed it
 	
 	
 		uh well
 	
 	
 		nice i bet
 	
 	
 		we are lucky enough to now be on a cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> that has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> public TV channels
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um boy</ENAMEX> that is that is good
 	
 	
 		so we get
 		we get things over and over so if we miss them we can catch them later and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gardens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Worlds</ENAMEX> was absolutely glorious it was
 	
 	
 		i bet it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Audrey Hepburn</ENAMEX> was narrating it
 	
 	
 		um  i like her
 	
 	
 		and they took you all over uh
 	
 	
 		oh i like that
 	
 	
 		started in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England France</ENAMEX> some in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> uh also <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> anyway it was a really a a visual treat
 	
 	
 		um
 		really nice i bet
 		i bet
 		yeah the interesting thing about public TV is it's not public around here you have to have cable to get it
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well uh
 	
 	
 		silly
 	
 	
 		when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> there was one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> of just uh
 		it was uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Houston</ENAMEX> station
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so it had not all of the stuff that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> were getting because each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> gets its own mix
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but when i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and all of a sudden i had this uh
 		surfeit of public television
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we can get all sorts of things everything from i guess on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> there you can watch something like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> different cooking shows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i don't but i could if i felt like it
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i i spend a lot of time down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> uh and on their just the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the regular</TIMEX> TV not cable you can pick up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PB</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> channels
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		the closest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX> is in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel Hill</ENAMEX> which is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about twenty five miles</NUMEX> away and believe it or not you can't pick it up
 	
 	
 		really i would have thought that was close enough that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it was it should be close enough but i guess they have the antennas pointing it the other way or something
 	
 	
 		or you got a hill between you or something like that
 	
 	
 		bu t
 		yeah it's uh it just you can barely see the picture and you can't hear anything so
 	
 	
 		well the only about the only things i watch on commercial television are <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Thirty Something and Twin Peaks uh</ENAMEX> and i just discovered that they uh have have canceled both of those so
 	
 	
 		oh really yeah i've i've never seen either one of them
 	
 	
 		well let me tell you that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> was much better when it just started so maybe it's time for it to quit i they've gone downhill too
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well i guess there were i guess it was pretty popular because there was quite a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twin Peak</ENAMEX> conversation
 	
 	
 		well the thing i liked about it was that it was so unconventional that you couldn't predict what was coming next
 	
 	
 		well at least that that's what i like about a show if if you can predict it it's not worth watching
 	
 	
 		that's right and this one had all sorts of weird little things and would go off in uh strange directions and it had lots of
 		uh little subtle touches that if you weren't watching you would miss uh that
 		they'd have references to literature and things like that and they'd also just have odd thing they walk into a bank <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vault</ENAMEX> and there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deer head</ENAMEX> lying on the table in the bank vault
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and there's no explanation for it they treat it as perfectly normal and somebody says what's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deer head</ENAMEX> doing here and they said oh it fell off the wall so why was it doing on the wall
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> was making <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and they said there's a fish in the coffee pot
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well
 		i suspect that that's a reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thoreau's Fish in the Bucket</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Milk</ENAMEX> but i don't know for sure and i'm not sure what the relevance would be if it were but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sounds like a pretty good show i'm sorry sorry i missed
 	
 	
 		anyway
 		it had a lot of things like that thing to make you keep watching just for the novelty and the surprise of it
 	
 	
 		sorry i missed that one
 		you know i i don't watch very much TV i i watch um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funniest Home Videos</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and that's about it
 	
 	
 		well they
 	
 	
 		and i watch the i sometimes watch the the news
 	
 	
 		yeah i'd say probably what i watch the most faithfully is the news which i really don't watch as much as i just listen to it
 	
 	
 		yeah back well when i had cable i used to just keep it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> not to watch it but just to have it in the background because i'd always listen to it
 	
 	
 		when i'm fixing dinner or something like that it's i uh at least know if there's anything i want to read thoroughly in the newspaper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i get the headlines off the television
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah the uh cable prices are just too high nowadays and i'm not going to
 		i i just won't pay that that kind of money for for what i'm getting i mean i miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A&E</ENAMEX> and i miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Discovery</ENAMEX> and i miss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> but that's it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it just it just wasn't worth it just to get those three
 	
 	
 		uh we just about had to get it because the reception in our particular locality was so poor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that we could only get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> and uh only one was a public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and we had a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> but neither one of them was very clear they were both
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		barely adequate
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		so we decided when the cable came through that we would get on it just so we could see what we were watching if we watched anything at all
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i'd i'd probably i'd probably get cable but i've got we got the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> and that
 		fulfills my needs because i don't watch TV that much anyway anymore anyway
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i think i would be inclined to do the same thing if we could see anything without the cable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know what you mean course like i say the only thing i do miss is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> because i there several things on there i like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Masterpiece Theatre Mystery</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		especially those
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh Masterpiece Theatre</ENAMEX> is really good
 	
 	
 		they have had some absolutely wonderful shows and they do they have incredibly good what are called production values they have
 	
 	
 		yeah and and you
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		really well researched uh locations and sets and costumes and so forth and as far as i can tell on places where i have some knowledge their historical research is excellent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	