
 
     		
 	
 		okay so i guess um
 		i start with maybe if if does do you know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> favors statehood or
 		what are we you were supposed to whether we favor it
 	
 	
 		well i'm not i'm not sure what what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> feel uh how do you feel about uh the possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> becoming a state
 	
 	
 		well see i have mixed feelings because um it it the with the financial situation i don't really quite understand what would happen there if they would be a burden to us
 		or if they already are a burden
 		so i i really
 		what uh i really don't care you know i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah well i question whether it's in their best interests to become a state right now they are a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">commonwealth</ENAMEX>
 		and that means that they are under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> protection in the event of uh defending their their country
 		uh they do not have any voting privileges though and i don't believe they have any representation in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes that i think that's true so that makes them feel definitely like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsiders</ENAMEX>
 		but like getting back to the their government benefits
 		they they do have a lot of uh tax benefits
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't believe they have to pay any uh like federal tax uh
 	
 	
 		yeah so um also of course they they can they join the they can always join the military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> they are considered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> i believe
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i think they are they they do get uh privileges privileges like that
 	
 	
 		yeah they can
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure how much that uh carries on
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a strange situation you you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> yet you can't vote
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so so if
 	
 	
 		well i think we've got uh like a language barrier too i think most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there speak only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> i'm not sure how fluent they are in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>
 		and that's one of the major problems i i see with uh
 		other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as such being uh say the possibility of becoming states that we don't have a common language with them
 	
 	
 		yes i went i worked um i went there for a class in a factory
 		and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> couldn't speak fluent <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> they had a very difficult time with it and they and they couldn't the ones that could speak
 		speak it had a really hard time reading it so
 	
 	
 		right i think we'd have the same type of problem say with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Canada</ENAMEX> on the other hand uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> is one of their national languages they have
 	
 	
 		yes as well as the the um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quebec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">French</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and they're supposed
 	
 	
 		so i think they're
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they're supposed to be bilingual
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		i just see a lot of uh social and cultural differences that could uh pose problems with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> becoming a state
 	
 	
 		yes what do you what do you um do you do you think they should become independent maybe or do you think they should  benefit
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't think they're strong enough myself to become independent
 		uh i think that it's in their best interest right now just uh to remain as is
 		keep the status quo and uh keep uh stay under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the United United States</ENAMEX> protection
 	
 	
 		yeah i think if i was a middle class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> maybe that that would be the um stablest thing to do
 	
 	
 		yeah because i think that if they if they tried for independence they would probably have uh
 	
 	
 		they would
 	
 	
 		military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> that would oppose each other and and they would vie for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are well off there the middle upper class if there is such a thing
 		uh they would probably be at a disadvantage losing possibility of losing their uh their assets or wealth
 	
 	
 		yes
 		so they've been talking about this for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> do you think they're going to ever vote
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		whether they want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> choices
 	
 	
 		i don't see it in the near future
 	
 	
 		i know because i think i've been reading i read this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> that they were having these big uh
 		um rallies and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> flashing signs statehood yes and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would statehood down the statehood
 		it's it down there if you're um familiar with their politics
 		they uh
 		it's very uh i i don't know it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latino</ENAMEX> there they have loudspeakers on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and they run down the neighborhood saying vote for you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre</ENAMEX> he's or uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX> uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX> he's the best it's it's really kind of comical
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well i've never been there i'm not quite familiar with with uh the way they do things
 	
 	
 		yeah these these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they have the big loudspeakers because they have uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> system just like ours where they elect their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> and their councilmens it's really kind of funny it's it's kind of an invasion of your privacy privacy too they're going down these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> with these really loud speakers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah oh i think that you know part of the biggest problem there is that they still really are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">third</NUMEX> world country
 		and they haven't uh caught up uh economically with uh say the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah there there's some really poor areas where when i went  uh
 		it it looked like it was it was always
 		you couldn't if you didn't know the area they they didn't advise you to go out and uh you know go in the the uh poorer sections of town
 		but the the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> where the uh big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> were
 		that that was that was safe ground to walk around but uh particularly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Juan</ENAMEX> we wanted to go walk on the beach at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and they looked at us like we were crazy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		says no you can't go at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> because uh
 		we were we our business was on the other side of the island we were only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Juan</ENAMEX> it was at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		they don't want us go out on the beach you know said it was very dangerous
 	
 	
 		well did you have guides from the area or escorts or uh
 	
 	
 		um actually we um met met some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were in the naval <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> down there
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and uh they didn't particularly like living down there because it was very foreign very different the the people
 		they they didn't treat them nice they you know um so i think there i what i learned from them there was a lot of resentment towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so and it was like they were they're <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> and were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so that's why they're so um emotional about about statehood yet like you say it's
 		they can't really support themselves so
 	
 	
 		yeah well they've got that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> they get fired up about every little thing anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah that's very true
 	
 	
 		i think one of the most interesting things about the possibility of uh attaining a fifty first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is what would we do about our flag how do you arrange fifty one stars
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what kind of pattern does do we come up with for that
 	
 	
 		i don't know that that's a good one
 	
 	
 		could have a contest
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah but the thing the thing that bothers me about it the most is
 		they don't make decision they don't vote i i think if they voted that that as you say the um
 		they they would probably stay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">commonwealth</ENAMEX> or that would be the best for them
 	
 	
 		well that would give them them more of an interest in what goes on in this country
 		if if they had uh uh a a uh a privilege of voting
 		uh that would give them a vested interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and uh
 		i would see that as as a positive uh thing for them to consider
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but as you say it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different cultures
 		i don't i don't know
 		um so uh you like i say i was reading this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> whether they could they're going to be talking about this in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably
 	
 	
 		i don't see them doing anything
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i really don't see any change in the near future
 	
 	
 		so
 		i don't know and it's also a long way away
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		if you know if it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuba</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>'s closer but uh
 	
 	
 		yes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>'s really close but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rica</ENAMEX> is uh is it's like uh i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> it's another
 		another uh what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen hundred</NUMEX> miles across the ocean
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		that is a good distance
 	
 	
 		yeah and they have to they have to import a lot of their um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereals</ENAMEX> and things and and i don't understand now why they don't have a processing i guess
 		it i uh they it's just as easy to bring the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cereal</ENAMEX> in boxes as it is to bring it in in you know bulk <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grain</ENAMEX> and produce it there
 	
 	
 		what is their major industry
 	
 	
 		uh i really don't know um
 	
 	
 		is it uh i i believe is it <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar cane</ENAMEX> or i'm not sure sure exactly what they do
 	
 	
 		it could be i'm sure they rely heavily on tourism and even the all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> down there with their uh electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX> are big down there
 	
 	
 		right okay
 	
 	
 		that's one thing i did notice uh pharmaceuticals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">electronics</ENAMEX> that makes up i mean enough to be like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent of their business
 		but um i really don't know agriculturally they could have so much and they and they don't they don't seem to uh i don't know if i heard they don't feed themselves or not i don't think they support themselves
 		agriculturally i found that to be really odd
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not very familiar with with the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of their agriculture agriculture
 	
 	
 		you know well they see they can't grow the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grains</ENAMEX> i mean they're if the i guess their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grains</ENAMEX> don't do well in the tropics
 		so like you say they grow grow <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> beets and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar cane</ENAMEX> and that's all export
 	
 	
 		right you have to question
 		you have to wonder how much tillable land they have uh being an island
 	
 	
 		well yeah that is it's mountainous and uh but it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it looks fertile and it it um i mean it rains enough they have the climate and the rain
 		and if not it's like i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint Thomas</ENAMEX> and it just starts from the ocean up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's and it's very it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big rock but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX> has lots of uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		lots of uh mountainous <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> and coastal regions
 	
 	
 		yeah i know they must have a lot of tourism too but i don't see as much advertising there as you do in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> the say the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know uh i it
 	
 	
 		with uh say uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint Thomas</ENAMEX> uh Virgin Islands uh places like that
 	
 	
 		that's very true i don't know if they just
 		take it for granted that they you know it's an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">commonwealth</ENAMEX> they really don't have to advertise that much but that is an interesting point
 		but i i believe it's a very popular vacation destination
 	
 	
 		right well the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin Islands</ENAMEX> are an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> territory
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and but you see a lot of advertising for that uh as far as uh vacation uh cruises and retirement
 		
 		
 	