
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think i was one okay um first thing i thought of was
 		was just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that put the flyers on the door and i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and i think i feel sorry for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have to do that you know what i mean i always pray for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> but when i'm sitting on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> and it's and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> just walks up and puts his hand on my doorknob
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's kind of frightening like whoa and i've i've kind of gotten used to it but it seems kind of bizarre to me to get used to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> just coming up
 		from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> because you can't see them approaching your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you know they just
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah because they're just sort of coming from the side or whatever yeah
 	
 	
 		exactly and when i'm sitting here on the sofa cross-stitching and all of a sudden somebody a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s got their hand on my door knob it's like uh
 		like oh no and so i don't i don't like that and i guess the only way to prevent it would be just to pass a city ordinance to prevent that or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so i think there's other ways to advertise other than a flyer on your door
 	
 	
 		yeah plus uh you know look at the you know the besides the pollution the the aspect of invasion of privacy there's a big pollution aspect too i find i throw out a lot of those flyers and i have no interest in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whatever they are i i do i find and and they go alone with that just the things you get in the mail
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i you know my my name being sold if i if i give money to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wild Wildlife Federation</ENAMEX> you know it's a it's a i feel it's an invasion of privacy to receive so many pieces of junk mail because they sell my address
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right i do too even the credit card things and like we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> and we've got we get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> applications probably a month
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		that's i agree yeah and it
 	
 	
 		for other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Visas</ENAMEX> and it's like wait a minute we have a commitment with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> we're with if i want a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> from your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i'll call you yeah
 	
 	
 		i'll call you that's right and they all say that they're the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> but you know i definitely have the one that i've
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know very rarely do you receive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that has a real low interest rate they're always more expensive and they uh you know if you stay if you stay with a good one for the while you get a good credit rating and you get a good um a good credit line so you don't like to i don't like to bother with it yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 		it shows stability but um now i also thought uh i i get calls i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> so i'm home a lot in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i get probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> calls probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four a day</TIMEX> probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three day</TIMEX> a norm but seems like
 		it seems like it's more than that of phone calls and and it i've gotten to where i've really had to say okay wait a minute this you know it's okay to be nice and sometimes
 		you know i feel like God says talk to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or something but most of the time i just have gotten where i can say i'm not interested thank you and i just hang you know and i hang up real nicely but
 	
 	
 		yeah huh
 	
 	
 		um i know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> ago
 		i i would feel that i had to explain to them that i'm on the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> or i'm in the middle and it's i've just come to a realization that
 		i don't have to explain to this stranger what i'm doing it and give excuses that's it's okay just to say i'm not interested and go ahead and hang up but i i don't know i don't think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are secure enough to probably answer
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's right
 	
 	
 		like that and therefore i feel it's an invasion of privacy because i thought all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> share you know what they're doing even though it's none of the business
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 		
 
 		it takes uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i did it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and and i just i feel like that was one i thought of that right off
 	
 	
 		yeah they ask you a lot of they ask you a lot of personal questions and they yep and you know they and they just keep talking to you too i i i find that a big pain yeah i think
 	
 	
 		yeah right they don't want to let you go they don't believe you if you're on another line long distance and they just want to keep going and going and stuff so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		i think do you find that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that you probably see more things of invasions of privacy than uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> would
 	
 	
 		um yeah i probably do i feel like i don't know i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> i feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are more usually deceived you i feel like i don't think that's necessarily a bad thing
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because God gave us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> to help look out for us but i know that during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the when the cults come by they come by during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and it says in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> that
 		be weary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming door to door trying to proselytize the silly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> lay captive with gossip and stuff and i see that they don't come home when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s here they don't come to my house
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		normally when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s here they come when i'm here alone and i notice that and it's almost like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there's a a subconscious understanding i think it's spiritual that you can rationally explain the subconscious understanding that you know there's there's a more gullibility here when there's not a
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> present i don't think i'm less than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> because of that
 		i but i see that and God's really shown me that and i don't talk to them i don't try and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> to them don't try and convert them i just say you can you can either you can come back when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you'd like to but we're <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Christians good-bye</ENAMEX> and i shut the door and that's it and i'm not ugly to them you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah what you know what's really funny um is that i get calls you know mostly telephone sales <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i just you know that want to start beating my ear you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um and then they start asking you know well is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> there and then i'm thinking well how did they know i was married you know and i'll say i'll say no she's not because actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i live apart <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> because i'm in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i only get to see her on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and it's one of those things where they'll say oh your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s not there and i'll say i'll say no oh well when is she going to be there and i'm like well she's never going to be there yes she's never going to be here so you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		are you kidding
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they do that really
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh and and they'll keep going until they get that out of you when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is going to be here because they want us to be here together because i guess uh it's it's
 	
 	
 		see i
 		she can talk you into that most a lot of women
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe she would talk me in yeah maybe they'll
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> control the budgets and they control the money and they control the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>  i mean most of the time that's how it works so so therefore i guess that they their they see that um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah they they do what do you think i just just threw out stuff <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> that uh i walked out of a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> said you know for a dollar you can win this <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred dollars</NUMEX> worth of groceries
 	
 	
 		so they feel like i can talk her into
 	
 	
 		and normally when you see these things it's normally um
 		uh a church you know that's doing a raffle or it's some type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scouts</ENAMEX> or it's some type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> or whatever and i automatically you just think oh it's a raffle must be for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so you pull out your dollar and you fill out this coupon and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then when you look at it as you walking away you see that it's for some sales pitch of some kind where they're going to
 		you know and i find that a big invasion of privacy i just i'm from then on in it's like oh this makes me angry you know now you have to question everybody on what they're doing now you sure this goes to such and such organization
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you sure you're with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">multiple dystrophy muscular dystrophy</ENAMEX> or whatever i find that a big invasion of privacy too
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		because they they sort of pull that over on you you know like um like this is a charitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> but actually it's not it's a come on so that they can get your name and phone number
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so because you always put your phone number down so they can call and tell you that you won
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but actually they started calling me telling me that i could you know buy a soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water softener</ENAMEX> and they called me for um what else other than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water softener</ENAMEX> the same place called me for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		something else in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> it was all kitchen stuff they put me on and they all called me you know and each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> asked me when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was going to be here
 	
 	
 		that's funny uh-huh
 		oh they're i know it's funny how you can look back as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> you can see how these things apply and they're true and in even even in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that aren't even <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> there's just a pattern
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that you can see in things like that i've noticed that about the cults that they work our neighborhood in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and they work them good and i consider that i kind of consider that an invasion of privacy but not so much as i do the other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know what i mean because but i do in to a degree there's also not a day to day occurrence it's not that often that they come by but i've notice it's kind of gone down before when we first moved here it was
 		pretty often but i've noticed that though they really work in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and you very rarely see them in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are home and so
 	
 	
 		well i think also you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are home during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> they're they're um they might be unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who might be more apt to um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know be at the end of their rope you know and be looking for uh uh a salvation in the sense or looking for a uh saving grace you know i
 	
 	
 		right
 		looking for something yeah kind of depressed or something
 	
 	
 		looking for something yeah they're searching for something yeah and also and also you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> at home during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> if if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> is at home um
 	
 	
 		yeah i didn't think of that but yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		she may be bored at the time so she'll spend a little bit more time to listen i think you know because she may have finished her work the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> may be taking a nap they may uh they may be playing some place you know or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right
 		and and there's nobody but there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> there to come in and say wait a minute
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i really think this is good and that well i don't know i think we need that but i know i need it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um the only thing i would have thought of is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> just said this he said public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX> he
 	
 	
 		he said what
 	
 	
 		public <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom  well</ENAMEX> he was teasing but he was just being smart because because you know you don't want to go in the public you know
 	
 	
 		that's an invasion of privacy
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh that's true that's true
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what can we do to solve that we can make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> make private <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stalls</ENAMEX> for everyone i thought that was funny but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		what you know the the terrible thing is i don't know if you've watched the news lately i i guess we just had something up here here i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um i get you know we i saw some news out of like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and a big thing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> right now is um they don't have enough stalls in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX> as they do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's funny
 	

 	
 		so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> you know because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> design these things <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> can go in and use the urinal or use the toilet but their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">lines</ENAMEX> are always you know they go through much faster
 		but but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have to wait in long lines that are uncomfortable and and if they really have to go it's a very difficult problem to be you have to stand in line for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> and uh and then the whole
 	
 	
 		yeah i did hear that on the news
 		
 
 		
 		
 	