
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay Art you say you own a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> or you own a uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> compatible
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i have one of these little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zenith</ENAMEX> laptops which uh the uh everybody here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> has to buy one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		oh you're in school
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i'm a student uh at
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Business School</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		tremendously useful thing it's uh the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the portability</TIMEX> and the compactness of it are uh pretty nice it's uh you know enough that you can kind of throw it in a briefcase or uh slap it over your shoulder and carry it around
 	
 	
 		what what do you use to to download into the system can you put hook up a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a</NUMEX> floppy to it
 	
 	
 		uh it's got an internal <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three and a half inch</NUMEX> floppy
 	
 	
 		oh it's built in
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh it also has a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty megabyte</NUMEX> hard drive built in
 	
 	
 		oh that's pretty good um
 	
 	
 		and uh you know the batteries carry it for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least four or five hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and so
 		you know i use it um
 		both in school
 		to do uh spreadsheet analysis for various uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that we're studying and also uh you know it hooks up to normal printers and what have you and uh works pretty well in that mode as well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm curious what you use your uh home computer for
 	
 	
 		uh  i do i do uh word processing on it primarily uh the main reason why i'm i'm hanging on to it is because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> that i'm in the the home computer business i have a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> where i've got the uh the hardware and the software and i also do repair work on the system
 		if if i started using a different computer at home then i wouldn't be using the the software and the hardware and it would be that much more difficult for me to try and market it the the product
 	
 	
 		does it does it cause a problem for you to use a different computer at work than you use at home
 	
 	
 		uh oddly enough no uh because i do different things with it at home i i do mostly play and at work i do mostly work uh it's  you know you you you can put a game on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> compatible computer uh but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i i don't normally do that at at work uh and i i typically deal with uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> uh WordPerfect which is a spreadsheet
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh we also have a tie in to a mainframe out in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the mainframe has a lot of software out there where i use to
 		interface my computer with
 	
 	
 		are are you at the point where the the mainframe appears slow to you relative to your personal computer given the the ratio
 	
 	
 		no um
 		there was at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in time where where it was continually down it it appears at though whenever i wanted to use it it wasn't working and this was about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven ten years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they made a dramatic effort of trying to reduce down time down to nothing and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> uh i can't say that i can remember the last time it went down uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> it's it's just up all the time now
 		they take it down like on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> like for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> to do maintenance or whatever but uh unless there's something dramatic that happens with the telephone system uh usually doesn't break down and i think what they're doing is they're using satellite somehow
 	
 	
 		that's
 	
 	
 		to uh to transmit the signals to have a backup some to back that that system up so that there is no no down time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you you don't think that they went and did a uh what is it an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ishihara</ENAMEX> uh quality analysis
 	
 	
 		analysis  i don't i don't know how they fixed the problem but they're uh you know the whole theme of of what they were doing was was to measure and record and and uh reduce down time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the other big thing is uh
 		quality satisfaction or customer satisfaction
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do how do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> feel about the the system and what are their likes and dislikes and that's that's uh that's where they they were heading and
 		the system is fantastic so it's it's not slow if anything the the PC is now slower than the mainframe
 	
 	
 		that
 	
 	
 		we're transmitting from from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX> and i'm getting responses in in split <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's tremendous are are your computers at work net uh networked at all or is that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh well that that's another system that i link in to i i network internally to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> in Attleboro
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and use the mainframe for
 		corporation uh type programs like payroll and uh financial data bases and we also have uh
 		uh a message system
 		which is a worldwide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> within within the corporation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where i can send telegrams to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> site
 		and they've also hooked up to some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to allow us to do E-mail and allow it to convert it
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> so that the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can recognize our E-mail and now we're getting into faxes as well
 		right off the PC
 	
 	
 		that's tremendous
 	
 	
 		yeah that's uh the technology is really  really blow you know going going crazy with this
 	
 	
 		it's clearly a uh a uh
 		a uh
 		productivity enhancement
 		uh device and allows you to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> originally i didn't think it was i thought that what ended you know we ended up doing was uh doing all of the secretarial work and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> had nothing to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and that i guess part of that is true  uh i do all my own typing i i i don't give anymore uh paper to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> to type up only because it takes me longer to write it
 		and redo it and then give it back to her again for me to sit down and and do it and correct it myself i i i am not a typist i type with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fingers but i do very well at it
 		and uh i i do everything i do my only typing do my own foils uh it's just it's just so much easier for me to do that
 	
 	
 		that that's been my experience also i've actually i guess i've been doing that since probably when i was in high school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and uh
 		uh it it it's gotten to the point now i think where the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> are are finding other jobs to do because you know the typing and to some extent the filing is just not there anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah and
 	
 	
 		big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> files are disappearing
 	
 	
 		the the files may be disappearing but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> are not the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> in power are are afraid to give up that status symbol
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh although what they're doing now is is they're maintaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> but they're piling more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> onto that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> rather than get rid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>  they're they're just you know they're finding justification by adding more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to her
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i guess there's there's a fear that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> if the computers ever stopped working
 		there'd be a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> staring at the typewriter with no idea what to do with it
 	
 	
 		well i don't know like back in my particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> there must be at least uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> no typewriter it's all computers everybody's got a a PC sitting in front of their desk
 	
 	
 		huh
 		do you uh if if i assume you all are networked to a a variety of of laser printers
 	
 	
 		oh uh i i have a laser printer i have access to a laser printer in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> but i don't have one tied in to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">system</ENAMEX> yet uh i'm i'm networked into it but it's so inconvenient for me to to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to run all the way downstairs that  that i don't use it
 	
 	
 		huh because what i was what i was going to ask you is it seems like the next big jump will come with color printing you were talking about doing your own presentation and foils it would seem that color capability would be the next big sort of leap in presentation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think what i see is a different direction i don't know if you are you familiar with uh programs like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Graphics</ENAMEX> where they have uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like a print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> or or a thing in the system well we have uh instead of using view view foil machines we have uh a transmitter that will pick up the signal from the the monitor
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and transmit it just like a view foil
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so we we do that somewhat uh we also have uh teleconferencing where we have
 	
 	
 		a
 	
 	
 		um
 		so we we do that somewhat uh we also have uh teleconferencing where we have uh the the mainframe as being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> in other words if you've got foils you pull it out of the mainframe and then use the telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> system to communicate with
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and and we use uh
 		we do teleconferencing that way
 		so that that everybody's looking at the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foil</ENAMEX> because we're pulling it off the network
 	
 	
 		interesting
 		yeah that's uh
 		that's uh
 		pretty powerful
 		set of tools to give to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who traditionally have had to go through a whole production process just to get the
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i can remember at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time the the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> actually had to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and  and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> uh with the laser printer
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they're uh really not being utilized as much as they had been in the past i'm making some really pretty foils that uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years ago</TIMEX> i wouldn't have ever dreamed i could be doing them and it's it's so easy to do uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		with the with the programs that are out there now
 	
 	
 		huh
 		huh well uh Frank i think i kind of need to get back to some other things so i i hope we've talked uh
 	
 	
 		all right okay
 		i believe we have
 	
 	
 		covered enough of of this for for what this is all about
 	
 	
 		okay nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah it was a pleasure
 	
 	
 		take it easy
 	
 	
 		thank you
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	