
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay uh could you tell me what you think contributes most to uh air pollution
 	
 	
 		well it's hard to say i mean while it's certainly the case that things like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> uh pollute a lot um if you
 		look at how much pollution is say kicked up by an active volcano uh it's certainly less than clear that anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can do in this sort of scale of things has much effect at all
 		what do you think
 	
 	
 		um well
 		you talked about uh volcanos i'm not sure how many active volcanos there are now and and what the amount of material that they do
 		uh put into the atmosphere  i think probably the greatest cause is uh
 		vehicles
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		especially around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> um uh do you live right in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> itself
 	
 	
 		uh no i'm more out in the suburbs but i certainly work near a city
 	
 	
 		uh okay so can can you notice well it's it's i live in a rural area
 	
 	
 		how about you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's mainly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> and  uh no heavy industry uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attleboro</ENAMEX> itself i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and it's in the north i live up in the uh northeast <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corner</ENAMEX>  and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Attleboro</ENAMEX> sits in just over the line
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> is but there isn't a lot of heavy industry there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeways</ENAMEX> and we get an occasional well it depends which way the wind's blowing from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> because we're only like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about forty miles</NUMEX> south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> so we'll pick up that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i've noticed
 		over the past say maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or six years</TIMEX> uh we live
 		<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about twenty miles</NUMEX> away from the state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> and i notice the fly patterns now of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> are they getting bigger they're swinging wider so that now they're coming over the over the our homes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it seems like uh um we're catching all their residue i'm not sure if it's kerosene or what that's dropping
 		but other than that you know we don't have the unless we're catching it from the midwest the emissions  yeah from the power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		don't you mean like from the coal
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we generate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our our biggest electrical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> uses <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX> to uh generate electricity um
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		there doesn't seem to be much emission from them but i'm not sure about the rest of the country
 	
 	
 		yeah i've noticed locally a major problem is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> um it's interesting because in order to uh keep with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> standards which which tend to be visible
 		uh what's coming out of your  smokestack they do all their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> uh so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get up
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> in that neighborhood and they've got this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">black ash</ENAMEX> on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>  which you know seems to be
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah yeah surprise surprise
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i really think if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> had anything on the ball they'd go in there with a few phosphorous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">grenades</ENAMEX> light up the sky photograph the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">emissions</ENAMEX> at that point and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah them there must be uh um some of the some of the uh
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		uh larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> up around up around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one twenty eight  um</TIMEX> we've got reports that uh during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> too like they blow off their their stacks from uh the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		the boilerhouse for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">powerhouses</ENAMEX> and they do that at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> too because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> been complaining that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> have been pitted and you know spots all over them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you're right they could do something about about that i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah that seems a little ridiculous
 	
 	
 		how are your uh
 		your lakes and uh
 	
 	
 		oh they've been getting cleaner
 	
 	
 		they have
 	
 	
 		sure but um
 		yeah i'm not sure how much the water pollution is is directly related to the air pollution other than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain yeah</ENAMEX> that's that's what i was uh
 	
 	
 		i mean the stuff i've read recently in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology Review</ENAMEX> basically indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> may be a little bit
 		um overstated that a lot of the die off they've seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">forests</ENAMEX> may not really be due to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX> at all um yeah i'm not an expert
 	
 	
 		yeah no didn't they just have an article oh on uh  they were dumping lime up upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> somewhere
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		um over over huge areas and and they thought that was more beneficial because you know and it some of it does soak in and some of it runs off right away into the into the streams and rivers and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> were supposedly making a comeback
 	
 	
 		i haven't read that
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't remember where i i read that recently somewhere and i can't remember where but i thought it was up there  so that's interesting because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's interesting
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> um they showed pictures of of extensive tree damage that they attributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>  um
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		do you kind of think it's something else then
 	
 	
 		well that's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">environmentalists</ENAMEX> were claiming in this article so that
 	
 	
 		oh they didn't say they didn't say what though they just said they thought it was
 	
 	
 		they didn't say what they just said they thought <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rain</ENAMEX>'s contribution may be less than was previously suspected um but it may be other natural things at work
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX> natural disease
 	
 	
 		yeah so it's it's less than clear like i said i don't remember the article that well
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but um i don't know i mean what do you think we can uh i guess as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> or as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> do about uh air pollution
 	
 	
 		uh we can demand uh more efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> for one thing i still think that's that's uh one of our major causes of pollutants
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh how we go about that it's uh uh it's a little bit difficult
 	
 	
 		so you think it's just up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">automakers</ENAMEX> for uh  less polluting vehicles
 	
 	
 		yeah you need you need i think you need a a uh vehicle something like uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Ralph Nader uh Nader</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raiders</ENAMEX> or uh where uh  or uh  uh AARP
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which has a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> uh if you can get those types of groups
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you really think new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> though is a
 		big problem i mean i remember reading an article that said like it's the older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">polluters</ENAMEX> the the twelve and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> you know contribute <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like ninety</NUMEX> percent of the automobile pollution and the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> it's hardly it's hardly anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		they're better but how about all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> that are out there uh when when was the last time you saw a truck that didn't belch
 		smoke or uh or
 	
 	
 		yeah but doesn't that just mean they're out of tune
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i'm not really sure you think that that the uh the trucking industry uh industry is that uh incompetent that they wouldn't
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> is is one of their biggest costs
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so you would
 	
 	
 		but diesel engines
 	
 	
 		yeah diesel engines
 	
 	
 		it you know it's it i mean they do generate a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soot</ENAMEX> but that at least you know that kind of particulate comes out of the air pretty quickly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we could also uh push for legislation for uh rapid transit systems uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> seems to be a little behind on that
 	
 	
 		yeah on the other hand most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't use rapid transit because it's so inconvenient
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah but only because we got used to  uh
 		single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> single <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> driving a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't even like to carpool
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we could do that that'll help
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pollution air pollution
 		the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> are i guess is is uh it going into uh some types of agreements to limit uh what's being given out by power <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s quite concerned that we're sending a lot of our stuff up there
 	
 	
 		yeah sure
 	
 	
 		so that's helping
 	
 	
 		well what do you think about like a device a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> on right on a tailpipe and you paid a tax based on how much you polluted
 	
 	
 		now that's an idea
 		don't say that too loud though because uh every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> will have a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX> on your  tailpipe generate  generate revenue
 	
 	
 		well it just means that if you don't pollute right or you pollute very little you don't have to pay any tax or you just buy one of these things and it it um i mean you could you could probably devise them so that it slowly closed off your tail pipe
 		and uh the less you pollute the longer the device lasts and if you pollute a lot then it closed off your tailpipe and you couldn't start your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> anymore
 	
 	
 		that's a that's an interesting concept is that your idea
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh you know  it's uh
 		i guess the difficulty would be to  somebody could obviously just take it right off the tailpipe again so you'd probably have to build it right into the muffler or something
 	
 	
 		well i was gonna to say right you could put it in you could you could it could be installed like a catalytic converter i mean i guess you could take those off too but
 	
 	
 		right
 		you could take catalytic but mufflers would be a little more obvious if you took that off
 	
 	
 		yeah if you can take a muffler off and only replace well not unless it was built into every muffler
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that's
 	
 	
 		but if you were just talking about something which was more or less universal that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> and any kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> had to pay a pollution tax
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um this would penalize the heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">polluters</ENAMEX> and not penalize the light polluters
 	
 	
 		that's a that's quite a concept
 		you should uh pursue that i think or patent it  you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah patent it that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		if you could come up with a device that's the thing
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it shouldn't be too hard to do something like that but that's a that's a thought no you're right and that will solve uh a lot of problems i don't know if you uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you approached the automobile industry if they would be too keen on installing something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but
 		you know a proposal to uh uh
 		i guess the proper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> well you might uh generate some
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah the automobile regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah you might generate some interest in it but that's a that's a good idea other than that i'm not sure what what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> can do other than like i said get involved through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> or an organization
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	