
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		well let's see
 	
 	
 		uh probably uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few weeks</TIMEX> the biggest uh way i've had of keeping up with what was going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and i think maybe that's probably true for everyone
 	
 	
 		right uh we don't uh get that in uh straight fashion but you know the other major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> have been carrying a lot of it so i've seen a good bit of their coverage
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well we get we get the
 		first you know it comes directly to us from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and it's a continuous coverage and course they repeat themselves a lot  and it was really easy when
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as we said well nothing's happening in the war because now they're interviewing the what seems to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mideast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> all at once
 	
 	
 		right oh they've really done uh good job of keeping everybody informed of what's going on sometimes i've wondered if it wasn't almost more than we needed to know
 	
 	
 		hm
 		a little much yes we have uh we're a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five thousand</NUMEX> and so our local newspaper is not too swift
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well our um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> does a pretty good job on most things but you know its uh not totally in depth and quite frankly i didn't read all of the war stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it was just there were too many long article and i try to quickly read through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> before work in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> so i don't don't get to spend a lot of time on everything
 	
 	
 		so you are off to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm at work yes
 	
 	
 		oh you're at work oh i assumed that these were home telephone numbers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we also get a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> uh paper and course that's where our main coverage as far as world events are concerned our local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is just current events
 	
 	
 		what about your uh radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> do they uh provide much in the way of current event stuff
 	
 	
 		in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> we have one that is uh local FM AM <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and their news is fed from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> too uh it's more of uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh call in for a trading post type thing and uh the fifty music from the fifties and uh  it's i guess what you'd expect from a farming community
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i've lived in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> before and was quite aware of the local radio station at that time and i know how they are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well ours uh that we
 		tend to listen to most um i like the way they handle news type things because in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> they'll have you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> worth of news every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the day</TIMEX> they don't just drown you with the same old stuff and they won't interrupt unless it's you know really important
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and of course they did a good bit for some of the war stuff but they didn't just over do it
 	
 	
 		i only watch one soap opera a day and it seems to me and that's probably about once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> retired it seems to me so often times that they cut into that soap opera
 		with what i don't really consider as earth shaking i guess maybe i think sometimes the uh the coverage is almost too intent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think so i i don't really think we
 		need to know or even sometimes care so much about all the little nitty-gritty things they keep asking over and over i think think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> sometimes ask the silliest questions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you mean when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> sticks the the microphone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> says the face and says how do you feel that you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> has burned to the ground
 	
 	
 		yeah  things like that are just kind of absurd or once in a while they'll they'll keep uh just hounding someone that they're interviewing
 	
 	
 		that's a bit much isn't it
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there seems to be no purpose um you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has stated you know some opinion or fact or whatever and that should be the end of it and they just keep on and on and on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i guess maybe they have so much time to fill i've thought often times that maybe our world was a little bit better place when i was in high school and the world and the news like your radio station was on
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes in the evening</TIMEX> and then they went on to i don't know i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Williams</ENAMEX> show or something that filled up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other fifteen minutes</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that half hour</TIMEX> and we just weren't so heavy with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well it's sure been nice visiting with you
 	
 	
 		well you too
 	
 	
 		we're having sleet and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> this morning so
 	
 	
 		oh well we're having sunshine i think it's gonna be up in the seventies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh well have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> then  bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you too  good-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	