
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay we're rolling
 		i uh what what would you what would has your experience lead you to advise uh if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> were thinking of going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Academy</ENAMEX> what would you say
 	
 	
 		i'd encourage it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a good general education education education for a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and obviously and obviously it's where they don't have a
 		any post graduate program there but you get a
 		an excellent
 		wide
 		uh basis of topics you know you get a good broad education out of it you don't they don't graduate the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> or the best <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe a graduate pretty good overall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> out of there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-</ENAMEX>hum how do you feel about it must be a somewhat different environment from a regular college how does that uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		how do you feel that is for someone at at that phase in their life
 	
 	
 		well the
 		for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it's good because they maybe they need a little discipline need a little reining in at that
 		that stage in their life uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it uh it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> suffocating you know you kind of choke on it um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it depends on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on the individual but uh the one factor i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		more than anything else in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX> that's got to
 		be a big factor in your decision's just the the cost of
 		how much you're gonna pay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no matter where you go to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if you've been in for twelve years i'm sure you've you've got a your share of student loans that uh you're
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		probably going to be paying off or have been or
 	
 	
 		well i sort of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the reasons it's taken so long is i've been working
 		uh you know it's sort of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> student <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> working and source of income and stuff so i'm actually managing to do this with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> debt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		uh i couldn't you you couldn't do it otherwise
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i mean i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that graduated
 		or that i went to high school with that went to civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and they they've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty thousand</TIMEX> dollar debts i mean you could have uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think if there's any major piece of advice i'd give is to find a way of getting an education that doesn't incur that kind of debt
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's not i mean i remember seeing an article <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time about you know if the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who spent that much money going to college just took the same amount of money and put it in a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a</NUMEX> in an investment fund
 		they'd be considerably wealthier than they would be from the  job they'd get after college so it's it's really kind of crazy
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		it's it's staggering when you think that just
 		here in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamilton College</ENAMEX> is just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> south of you know maybe <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about twenty miles</NUMEX> to the south
 		from where i am and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're looking for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand dollars</NUMEX> for tuition and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		a year
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		at just a small
 		i mean they they they are select it is a select college
 	
 	
 		yes yes i know i was actually i think i was thinking of trying to get a job there i heard of it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but you're talking incredible tuitions now i don't know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually pay the whole shot very few i would imagine but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i get i i just couldn't imagine i mean it's more money than i make in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> so  you know it you know me being <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with a above the median
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		income for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state you know i'm a second i'm a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> lieutenant in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> now and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i even even as a
 		somebody making twice what i was making how could you
 		put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of that into
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s education and then just when they make made make it to the college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> it's
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		my God i can't imagine
 	
 	
 		well my my real feeling about
 		about the purpose of undergraduate education is
 		it's really the time yes you do get an education you do learn some things but you eventually forget most of it
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but what you don't forget is the growing up it's really the period when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
 		i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't go to college become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in other ways but really it's the entry into adulthood i think and i think that the best way to choose a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> is to decide what kind of environment you want to
 	
 	
 		i'd
 	
 	
 		be fostered in as you become
 		you know as you gain new social skills as you become you know more of a functioning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of society
 		and maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Academy</ENAMEX> is appropriate as you said for someone who you know a more you know who needs to learn self-discipline and so forth would be appropriate for them
 	
 	
 		or
 		or it's also a good environment it may be good for someone who already has self-discipline who has a certain amount of
 		leadership quality in their own
 	
 	
 		yeah and want to develop that
 	
 	
 		and that yeah the same it's the same it can benefit different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> different ways but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i i agree with that because i see people
 		that i know a again from high school that i still keep in touch with that didn't go to college and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they do the same old things they did in high school
 	
 	
 		the same patterns of behavior you mean yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		same patterns of behavior same
 		uh same socializing same exact <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> that they hang with and it's like it's like frozen time you know
 	
 	
 		exactly it's kind i find it kind of sad i really do
 	
 	
 		it is it really is that they haven't found anything anything better that
 		um or their experiences haven't been broadened at all that you know its a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a tremendous thing when you sit in a in a college environment and discuss some issues and really sit there with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with disagreeing opinions and you hear
 		all these different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of the story
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		that you never thought of
 		and uh that's another big thing i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get out of college is the appreciation for
 		different point differing points of view you know or different opinions
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum yeah in high school everyone sort of tries to have the same opinion it seems
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah the the one thing i think that's no good for anyone is these monster <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i
 	
 	
 		and i see some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX> wandering around in there and they're
 		they're just like you know someone from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> lost in the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> i mean they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they i don't see them getting
 		i mean when i was undergraduate i went to a relatively small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my first two years</TIMEX> and then i transferred to a very large school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that worked out pretty well i went from a you know a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> rate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> to a higher rate institution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first couple of years</TIMEX> it doesn't matter to me what the quality of the education was i needed to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> i needed to sort of learn the ropes you know there were things like that that mattered a lot more and i needed basic really simple education that you can get
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		pretty much anywhere for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first couple of years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well your education's a lot what you make of it too so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah exactly and if you're alienated
 		i mean i see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at supposedly really good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> who are just having such psychological problems that you think this isn't sinking in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i i've seen more graduates from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> and that being
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i work in a in a laboratory an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> and so we've got a lot of uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> graduates that are in there
 		and they are the biggest collection of screwed up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i think i've ever run into even even more so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh like military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy grads</ENAMEX> are a strange lot too i i mean i have to admit confess to that
 	
 	
 		yeah it's sort of a a rare select environment
 	
 	
 		yeah and they they have their own quirks and tolerances and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know
 		certain things that don't bother us at all that would drive other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> nuts and then certain things that ways things we do the way we do it that drive other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> nuts that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right right sure
 	
 	
 		but these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grads</ENAMEX> are off in their absolute own world it it's a
 		i i have more respect i have a lot of respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> master's and doctorate uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a top rated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> and now i
 	
 	
 		degrees but but their undergrads are like
 		i i'm amazed at at that's a lot of them even graduated
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		well i
 		i had known a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">undergraduates</ENAMEX> who pick
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> because they want the best reputation for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> not realizing that the reputation for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> is because of the of the doctorate research
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> who go there and you're not going to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> you know you're going to see some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TA</ENAMEX> you know uh
 	
 	
 		nope
 		the
 	
 	
 		so they put they they want you know they want the best and they don't think they think what the best is is reputation for for research and that's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> standard but it's not relevant to what they need
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no
 		it's interesting that you mention that i didn't think about that before when you were talking but the service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academies</ENAMEX> have all
 		all the faculty uh for the most part is is military with a few exchange
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		instruct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> from other
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh having the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> is really beneficial because they see it as
 		doing their job and spending time with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadets</ENAMEX> there uh is investing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and it or the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> itself it's the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer corps</ENAMEX> and so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i hear horror horror stories from
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of mine that they could never see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> they could never get extra help
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for me any time i needed extra help any time of the day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i had all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> home phone numbers and could call them you go to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> anytime i had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would invite me over to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for extended
 		study things on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> when i was having trouble with something and
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah you won't get that at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> or anything like that and you can and you know you can't blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> either because you look at their job description you'd see you know teaching is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> down on the list of importance things and
 	
 	
 		no no and that
 		no
 		right right publish <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		yeah and and that's appropriate if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> is trying to do serious research because it's hard to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> at the same time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i'd say go to a go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> that has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers people</ENAMEX> who really are committed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and can afford to be because that's their job
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but oh well
 	
 	
 		yeah it's there's a lot of factors that people
 		don't ever ever consider
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in their selection of a college and uh i don't know maybe
 		i wonder if if they enter these conversations that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been having um that
 		
 		
 	