
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> doesn't really have any organized recycling drive
 	
 	
 		where do you live
 	
 	
 		i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well um i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> and we're just beginning to
 		we we just built a real big recycling center
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that recycles everything imaginable but
 		as far as that um
 		trash pick up and stuff that a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> are doing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're testing that so they're really not full
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> into it but they're trying so we're attempting it
 		but i wish we could do more
 	
 	
 		yeah there's there's been no emphasis on recycling at all in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> i used to work for the power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> here and there was discussion
 		for a while about uh building a garbage burning
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh electric generation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> but it just wasn't cost effective at the time
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and there's there's a little recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> and things throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> but there isn't any um
 		advertising campaign there's just not any push to recycle i recycle my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and uh aluminum my aluminum stuff
 	
 	
 		huh
 		right that's what i do
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		they make it as hard as possible it's not very convenient to do
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right where they put <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well we have those um which i think is one of the best things is those cash for cans i don't know if you all have those around
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and i really like that because that makes it real convenient because they're in almost every shopping center
 		and you can just stop by now  everything else like the trash um
 		paper and
 		plastic and stuff you still have to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but for aluminum that's real nice and i started doing that at work  um i put out a
 		a trash can and and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to put their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> cans in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's really helped a lot i mean everybody's pitched in and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it doesn't bother them to walk little bit farther put their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> in a can rather than just throwing it in their trash can
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i really i really like that but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are really concerned it's just that sometimes it's not the right people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which is really really sad
 		because i wish we would do more  at work we started
 		um
 		all the recycling stuff they're really trying i think what started it at work was that planet <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> thing we had last year
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and um that really started a lot of stuff off but
 		you know sometimes it dwindles down
 	
 	
 		yeah where i work now we recycle all the computer paper
 	
 	
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		but that's about the extent of it
 	
 	
 		well that's well at least your trying something
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just yeah it would be nice if it could be more
 	
 	
 		and i'm sure that the uh driving factor for recycling the computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is that we get paid to do so we sell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> back to
 	
 	
 		oh do you really
 	
 	
 		the uh to a paper manufacturing company
 	
 	
 		well that's a neat idea
 	
 	
 		well it it defrays the cost of buying the paper i think i not by much but it does defray it some
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		enough to make it worth our while to have several bins through out the building
 	
 	
 		sure
 		well that's that's really good i mean at least they're trying
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that waste so much that
 		i'm even trying you know that was one thing we  noticed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that
 		we had some new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> move into our building
 		and  you know the nice cardboard boxes that you move packing boxes
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and they were just used one time and thrown in the dumpster and i thought
 		i don't understand this you know we're trying to cut cost and everything like that and and recycle and all that stuff and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and here we are wasting and i don't understand sometimes the way the thinking the logic behind it
 	
 	
 		well the last time uh
 		someone moved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and uh the uh properties <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> came in with all with the good cardboard boxes not the cheap ones of course and packed everything up and moved them and left them lying around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> because i'm moving pretty soon and they're good boxes and they were just going to throw them away
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's exactly what i did
 		that's exactly what i did exactly because i didn't want to waste that and it's hard enough to find good packing boxes though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 		right and and these boxes are you can unfold them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so you know there they don't take up much storage space
 	
 	
 		that's exactly right well that's very good
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i i felt a little guilty about taking the boxes for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two seconds</TIMEX> until i realized they would be thrown away so
 	
 	
 		uh
 		right right i found about
 	
 	
 		and i thought well i was doing them a favor by taking them
 	
 	
 		i found <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about five um about nine</NUMEX> of them that had not even been folded into boxes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that were in the dumpsters and i was like oh gosh so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go to the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and stuff and get those boxes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when you know these are perfect so
 	
 	
 		yeah the ones at the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> half the time they've pulled the lid off so you can't use it anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 		right  right
 	
 	
 		those and the real sturdy boxes that copy room paper comes in with the nice lids those get thrown away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i am constantly scouting out the copy room for those boxes
 	
 	
 		that's exactly what i do
 	
 	
 		those are
 		those are perfect boxes to put files in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they're good for storage and stuff like that that's what i do with a lot of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s things is i'll store her
 		you know like her out dated cards or out of out of season clothes in them and they're just perfect
 	
 	
 		what
 		what i've done in the past i don't have any now but i would buy some cheap wallpaper from somewhere and cover those nice boxes with the lids
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you can stack them up and and leave them out and put things in them even
 	
 	
 		and they look just as good that's a smart idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think i have to that that's really cute
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well you know it's cheaper than going and buying the kind at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX> that are all ready with the little design on them or whatever
 	
 	
 		and now they
 		they're the exact same thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's all they are they just made them look fancy
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		save you some money
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you're recycling
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well that's neat well do you all have um
 		we have
 		places that um
 		pay for paper
 		to recycle i know you do yours at work but for newspaper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but ours are real hard to find that's the one thing that really discourages me i saved paper you know i recycle paper
 		but they
 		it's almost like they don't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> because they don't pay
 		at all i mean they're real hard to find the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> that pay and that's really discouraging i mean i just go ahead and take it to the the regular place where it's
 		you know they just accept it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they um i think they should you know they want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to recycle i think it's a
 		you know like the aluminum you know it gets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to uh doing it you know you might you don't have to pay them a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah i live near a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WalMart</ENAMEX> and there's a big uh uh
 		huge dumpster looking thing sitting out front in fact i think there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them that have several openings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's for recycling and they have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and some other category i don't maybe there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> for aluminum
 	
 	
 		
  
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you don't get paid but it's real convenient just to chunk the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in there
 	
 	
 		well that's that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's good i the one thing i don't like about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> also is um
 		like at work we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different trash cans at your desk you have one for paper
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for just your normal trash  but in uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in the paper one you have to separate you have to make sure you don't throw away any of the slick <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> like magazines
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you can't throw any of that away and you can't throw
 		certain file type things away and i just think it's such a hassle it seems like it would be
 		be easy to take it all i don't know of course i don't know all that about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		recycling so
 		probably it is a hassle but i do get tired of having to separate paper you know we
 	
 	
 		um-hum it gets to be uh i guess you have to make it a habit i mean you have to get so used to doing it that it's a habit
 	
 	
 		right
 		right we had uh a write up in our paper
 		uh this last time at work about um
 		they come and empty your trash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every other day</TIMEX> they do your normal trash and every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> they do your recycling trash
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and somebody was writing in complaining that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had um dumped all the trash in the same bin
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and when they were questioned about it they said well we're running late or we didn't have time to do those bins or something
 		and that's real discouraging thinking you're sitting there working to separate it and then they
 	
 	
 		and someone else isn't going to take the time to put it in two separate bags
 	
 	
 		right right so they're they're really trying to start keeping an eye out for those you know talking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> again about
 		you know separate them because that is discouraging when you
 		when you do that it was hard to get used to those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different trash cans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but luckily that'll all get straightened out and
 		and they'll they'll start separating them because i don't mind doing that i feel like i'm doing uh
 		doing something for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> when i'm doing that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but anyway
 	
 	
 		well i've enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		you too
 	
 	
 		well
 		thank you bye bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	