
 
     		
 	
 		well oh our topic is capital punishment
 		i guess uh
 		one thing is to compare uh how it is maybe here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> versus uh
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe your part of the country
 	
 	
 		yeah i you know i'm not sure if we have the death penalty here
 		to be perfectly honest with you hold on a second
 		do we have the death penalty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> no  okay no we don't
 		but you know um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i have some feelings about it in the sense that
 		i feel if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is guilty beyond a reasonable doubt
 		and it's a really heinous crime
 		i feel like the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> says an eye for an eye
 	
 	
 		um-hum describing a heinous crime being like murder or
 	
 	
 		yeah you know something really a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		what other ones would be
 	
 	
 		you know someone who who really has no remorse
 		you know that that just does these things uh
 		i don't know without feeling guilty about it at all you know and the and their
 		we in fact we have an example going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> with this uh school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> involved some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		into uh committing murder get getting rid of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you're familiar with it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pamela Smart</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		don't think i've heard of that one
 	
 	
 		see now in a situation like that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> are only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years old</TIMEX> and they were sexually involved with her
 		and i think like at that particular point she was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX>
 		you know so she wasn't really that much older than them
 		and being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> at that age i think that they're very
 		um you know let's face it that's at a point in your life when you you're just starting to realize all the things of life
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think she probably had a lot of influence on them and they probably would have never done something like that
 		if it wasn't for the crime of passion type of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah we had one uh course in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they uh  used to string them up now they
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		got more uh civilized and uh give them lethal injection so we definitely do have uh capital punishment
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		now see i agree with that i i don't think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> should be electrocuted or
 		hung or you know in in other words i believe that they should be punished and done away with
 		on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand like i say if they're if they're guilty beyond a reasonable doubt
 		but if there's
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other</TIMEX> the other hand where you say you know if there's just that slim chance that they didn't do it
 		and then you know spend the time say life imprisonment
 		then at least they have a chance to over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> be proven not guilty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		there was one here recently that comes to mind that's about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that uh this is ridiculous i mean it's almost uh
 		it'd be funny if it wasn't so so sad i mean this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> went out and hired somebody to uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to uh kill another mother
 	
 	
 		oh that's the cheerleader thing
 	
 	
 		yeah right have you heard about that one
 	
 	
 		oh yes that was on TV here
 	
 	
 		yeah isn't that something
 	
 	
 		it made national um
 	
 	
 		i didn't know it made the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> news

 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that was something wasn't it uh it's unbelievable this
 	
 	
 		but you know i i i saw i can't figure out what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are doing any more
 		i mean it's getting so bad
 		and i don't think unless that the crime that the laws get to the point where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are afraid to do something because they know they'll be punished
 		you know what i'm saying
 	
 	
 		well that brings up i guess part of what would be a question is uh you know is i guess you feel like that's a deterrent in uh capital punishment should be
 	
 	
 		yeah and you know and i i don't know if it would be
 		but i mean we don't know that it wouldn't either
 	
 	
 		well it uh  must be i think it's a matter of degree and uh of course uh course it varies from case to case or individual
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and the other point someone made at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> time was that
 		if someone is guilty of a terrible crime or they're a serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> or mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>
 		that if they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> that gives you the chance to um get into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s mind
 		to find out uh what led them to the point that they were at when they committed the crime
 		to uh try to understand how their mind worked to prevent
 		uh you know another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> from getting into the same situation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't know you know  maybe you could do that for a certain period of time
 		but i mean how long does that kind of a thing take
 		you know to to um say to question the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or to get into their head
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know even if it took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> i think that if at that time you you feel that they were guilty or that they were uh of sound mind where they knew what crimes they were committing i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know what they're doing
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you know that that i really do i believe that that capital punishment should be there
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> are overcrowded
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it costs the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> a lot of money
 	
 	
 		that's one thing down here we certainly have a problem with overcrowded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah  i'll tell you in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> it was so bad
 		that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">intake center</ENAMEX> that they have to house the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> before they go to the uh penitentiaries and stuff
 		um were overcrowded and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> fined the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX> a day
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		to build a bigger intake center
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i mean it it's like where does this all stop
 	
 	
 		well they're releasing them uh early here
 	
 	
 		exactly same thing here and that's that's what they did
 	
 	
 		and
 		and then uh then you hear about ones that are on early release going out and
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		committing a
 	
 	
 		in fact the news tonight they had uh someone come on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy three year old</TIMEX> man
 		they they had gotten into a housing for the elderly and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who perpetrated the crime went in with someone who had a relative there
 		and uh apparently this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was an invalid and he was in an elevator and he died for twelve dollars
 	
 	
 		um
 		well i tell you what i think that uh you know this may this may be a cause rather the actual topic but uh i think that a lot of this is caused by
 		the steady diet of violence they seem to
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		want to be uh
 		you know showing on movies and television
 	
 	
 		yeah and i also think that the uh fact that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are working today
 		and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are not bonded to the parents
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take the responsibility for raising these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are left out
 		you know
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		on their own and they don't really feel the family um closeness that we had when oh when i was growing up
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> didn't work you know  and when she did uh a part time job she was there
 		you know it wasn't like she
 	
 	
 		well well what seems to be the answer is to concentrate on uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> back in the home
 	
 	
 		well yeah well i don't know if that's
 	
 	
 		you know kind of
 	
 	
 		going to be necessarily workable but it would be uh one way
 	
 	
 		oh i know i know
 	
 	
 		it certainly has to start with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about it do you do you think there should be capital punishment
 	
 	
 		yes i do i think it's uh something that unfortunately uh at this stage of the game i would hope that at some point we would become
 		you know civilized enough where we could do away with it but as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and the way things are i think it's uh something we just have to have
 	
 	
 		yeah i i do myself i really think that it's it's all well and good to um be a do-gooder or to to um
 		you know try to spare everyone's life but when someone has no regard for another person
 		excuse me their property or their personal
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> being or their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> i mean you know when whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are killed and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and yet you have someone who'll commit a crime of robbery and spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> in jail
 		i mean to me it's like we have things messed up somehow
 		you you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and like this banking crisis thing where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have stolen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> and they're out walking around
 	
 	
 		huh well i just uh
 	
 	
 		i think all our laws are are really screwed up
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i do i i don't know what to do about it i wish i did
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well i think it comes back to uh starting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> once you get them you know if you get them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		where they have a sense of values and uh you know that uh that's what it takes
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 		morals yeah
 	
 	
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> start uh oh you know repeat about it you know they start to see this violence in a steady diet and uh it's to be uh just
 	
 	
 		did you ever see the program uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Why Does Johnny Kill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		about these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who
 		were were not even like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years old</TIMEX> they were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and twelve and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen and fifteen year olds</TIMEX> and they they actually committed murders
 		and the question was whether to try them as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> or as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all right
 		can't remember that
 	
 	
 		and whether or not to uh institute you know capital punishment where it was necessary and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that has to
 	
 	
 		that's a tough one too
 	
 	
 		yeah i i mean what would you do in a situation like that you say well he's only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX>
 		but the crime he committed is that of an adult
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he made that decision
 	
 	
 		we had a personal experience with something like that it wasn't didn't go as far as murder but this
 		this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> had uh she had gotten hold of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and she came around to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> worked and she was she had this mental problem with uh with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> she works for him and uh he was she was just
 		after him you know and the cops pick her up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh there wasn't a thing they could do you know they'd take her down to the juvenile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> and then they'd have to let her go and she'd be back  doing it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		imagine so see this is what i'm saying and even with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are mentally incompetent you know uh like deranged
 		it's so hard to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even institutionalized because they're overcrowded
 		so you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walking the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> molesters
 		or uh
 		
 		
 	