
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		you want to start
 	
 	
 		well i guess i would
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> identify myself as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">middle</ENAMEX> aged and therefore having seen the last generation i guess it puts me in you know gives me a perspective on that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		i  am quite positive on the things that i have seen happen recently relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in
 		both in society and in the work place uh
 		there's no doubt about the fact that when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> was first graduated from college the impression was that
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s career would consist of a childbearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and perhaps a return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> but not necessarily
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> now i think the change that i've seen as much as anything is one where
 		couples uh are more carefully planning their intention on how to share both share homemaking duties and also how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> will
 		uh have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and then deliberately sort of plan how they go back to the work place
 		and i guess that's a significant change that of i've both participated in and and noticed
 	
 	
 		i agree um the equality of uh the roles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> between the sexes i guess has been dramatically
 		demonstrated with this war especially compared with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX> and you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> going off to wars as well as men
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i have wondered why they allowed or let you know both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and mother
 		go uh and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are left without either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> now to me that's kind of a drawback
 		but uh i guess it's a price you pay
 		and i also wonder about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are being brought up
 		in the uh
 		uh day care centers
 	
 	
 		wonder about them in what way
 	
 	
 		well uh from what i understand there's been studies that uh these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are uh more rebellious
 		uh they term it as more uh
 		creative
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh that they uh are much more contentious
 		so i i don't i i guess we'll have to see another generation
 		to see what differences
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> being brought up you know in in a uh kind of a uh community
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		rather than a home
 	
 	
 		i have not to be honest had much experience
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in that situation i i guess one knows one's own storly and i know
 		uh in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s case it was one where uh pretty much up until
 		the older of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> was in
 		uh let's see i guess basically starting junior high and the younger was in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> grade when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> reentered the work force
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 		so i guess my experience is is just with what we did and and so they didn't really go through the child care route they were able to be home together
 	
 	
 		so they
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		and we never actually experienced that
 		what in terms of changes relative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the work place and and potential changes over the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next</TIMEX>
 		generation or so i guess i anticipate um
 		an increasing equality uh greater presence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in management roles
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't know whether
 		there will be
 		an increased amount of of surrogacy that we see i just don't know
 	
 	
 		what do you mean
 	
 	
 		um deliberate childbirth by surrogate mother
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		sort of rent a mom to be you know not to be crass about it but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's strange
 	
 	
 		uh whether one might conceive  no pun intended of the possibility that there might be a kind of a deliberate uh um
 	
 	
 		a nanny sort of
 	
 	
 		a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> a person
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for instance that and i could you know i could envision a society where that would happen and make an interesting uh
 		uh story or whatever i i don't think i have a philosophical problem with that in fact i think it sort of raises
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nurturing</ENAMEX> and being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to what it ought to be which is a respected profession
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		uh um
 		i i don't have a other than than a reading and and male perspective on on
 		the various on the biological urges involved relative to being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> or not
 		uh i know that that my sense is that i have
 		very much an interest and had one in being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> i i don't know that i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> felt myself necessarily encumbered with the necessity to have heirs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> that doesn't didn't bother me never has vision more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> deliberately raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> either in surrogacy or
 		or as a professional nanny nanny as you put it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		maybe we'll see a growth in that where someone makes uh a career out of say taking care of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as opposed to day care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it would be a sort of day care but it would be more of a family setting
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um i know that there are young people
 		characterized i guess as being half my age so that by definition that means they're young uh
 		that in my work place who are both of them earning rather
 		decent professional salaries who probably would consider paying
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or nine or ten</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to take care of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> i could easily envision that pardon
 	
 	
 		to come in and live with them to come in and live with them
 	
 	
 		or to put their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> into a setting into a home setting where they would you know like they they would get leave at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight in the morning</TIMEX> and and drop <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a two year old</TIMEX> off in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> where you knew there were going to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you were paying for really high quality care
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i have
 		acquaintances of mine where i know that they are paying figures on on the order of what i quoted to someone because that's what the experience they want
 		and i would imagine if there are more of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that with an opportunity that that's a possibility of a change that we could see in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and then you might have more control over uh the the morals that they would be taught rather than
 		in like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> or a day care center
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know the day care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> are not cheap either
 		you know they're
 	
 	
 		i haven't ever really looked at them are you aware at all of of what they would what they cost
 	
 	
 		uh well no i just know i know several single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who absolutely can't afford it they have to go with the a single
 		uh what i mean a babysitter more more or less
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about sixty</TIMEX> dollars a week
 		for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> if i'm not mistaken
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you have to pay that whether you're on vacation you know and taking care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are at home at home sick
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean that is you know just a a rate that you have to pay
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		what do you envision for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next twenty years</TIMEX> as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i think
 		i really don't have a vision
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's okay too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i um
 		i think that they will be more in the work place because
 		uh the door's open
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's just human nature to walk through an open door
 		so and i would be glad to see that
 		i hope i don't see a lot more single moms
 		but
 		i it seems in my experience i'm running across single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm noticing that too and and i notice the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the</NUMEX> a terming  emerging called solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that i am very aware of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the number of solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> that that i encounter in the work place and that that is a little troublesome
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because the pressures on them are are rather rather formidable
 	
 	
 		it's awful
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and maybe that's a change we'll see maybe uh possibility the possibility of of women
 		uh who deliberately say no we'll let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> will take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> perhaps in the event of a separation or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well i think we've done it  thank you very much it's been interesting
 	
 	
 		well i think we're about done okay uh good bye
 		you take care bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	