
 
     		
 	
 		what are your music music interests
 	
 	
 		uh just about any kind of music except <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rock</ENAMEX> i i don't care for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rock</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		me too  oh
 	
 	
 		but uh i grew up with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western but uh just about any kind of music i even like classical music
 	
 	
 		yeah i did too and then
 		yeah uh i'm pretty diversified too i i don't i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rock</ENAMEX> either i've  i grew up in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> so uh the only  we only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> radio station so it was country music but then uh when i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i grew up with  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Snow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty Frizzell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams</ENAMEX> and all of those old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western songs
 	
 	
 		oh really you're older than i am  oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but uh i did you happen to see last night the special on channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Galway</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we don't get channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> my our cable doesn't i wish we got that one  it was it well we don't get channel two
 	
 	
 		oh
 		that was fabulous when
 		yeah when he played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Boy</ENAMEX> it just almost brought tears to your eyes because he can make that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flute</ENAMEX> sing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh it was tremendous
 	
 	
 		now he he is a good uh actually i did i played flute for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost ten years</TIMEX>  and and uh so i i i i appreciate his too his his music he he he's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> isn't he
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah uh-huh and it was uh mostly all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> tunes they they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> with him that uh had a harpist and another flute and then
 	
 	
 		was yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> that played the bagpipes plus the uh tin whistle and a couple of violins and a drum and they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they played all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> jigs and so forth it was just fabulous
 	
 	
 		yeah i he he is really good yeah i've i've
 		i come from a musical background so uh um i've played flute flute flute and piano so  i i i have uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a big appreciation for music
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		up to a point i i'm getting now to the age where i don't like the new stuff that's coming and much of the new stuff that's coming out  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> says i'm getting old
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i love uh i like i especially like instrumentals
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		yeah i love to just lay back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> and and turn a good good instrumental on and just close my eyes and listen
 	
 	
 		that yeah that that's nice to do that that is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i've got a i've got a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> who's now getting  i'm getting well well versed in in kiddy music
 	
 	
 		uh i'm i never played an instrument in my life i've always wanted to i've always wished my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> had forced me to learn the piano or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah  well i was one of the forced ones
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		but i i'd just love to be able to go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> or something and sit down at the piano and bang out music
 	
 	
 		oh i could never do that  i was never that brave but um  yeah
 	
 	
 		hm
 		hm
 		
  
 		but i guess the closest i've ever come to participating in music is singing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah i've i've done i've done that at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> too haven't done that in a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so let's see what
 		well what kind of music do you not like
 	
 	
 		well like i say the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid rock</ENAMEX> i just do not care and i don't care for rap music either
 	
 	
 		oh oh gosh that's not music  that is not i don't know what that is but that's not music
 	
 	
 		huh-uh no no
 		if i can't understand the words i don't wanna listen to it
 	
 	
 		well it's it's it's not it's not music it's just it's just uh uh beat talking in a beat it is just it's not exciting at all it doesn't  it doesn't give you relaxation you can't dance to it you can't do anything to it yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		right
 		but i and i love uh i look at the orchestra music too like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> Pops or or anything
 	
 	
 		did
 		yeah
 		have you ever been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">to</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Symphony</ENAMEX> have you is it are they good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah they're good
 	
 	
 		are they i i have never i've never been
 	
 	
 		and uh we went and saw uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Les Les Miserables</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		oh the music in that was fantastic
 	
 	
 		i've i've heard i've heard that that is a really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i heard that was hard to get tickets to
 	
 	
 		yeah it it uh
 		i can't remember how far in advance we reserved tickets but it was out you know out at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">State Fair Music Hall</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably cost
 		yeah  yeah that was a real
 	
 	
 		and uh it was well worth the price yeah
 	
 	
 		was it i i bet it was i bet i really bet it was  is that the only uh musical do you go see musicals musicals a lot of musicals
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		just just ever so often you know a real a real good one like that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah the
 		that that would be that would be nice
 	
 	
 		we went and saw uh i think it was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sugar Babies</ENAMEX> that was good that had good music in it
 	
 	
 		was it i how how i can't i don't know what that's about
 	
 	
 		uh that was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Rooney</ENAMEX> and uh oh what's that real oh not real old uh well she is old too dancer um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i can't think of her name i got it right on the tip of my tongue and can't say it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX> something
 	
 	
 		uh oh oh i think i know who you're talking oh i know who you're talking talking about she's got black hair
 	
 	
 		uh
 		real long legs and dark hair
 	
 	
 		yeah okay i know who your talking about i can't think of her name either yeah that was that was that was i remember that being uh here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i can't think of it
 		yeah
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		oh oh the last country music  my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> still uh really like country music and they they like um they like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oak Ridge Boys and the Stadler Brothers</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh well my my my my parents
 	
 	
 		Blackwoods
 	
 	
 		yeah my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes uh country music real well and he he likes some of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shenandoah</ENAMEX> and uh yeah he really likes Shenandoah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> well yeah yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> i think they're i think they're a bit too over exposed  i get kind of tired get tired tired of every other song being <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> on the radio
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		but i
 		yeah either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams Junior</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i i i i've never cared for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams Junior</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i never neither and i never have figured out how he won the entertainer of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three or four years</TIMEX> in a row
 	
 	
 		i  oh we we watch those award shows too we like we enjoyed watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammies</ENAMEX> and stuff but i just i just don't care for him i just never have i don't
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 		i guess probably my favorite all time <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western song or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> is uh probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddy Arnold</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is is it okay uh i i i think i i know who that is uh-huh i think my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have  have uh some of his records
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		but i got about i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a hundred and</NUMEX> or had a uh some uh i sold some of them i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a hundred and fifty</NUMEX> old
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy eight</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPM</ENAMEX> records of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western songs
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiley Burnette i</ENAMEX> don't know if you're old enough to remember him
 	
 	
 		i've heard the name
 	
 	
 		he was uh played in the old western movies he was the sidekick of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Autry</ENAMEX> i believe or they i think his name when in the movie was Froggy
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		had had a real raspy voice
 	
 	
 		i've i've never seen a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Autry</ENAMEX> movie hm
 	
 	
 		and uh some of those old ones of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Wills</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Playboys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Tubbs</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		no i never have
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		Red <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foley</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah those go back quite a ways
 	
 	
 		yeah i took them up here to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collectors Rector Records</ENAMEX> and was able to get a little money for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> used to own a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and they had a they had a uh nickelodeon of course in the restaurant and when they would come and change the records
 	
 	
 		it's hard to find
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> would and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> would give her the old records
 	
 	
 		well that would that's neat
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		that's where i learned about
 	
 	
 		that would be great great if they weren't too worn out at the time
 	
 	
 		yeah course there's not a whole lot of market for seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RPM</ENAMEX> records
 	
 	
 		is there not you you'd well you'd think there would be
 	
 	
 		well the problem is that most of the record <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> now will not play them because you have to have that needle that uh particular kind of needle
 	
 	
 		well that's true
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh they just won't play on a
 		modern day uh
 	
 	
 		well that's a shame
 	
 	
 		phonograph
 	
 	
 		because i i we go to antique <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> a lot and you see seventy eights
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh a lot at at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at</TIMEX> at or in record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> you'd
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		think there'd be a market for i i'm sure you could find old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> for them but that'd cost a fortune if you could find them that worked  oh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		course they you know just don't have the quality of records nowadays either because you you you get that scratchy sound
 	
 	
 		no
 		um-hum well those things were big and thick weren't they
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		now you could kill somebody with them  and the one you buy go out and buy one now and they're just so thin and flimsy and
 	
 	
 		yeah they warped real easy
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they just they're not meant to last at all
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		no neither are tapes i i i buy we buy cassette tapes and machines will eat them you did so you're best bet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> anymore <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> is a compact disk those things are practically indestructible
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yes
 		but i i guess you know the old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western music you back then when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> there wasn't that much TV so that's all you had to listen to was the radio
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		radio yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		that that's just what  just what you had back plus i think it was better back then to the TV there's too much TV now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the radio is you know more exciting really than than television  kept your imagination
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		was it it it kept it it just didn't vegetate your mind like television does
 	
 	
 		yeah i remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> always turned on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Ole</ENAMEX> Opry
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		was that on the radio every week
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what what day what day was that on do you have you can you recall
 	
 	
 		i i seems like it was on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday Friday</TIMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
 		
 		
 	