
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		here we go
 	
 	
 		okay um have you ever been involved in any trials
 	
 	
 		i sure was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX> i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some Fourth of July to Labor Day</TIMEX>
 		on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that was uh a change of venue from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbus Ohio</ENAMEX> for aggravated uh murder and kidnapping
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		yeah it was quite a session that disrupted disrupted my whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> of course
 	
 	
 		sounds like it
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days a week</TIMEX> but it was an absolutely fascinating experience
 	
 	
 		oh it sounds like it i haven't had any actual real life experience but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father-in-law</ENAMEX>'s been involved in uh several trials including uh a couple of murders and uh
 		you know talking to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been there and so i don't have any real experience with trials but i do you know i i've i took a little business law in in college and and i've you know try to keep abreast of things but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm i think that the uh trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is is a great idea at it's inception back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred years ago</TIMEX> hm
 		right now though it's it's so difficult because there's so few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> to to get anything really done as you know you spent you know a whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> trial
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's just that i think they're just tying up the um whole judicial process um there's a lot of things they could do
 		to uh make things easier and uh you know like uh the suggestion that uh maybe the uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> should be the one who decides on what the sentence should be rather than the jury
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i think that there are many cases where uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> probably do make the decision rather than the jury Our situation was somewhat different
 		uh in view of the fact that uh we haven't we were a landmark case it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> that um D <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX> A testing was entered as evidence
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> was being especially careful that everything was done correctly so there couldn't be a a mistrial of any kind uh the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the interesting thing was the tremendous selection of jury process uh that we experienced That took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one full week</TIMEX> uh to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> qualified to sit on the jury
 		And then it was a matter of the selection of uh twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> after that actually it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen</TIMEX> because we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> alternates
 	
 	
 		jeez
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> was extremely concerned for our welfare if we were well if we were comfortable and uh things of that nature which made us feel good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and we were sequestered but the makeup of the jury uh was truly a cross section of uh you might say a cross section of a country
 		there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> besides myself we were the only ones that had ever been to college hm one was a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of mine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> before who was out of work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> others were ones who had never finished high school and were out looking for jobs yet um a couple of them were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewives</ENAMEX> who had never worked and then some are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who did work
 	
 	
 		gee
 	
 	
 		so we had quite a cross section of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">white</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and men
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it uh it was interesting just to listen to the rationale uh being proposed and the logic of some of the people
 		uh it was also extremely difficult to stay awake sometimes because there was so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> and we were not allowed to take any notes of any kind
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i thought that that was a failing because uh
 		from the standpoint that it was difficult to try to remember everything and and yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> said well um if you're taking notes you're missing something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and he was right there also but uh uh certainly um i think it depends upon how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> handles the case
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and if the criminal chooses to have a uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panel judge</ENAMEX> uh a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> panel i should say i think he can have that rather than trial by jury
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes yes i agree uh would surprise me that uh when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i had the uh displeasure of getting a uh traffic ticket
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i went to court and you can even get a trial by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> for a traffic ticket
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 	
 	
 		no and i thought my God talk about tying up things for for
 	
 	
 		yes and money
 	
 	
 		yes i mean that's extremely expensive i mean the first thing you had to do when you came before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> was waive your right to a jury trial
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm like God this is ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i do think that that uh i do think the jury system works but i'd i also feel as you said that the original concept of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> as it was originally setup
 		uh back uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years ago</TIMEX> was fine but that it needs to be more refined for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s standard of living and the the uh level of education of them of so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh by the same token we had um uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who wanted to had vacations planned
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in particular had reservations made <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> tickets made everything and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> called and had it all canceled so he could get his money back and then he wasn't selected on the jury
 	
 	
 		oh my God
 	
 	
 		and then another young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> had to meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> and the defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different occasions before he was finally excused from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> because his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was about to have twins
 		and they had he had to go through all of that if in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> to get excused from that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> to be with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> on the birth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> and uh you know some of it just seemed rather extreme
 	
 	
 		yes i i think they can probably come up with some ways to insure that uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would get a fair trial and not have to go through this process
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean some things are just so cut and dry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um</ENAMEX> in the in you know the the level of evidence that they come up with now i mean you know when you start thinking about well they've got videotape and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and audio tapes and they've they've got you know they've got ways to nail <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  to the point where they they really shouldn't even be going to trial
 	
 	
 		right well i guess he'd have to be careful whether with entrapment or some of those things
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't i assume you have seen on television recently as probably the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has the beating of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was horrible
 	
 	
 		isn't that terrible And uh you know and that certainly uh cannot be said to be uh something that happens everywhere
 	
 	
 		that it
 	
 	
 		but the fact that it can happen that it probably does happen in many places it's it's horrendous and
 		it's just a stroke of luck that someone was able to get it on tape and then uh to listen to the tape recording uh at the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> of the whole conversation afterwards
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes i know i mean i only heard portions of that but it's absolutely terrible and you know if you beat a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> like that they'll put you in jail
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		absolutely
 		well we just had a case uh
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		like up at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of last year</TIMEX> where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> it was on a drug raid uh was trying to extra extricate um
 		a confession or information from a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> and did so by placing a hot a hot iron on his chest his bare chest burned him
 	
 	
 		jeez
 	
 	
 		they wound up paying him uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> of course was fired but they paid the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> or something to drop the lawsuit
 		and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> someone shot and killed the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX>
 		so uh as some of those things uh are absolutely horrendous and we do need an all an overhaul and we just need more discipline <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> wide it would then we'd need it on that yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yes i i believe that too
 	
 	
 		well it's been very nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		well it's been nice talking with you
 	
 	
 		yes and uh good luck on on some other calls
 	
 	
 		okay thank you you do the same bye-bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh bye-bye</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	