
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Mary</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		um the uh the latest one i've seen uh had to do with a uh uh the uh basically a manhunt um and it was uh it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhunter</ENAMEX> actually
 		uh the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> uh apparently had a a mental dysfunction in which he needed to go out and just slay people
 		uh just uh kill them with uh with as much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and and guts as possible
 	
 	
 		oh how awful
 	
 	
 		it  was true it was truly awful it was not one that i picked but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh it it it did show some some uh some interesting things about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> because they were the the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> trying trying to get him were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh
 		uh of the of the few good things that were in it it did show uh a lot about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> about the training and and how they go through training and how they try to to develop uh uh a mental picture of who they're looking for
 		before they go out and do it and all the different ways they go about doing that and it was uh uh it was was pretty telling about the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and and their procedures
 	
 	
 		i wonder how truthful all of that was or whether that was fictional
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i imagine a lot of it had to be fictional just to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> uh going i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah well they keep it rather secretive yes
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh the most recent movie i saw uh i'm afraid was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two two</NUMEX> of them actually uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rain Man</ENAMEX> was one
 	
 	
 		oh that was a great one
 	
 	
 		wasn't that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">fabulous and and Driving Miss Daisy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i loved it
 		you know i haven't seen that one yet and i need to go see it
 	
 	
 		oh you need to see that that is the most heart rendering story of relationships between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diametrically</ENAMEX> opposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the stand point that one was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> and one was Black and this all took place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> and uh normally never the twain shall meet
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		um you bet especially in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes right and um uh it it it really was a fantastic movie the acting was phenomenal
 	
 	
 		but as
 		it it as i recall it got some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> didn't it
 	
 	
 		oh yes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jessica Tandy</ENAMEX> won best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> and uh say
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's right it it might have one best picture too
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes it did yes it did just as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rain Man</ENAMEX> uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that was
 	
 	
 		uh that that was tremendous and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think it was more a lesson for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> than anything else in terms of uh of how to act from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yes uh oh that was that was uh what the much of the hype was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> learned so much from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it must have been great just being with him on on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis and seeing how he prepares for his for his lines and all that stuff and
 	
 	
 		yeah and a good bit of that was filmed right there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX> which is just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty five miles</NUMEX> from from where i am where i actually live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dayton</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		is is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX> there  that was
 	
 	
 		oh well we do have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX> here you better believe it isn't there a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Kmart</ENAMEX> everywhere
 	
 	
 		that was so funny had to or was it Kmart uh he had to buy his underwear at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right right yeah
 	
 	
 		that was hilarious the the i guess the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first the first</TIMEX> uh scene in that movie that really got my attention uh concerning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">the</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX> and all that was when he uh dropped the the uh the toothpicks
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		and he was able to count the number of toothpicks just by a mental image unbelievable
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		well you know there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh referred to as savants also uh who can do most phenomenal things and everyone feels they are totally retarded
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah well because that's the way they they might seem outwardly but boy there's a lots going on in there
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		it's amazing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and i the the i think the the best thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rain Man</ENAMEX> was the uh the way that they put together the the real awfulness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">of the</ENAMEX> of the disease
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and only and and and then they balanced it with the wonderfulness of it you know and and and you need to to to work with it uh you know certainly on on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis but then again then again work with it toward a good end
 	
 	
 		yes and the
 	
 	
 		not not toward you know winning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> for example
 	
 	
 		right well the warmth that developed between them and again it i think was a picture of relationships
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		again the relationship uh between the two uh that uh never would have occurred uh by accident
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right right i was uh i was so impressed with that movie i saw it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times i can i can say tell you oh oh so much about that movie just because it it
 	
 	
 		did you
 	
 	
 		it really rang uh rang a lot of my uh my personal background i i have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> myself that's
 		that's older and uh he's not you know nothing nothing of course serious is wrong with him but uh but we have gone through these these lapses of of a relationship somewhat sometimes
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and then you know uh for for for no real you know uh uh direct reason i guess uh we we get into uh uh a really good relationship for a while and then
 		you know back and forth so i i was really able to to relate to the the relationship aspect of the movie between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> that was neat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's tremendous that it's good because it does make you think about your own family
 	
 	
 		yeah a lot
 	
 	
 		and see it did bring out a lot of thoughts between you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum no question he the he was he's one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> though that doesn't really like to go see movies like that he likes the bang them up shoot them up things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		and uh it it was like pulling teeth to go get him to to see it but uh oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> he was
 		uh uh he he gave the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the best</TIMEX> response that i've heard him give of this type of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">for Rain Man</ENAMEX>  i mean he he certainly didn't he only saw it one time and he didn't go back for more but uh but he he said he enjoyed it and and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well he at least saw it one time
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah and and he really i don't know he he he's kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> anyway but he was but before he saw the movie he said he was like disappointed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX> would do this i'm like oh come on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 		well just think of what a phenomenal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX> is be able to do that to research it and be able to mimic a person uh uh with the kinds of problems that he had
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it
 		and to make it believable i mean i was i i was believing it i don't know about anybody else but i was it was great
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 
 		
 
 		well i'm sure everybody that saw it was believing it right along with them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		he did great
 	
 	
 		well it's just uh been delightful talking with you
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you take care up there and uh  let's hear it for the summertime
 	
 	
 		absolutely i'm ready for it they're predicting some more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> for our direction
 	
 	
 		no oh no oh well take care
 	
 	
 		take care now bye bye
 	
 	
 		bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	