
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy</ENAMEX> have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't have you
 	
 	
 		oh that is a wonderful movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it's not the length isn't too long
 	
 	
 		no oh goodness no you don't even you don't even realize it you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well
 		really i've heard different opinions about it uh uh-huh one that you know yeah it was too long and they thought that you know at certain points that it was going to end and it didn't and it kept going on and uh-huh
 	
 	
 		really
 		oh i thought it was great yeah
 	
 	
 		really now i've seen you know some different clips of it um
 		and it it looks good it's just i haven't had the time to go to the movies lately
 	
 	
 		well yeah and i heard a story about there's a there's a certain scene in the movie where there's um
 		where they're where they're on a buffalo hunt and they have a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child actor</ENAMEX> uh who's who's being supposedly run down by a buffalo
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when they were trying to film that the buffalo that they used for that scene was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Young</ENAMEX>'s buffalo i can't remember what they said his name was but he has a fetish for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oreo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh oh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they got him to run like he was running down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> by luring him with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oreo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX> that'd work for me let me tell you
 	
 	
 		i thought that was really funny
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX> now i've seen another clip of um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that plays in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murphy Brown</ENAMEX> i don't know his name but he's he played the uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in it that
 		was very like gross i mean very dirty and oh i saw the one clip of him and ugh it when he was first i guess he was taking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		like the site where he was going to be or whatever
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that was rather um gross
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah but other than that i've heard the the you know the um
 		the scenery in it is absolutely beautiful
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and uh the costuming
 	
 	
 		uh-huh really
 	
 	
 		yeah was the only thing about the costuming my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> remarked that it didn't that that um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> all appeared to be wearing new things
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and they should have taken them out and rolled them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> a little more probably you know age to age the material so they they did very authentic reproductions of the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the styles  uh-huh
 	
 	
 		of the actual stuff but they didn't they didn't age it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		quite enough it seemed but it was a very good movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh well i guess i will have to see it then
 	
 	
 		what have you seen lately
 	
 	
 		um actually have been to the movies um i think the last movie i saw was Misery
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't see that
 	
 	
 		oh very suspenseful
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really don't either but i went with someone and once i was there i couldn't believe i mean it's an excellent movie yeah
 	
 	
 		really i wasn't sure because uh just generally you know that kind of scary stuff i i just don't want to have anything to do with it
 	
 	
 		it's not necessarily it it's not necessarily scary as it is suspenseful i mean it's not
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i heard somebody talking about that she cuts his foot off or something you know
 	
 	
 		no in in the book apparently she cuts his <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX> off but in the movie she she
 		disables him but not by cutting his feet um she she breaks both of his ankles
 	
 	
 		hum
 		ugh
 	
 	
 		and that i couldn't watch and but you know you could tell when it was coming
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so yeah um that was so that he couldn't leave her cause she
 	
 	
 		it still just seems a little twisted to me  i'm not sure i would have enjoyed that at all
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i mean uh
 		yeah well as far as that goes yeah i mean you wouldn't like to see anybody anything happen to anybody but it was just how she got so caught up her emotions
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know and and she feel madly in love with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and it was just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but she was a killer and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> was you know prior to that had had been someone that had killed other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but no one knew that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		but  so yeah we just haven't had the time to go to the movies  lately
 	
 	
 		i know we don't see movies at the movies a lot the last we did go see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> and we went to see Not Without My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Daughter</ENAMEX> but mostly we wait until they come out on video tape and then we rent them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		right right now i want to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping With The Enemy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that looks really good too
 	
 	
 		um that yeah it looks good and there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> others that i just haven't had the time now see i
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambs</ENAMEX> i'm i'm intrigued by it but i'm not sure i want to go see it yet
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't think i want to see that either i know i don't i don't think i could
 	
 	
 		i think
 		well now we had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that went to see it and they said it was okay so it might not be as i think they may be playing up um some aspects of the movie that aren't the main aspects
 	
 	
 		really
 		really
 		
 
 		uh-huh know
 	
 	
 		now we went to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jagged Edge</ENAMEX> and that yeah so it's it seems like you know that kind of the thriller suspense and not not real um
 	
 	
 		oh well i liked that movie yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		strange in other ways
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 		well i guess that's about it
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it was nice okay it was nice talking to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		maybe we'll talk to you again
 		alright bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	