
 
     		
 	
 		okay uh you want to start by telling me what camping is to you do you backpack or hike or
 	
 	
 		well uh a little bit uh nothing nothing overly strenuous no the majority of my camping experience is uh a tent by the lake type situation or uh maybe a canoe trip or something like that
 	
 	
 		no i've never done a canoe trip that sounds interesting
 	
 	
 		oh it it's we've had a lot of fun uh i i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years ago</TIMEX>
 		and we've made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different trips since i've been here the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that i run around with of varying degrees uh of difficulty the
 		the last one we did and we haven't had a chance to duplicate was uh was a canoe trip in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> and the river was it was up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> feet so it was uh it was pretty it was pretty challenging
 	
 	
 		i imagine
 	
 	
 		but uh and then we uh as far as the camping part of that we just drag along all our tents and sleeping bags and uh find uh find a clearing in the woods and go for it
 	
 	
 		so they'll actually fit in the canoe and then you go for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> at a time
 	
 	
 		well yeah yeah it's the
 		that that particular one was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two day</TIMEX> trip so what uh uh there's uh there's a outfitter and uh they haul you up to the headwaters come down about halfway and then you get to you spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> and then uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second day</TIMEX> head on down to the to the pool at the end of the river
 	
 	
 		God that sounds like fun
 	
 	
 		yeah it it really is
 	
 	
 		well the camping i grew up with was like tents and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> stove type and uh
 		you know that just either out in the woods or actually i i grew up water skiing i was uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and so we would go up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> uh river sloughs the delta there
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and you just pick a campground on the river if it got you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a hundred and ten</NUMEX> degrees you went over the levee and jumped in the water
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		you know cooled off but uh when i got married my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had always backpacked and so we did that uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i guess that we haven't done it since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were born so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> and that was a new experience to me but i enjoyed it i like being able to go back up into the mountains or you know where the trail didn't necessarily lead and where you couldn't necessarily pitch a tent
 	
 	
 		boy i bet
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh that that was interesting i i have always wanted to do some white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> rafting and so your canoeing kind of made me think of that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that was uh that's always been our next step our our our little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> here we've we've been kind of getting married off and what not but uh that's
 	
 	
 		don't let that stop you
 	
 	
 		yeah that well it it it just puts a damper on things for a little while but we're we're starting to get everybody back together yeah we'd like to do a float trip down uh oh like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Big Bend</ENAMEX> area or something like that
 	
 	
 		i know
 		yeah so you haven't done that before
 	
 	
 		no no we haven't made that trip yet
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> uh were sailing uh this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> down off uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX>
 		and they took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks</TIMEX> and went into i don't even know the name of the river there but they went white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> rafting and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> said it was absolutely just a wonderful experience she said it was truly incredible
 	
 	
 		i'll bet yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know i there's that sense of it you know you're kind of scared that risk of like gosh what could happen and then the thrill of you know the excitement of doing it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		so
 		well do you have anything planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um not really just yet we've uh well i i do have uh a little bit of property i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and i've got a piece of property in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> that is completely undeveloped as of yet there's uh there's a little lake up there
 		and uh a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that i i went to college with um got together and we basically own all the land around this little lake there it's divided up into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> lots
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so we've got a private lake and it's completely undeveloped at this point so that's a possibility and the weather is typically always nice up there in the summertime it it's it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two hours</TIMEX> north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i imagine
 		oh that doesn't that sounds good
 	
 	
 		so uh yeah in fact uh uh well i got married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> and uh that's that's we ended up there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple days</TIMEX> uh on our honeymoon we kind of took uh a tour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for about a week
 	
 	
 		that sounds
 	
 	
 		and uh up through that area but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s real excited about it so we're uh we're going to hope to get up there sometime early enough <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of July</TIMEX> and it was a little too late for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> but uh hopefully get up there
 		early enough to to get into some of the some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and uh the the good weather and what not
 	
 	
 		we've been wanting to start camping again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> too uh my oldest
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago three and a half</TIMEX> and then i have a little one that just turned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and we are in the process of potty training i didn't want to go camping with diapers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh gosh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 		i and and you know at a time when they're afraid of their shadow all they need is you know some skunk or something to rub up the outside of the tent they'd be awake <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so but i think with him almost potty trained and
 		you know she's not afraid of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX> anymore that i'm i'm hoping and crossing my fingers that we'll be able to go uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> you know even if it's like over to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio Dosa</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> or something to get them used to it and get them started uh
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		with little back packs of their own and you know things like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		you bet yeah we'll that you know  and there's a lot of places with uh like nature trails things like that where they could learn a lot too
 	
 	
 		that's just
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's true
 	
 	
 		you know it's like okay this this is  this is what uh a pheasant looks like you know and okay now we'll go look for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and that kind of thing that
 	
 	
 		ugh i would need that before i could teach them
 	
 	
 		well  yeah that's everybody everybody might learn something that way but uh
 		but yeah that's there isn't there's an awful lot of things set up you know just any anything you want to do like like you say it can be uh
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> ski trip or uh fishing trip or just a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sightseeing bird</ENAMEX> watching you know hunt hunt with a camera type of thing or there's a lot of different opportunities for things like that it's a lot of fun it really is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	