
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so who's your uh favorite team
 	
 	
 		who do you think  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowgirls</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well  they did have a fairly decent year finally this year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at least they're coming around
 	
 	
 		yeah they're going to get better
 		i mean you know
 	
 	
 		well i mean you know i think uh once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX>
 		gets his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> established uh
 		they'll do all right
 	
 	
 		yeah as long as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy  Aikman</ENAMEX> doesn't get hurt again
 		that kind of killed them at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the season</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i don't i don't even know who your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is actually
 	
 	
 		i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		okay i think i did know that
 		i just forgot
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and they haven't been doing too hot so
 	
 	
 		yeah has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herschel Walker</ENAMEX> done much for them
 	
 	
 		no
 		in fact
 		in fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> got the best end of that deal
 	
 	
 		definitely well he was a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> i guess
 		i don't know he just never
 		i don't know for a while there he just
 	
 	
 		i've never been over impressed with him
 	
 	
 		well he could always get past you know he'd get past like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or seven</NUMEX> tackles and just keep spinning around and get on into the end zone
 		but um i guess you never could really see him play because with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> while he was with the team the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was pretty poor so you couldn't really tell if it was just him or the team
 		and i always just assumed he was too good for the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		well who's the running back is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Smith</ENAMEX> or is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmitt Smith Emmitt Smith</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmitt Smith</ENAMEX> yeah he's been doing real good
 		i'm pretty impressed with him so far did he did he actually play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pro Bowl</ENAMEX> i remember he was like a backup and then somebody got injured and he was supposed to go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		yeah i kind of i haven't been keeping up with football i mean in the fall i i can go on and on about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> but since it's kind of off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> it's kind of hard to think back about all that
 		but uh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh who else is uh
 		uh there's you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Lynn</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> he used to be the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> starting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Football League</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some uh
 		and that and he was trying to keep uh
 		uh
 		uh i can't even think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s name either the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i have no idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Jerry Burns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no earthly idea
 	
 	
 		going to keep  he was going to keep him as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> somehow
 		but uh
 		i don't know i'd like to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> get revamped somehow
 	
 	
 		how did they end up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> did they did they make it to the play-offs at all
 	
 	
 		well they started out really bad they went like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one and six</NUMEX> and then they won <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six</NUMEX> in a row
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they were in a shot to make the play-offs and they screwed up the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of</TIMEX> games
 	
 	
 		kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		yep
 		i guess you can
 	
 	
 		except i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> are on the upswing i don't know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just hadn't heard much about them lately
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinals</ENAMEX> were kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> in fact they were doing better than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboy Cowboys</ENAMEX> came on strong <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end of the season</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinals</ENAMEX>
 		got killed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinals</ENAMEX> i don't know  i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> probably have a a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> they just at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the season</TIMEX> the kind of got messed up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aikman</ENAMEX> getting hurt because uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laufenberg</ENAMEX> just couldn't never really get it together
 		at all of course he sat along the sidelines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all season</TIMEX> he never really got in a game never did a whole lot
 	
 	
 		oh don't make any excuses for him
 	
 	
 		well
 		i'm just saying i shouldn't i shouldn't blast him like that say oh well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laufenberg</ENAMEX> got out there and blew it for them i mean
 		he didn't get to see much action but it's too bad
 		because now now you know he had a shot and and didn't look too good and so no one is going to have much faith in him any more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in fact i think they're getting a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> for a backup <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> i haven't uh i haven't kept up with it lately but i remember reading something
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> about them signing somebody else on or or trying to go after somebody or trade for somebody but it wasn't anybody i'd really heard of
 		but i heard on the radio <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aikman</ENAMEX>'s back in practicing doing real real well um who is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Irvin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he said that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aikman</ENAMEX> was hitting him right on the numbers every time so sounds like he's going to be all right for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next season</TIMEX> they're just trying not to overwork him right now until he gets his shoulder
 		uh back in shape it was his shoulder wasn't it  that he had problems with
 	
 	
 		i don't know  yeah think it was
 	
 	
 		i think it i think it was his shoulder he had surgery on but anyway they're trying to keep him
 		you know keep him uh from reinjuring anything but
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		well i got my uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty day</TIMEX> notice yesterday
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty day</TIMEX> notice for what
 	
 	
 		um i'm done
 		where i work
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so
 		anyway i guess we can't talk much more about that but i just thought i'd throw that in there
 	
 	
 		what  oh okay  maybe i'll call you back after  after the recording is finished
 		actually i think we have talked about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> i i can't remember
 	
 	
 		oh we i've always ran out of time ever since i've done this
 	
 	
 		really i usually have too
 	
 	
 		they always say you've talked your <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minute</TIMEX> limit
 	
 	
 		yeah i've done that once or twice
 		i didn't look at the clock when we started talking so i guess we should talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> a little bit longer just to be sure we got <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> in
 	
 	
 		make sure we get our cash flow
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so other than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> who do you like
 	
 	
 		um
 		actually when i was younger i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cardinal fan</ENAMEX> too remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Hart</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Hart</ENAMEX> was playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Metcalf</ENAMEX> was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinals</ENAMEX> this was a long time ago
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't know who else i've ever
 		that's about it i was always a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> i think i was into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinals</ENAMEX> for a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		back when they were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		and yeah oh of course
 	
 	
 		since they've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> they haven't been uh
 		all that impressive i guess
 		i guess i've always been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cowboy fan</ENAMEX> other than that i mean you know when i've you know when you grow up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that has the you know one of the greatest football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> you kin d of tend to
 	
 	
 		yeah well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> there's no question about that so
 	
 	
 		get caught up in it
 		yeah
 		yeah i mean it it was really exciting growing up when when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> were really big because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would always have season tickets and they'd go to all the games and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know the hype were just unbelievable it's just you know the last oh i guess probably since <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eighty four</NUMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eighty five</NUMEX> was when they started kind of going downhill really but you know i'm just used to always growing up and hearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys Cowboys Cowboys</ENAMEX> and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> and all this other stuff so
 		i can't you know i'm not going to decide i don't like them just because they're having a few bad years i mean i think they'll pull out of it and you know they'll they'll wind up being good again they've got some lot of really good young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> that are going to
 		that are going to uh do pretty good i think
 		but they're raising prices on their tickets so they're banking on doing good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		again what are they going up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> bucks or something
 	
 	
 		i think tickets are yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thirty</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two</TIMEX> for really good tickets see they they sectioned it out even more they used to just have like uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all it was all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> price and then they sectioned it out to end zone and then everything else
 		and now they're sectioning it off to like from the
 		from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> yard line to the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> just on the lower levels is the highest price
 		and then the next highest price is that same area but above it on the upper level and then like from the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> yard line and then they're some sections kind of in the corner areas and then the cheapest of course is going to be the end the direct end zones
 		but um they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four or five</NUMEX> different prices now that they're structuring it with but obviously yeah they're all going up even more or less is what it's going to do
 	
 	
 		so now the tickets even got lower than the lowest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> last year
 	
 	
 		um you know i'm not sure i'm not positive i didn't
 		i didn't really think about that i just remember trying to figure out where you could get that was real close to the good section but in the little bit cheaper
 		but not that i'll ever go i hadn't been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> game last time last time i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> game was during that um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> strike or the when they had the scab team <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in there and it was the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Redskins</ENAMEX> game
 		and i went because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> can usually get a hold of some free tickets because a lot of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> have season tickets and they um
 		if they're not going to use them they'll give them to somebody else so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> i went with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> to a game that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time but that wasn't a real you know it was it was the scab <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> it was kind of
 		you know it was kind of different i guess and before that it's been quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> i've been wanting to go to a game i just never never have gotten around to it
 		so maybe this year
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX>  cheap cheaper i guess
 	
 	
 		that's interesting i almost lost our electricity here
 		
 		
 	