
 
     		
 	
 		okay i think we're supposed to discuss our view of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> as a continuing  threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> how do you feel about that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 		i don't really i more
 		i don't know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as much as um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh i wouldn't consider to be a threat at all
 		and i really don't feel much like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> itself is a threat anymore i'm i'm worried about them they're in a very uh
 		tumultuous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> right now with the kinds of uh adaptations that they're attempting to go through
 		so
 	
 	
 		i'm concerned about them not as a military threat but as a burden
 		they're very large
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they could become very quickly a large financial burden as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as one</NUMEX> more stepchild we have to carry around
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's that's a real important aspect and that uh as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the most the most</TIMEX> the most
 		let's see
 		the more that we do that we do or that we can do to help them become self sufficient is going to eliminate more of the risk
 		of that becoming a you know a reality  i know that uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last winter</TIMEX> was very hard on uh several areas in the in the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> particularly the coal mining regions
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Siberia</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there have money that's not their problem but there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for them to buy and its you can't eat money
 	
 	
 		and they have a a problem their their whole attitude um
 		i i'm not sure which crop it was but they had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX> that rotted in the fields because they couldn't get anyone to harvest it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> were saying well why should i go do that make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> do that that's not my job
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right they've got a lot of adjustments to make with coming out of what they've been through
 		now and um
 		they've been they've been under under the oppression that they've been under for so long that now they have some freedoms but they don't know how to act yet
 		they don't understand that to make that work they've got to take some responsibility for themselves it's not just the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s responsibility anymore
 		you can't just blame it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> when they give you the freedom to take care of yourself then that puts some responsibility on you as well
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		and and i think that they're having a hard time with the concept of you cannot go back <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> only go forward
 		and i think that that is giving them i'm expecting a call and unfortunately i think it's come through i've enjoyed talking to you thank you bye
 	
 	
 		okay all right bye-bye
 		
 		
 	