
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		yeah how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> what do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> girls
 	
 	
 		i have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s adopted
 	
 	
 		i have
 		uh-huh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and one boy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i got ahead of you there i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and one</NUMEX> on the way
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no but uh i know when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were growing up we did spend a lot of time together
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		uh school activities and my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> was in hockey
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> uh and and uh myself we rooted you know we didn't participate but we did a lot of family things together
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing and uh school activities type stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were involved in sports
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football and baseball</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whatever
 	
 	
 		did you find the time to attend
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah we did too
 	
 	
 		when they were growing up we did we were out in the middle of a desert out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ridgecrest California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that's kind of the key don't you
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i think that's kind of the key
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is to not be in the big city
 	
 	
 		yeah there wasn't a lot of other things for them to do
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh so when when they participated in sports or whatever well uh all nearly all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> went
 	
 	
 		and
 		yep we did that too and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> where um when in fact when my youngest was about two we decided to get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and go to the country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it's not as vast a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> as like you know where you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are from because i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abilene</ENAMEX> for a little while
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i know what nothing is when i moved out there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> itself is great but i mean you go in the in the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for a drive and you could see nothing for miles and miles and miles
 	
 	
 		we came back when they were teenagers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course uh then they came to the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> and that the time with them wasn't as much as it was when they were out there in the small
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> out in the middle of the desert
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but they at least they had the background
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the the home uh the family type unit you know and i think when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have that they don't  get into as much trouble or seek to
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know do other things that are really not good for them you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		gosh our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were fortunate they had good good other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to play with
 	
 	
 		yep same here
 	
 	
 		uh
 		maybe it's not like it is nowadays really when there's so much uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and everything else
 	
 	
 		no
 		no i know i'm so happy that i had mine had mine when i did and that i'm not having them now i think about it
 	
 	
 		yeah i would not want to raise a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> today
 	
 	
 		no no
 	
 	
 		from scratch you know from start
 	
 	
 		and plus i think that the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> both having to work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's not a matter of choice anymore i think most people
 	
 	
 		no it's a necessity
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's a
 	
 	
 		and uh it that takes so much time away from your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i well uh
 	
 	
 		of course at the at the time i worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">third</TIMEX> shift to be with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and then uh my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was with them at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so they were always with a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and babysitters and uh day care and all that stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't really bond anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s aren't there
 	
 	
 		well i i i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> that uh i don't know what young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just starting out nowadays especially if they have uh
 		have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> if if they're trying to buy a house both of them have to work in order to pay for a house
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yep
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> really spend more time at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or with a babysitter then they do with their parents
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		but you know uh i wonder by the time they get through paying out for all the day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and everything else is it really worth all that
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		rather than to wait until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are like in school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then go for that type of goal i think that too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want everything now
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i told
 	
 	
 		like we had to save and plan and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do without and that kind of stuff where it's now the credit cards and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean they just go and buy it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> nowadays they want to start out with a
 	
 	
 		exact
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> brick house
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		and when we started out well we started out in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and then rented a a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">duplex</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and then went from a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">duplex</ENAMEX> to a little old <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> frame house
 	
 	
 		that's my point and and i think that they should like learn how to crawl before they walk
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's too much it and it's too accessible
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they get into it and they're over their heads i think that's why there's so many divorces too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because the money becomes uh an issue the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> become an issue the jobs become an issue and it's like you know what's left
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just to argue and that type of thing you know
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i'm i'm i really feel for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> nowadays
 	
 	
 		i do i do
 	
 	
 		i i just don't uh see how
 	
 	
 		they're like between a rock and a hard spot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it really is awful i think maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> should do more with day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and that type of thing it might bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> closer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know because they're able to spend some time
 	
 	
 		yeah they brought that up at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i don't know how many times to to uh have a day care
 	
 	
 		at
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working mothers</ENAMEX> but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> never has seen fit to do it
 	
 	
 		no huh
 	
 	
 		but there are a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that do
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's great because i mean you know you you it's less guilt you feel knowing that you have to leave them everyday if you can go in and see them for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen minutes around a lunch hour</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just know they're close by
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it's it's very hard
 		well it was nice chatting with you
 	
 	
 		well do you work at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attleboro</ENAMEX> or does your or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes i do i do
 		no i do
 	
 	
 		oh you do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i work in uh building twelve in Attleboro
 	
 	
 		oh well of course i always see see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attleboro</ENAMEX> mission on teen news and everything else but
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		never been up there
 	
 	
 		oh you should come it's it's a it's a nice place in the summertime though don't come in the winter
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i started to say what what's the temperature up there now
 	
 	
 		right now we're in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we're expecting a snowstorm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		possibly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh me
 	
 	
 		so it's supposed to be real bad driving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well we're supposed to get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> but no  snow
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but we're we're in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> and seventies
 		in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's terrible
 		i'm jealous
 	
 	
 		we
 	
 	
 		no i it it's well this is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> where it's very unsettled because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> is like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between winter</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> out here it's like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one minute</TIMEX> you've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> weather <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next minute</TIMEX> you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> like weather everybody's got a cold
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you don't know how to dress you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's kind of tough
 		and they say that the driving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> is supposed to be really bad in the afternoon
 	
 	
 		well the colds and the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">flu</ENAMEX> have been going around down here
 	
 	
 		have they
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i'm telling you everybody's and i think it's really the weather it will it will get warm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and then not real cold but pretty cool <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> and then warm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's just uh plus there's been an awfully lot of uh
 		uh mountain cedar and everything else in the air
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and it's really driving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with sinuses crazy and
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and sore throats and colds and whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well uh i i can tell by your accent that you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> and you know i miss hearing that  they used to make fun of me because of being you know my accent
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they they try to get me to say things because they they thought i talked so funny
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but you sound just like um the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that i worked with up there the same type of voice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i remember i remember when i was out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ridgecrest</ENAMEX> somebody had a flat and uh i asked them i said do you have a tire tool in the in the trunk
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he said a what and i said a tire tool
 		he said you mean a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> tool and i said no a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T I R E</ENAMEX> tool
 	
 	
 		yeah right  like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>  or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>  that's true  well listen it was nice speaking with you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		nice talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irene</ENAMEX> and you stay warm up there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Jim</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		take care
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	