
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Morbidity Report</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Jim</ENAMEX>:

            I will graciously forgive your <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">obsessions</ENAMEX> if you will indulge me
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> media sport du jour--writing your own obituary.

            You see: things have been a little morbid over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearst</ENAMEX> announced the purchase of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> and put a "for sale" sign on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Examiner</ENAMEX> . By most accounts putting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examiner</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> is just a cynical move to assuage the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX>
before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearst</ENAMEX> closes the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> and turns the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-daily <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Housekeeping et al.</ENAMEX> takeover of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> and the
presumed sickness-unto-death of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examiner</ENAMEX> has touched off an orgy of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retrospectives</ENAMEX> in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, complete with fond remembrances of the way
things were in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the good old days</TIMEX>. (Rest in peace, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Caen</ENAMEX>, sniff.)

            In the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Examiner</ENAMEX> , it's weirdly uncomfortable to read its
coverage, sort of like listening to an elderly relative talk obsessively about
his own imminent death.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> is relegated to Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A2</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> , while a story about "pruneburgers"--those would be your basic
hamburgers with prunes on top--being tried out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> high school
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cafeterias</ENAMEX> gets Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> treatment. It's complete with quotes from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
prune-industry trade group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exalting</ENAMEX>, "In our taste test, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> really
liked them." You don't say? This is the other not-on-the-Web pleasure of
reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> in the dead-tree format: seeing just how strongly the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> feel that fibrous school lunch menu innovations, as promoted by local
industry, clearly rank above the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">25th</NUMEX> anniversary of the resignation
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> among their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>' concerns.)

            All this grim <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">navel-gazing</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> (not to mention all that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fiber</ENAMEX>) is enough to make a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> reach <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> for the New York
Times on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> only to discover that her own profession is in
decline. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, I regret to inform you that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> ain't what they use to be,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Kuczynski</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">At Magazines, the Art of Stirring Debates Seems</ENAMEX>
Lost." The Internet is predictably trotted out as one of the myriad of causes
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glossies</ENAMEX>' decline. Ironic for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us, since as magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>,
we both cover the Web.

            Overall, it's a nicely argued and sourced piece, but it makes me wonder: Is
it worse to be a magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> have lost clout or a newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who writes about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> have lost clout?

            It's enough to make you want to write your own obituary and go back to
bed.

            Navel-gazingly yours,
Katharine

            P.S.: Just so you know who you're dealing with, I'll admit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>: I
never read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , although I am a fan of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Grok</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
