
   
   
      
         
            No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good News</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>'s
investigation of the massacre in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The current death toll is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10,000 and</NUMEX>
growing. Mounting evidence suggests that the massacre was premeditated and
centrally orchestrated. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> believes it has obtained the
written blueprint for the campaign. Allegedly drafted by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslav</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX>, the
plan, code-named "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Operation Horseshoe</ENAMEX>," was reportedly approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> even before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> peace talks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rambouillet</ENAMEX> fell through. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
fronts a different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> story--the area's worsening housing shortage. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> probably won't meet its goal of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> warm, dry room for every
family by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>, but it is doubtful that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> will freeze to
death.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s decision to dispatch federal officials
to all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to determine whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have improperly excluded people
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, and to investigate the surprising underutilization of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Insurance Program</ENAMEX>. Only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have been
enrolled since the program's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1997</ENAMEX> debut (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> expected at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 million</NUMEX>
enrollees by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>) and there are still around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> without
health insurance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes local with a report that neither
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> have come up with a workable solution to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">northern Virginia</ENAMEX>'s traffic problems, a key issue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s upcoming
legislative elections.

            The LAT fronts and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> stuff the assault by
Chechen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunmen</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> in neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dagestan</ENAMEX>. As the LAT
went to press, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">estimated 300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attackers</ENAMEX> held <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunships</ENAMEX> were dispatched to fire on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attackers</ENAMEX>. It is believed that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assailants</ENAMEX> are militants of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Wahhabi</ENAMEX> sect seeking to unite
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dagestan</ENAMEX> to form an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. The incident could
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">provoke Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> to impose emergency rule, with potentially serious

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also fronts the claims of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saudi Arabian Intelligence</ENAMEX>'s chief
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> were negotiating the arrest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taliban</ENAMEX> militia shortly before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s bombings of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>. The paper hints that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s arrest might
have prevented the bombings, but the deal dissolved after the attacks and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
retaliation.

            The WP front describes a suit filed against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX>
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paducah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ky.</ENAMEX>, nuclear processing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. The government-owned
plant unwittingly exposed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and the environment to small amounts of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plutonium</ENAMEX>, and greatly underestimated the health risks posed by exposure to
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anecdote</ENAMEX> describes plant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> who would salt their lunchtime
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uranium</ENAMEX> dust to prove to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> that it was harmless. The
suit alleges that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> were misled about their risk of exposure well into
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>. Cleanup of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$240 billion</NUMEX> and take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75 years</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front ponders the fate of aging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> militants
operating out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>. As peace with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> grows more likely, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> may not
be the haven for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> it once was. Many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> have long since given up arms for political activism, but some, such as
still skirmish with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> forbids such
actions on its own soil). If peace does come, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> will probably shut down
training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> and officially discourage violence against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>. They probably
won't actually expel <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> (many of whom are wanted as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>), because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> still wishes to be seen as sympathetic to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> national cause.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front notes that black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are still <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times as likely
as white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to die in childbirth, a statistic that hasn't changed since the
'60s. Though the number of maternal deaths during childbirth is small (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">327</ENAMEX>
nationwide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Surgeon General Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Thatcher</ENAMEX> maintains that the
persistent disparity is cause for concern. Not only are black women
statistically more susceptible to conditions (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hypertension</ENAMEX>) that create
complications in pregnancy, they also tend to seek medical attention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> and
only after more serious complications, further increasing their risk of
fatality. Attempts to address the issue are uniting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> across party
and ideological lines, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has set <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX> as the
target date for eliminating racial disparities in health care.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Trojan Cow</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bovine</ENAMEX> intervention threatens to further dampen
relations between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and South Korea</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that last year
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyundai</ENAMEX> donated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cattle</ENAMEX> to famine-stricken <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX> as a gesture of goodwill. Since then, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">herd</ENAMEX> has perished under
mysterious circumstances. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say autopsies
revealed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vinyl sheeting</ENAMEX>, magnets, large nails, and the like in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stomachs</ENAMEX>, and call the gift "a despicable trick in a bid to hinder and
frustrate nongovernmental cooperation between the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North and South</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> denied any wrongdoing. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Papers dismisses the
allegations as udderly ridiculous.

         
      
   
