
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair Witch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lessons for Hollywood</ENAMEX>
            

            When, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its third week</TIMEX> of release, indie sensation The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX>
Project took in an incredible <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$28.5 million</NUMEX> at the box office and set a
record for the largest per-screen gross in motion-picture history, the major
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> responded by commissioning studies to explain to them why this
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> film was crushing all their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million-dollar</NUMEX> spectaculars. Let's
hope that at the top of their list, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> of these studies say: "Lesson
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> was a really good movie."

            I'm exaggerating, of course. Quality alone isn't enough to propel a film to
great box-office heights, as the recent failures of Out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sight</ENAMEX> and
Rushmore demonstrate. But in the hubbub about the marketing of The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair Witch Project</ENAMEX> , which has been tremendous, it's important to keep in
mind that there really is no simple formula by which hits happen, and that
attempts to reduce popular success to that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">formula</ENAMEX> are bound to lead
you astray. In this, as in so much else, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> at the
beginning of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>: ceaselessly preparing to fight the last war, and
always getting blindsided by the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            What we can see in the endless analyses of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX>'s success is
how malleable the supposed truths of marketing and distribution are. For
instance, the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> trend in distribution in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> has been
the mega-opening, so that films like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild, Wild</ENAMEX>
West each opened on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 3,000</NUMEX> screens. It was the rare multiplex that
didn't have these movies playing on multiple screens, and these movies were
supported with multimedia marketing campaigns that drilled themselves into your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oversaturation</ENAMEX> has its perils, of course, but part of the thinking here
is that the massive opening guarantees an impressive <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> gross (even
if not necessarily an impressive per-screen performance) and that it allows
films with sketchy word of mouth to make a lot of money off the initial buzz.
Add to that the idea that a massive opening is a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> event in itself,
and you've got an argument for ensuring that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> won't be able to go
anywhere without thinking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> , by contrast, had a strictly limited release, playing to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX>-out crowds in big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first week</TIMEX>, opening at a few more select
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">theaters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its second week</TIMEX>, and expanding to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just 1,100</NUMEX> screens in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>.
That release schedule helped build the buzz for the movie, made it seem like
the hot ticket to get (call it the "I'll only go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> if there are a lot
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can't get in" principle), and ensured that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX>
didn't overreach themselves in terms of their advertising. Now this kind of
slow build-up seems like the smart strategy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Instinctively</ENAMEX>, the path <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> trod does seem to make more
sense. Though surprisingly few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in marketing will admit this, hits are
rarely made. They're almost always genuine bottoms-up phenomena. (Just go back
and look at the advance buzz on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> to see how the massive success
of that film came completely out of left field.) And catering to that
grassroots mentality by allowing word of mouth to do its work can be an
excellent approach, especially when you combine it with a brilliant use of the
Internet, which is the finest tool for word-of-mouth ever created.

            And yet it's worth remembering that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX> , which was the
anti- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> in its marketing, was a huge hit. And if <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild, Wild</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West</ENAMEX> hadn't opened the way it did, I doubt it would have made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX>.
Giving that film time to build would not have worked.

            The banal point is that marketing and distribution campaigns really do need
to be specific to the films they're intended to promote. The more complicated
point is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> need to recognize just how much of what happens to their
films is out of their control. Which means that instead of building the Maginot
Line of marketing, they should worry about the stuff that is in their control:
salaries, overhead, and quality. Remember what happens when you build a better
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mousetrap</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
