
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Front Page</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX> Page
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Katharine</ENAMEX>,

            I don't know anything about your reading habits, but these days a lot of my
newspaper consumption is online. There are a number of reasons for this: a
nomadic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> life over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last year</TIMEX>, which left me without a reliable
physical address; contributing to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Grok</ENAMEX>," an e-mail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX> that
thrives on Web links; and the sheer amount of time I spend staring at my laptop
screen. Although I find the convenience of online newspapers compelling, I'm
also <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to acknowledge that there are things you miss when not touching the
actual pulp.

            Take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . Like most political mammals, I am drawn
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Clymer</ENAMEX>'s front-page story on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">25th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s
resignation. The piece itself is tame and perfunctory, but when you open the
paper to Page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A12</TIMEX> where it continues, your eye travels immediately to the
continuation of another front-page story headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">G.O.P. Asking Top Donors To</ENAMEX>
Contribute <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 Million</NUMEX>." Forgive me, but if you've listened to those famous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX> tapes, you can't help but hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s voice echoing on how to get a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> of hush money to the plumbers: "We could get that." I love that
both stories end up, as it were, on the same page.

            One could slyly infer from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the A12</TIMEX> juxtaposition that with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> seeking
all top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> apiece, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>-style abuses will
inevitably reoccur. A facile assumption of the left? Sure. But at least that
would counter the right's facile assumption that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s crimes were not
substantially different from those of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, the tack taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frum</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX> commentary <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>.

            My fascination here is not that one must take any particular meaning from
the play of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stories, but that, as with a work of art, one can. The
"jump" of front-page news stories is a necessity borne of spatial limitation,
which the Web theoretically does not have. But working around those
limitations--and indeed manipulating them for narrative advantage--is one of
the great moments of the newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline</ENAMEX> writing in a narrow space
is another.)

            On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> --which I'm reading today
online--displays one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s great counterstrengths. You can click on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s front page and get a reproduction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>'s front-page
coverage from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 9, 1974</TIMEX>: the Web as microfiche. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> spoils the
effect somewhat: by calling its project immodestly "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>," and running only excerpts of the original front-page stories. Still,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> in me applauds the widespread availability of primary documents,
and the media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> in me notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> has no interest
in calling attention to the way that it covered (or rather didn't cover) the
Watergate saga.

            Sorry for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">obsessions</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
