
   
   
      
         
            How Strong Is the Case Against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>?
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Late last month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> indicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> for recording a
phone conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> without her permission on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 22</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. How strong is their case?

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> has said she will plead not guilty, it is almost certain that
she technically broke the law. She began recording her conversations with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, she says, for her own protection--she felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
wanted her to lie about her encounter with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> in testimony for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 24</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s then<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-lawyer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> with ties to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, told her that such recordings were illegal and ordered her to
stop. Because the state requires that you know about the wiretapping law in
order to break it, she was still in the clear at that point.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> suspected that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> were going to deny their own
relationship in their testimony in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case--which would conflict with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s planned testimony that they were involved. So on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 22</TIMEX> she
deliberately recorded a conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The following month</TIMEX> she
called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and handed over the tapes. She also played the
tapes for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> allowed her to continue taping
and eventually gave her immunity from federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> also got a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s defense relies on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major points:

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) She alleges that her indictment is a political vendetta. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>
is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> reportedly
encouraged his investigation. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> has never before enforced the
law. On the other hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say that this is the clearest-cut
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wiretapping</ENAMEX> case they have seen.

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> will also argue that because her tapes were subpoenaed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>,
their use in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> case violates her <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth Amendment</ENAMEX> protection from
self-incrimination. However, the indictment claims that it was illegal for her
to play the tapes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> will argue that her federal immunity deal protects her
from state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">prosecution</ENAMEX>.

            Next question?

         
      
   
