
   
   
      
         
            Our Race <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can Kick Your Race</ENAMEX>'s Ass
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>,

            I'm sorry you find so little promise or fascination in the nascent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, you said the same about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. Who
does interest you?). I disagree. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s a far more complex and
appealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> than your caricature indicates. And I guess we don't know the
same liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> are completely fired up about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s
run. So please refrain from inviting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
Springer, or anyone else into our race.

            Back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> you remarked on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Appelbome</ENAMEX>'s warmly
honest obituary for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Morris</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> I want to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Apple</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lovely</ENAMEX> goodbye to the cookbook <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Olney</ENAMEX>. I never thought an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obituary</ENAMEX> could make me hungry. But this one does, by describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olney</ENAMEX>'s
favorite dishes, most memorable meals, and culinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX>. The accompanying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photo</ENAMEX> is just as striking and informal: It depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dishcloth</ENAMEX> tucked into
the waistband of his jeans, shelling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peas</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Provence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>.

            In contrast, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deaths"</ENAMEX> column--that is, the brief announcements placed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the less-famous deceased--is depressingly uniform and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">impersonal</ENAMEX>. (These announcements aren't printed in the national edition of the
Times . But every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>--except the one you write for--has its own
space for local deaths.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s all read the same way: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surname</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name.
Cherished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. Deeply saddened ... heartfelt sympathies ...
sincerest condolences." None mention a single personal characteristic of the
deceased.

            I wonder how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> would have reacted if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olney</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had
submitted an announcement as personal as his obituary. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olney</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>. Adored
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Waters</ENAMEX>. Lived next to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">grape arbor</ENAMEX>. Devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> of garlicky
chicken and supple mashed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>. Survived by his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> books on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>."
Do you think they would have taken it?

            Write soon,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jodi</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
