
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poetics of Traffic Jams</ENAMEX>
            

            I loved the traffic story: for its winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thermodynamics</ENAMEX>" and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>"), its clear explication of competing
scientific theories, and the satisfaction of knowing that our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s best
physicists are even more annoyed by traffic than are the rest of us.

            I noticed that the story didn't use the word "sprawl." It didn't reference
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s "livability agenda" for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> election or quote any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
decrying the pernicious social effect of traffic. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sipress</ENAMEX> did call the Eastern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">seaboard 'sprawling</ENAMEX>,' but that's it). Instead, the story was nicely focused on
local trouble spots such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Capital Beltway</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodrow Wilson Bridge</ENAMEX>.
I wonder if this indicates that sprawl has ebbed back into the realm of the
regional, or just that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sipress</ENAMEX> was so annoyed by all the rhetoric that he left
it out of his piece.

            Speaking of local issues, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbagger</ENAMEX> issue rankles me, too, but for
different reasons. I keep hearing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> described as transient drifters
whose own roots are so ephemeral that we are willing to let any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> rent
a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and represent us. As someone who's lived in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
boroughs, whose family (on both sides) has lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> since arriving in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, and who worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of New York</ENAMEX>, I am offended. This is partly
because my local pride has been injured, but also because I think that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>--with its size, diversity, abundant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, crumbling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, huge
infrastructure, and so on--has local needs that are just as (if not more)
particular as any other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. And even if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s
denizens are more transitory than the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
State are not. So even if we elect an adopted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> rather than a homegrown
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, it won't be because we lack a sense of place.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> you warned me not to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> you with radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> who chide <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
for capitalizing on her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s fame and power. Yet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you wrote that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> owes her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> solely to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s political career." Yes, she
does--just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kennedy</ENAMEX> once owed theirs only
to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> can create political careers based on the successes
of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX>, why can't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> do so based on those of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>? If
you're going to prevent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> political dynasty from being created, you're going
to have to topple them all.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>, our correspondence is drawing to a close. Thank you so much for
sharing your breakfast thoughts, especially with someone with far fewer years
of newspaper-reading (and writing!) under her belt.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cheers,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jodi</ENAMEX>

            P.S.: I never responded to the wager you made with me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazio</ENAMEX> wins the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX> race, I'll buy you a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> of
your choice.

         
      
   
