
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> Epoch
            

            It's hard to imagine, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, but when The Coming of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Industrial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> was first published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, much of the controversy it generated
arose from the threat it seemed to present to scientific Marxism. How dare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>
suggest that there might be an interim "post-industrial" stage between the
twilight of monopoly capitalism and the dawn of socialism! You are right that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> is not "in vogue" at the moment, although there are some
soi-disant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> stirring in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX>. I do not know of
any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">ist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guerrillas</ENAMEX> anywhere, except perhaps at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>.

            You are, of course, bang right about stock options muddying the old
dichotomy between the capitalist and working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>--although some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
told me that they can feel quite proletarian when their options are under
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.

            Before delving back into this slag-heap of a book for additional nuggets,
let me take a breather and say a few more words about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            

               He marks himself off from his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> by describing
himself as "a social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">democrat</ENAMEX> in economics, a liberal in politics, and a
conservative in culture."

               In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid '60s</TIMEX>, he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irving Kristol</ENAMEX> founded the policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Interest</ENAMEX> , arguing that, with the end of ideology, the ladder to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of Heaven must be an "empirical <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>," based on hardheaded
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">problem-solving</ENAMEX>.

               Nonetheless, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> refused to be lumped with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irving Kristol</ENAMEX> and
the neocons, saying, "Whenever I read about neoconservatism, I think, 'That
isn't neoconservatism; it's just <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irving</ENAMEX>.' "

               Although it is not always apparent in his writing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> can be witty,
sometimes wickedly so. About his late brother-in-law, the loveable but
notoriously irascible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Kazin</ENAMEX>, he once remarked, "We're all human, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred</ENAMEX> abuses the privilege."

               An index of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s stature abroad: An international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> has just honored
him with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prix Tocqueville</ENAMEX>, which carries a cash award of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">francs</ENAMEX>. Previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Aron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Popper</ENAMEX>, and Octavio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paz</ENAMEX>.

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yiddish</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">language</ENAMEX> as he grew up on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower East</ENAMEX>
Side. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> changed the family name from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bolotsky</ENAMEX>" to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX>."

            

            Now back to the book. The more I think about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s farsightedness, the less
impressed I am by it. Most of the trends he wrote about were well established
by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '70s</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> had already become the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in the
world in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> had come to dominate manufacturing (both in employment
and as a share of GNP). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computerization</ENAMEX> had been under way for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades</TIMEX>.
Information technology had been playing an increasing role in industrial
production since after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX>, when the field of "operations
research" (inventory control, etc.) was invented to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> miliary
manage its massive war effort. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> peers into the future, toward the year
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, his forecasts are often the opposite of what has proved to be the case.
For instance, he predicted that more and more public outcomes would be
determined by government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technocrats</ENAMEX> rather than the market (the way things
are, say, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>). That has not happened--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>, for instance, health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, which, after the political fiasco of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s abortive reform,
is increasingly being governed by insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>.

            So what is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s achievement in this book? He was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to identify the
structural changes in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society that led to the "information age." He
dreamed up a conceptual scheme, full of ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> and whatnot, that tied
everything together. I don't think that conceptual scheme has a whole lot of
explanatory or predictive value--the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>'s would if only it were true--but
at least it has helped us to see the post-industrial society steadily and
whole, and as something qualitatively different from the industrial society
that it superseded. By naming the thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> ushered it into existence. Thanks
to him, we see it as obvious, a cliché.

            One thing still bothers me, though. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> often writes about information as
though it is something we consume directly, something that makes us happy. In
fact, our "utility functions," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> call them, have not really
changed. The final goods from which we <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">derive</ENAMEX> satisfaction are food and
manufactured objects--the products of agricultural and industrial society.
Information has transformed the mode of production, rationalized it, made
production and markets more efficient, and so on. But the information
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolution</ENAMEX> has not changed the nature of the good life. Or has it, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
