
   
   
      
         
            Talked Out
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>:

            Inspired by your accolades, I am going to tell the truth. I was wrong last
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. I hunkered down with Talk only to find it ... bloated and oddly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uncompelling</ENAMEX>.

            Not all of it. I enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Bowden</ENAMEX>'s account of the perils of being a
young female factory <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, safari guide <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Ross</ENAMEX>' harrowing if
sentimentally written account of his kidnapping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>, and
much of the front-of-the-book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Conversation</ENAMEX>" section. But other features seemed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretentious</ENAMEX> and empty, like a photo spread of male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and their ponderous
quotations. "Celebrity is the pox of success," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX> as he gives
the camera his trademark weary stare. Some others have been amply reported
elsewhere--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX>'s piece on the emasculation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNSCOM</ENAMEX> is his own
telling of material that's appeared in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> , and the Wall 
               Street

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> got to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lorna Wendt</ENAMEX> way before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mimi Swartz</ENAMEX> did
(she does, however, have the good grace to acknowledge it). And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s
attempt at edginess seems desperate and strained. I've already seen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a million</NUMEX>
cheesecake photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Barrymore</ENAMEX>, and despite the
dictates of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Talk's "Hip List</ENAMEX>," I am not prepared to believe that scabby
knees are cool.

            In her editorial message, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> writes that she chose the name
Talk because of its "unpretentious brevity." But this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>, with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13</TIMEX> feature stories, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> front-of-the-book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Conversation</ENAMEX>" items
(many of which are almost feature-length), plus fashion spreads, celeb pics,
book reviews, an astrology page, and more. This doesn't feel like editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bounty</ENAMEX>--it's as if Talk is throwing everything to the wall to see what
sticks. I kept looking for a unifying sensibility, for flashes of brilliant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina-osity</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX>'s sumptuous glamour or the The
New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX>'s pensiveness or wit. I also didn't find a single phrase
to stop and admire--or even one that carried the metaphorical oomph of that
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">terrific milk</ENAMEX>-carton quote you found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise</ENAMEX> of you not to take my bet about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> profile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>.
You wouldn't have won. The piece contained no new revelations at all-- unless
we counted the news that, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Northern Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX>, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> is responsible for the region's recent economic boom.

            Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Klain</ENAMEX> and his stellar sense of wordplay. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has
consistently been printing dishy, embarrassing quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>-niks about the
campaign's weaknesses (landmarks in this <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s worries
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the veep</TIMEX>'s electability and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Squier</ENAMEX>'s railings against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carter Eskew</ENAMEX>).
And now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>, clearly upset at his departure, have blurted out a goodbye
speech. This strikes me as just as much a testament to the campaign's poor
morale and weak <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> as it is to the skill of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seelye</ENAMEX>.
Hasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Coelho</ENAMEX> told everyone to keep their mouths shut? What are we going
to hear next? I worked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and no
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> spoke to the press. The policy was overly suspicious and vituperative,
but it also cultivated a sense of common purpose and team loyalty. Even though
I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> now, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> in me wants to hush the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blatherers</ENAMEX>.

            No more stabs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>. Let's keep talking about money and risk--and let's
agree not to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Barton</ENAMEX> represent the perils of the Internet economy. I
enjoyed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> story quite a bit more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s. With
(smile) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> quibble. The piece argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are newly eager to embrace
risk, and compares risky career moves and aggressive investing to " 'hard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX>' travel, where risk-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seekers</ENAMEX> hack through jungles with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machetes</ENAMEX> or
scale the world's highest mountains." Is this really all part of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trend</ENAMEX>?
I'd give you my thoughts now, but then we'd never eat lunch ...

            Talk soon,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jodi</ENAMEX>

            P.S.: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Papir</ENAMEX>, one of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">helpfully</ENAMEX> told me that after losing
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $4 million</NUMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> crash, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Kane</ENAMEX> killed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynch</ENAMEX> office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and seriously injured a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockbroker</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
