
   
   
      
         
            Off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jim</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Bell</ENAMEX> spends such an extended amount of time writing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>, that
it's hard to discuss this book without making reference to Marxism. Perhaps in
some trendy way--much as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX> revived <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che Guevara</ENAMEX> with a swoosh instead of a
star on his beret--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> will be back in vogue sometime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '00s</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hip-hop</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">information</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> will discourse on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road Rules</ENAMEX> .
We'll have a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> analysis of banner-ad "click throughs," and tomes on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">five-year</ENAMEX> plan for the collectivization of Windows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.

            I find it difficult to discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, because it's so hard to make
sense of him in the context of our time. Let's take a look at some of the more
super-capitalist <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>: the use of stock options to "incentivize" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, like, err, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> for instance, get vested with
options (convertible to stock), or get to buy stock at a discounted rate
(typically <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>'s market price), it's hard to say where the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist class</ENAMEX>" ends and the "proletariat" begins. The tension between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">haves</ENAMEX> and the have-nots is supposed to destabilize the system, leading to--in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>'s view--a revolution of the proletariat. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> examines this question, but
phrases it in terms of "envy," writing, "Democracy is by nature contentious
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> constantly covet what other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have ... the result is often--in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nietzsche</ENAMEX>'s term--ressentiment or envy, anger, and hatred towards those
at the top." What then to make of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>'s recent cover story, with a
tag line (paraphrasing) "Everyone is getting rich, except for me!" accompanying
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>-esque caricature of a 1950s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> with furrowed
brow?

            The cover--a reference to the omnipresent Internet/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> slow-mo capitalist
money shot that's lasted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>--doesn't hint at any sort of destabilizing
class conflict, but rather phrases it in terms of envy alone. There's always
someone else with a better package. By turning the stock market into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
national lottery, everyone gets a chance to become a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX>. Our
gonzo day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, high on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starbucks</ENAMEX> double lattes and monitor afterburn, are
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. With <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of them estimated to lose money,
extending their margin calls on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> bills, they're modern-day
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sharecroppers</ENAMEX> of a sort, indebted to the dot-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">com company store</ENAMEX> known as an
online brokerage. In this kind of environment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s analysis seems off in the
wrong side of the woods. As you point out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> is really a reformed
old-school lefty. As far as I can tell, the main element of his vision that's
come to pass is his rather abstract statement that "Now reality is primarily
the social world."

            He also wrote, "The post-industrial society is essentially a game between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>." (There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kaczynski</ENAMEX> quality to his writing--earnest,
structurally obsessive and plodding.)

            I take this to mean that our media-matrix--TV, radio, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX>, and
magazines--have come to form our reality. And this media world, obsessed with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrity</ENAMEX>, famous "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>," and the game between them, does form the shared
experience as a society. This aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s thinking isn't developed much in
his book. Another aspect of our future that he mentions, but fails to really
investigate, is his criticism of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>" ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>," hippies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, etc.) and
his sense that a cultural fissure is appearing between young and old. Where he
sees these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> as destabilizing and misguided, we've come to understand
them as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">modern-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribalism</ENAMEX>--what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX> like to call "affinity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>."
But from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s perspective, affirmative action, demands for quotas, and
automatic inclusion of minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in democratic decisions through mandates
are his red flags. He imagines a future where the call of every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inclusion</ENAMEX>, by quota, destroys the meritocratic principle of his favored
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">scientist-citizenry.</ENAMEX> The problem with revisiting this book is that so many of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s bugaboos from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> don't exist anymore. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan-Bush</ENAMEX> plus
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> took care of that, along with the longest peacetime economic
expansion in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history.

            So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, what's the takeaway from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> that you're left with? Any gems in
this coal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
