
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Quiet Revenge of Vile Food</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Chris</ENAMEX>,

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fourteen</NUMEX> volumes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosalynn Carter</ENAMEX>! Now there's a dreadful thought! Which
reminds me to say, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>'s behalf, that she is at the very least extremely
interesting. In general, the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> journalism bores me to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tears</ENAMEX>, and I think <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>'s tenure misled subsequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> into thinking that the firstladyship, or whatever you call it, would
go on being a noteworthy role. The truth is that almost all writing about first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ladies</ENAMEX> chews more than it bites off--including, I think, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine-tenths</NUMEX> of the ink
we've all spilled over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRC</ENAMEX>.

            Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> is obviously something of a freak in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and
age--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who is famous chiefly for being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>; and in most cases, a woman
whose life has been hideously warped by the fact that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> chose a career
in politics. Such a life has very little to offer other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the way of
exemplary lessons, and we're right to feel a bit queasy over a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> who
promises (or threatens) to accomplish anything very substantive on the strength
of who she's sleeping with. (Note: The major exception to the boredom rule was
the revelation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX>'s all-powerful astrologist. Now there was
a good story.)

            But thanks for taking me up on that question of how first <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> have
sometimes served their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> as useful camouflage. You chose great examples
of the benign and malign forms of this phenomenon, in citing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tag-team</ENAMEX> response to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bonus Marchers and ER</ENAMEX>'s later cover for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>'s neglect
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. I agree that the problem isn't gender stereotyping; it's the
sleight-of-hand the arrangement encourages. This used to drive me crazy about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, when everyone was writing mistily about how deeply "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bar</ENAMEX>"
cared about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> Start funding, and how she was secretly pro-abortion-rights,
and how, in effect, she represented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s moderate domestic-policy impulses.
He seemed, over time, not to bother having much of a domestic policy himself,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX> was a huge part of the cover. None of this is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>'s fault , as
you say, but to some degree it is her doing. All you've got to say to promote
the power-behind-the-throne theme (as either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observer</ENAMEX>) is,
Why, look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX>. Surely this is why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> was communing
in the solarium with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>'s spirit. (An interesting question to consider is
whether this legacy is more useful to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>--who can use it, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> did,
to mediate their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>' ambivalence toward government action--than it is
to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. Don't you suspect that, when push comes to shove, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s "compassionate conservatism" is going to consist, in very large part, of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Bush</ENAMEX>?)

            I'm with you on being mystified about why <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hick thought ER</ENAMEX> might leave her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>; I do think it's a symptom of the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s focus on the marriage
sort of wavers in this volume. However, I can't let our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> of discussion
pass without praising <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> for one of her neatest insights into <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> and her
marriage--concerning the passive-aggressive behavior by which she punished
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> and others. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> apparently avoided confrontation, but kept <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> nasty
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>, who snapped at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>; the larger of them actually bit
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. And when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roosevelts</ENAMEX> moved into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX> carefully employed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housekeeper</ENAMEX> the dreadful,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inexperienced Henrietta Nesbitt</ENAMEX>, who barked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and sneered at
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dignitaries</ENAMEX> and made sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> served the worst food in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>, properly chastened, had to flee to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde Park</ENAMEX> to eat the good
food he loved. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shades</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> banning smoking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>?)

            I liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX> for giving <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Eleanor's Revenge</ENAMEX> a nice fat chapter near the start
of this volume. But I fault her for not quoting the best thing I've read on
this subject, a passage I came upon in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Alsop</ENAMEX>'s centenary memoir of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX>.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drink</ENAMEX>, being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, was not actively repellent,"
wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alsop</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>!

            
               The salads were especially deplorable; for they tended to be
complicated and decorative, and might even conceal bits of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marshmallow</ENAMEX> in their
dreadful depth ... What [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nesbitt</ENAMEX>] perpetrated was only part of the story,
moreover. Scrambled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> are not an easy dish to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> in such a way that hungry
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> turn away in discouragement, yet the scrambled eggs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Roosevelt</ENAMEX>
always made in a chafing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> supper were undeniably
discouraging.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor</ENAMEX>, he wrote:

            
               was never against quiet revenges with a moral excuse. She equated
plain living with high thinking, so it was moral to eat badly. And if her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> did not like eating badly, why there were passages in their joint past
she had not liked either.
            

            Reading this did make me wish, in hindsight, that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biographer</ENAMEX> were a
little less admiringly sober. Now that I've said my piece on behalf of the New
Deal, I can admit to having found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>'s prose clear and readable but not
especially memorable. I guess there's not much hope that she can kick up her
heels a bit in Volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX>, what with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> just over the horizon.

            But when that next book does hit the shelves, I'll pick it up and remember
this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> with pleasure.

            All best,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Marjorie</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
