
   
   
      
         
            Can a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Magazine Survive</ENAMEX>?
            

            The predicted demise of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> and the launch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s Talk raise the question: What are a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s chances for
survival?

            If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is intended to reach a broad, general-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, the
answer is: not good. The total number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> published in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> has actually soared <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">from 2,500</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,500</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. But this is
entirely due to special-interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> with names like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Asthmatic Day</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trader</ENAMEX> (imaginary) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart Living</ENAMEX> (real). Even here the
odds are against a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newcomer</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 1,000</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> were launched in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> have already folded--most after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> issue. In general, only
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> make it to their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
anniversaries.

            Among general interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newcomer</ENAMEX> to survive and thrive is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> . ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">InStyle and Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> , both published by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time Warner</ENAMEX>, might also qualify, depending on
your definition of "general interest.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Condé Nast</ENAMEX> is privately owned, so
actual financial data are not available. But it is widely assumed that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , though making money now, is far from recouping its early
losses. Even ultimately successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> and many millions
before reaching profitability. Unsuccessful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> spend the money and never
become profitable. How much money? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>'s start-up costs were said to
be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX>. Rumors about the cost of launching Talk range <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $50</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>.

            Why? Partly for the same sorts of reasons that any new business must spend
money before it starts coming in--hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, stocking up on yellow
notepads, throwing a launch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, etc.--but mainly because of the cost of
acquiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>. You mail out masses of subscription offers (i.e., junk
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mail</ENAMEX>) and are happy with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent to 2 percent</NUMEX> response. It can easily cost
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> or more for a glossy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> to acquire a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> who pays <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. Then you are thrilled if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of those renew at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of a year</TIMEX>.

            Even an unsuccessful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> can have a large circulation if it is willing
to pay enough for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX> comes when you have a high renewal rate
and new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> are easy to entice to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dropouts</ENAMEX>. Then your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subscriber</ENAMEX>-acquisition costs plummet. Even so, the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> may cost
more to acquire than he or she ever pays. But meanwhile your large and loyal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience entices</ENAMEX> lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>. At best this takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            Of course, even a money-losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> can always survive indefinitely if
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> is willing to cover the losses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , owned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>, has joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> ,
and other older <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> in the tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> subsidized for
political reasons. But there is another, more amorphous and less acknowledged
tradition of money-losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> kept alive for reasons of general glamour
and corporate synergy. Talk , co-owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miramax</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>)
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hearst Corporation</ENAMEX>, may survive and even thrive in that tradition.

            And then there's the Internet, where there are no postage, printing, or
paper costs. And there are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> acquisition costs either, since
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> are given away free (though Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> do spend some
money on marketing). The theory is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>--who don't seem to mind the
lack of paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>--eventually will cover the entire cost with a bit
left over for profit. So far, this remains a theory.

            Next question?

         
      
   
