
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Tax Break</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffett</ENAMEX>?

            News coverage of the tax cut bill now in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has noted that the bills
contain special favors for certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffett</ENAMEX>, the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. What
exactly is the special favor for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffett</ENAMEX>?

            Special favors in legislation almost always are disguised as provisions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX> application. They apply to "any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1958</TIMEX> and
located in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with a population <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 150,000 and 200,000</NUMEX>," or similar
language that fits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX>. The alleged "special favor" for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffett</ENAMEX>, however, really is a change in the general law, for better or worse,
and not a sweetheart deal just for him.

            Under current law, a charitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> cannot own <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 20 percent</NUMEX>
of the stock of any publicly traded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX>. This law was enacted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>,
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> was concerned about the power and possible misuse of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>.
The purpose of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> limit was to prevent wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> from
maintaining control of public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> indirectly through a foundation. By
passing his stock on to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>, rather than to family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> themselves,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> could guarantee that it wouldn't be sold by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX> or dispersed
over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> version of the new tax bill would raise the
limit from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent to 40 percent</NUMEX> and ultimately (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX>) to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent</NUMEX>.

            The provision was sponsored, at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffett</ENAMEX>'s request, by his home state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffett</ENAMEX> owns <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of his
holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkshire Hathaway</ENAMEX>. He has publicly stated that he will leave
his stock to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, or if she dies <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX>. "In either event, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkshire</ENAMEX> will possess a controlling shareholder
guided by the same philosophy and objectives that now set our course," he
writes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkshire Hathaway</ENAMEX> Web site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffett</ENAMEX>'s "philosophy and objectives"
are widely admired, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> have not been raised this time
around.

            Next question?

         
      
   
