
   
   
      
         
            I Want <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Electronic Baby Sitter</ENAMEX>!

            A 
                  Slate
                contributor 
complains that the headline on the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pediatricians Urge</ENAMEX>
Limiting TV Watching," is evergreen, and damn the copy desk, he's right. The
story had some news in it, though. Pediatricians are now supposed to take
"media histories" along with medical histories when they see their young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> are to teach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to teach their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> "media
literacy." Imagine taking your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> for a stomachache and having
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of you interviewed about her ability to deconstruct a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX>
ad.

            Everyone knows television is bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>. The time they spend in front of
the TV is time not spent working out the verbal and physical intricacies of the
real world. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who doesn't develop his inner resources is left with no
other source of entertainment than television. The unformed mind can't be
trusted to discount for televisual hyperbole, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> claim that its
petroleum-based "milk" shakes can make you deliriously happy to the cartoon
causality that holds that shooting a criminal has roughly the same consequences
as bopping a bunny to the seeming ubiquity of rape, murder, and mayhem.

            But just because we know all this (and will dutifully recite some version of
it for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s benefit, if he insists) doesn't mean we want to
do anything about it. Television is like air conditioning: You can't imagine
how we ever survived without it. Chilled air made the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> prosperous;
television makes the dual-career or single-parent family possible. No one
returning from a day at work or rushing through all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">errands</ENAMEX> crammed into a
weekend can imagine coping with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s demands for distraction without
recourse to the boob tube. We could never get away with paying neighborhood
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitters</ENAMEX> (or local unlicensed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">day-care centers</ENAMEX>) such ridiculously low rates
if their child-care techniques didn't partly involve plopping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in front
of the TV. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> are annoying little buggers, and in a world of limited
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flex-time</ENAMEX> (and probably even in a world of unlimited flex-time) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> need a
break. The pediatricians would do better founding a national nanny service.

         
      
   
