
   
   
      
         
            After the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flood</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jodi</ENAMEX>,

            I feel a little like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX> on an old-time game show like "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supermarket</ENAMEX>
Sweep," staggering to the check-out counter with boxes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cheerios</ENAMEX> and
cellophane-wrapped Porterhouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steaks</ENAMEX> dropping off the top of my overstuffed
grocery cart. So many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, so little time.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, it seems like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX> that we started these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> musing about
the cosmic meaning of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading. It may be a reflection of our amnesiac media
culture that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s societal menace of crazed stock-market fiends has already
disappeared down the memory hole.

            As I prepare to pack up my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, I can't resist passing on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more
gem. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ran a mournful headline that read,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hundreds Are Killed, Millions Left Homeless by Asian Floods</ENAMEX>." Guess where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> played this story? <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Page A-15</ENAMEX>, beneath the fold.

            But don't blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> kissed off
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.8 million</NUMEX> homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> terse lines towards the bottom of its
front-page news briefs. And what about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , rightly famed for its
international coverage? Not a word in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s paper about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> floods,
presumably because they deemed a chatty feature on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX>' obsession with
cell phones to be more relevant to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>. In fairness, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of
record ran a wire-service picture on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A-6</NUMEX> of flood-drenched
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mourners</ENAMEX> crossing over to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> in rowboats.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, I'll especially miss our e-mail exchanges <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> arrives with its special "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weekend</ENAMEX>" section, which frankly I find
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">addictive</ENAMEX>, packed with stories about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7 million</NUMEX> vacation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and new
electronic gizmos for the bored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> found
a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">titan</ENAMEX> who admitted that he had fired someone over his cell phone
while lounging on the beach.)

            This is getting to be a long good-bye. So before I wax too maudlin, let me
just say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, that you've been a great morning pen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pal</ENAMEX>. Enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>.
And here's hoping that you enjoy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer weekend</TIMEX> without thinking for a
single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> minute about the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race.

            Fondly

         
      
   
