
   
   
      
         
            Talking the Talk
            

            Dear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>,

            My high-minded self desperately wants to begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our week</TIMEX> with an in-depth
discussion of the troubling article on the back page of this morning's Wall
Street Journal entitled "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drop in Food-Stamp Rolls Is Mysterious and</ENAMEX>
Worrisome." This story, triggered by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, is a
cautionary reminder of the unintended consequences of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s signing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> welfare bill. Amid all the triumphant rhetoric about the orderly
transition from welfare to work, it seems that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are still
entitled to food stamps aren't getting them for reasons that include ignorance,
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">state</ENAMEX> restrictions, and the general down-with-the-welfare-state ethos of
the age.

            But try as I might, my tabloid sensibility keeps being drawn back to the
flap over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Franks</ENAMEX> in the debut issue of
Talk . (I particularly love the discreet four paragraphs buried on Page
A-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> devoted to this topic in my edition of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s paper.) Like everything else about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, the interpretation of this
interview completely depends on your pre-existing opinions of her. For example,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>-owned, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>-hating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> has a vintage headline
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their second-day</TIMEX> story, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shrinks: Hillary's Got Poor Excuse for Hubby</ENAMEX>."
Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort Zuckerman</ENAMEX>-owned, pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Daily News</ENAMEX> finds
different "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>" who claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HRC</ENAMEX>'s "analysis was probably correct when
she said her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s philandering was rooted in an emotionally abused
childhood." Personally, I pity <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> (myself included) who will be
emotionally abused by every element of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race. But I also cannot help
but be awed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s ability to dominate the news.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> last thought on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead story on the demise of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX> as a potent political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. As someone who covers
politics, I've long been amused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> that surrounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX>. I'm referring not to born-again <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> but to
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. Uncomfortable with religion and culturally out-of-step
with fundamentalism, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> on the campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> overhyped a
phenomenon that they didn't understand--the rise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Right</ENAMEX>. Only
now are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the rest of the press belatedly offering a
corrective revision.

            Many more thoughts, but I should get about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of getting these
yawn-filled, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Monday-morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reflections</ENAMEX> posted.

            Eagerly awaiting your response,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>

             

         
      
   
