
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billion Underserved</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Treasury</ENAMEX>'s announcement that it would like to take advantage of
projected budget surpluses by buying back some government bonds before their
maturity dates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the settlement of differences
among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s leading water <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> dating back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX> about their
individual rights to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado River</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s top
non-local story is the government bond buy-back. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Water</ENAMEX> is also the top local
story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> --specifically the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s
reaction to the drought there, new regulations that will shut off lawn
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sprinklers</ENAMEX> and end unrequested drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s
top non-local story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s approval of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.4 billion</NUMEX> emergency aid
package for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>, which is a response not only to drought conditions but
also to falling commodities prices. The paper points out that this bill would
spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s projected budget surplus and comes on the
heels of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>'s "one-time" farm fix of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s ruling that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX>' ouster of
a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout leader</ENAMEX> constituted illegal discrimination. In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> previous cases
in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, the paper informs, the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> sided with the scouts. The
issue is considered ripe for review by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
Times front the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout</ENAMEX> story, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs it inside.

            The basic idea behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s buy-back, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains, is to retire older
high-interest debt and then to replace it with newly issued lower-rate
securities. The plan probably won't take place until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. The paper
points out that contrary to the current tax cut/surplus debate, this strategy
does not require congressional approval. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> note that it also is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> for reducing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s reliance on foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX>, who
currently hold <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> publicly held debt. In addition, they say,
reduced government borrowing will also lessen competition with private
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> for funds, thereby lowering interest rates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> notes that the announcement spurred a
rally <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> in longer-term <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasurys</ENAMEX>, the supply of which would be reduced
if the buy-back happens.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that in a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, the fastest growing
country on the planet, will reach a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1 billion</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
population explosion offers a mixed demographic bag: increased life expectancy
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 63</TIMEX>, up from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">39 just 50 years ago</TIMEX>), a lower fertility rate (from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> births
per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, down to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3.1</NUMEX> over that same period. But what good is this if there
are so many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>?), <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">500 million illiterates</NUMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">320</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> abjectly poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that the war between No. 1 online service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> and No.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> won't stop with the instant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">messaging tiff</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s next target is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s dial-up business itself, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> is planning
to address by offering low-price or even free access to the Internet. There's
precedent, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Price-cutting</ENAMEX> was the strategy that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enabled MS</ENAMEX> to catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> are really chafing over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>'
discounts for Internet ticket purchases. Travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> now book about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>
percent of airline tickets, but increased Internet purchases are a clear
threat. And since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> scrapped the traditional <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>'s fee
for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> fee per transaction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> fee rates overall have fallen to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.3</NUMEX>
percent.

            A top-front-with-picture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story describes how, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the
national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX> distracted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> from her great interest in the
Jamestown, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, regional economy with still more questions about her comments
in Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. Asked
why she agreed to discuss in an interview such a personal subject, she said,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, I'm not going to anymore." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that the non-media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">types</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> responded to this with applause.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pollster Andrew Kohut</ENAMEX> writes in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed that fresh polls show
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prospects</ENAMEX> are not likely to be helped by any
revelations regarding her relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX>. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohut</ENAMEX> says, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74</NUMEX>
percent of a recent sample say they are tired of all the problems of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. He concludes, "For most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>, there are no unanswered
questions about the personal lives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
