
   
   
      
         
            Gross <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Film Gross</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s agreement by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> on a tax cut bill. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> weren't invited to the
discussions.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes inside with that story and leads instead
with the first guilty plea in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> bribery scandal, a story
nobody else fronts. The plea bargain describes phony paperwork designed to
falsely portray as a salary payments made by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of an influential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IOC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> compromise tax bill, imposing an aggregate cut of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, provides for a reduction of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> percentage point in all income tax
rates. There's also a drop in the top rate on capital gains, from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>
down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>, a reduction in the "marriage penalty" for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> filing
jointly, and a phase-out of the inheritance tax that now applies to large
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">estates</ENAMEX>. The tax rate reductions are conditioned on continued success at
reducing the national debt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has vowed to veto any bill
putting this much of the budget surplus toward tax relief. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> point out that the main
political objective of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> was to have an agreed-upon bill on the
table to enable them to use the summer recess to build popular anti-veto
pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The only real departure from the reporting template comes with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>'s observation that high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> have been working feverishly
for months to incorporate into the bill its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> and D tax credit, a feature the
paper calls a "particularly glittering <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> have included a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>.

            A WSJ front-page feature notes that even without such new wrinkles,
the tax code allows many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> to legally pay little or no federal income tax. More
than half the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , quoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX>
study, paid no federal income tax at all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1989 and 1995</TIMEX>. And in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>,
says the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> managed to get itself in the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.8 percent</NUMEX> tax
bracket. (This story is a dramatic reminder of the difference between the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s news and editorial pages.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front a fresh study from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disease Control</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevention</ENAMEX>, appearing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> , with a
counterintuitive result: a significant decline in high-school violence in the
1990s. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> possible explanation of the disconnect that the stories don't
address: that the study ends with data from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998 and 1999</TIMEX> have been
marked by some major school shootings.

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JAMA</ENAMEX> study, written up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
calculates that the cost of treating the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s gunshot wounds for a recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year, 1994</TIMEX>, was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.3 billion</NUMEX>. Half of that cost, says the study, was ultimately
borne by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. The average cost of a gunshot wound that requires a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX> visit is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,600</NUMEX> for emergency care and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,400</NUMEX> for lifetime follow-up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> front, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> stuffs,
word that an arbitration <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> has ruled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> must pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heirs</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Zapruder</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 million</NUMEX> for the movie he shot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
assassination. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zapruder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had been asking for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX> and the
government had been offering <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> dispatch noting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX>'s announcement that it
will be licensing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hot Wheels</ENAMEX> to a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX>
computers will be silver with pink and purple floral accents and will come with
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbie Digital Camera</ENAMEX> and a flowered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hot Wheels</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> will
feature the toy's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flame</ENAMEX> logo and a steering wheel.

            The lead editorial at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reminds that it's been almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>
since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> promised to post all congressional proceedings on the
Internet and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost four</NUMEX> since the passage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic Freedom of</ENAMEX>
Information Act, which required all federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> to grant <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> prompt
access to relevant information in their databases. The paper observes that most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">branches</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> stand in violation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Act</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mongolia</ENAMEX> has a Web site, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court does not.

         
      
   
