
   
   
      
         
            Civil and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncivil Actions</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times goes local. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX> endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, despite their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">chilly</TIMEX> history, for the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Senate</ENAMEX> race.
The national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> reportedly pressured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX> to do it so there'd
be a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> campaign against the probable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> also leads a local piece, about how two
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> are handling a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> gubernatorial announcement. It, not
spelled out in the story, declared mandatory restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> usage
throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montgomery County</ENAMEX> is printing educational pamphlets,
fining violators, and authorizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">county</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> "to confront
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">scofflaws</ENAMEX>." Conversely, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prince George's County</ENAMEX> hasn't planned to do any of
these things. PG <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> note the "water <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> serving both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">counties</ENAMEX>
insists it has enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to last into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>" even with no rain till then.
(All of which begs the question, not addressed in the piece, what does the term
"mandatory restrictions" mean?) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that the drought was
the worst in history for the agriculture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy update. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">310,000</NUMEX> jobs
were added, wages roses at the fastest rate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and unemployment was
steady at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.3 percent</NUMEX>. The shrinking manufacturing sector added <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31,000</NUMEX> jobs,
its biggest gain in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>. (Back then, notes a similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
piece, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1998</TIMEX>, striking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> returned to work.) The
news increases the possibility that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> will raise interest
rates at its next meeting, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 24</TIMEX>, to protect against inflation.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manicurist</ENAMEX>, charging heart damage after taking a weight-loss
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cocktail</ENAMEX> called fen-phen, won a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23.3 million</NUMEX> jury verdict <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, fronts the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . This was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Home Products</ENAMEX> (AHP) for
making fenfluramine, the dangerous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the combination, which "cause[s]
heart valve damage in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and lung problems in others." The larger
significance of the case: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defendants</ENAMEX> "usually win the initial cases in such
product liability law suits" so that this loss "could lead to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of new
cases." The piece mentions other liability suits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHP</ENAMEX> has faced. It does not,
and should, discuss other recent product-liability cases of national
importance, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asbestos</ENAMEX>, tobacco, and hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fen-phen</ENAMEX> ruling
supports a trend of decisions against product-liability <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX>.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who until recently commanded a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military
unit running anti-drug operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colombia</ENAMEX> has been charged with smuggling
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie Hiett</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Hiett</ENAMEX>,
surrendered to federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
(quoted) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead this story; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts it. Both
off-leads credit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> for the scoop and report that two
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, who received the packages, have also been charged. Hiett mailed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 16</NUMEX> pounds of pure coke via <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> packages. She claims to have sent them for
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chauffeur</ENAMEX>, who charges Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiett</ENAMEX> abuses <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, without
knowledge of their contents. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX>
voluntarily stepped aside <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in light of the allegations, though he
doesn't seem to have been involved; and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$289 million</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> aid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, most of it to fight <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> sets the
scene best, reporting an anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Columbian</ENAMEX> government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> who said
Colombians frequently ask foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> they know to send mail for them
because lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have unreliable mail services.
However, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, it's customary to leave such mail unsealed to show
nothing illegal is being sent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece also claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>
have evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hiett</ENAMEX> knew what she was sending, and reports the street
value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coke</ENAMEX> was in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$230,000</NUMEX> range. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> focuses on how the
situation will affect the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> anti-drug effort in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts a piece analyzing the budget shenanigans. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
passed a tax bill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has promised to veto, and passed spending bills
intended to financially disable his priorities despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s consistent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">triumphs</ENAMEX> in budget standoffs over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past four years</TIMEX>. But even if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> does
win this time, some have admitted that his goals of long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> stability may not be realized. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial makes
similar points but is more aggressively anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. It also comments that
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is rhetorically moving
against his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. And the surpluses projected for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 10 years</TIMEX> are enough "to save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, increase
defense spending, run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> in a way that would be satisfactory to
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> and even provide a modest tax cut."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s presidential campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Coelho</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> reached outside his
inner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> to recruit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coelho</ENAMEX>. Some like him; some don't--such as former vice
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald A. Klain</ENAMEX>, who resigned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> doesn't
come away with much sense of whether to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coelho</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign, from
the piece.

         
      
   
