
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plucky Code Jockeys and Workplace Rage</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Jim</ENAMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pothole</ENAMEX> profile really was one great
zinger after another.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> beats the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> to the punch in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
issue, making very similar points, but with a somewhat more forgiving tone, in
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jerry Brown Gets Real</ENAMEX>." One highlight: When peace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX> took over Mayor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to object to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Marines</ENAMEX>' conducting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of urban warfare training in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> expressed bafflement:
"There seems to be serious problems on the left with finding ways to express
themselves." Oh, those goofy wackos on the left. Why don't they find some
constructive way to express themselves? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meditation</ENAMEX>, perhaps?

            But enough about real news, because it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, which means it's time to
play another round of workplace trend-watch with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>.

            First, on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> deadpans that
humor is both mandated and frowned upon in the workplace: A survey found that
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">275</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> discourage humor, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> include it in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> or values statements, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> have hired humor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> to
yuck it up. Note to self: Check mission statement before fowarding jokes
around.

            Another classic of the career trend-watch genre: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s installment of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Managing Your Career</ENAMEX>" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal Lancaster</ENAMEX>, which introduces us to an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-year-old</TIMEX> who makes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> plus stock options as a code jockey in,
where else, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX>. I'm all for extracting lessons from the savvy
career moves of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> to teach us old <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> a thing or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. But while this
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> tells us that our talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tyke</ENAMEX>'s precocious success is "partly due to
his talents and partly due to the abundance of opportunities in high tech
fields <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>," we then learn: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) He's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a venture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) he
had trouble getting a job, until some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> dad
founded hooked him up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hotmail</ENAMEX>, one of their portfolio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) at
Hotmail, he struggled to do the job, but by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the summer</TIMEX> had written
some code they could actually use.

            Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> could find in the above events an uplifting story
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a plucky</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s "first lesson in the power of connections."

            Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury News</ENAMEX> gets into the workplace trend game as well, with an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story on "workplace rage." Yes, you've heard of "road rage" (anger while
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">driving</ENAMEX>) and "air rage" (anger while flying). But based on a dusty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX>
Poll, we learn that one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> feels "generally at least somewhat
angry at work." The story advises us to add "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">workplace rage</ENAMEX>" to the culprits
(read: Internet, Internet, Internet) that made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Barton</ENAMEX> pull the trigger in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>.

            I, for one, am livid that we're now saddled with yet another pop-psyche rage
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX>.

            Furiously yours,
Katharine

         
      
   
