
   
   
      
         
            Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Stuff</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jim</ENAMEX>--

            It was a pleasure to get your e-mail about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Bell</ENAMEX>'s book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Coming</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Industrial Society</ENAMEX> . Like you, I was put off by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s prose, which
hasn't aged well. But I'll avoid dwelling on that for now, and skip right to
your request--an explanation of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Bell</ENAMEX> means by the post-industrial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>. Then we can get into what relevance this book may have in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>, the post-industrial society has several distinct
characteristics. Since we live in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age of Information</ENAMEX>, I'll "bullet point"
them for easier retrieval:

            

               A shift from manufacturing to services.

               The "centrality of the new science-based industries."

               The rise of new technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> and the advent of new principles of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stratification</ENAMEX>.

               A changeover from a "goods-producing" society to an "information or
knowledge" society.

               A change in abstraction from "empiricism or trial-and-error tinkering" to
theory and the codification of theoretical knowledge "for directing innovation
and the formulation of policy."

               A change in reality from "nature" (during agrarian times) and "technics"
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Industrial Revolution</ENAMEX>, to reality existing as "the social world" ...
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> itself becomes a web of consciousness, a form of imagination to be
realized as a social construction."

            

            That about sums it up.

            So why read this book now? Well, I'm reading it because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Shulevitz</ENAMEX>, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at 
                  Slate
               , asked me to. My reasons aside, why should anyone
else read this book? I can't say I recommend it. Heading to the beach with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>
may lead to sudden extended bouts of deep sleep that, if you're not wearing SPF
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, can cause second-degree burns on exposed skin. This book should be kept
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indoors</ENAMEX>, and used primarily as a sleep aid.

            What's most interesting about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s book in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> is its time-capsule
quality--extended sections on Marxism, the use of science to develop atomic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombs</ENAMEX>, and multiple pages on the arrival of affirmative action in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>--and how totally dated these arguments now seem. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s world, circa
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, was one where Marxism seemed important, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX> appeared powerful,
and "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>" politics was poised to tear <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> democracy apart with tribalism
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s rights, black power, hippies, labor, etc.). His vision of a
post-industrial society is one where science and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>--because they're
the ultimate knowledge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>--rise to prominence:

            

               The rated power of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> no longer rests on its steel capacity but on
the quality of its science and application, through research and development,
to new technology. For these obvious reasons the new relation of science to
government ... completely affects the structure of science as "charismatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>" and as "occupational society." What becomes central, therefore, is
the question, Who speaks for science and for what ends?

            

            That's a telling section, both stylistically (pretty dense) and
theoretically--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> believes in the "helmsman" model of directing society. For
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>, the post-industrial society is one where science, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, and the
scientific method become the dominant model. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> through
their work have the capacity to steer society. It's similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norbert Weiner</ENAMEX>'s
thinking (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">originator</ENAMEX> of the term "cybernetics" from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> word for
"helmsman"), which postulated that society would be increasingly governed by
"feedback," allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elites</ENAMEX> to steer better. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s post-industrial society is
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Government</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Corporations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Thinkers</ENAMEX>, do Big Things.
It's Top Down. And looking back at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s and 1990s</TIMEX>, we see how very off
that thinking became.

            This, after all, is the era of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaires</ENAMEX>, of "bottom up,"
"chaos theory," "complexity theory," the Internet, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>, "viral marketing,"
"tribal marketing," niches, fragmentation, heterogeneous globalization, the
"hive mind," the "noosphere," and so on. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX>? What was that? The "atom
bomb"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>--by that I take it you mean those crusty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICBMs</ENAMEX> somewhere in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>--what about <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">smallpox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biohazard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4</ENAMEX>, subway <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sarin</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anthrax</ENAMEX>? The
consumer-centric "long boom" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> seems utterly distant from the dry
post-industrial world <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> describes, full of references to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rousseau</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenin</ENAMEX>. Of course, you can't fault someone for failing to predict or
describe the future, but you can compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> who had a far better
sense of it. Most important, circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970s</TIMEX>, would be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvin Toffler</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Third</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wave</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart Brand</ENAMEX> (who wrote a crucial article for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> about how the real legacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> cultural revolution
was the computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hacker</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authors</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brand</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toffler</ENAMEX> understood the rise of what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> we call
"libertarianism," with its cross-pollination between cultural trends
("do-it-yourself" rock and roll, homebuilding, computer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, etc.,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">symbolized by the Whole Earth Catalog, the Sex Pistols</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX>) and
economic trends (the rise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, the "brand of me," and
ever-lowering barriers to the flow of capital from market to market). Go back
and read their work, from around the same time as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell's</ENAMEX>, and you have a
totally different response: At least these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' arguments fall somewhere on
the map of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> (and neither of them seem to pay much heed to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.S.R.</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s inability to see a world beyond the context of military and economic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Stuff</ENAMEX> is what dates this book most of all. Big, centralized <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">models</ENAMEX> are out.
Network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">externalities</ENAMEX> are in. Which leaves the question--what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s
post-industrial society has come to pass? Any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Thoughts</ENAMEX> on this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
