
   
   
      
         
            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Going Nasdaq" on Taiwan</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post lead with the designation of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> and parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> as federal disaster areas, a story
fronted by the New York
Times . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Farmers</ENAMEX> in these <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">regions</ENAMEX>--who are suffering the worst drought
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>--are now eligible for low-interest federal loans, which would,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , cover <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to 80 percent</NUMEX> of their losses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX>'s prohibition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>-and-vegetable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>, a story
fronted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX> kill <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">insects</ENAMEX> by interfering with their nervous
system; some fear the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> may affect the nervous systems of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
although there are no hard data. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>'s top non-local story is a
massive head-on train collision involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, a story at the
top of the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s front-page "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldwide</ENAMEX>" box and reefered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> put the death toll at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over 200</NUMEX> (many of whom
were burned alive or dismembered) but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> deadline,
says the number approaches <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">400</TIMEX>. A signal failure was the likely cause.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> except <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> front <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s unusual announcement of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">long-range</ENAMEX> missile test within its territory. Almost every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> has a
different angle: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes that the announcement will
frustrate efforts to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> from testing its own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the announcement was done in tandem with a harsh public
critique of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> for selling military technology to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX>; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> puts the missile test in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> paragraph of a larger story on
increased sorties over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Strait</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> military
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jets</ENAMEX>. In separate stories, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> report that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> meted out harsh prison sentences to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s accidental <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 7</TIMEX> bombing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgrade</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has sentenced <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> to prison terms of up
to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front a decision by a federal district
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to throw out most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 3-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election Commission</ENAMEX> lawsuit
against the beleaguered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled that, in all but
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cases, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>'s distribution of voting guides did not
constitute specific endorsement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--which would have amounted to an
illegal campaign contribution. The decision is expected to allow more citizen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> to distribute election literature in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> without the burden of FEC
regulation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> both run articles on the risks and
rewards of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading, which apparently contributed to the recent massacre in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says it's not surprising that the rise of
non-professional, home-based Internet trading can encourage the occasional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bankrupted</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> to "go <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>"--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Barton</ENAMEX>'s murders have been termed.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> sit at home alone, get unreliable tips through chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, and
lose their own money rather than that of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
acknowledges these risks but argues that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading makes financial markets
more efficient and provides greater odds than (other) legalized forms of
gambling, such as lotto and blackjack.

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>
D'Andrea <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> tries to convince the financial markets that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s report
of unexpectedly high labor costs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second quarter</TIMEX> does not necessarily
mean the economy is overheating. As if in divine confirmation of her argument,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX> fixed-rate mortgages have climbed over
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, signaling an end to the housing
boom. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that economic growth and price increases in
the manufacturing sector were less than predicted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, "easing Wall Street
fears of an overheating economy."

            Writing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> opinion page, contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Scheer</ENAMEX>
makes the provocative argument that the quickest way to halt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">belligerence</ENAMEX> is to simply hand over all our nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">warhead</ENAMEX> and ballistics
secrets. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s current saber rattling, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scheer</ENAMEX> reasons, stems from an
inferiority complex about its relatively primitive nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX>. Once China
has a deterrent equal to that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheer</ENAMEX> says, it won't feel
the need to taunt its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> after every tiny technological advance.

         
      
   
