
   
   
      
         
            Pigeon Killers and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hate Groups</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Katharine</ENAMEX>,

            Someone is poisoning <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> pigeons, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> sparrows, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> grackle and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX> were
found dead in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. (I did
not know that grackles were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">native</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>; I don't think I could pick
a grackle out of a lineup.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Stern</ENAMEX>--himself a bit of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">loon</ENAMEX>--admits that until autopsies are performed, they can't be certain of the
cause of death, but everyone agrees that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fowl</ENAMEX> play is likely. Evidently there
have been signs of such <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> murder since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> continues with
the information that "Killing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ducks</ENAMEX>, sparrows and grackle would be a
violation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Federal Migratory Bird Act</ENAMEX>." Reading between the lines, one
can infer that poisoning a pigeon is not a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX>. I guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Lehrer</ENAMEX>
would be pleased.

            If the pigeon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> is still at large, thank heavens there's a real culprit
for the mass shooting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. There's something oddly reassuring about
having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> in custody, and having him be an avowed racist to boot. So
many of these shootings end up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> killing himself, which makes the
entire incident impossible to grasp. Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buford Furrow</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> very easy
to grasp: a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliate</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aryan Nations</ENAMEX> who is obsessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
and mass murder and who eventually tips over from theory into practice.

            About the only part of it I don't get are the peculiar reports about his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">getaway</ENAMEX> strategy. On the run in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furrow</ENAMEX> abandons his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> and
carjacks a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX>. That all makes sense. Then he supposedly kills a mail
carrier? Why? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> is found abandoned "in the parking lot of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suites Hotel</ENAMEX>," according to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . Then, we're told,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Furrow</ENAMEX> hailed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Fernando Valley</ENAMEX> and took it to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, an
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800</NUMEX> fare. Since when can you hail a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>? I guess it's easier if you're
armed.

            The best detail I've encountered is from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , which
traced a crucial piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furrow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AR-15</ENAMEX> assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bushmaster Firearms</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>. Of course it's a coincidence, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is a
former state finance chair for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hopeful</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. I'd
like to see this shooting become an issue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> primaries. Which of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> is willing to say that there is a deplorable,
violent movement of hate in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society, and that anyone affiliated with
that movement is unwelcome in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>? Which ones are willing to
say that taking an anti-crime stance means finding a way to either stamp out
these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> or isolate them so completely that they can't try to kill more
innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?

            Ever yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
