
   
   
      
         
            Deep <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Throat: The Game Is Afoot</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reporter David Daley</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hartford Courant</ENAMEX> has found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Mark Felt</ENAMEX>,
the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> believed by the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> and
various other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to have been <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>. (See "
Another Bulletin From the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat Desk</ENAMEX>," "
Deep <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Throat Revealed [Again</ENAMEX>]," and "
Deep <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Throat Revealed [One Last Time</ENAMEX>].") Knowing that Felt had denied being
Deep Throat before, 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wondered aloud <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> whether Felt would still deny
it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> did better than wonder: In a story published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courant</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> tracked the
85-year-old Felt down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and asked him if he was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>. "No,
it's not me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felt</ENAMEX> answered.

            
               I would have done better. I would have been more effective. Deep Throat
didn't exactly bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> crashing down, did he?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't know what to make of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felt</ENAMEX>'s claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> was
"ineffective," but will set that aside for now. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>'s story, which was picked
up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>, broke the news that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Port Chester</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase Culeman-Beckman</ENAMEX> claims to have been told by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Bernstein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">son Jacob</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> was ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Felt</ENAMEX>. Culeman-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beckman</ENAMEX> says that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> he attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampton Day School Camp</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bridgehampton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX>
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Bernstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX>, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> was the one who told
him. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culeman-Beckman</ENAMEX> "said the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> told him the
information came straight from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>," who of course is one of the three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> known to be party to the secret. (The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradlee</ENAMEX>.)

            Chatterbox, who is increasingly drawn to the hypothesis that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> was
indeed Felt, finds much to like in this story. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> knows
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> tend to blab family secrets--and recalls that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authorship of Primary Colors</ENAMEX> came to light partly as a result of some
things his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> talked about at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp is a well-known crucible
of intimacy. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culeman-Beckman</ENAMEX> has written on the subject tells the
story most beguilingly:

            
               
                  I was in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Herons</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about fifteen</NUMEX> other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">9,</ENAMEX>
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 year olds ... One Friday</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> we went on a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX>, Sag
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harbor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> and I ended up sitting in the sand precociously talking
about politics. It was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election year</TIMEX> and I was in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>
because he had gone to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenwich Country Day School</ENAMEX> where I was attending,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> were for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX>, although I do not remember why.
At some point, the conversation turned to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> ... which I knew
little, if nothing, about. During the conversation <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> told me: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Felt</ENAMEX>, he's someone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. I'm <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> sure."
               
            

            Still, it would be rash to consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culeman-Beckman</ENAMEX>'s paper (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>'s
story) dispositive. Most crucially, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culeman-Beckman</ENAMEX> does not back up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>'s
reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Bernstein</ENAMEX>'s information came from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Bernstein</ENAMEX>.
Culeman-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beckman</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that the context of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>
conversation was a discussion about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Bernstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>. But when pressed,
Culeman-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beckman</ENAMEX> admitted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Bernstein</ENAMEX> hadn't said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Bernstein</ENAMEX>
actually told him <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Felt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culeman-Beckman</ENAMEX> just
assumed that was how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> knew. "I think that would be the only way for
an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to hear such a name," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culeman-Beckman</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>. But
that isn't quite right. It's at least as possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Bernstein</ENAMEX> got the
idea from his mother , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>-turned-movie-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Ephron</ENAMEX>, who
has stated publicly in the past her suspicions about Felt. ("I always thought
it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Felt</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>," she told the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Intelligencer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. "But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX> would never tell me. So I honestly
don't know.")          



	Sure enough, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Bernstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Ephron</ENAMEX> both
saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> was merely parroting his mother's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat hypothesis</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> says that neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ephron</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Bernstein</ENAMEX> knows <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>'s
identity "any more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in the moon does," and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> was
"repeating his mother's guesswork." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ephron</ENAMEX> says that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX> never told me who
Deep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Throat</ENAMEX> was, which was very smart because I would have told the whole world
by now." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ephron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernstein</ENAMEX> had a famously nasty divorce, chronicled in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ephron</ENAMEX>'s novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heartburn</ENAMEX> , later made into a movie with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Nicholson</ENAMEX>.)

            Incidentally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culeman-Beckman</ENAMEX>'s paper unearths a nifty Felt-related snippet
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> tapes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> didn't know about. As in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> tapes excerpt 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> previously cited, Felt is discussed as a probable leaker. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> (who, among other things, will likely be remembered as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s last <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Semitic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>) expresses horror at discovering Felt to
be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> . This conversation, dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 19, 1972</TIMEX>, is even more Gothic
than the last:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: Well, if they've got a leak down at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, why the hell can't
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> tell us what the hell is left? You know what I mean?...
            

            Haldeman: We know what's left, and we know who leaked it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: Somebody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>?

            Haldeman: Yes, sir. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Felt</ENAMEX>. You can't say anything about this because it
will screw up our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> and there's a real concern. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX> is the only one
who knows about this and he feels strongly that we better not do anything
because--

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: Do anything? Never.

            Haldeman: If we move on him, he'll go out and unload everything. He knows
everything that's to be known in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. He has access to absolutely
everything ...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: What would you do with Felt?

            Haldeman: Well, I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> ...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: You know what I'd do with him, the bastard? Well that's all I want to
hear about it.

            Haldeman: I think he wants to be in the top spot.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: That's a hell of a way for him to get to the top.

            Haldeman: You can figure a lot of--maybe he thought--<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all, he has to
figure that if you stay in as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> there's a possibility or probability
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> will stay on. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGovern</ENAMEX> comes in, then you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>'s going to be out
...

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: Is he <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>?

            Haldeman: (unintelligible) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>, put a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> in there?

            Haldeman: Well, that could explain it too.

            [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Update</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8/4/99</NUMEX> : After much pestering online and by phone,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has finally gotten The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX> to post on its Web site <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>'s watershed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX> piece. Click here and wonder no more about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Throat</ENAMEX>'s place of
employment.]

             

         
      
   
