
   
   
      
         
            Surfing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> on the Internet
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Jim</ENAMEX>:

            Your theory that the Internet is the crack of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keeper</ENAMEX>, if not a
PhD dissertation waiting to happen. From <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine</ENAMEX> to the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
shootings, the Internet did it. Or, if it didn't exactly pull the trigger, it
sure didn't tackle the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX> and restrain him. So goes the conventional
wisdom: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX> trading = death, and the like.

            For the latest installment of the Internet as crack, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Faludi</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> column, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rage of the American Male</ENAMEX>," where the computer is front-and-center
in her portrait of the alienation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, as exemplified by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Burton</ENAMEX>:

            

               That culture holds up a frightening mirror. Reflected there is an image of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> alone--isolated from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX>, unneeded by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, staring
into a computer screen on which he seeks a disembodied fortune or, if that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fortune</ENAMEX> fails, types a suicide note.

            

            As I sit here in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, staring into a computer screen (reading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faludi</ENAMEX>'s
piece online), isolated from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellows</ENAMEX>, maybe I should be grateful that I have
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX> for a little human connection (or that I have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">X</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chromosomes</ENAMEX>).

            Murderous rampages not enough for you? How about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nazism</ENAMEX>? The section of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger</ENAMEX>'s line about how that the Internet is
contributing to the demise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> also includes an intriguing piece of
reporting about how the Internet pedals <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> propaganda to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Harmon</ENAMEX>'s story "Internet Sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nazi Books</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany Assailed</ENAMEX>" relates
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnesandnoble</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> are drawing the ire of an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>-based
anti-Semitism watchdog <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> for shipping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mein Kampf</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, where
the book is banned. (In my edition, this story coincidentally appears right
above an ad for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-day</TIMEX> free trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TheStreet</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, where they are presumably
not selling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> literature, but may be implicitly promoting day trading,
which, as we've seen above, is suspiciously connected to murderous mayhem in
its own way, even though we're not sure exactly how.)

            The best part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmon</ENAMEX>'s story is this priceless detail: "The researcher
who ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mein Kampf</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX> received E-mail suggesting that he
might also like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Power</ENAMEX> , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Nazi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lincoln</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockwell</ENAMEX>, for instance." And if that isn't enough synergy for you, if you go to
the pages for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mein Kampf</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>, as I did, you'll also find links to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recommended Amazon</ENAMEX> auctions, including a collectible sign of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
photographed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and various commemorative stamps. You have to
love shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bots</ENAMEX>, always thinking ahead to your next purchase. "Gee, I didn't
even know I needed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> figurine, until I saw the link right there!"

            Maybe the greatest irony of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuczynski</ENAMEX> piece on the declining influence
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> is that the story is much more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>-like than what you'd get
from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years ago</TIMEX>. It reads as a
reportorial essay, in contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmon</ENAMEX> story, which is much more of a
straight newsy item.

            Could it be that since there are so many other news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> (Internet, cable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> are doing more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>-style stories? Maybe next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX>'s lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> article should be about
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have become more like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> in their struggle to
maintain and build <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX> in these trying digital times.

            In any case, I'm sure it's the Internet's fault.

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>,
Katharine

         
      
   
