
   
   
      
         
            We <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Can't Stand Pat</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s dismissal of yet another prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sergei Stepashin</ENAMEX>, called back to get the news, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dagestan</ENAMEX>, where he was supervising the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
military counter to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> has once again picked an obscure
career intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> as the replacement. What's different this time, the
papers all note, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> has endorsed the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX>, as
his chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>, urging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> to vote for him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s
presidential election. The papers agree <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Putin</ENAMEX>'s likely to be approved by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with a story nobody else fronts, the
inauguration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of a new digitized fingerprint system that will allow police
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to send in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>' prints electronically to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> main
lab from their patrol <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> in the field and get a definitive comparison with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>'s prints on file, not in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> as can sometimes be the case now,
but in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.

            The papers (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>) react to the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX>
shuffle--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> one in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 months</TIMEX>--with a calm verging on bemusement. Both
Times note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, in his televised announcement of the move,
spoke very slowly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes even further, saying that he was
"speaking as if the words on the teleprompter were moving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at a time."

            The papers trot out a range of theories for the change in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes the most idealistic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is intent on bequeathing
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, as his parting legacy, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who are committed
to completing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s democratization. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> leads all observe that
the rise of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">confederation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> led by a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> is seen by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> as a threat he wants to head off.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is trying to engineer his succession by a
friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> because he's worried about prosecution for corruption
after leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has this too, quoting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX>
official as saying, "He is not concerned about his legacy, or about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and
its fate. He is afraid of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ceausescu</ENAMEX> scenario."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes top front with the negative conclusions of a group of
state securities <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> concerning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many day</TIMEX> trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX>, they say, use deceptive
marketing practices to lure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> into a rapid-fire trading approach that
will probably cause them to lose money, and then often arrange for them to
receive illegal loans (sometimes directly profiting from those loans). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> had been working on their report for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX>, long before last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>'s stock shootings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>. Yet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> cited questionable
practices at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> office
was one of the murder scenes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> striking conclusion: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 11.5 percent</NUMEX> of day
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> at that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> could make even a short-term profit. And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> noted that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are bent on speculative investments, the
futures and options markets present ample opportunity, at lower cost and
greater leverage. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> also runs a story on the report, noting
that it likens day trading to gambling.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> says his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> will
turn in a final report on matters <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonian</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>
elections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is saying his report will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX>, but will "not engage in characterization." (In other words the
exact opposite of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report that was the basis for the impeachment
proceedings.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reminds that it had previously quoted some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> saying that the final report would criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> by
raising unanswered questions about her behavior in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Whitewater</ENAMEX> matters.

            The LAT front-page "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" feature reports that just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>
after it was considered laughable, abstinence-based sex education is on the
upswing. The concept is now blessed by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
and publicly funded to the tune of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX>. And concomitantly (nobody
knows if there's a causal connection too), sexual activity rates among
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> have started to drop. Although, says the paper, those who are having
sex are paying an increasing price--there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3 million</NUMEX> new cases of STDs
diagnosed among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. Next goal among the conservative policy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mavens</ENAMEX> who pioneered abstinence for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>: abstinence for unmarrieds in
their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20s</TIMEX>.

            
               Let him who is without sin fire the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> shellfish <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX> round: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on his TV show that assassinating troublesome world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> is an
option the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> shouldn't deny itself. "It would just seem so much more
practical to have that flexibility," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying. "I don't
see anything un-Christian about it."

         
      
   
