
   
   
      
         
            More Talk on Talk
            

            Hi, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>:

            Pleasure to share the pages with you. I warmed up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> at my usual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>, whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> are the most literate and
convivial of any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX> subway line I have ever ridden. On average, every
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is reading a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>: There are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contortionists</ENAMEX> who fold the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ever-expanding Times</ENAMEX> into readable wedges, the tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> (whose
papers are enviably scaled for reading in motion), and a scattering of people
clutching <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> papers. The close <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> and the jostling
practically make eaves-reading inevitable, and the paper-bearers don't seem to
mind sharing. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> I saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s eyes well up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story on
live liver donations. I also saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> contorting themselves to read the
very <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> story you mention on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s interview in
Talk .

            I was not one of them. My appetite for Talk has been weakened by
these "revelations," which seem as banal as they are carefully meted out. If we
are going to be subjected to any additional dirt about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s mystery
marriage, it better be loamier than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-planted soil we seem to be farming
here. I agree with you about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s domination of the media/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>:
amazing how she is reinventing old news--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s tough childhood and
repeated philandering--as the talk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.

            I suppose we'll have to reserve judgment until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, when the actual
magazine hits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX>. I'll make you a bet: If the interview shatters
any boundaries not already shattered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>' post-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gennifer Flowers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> interview in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, I'll buy you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s subscription to the
magazine. Are we on?

            My favorite Talk comment so far comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> (in his straight news item on Page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A2</TIMEX>, not in his long
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Remnick</ENAMEX> comparison in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX> points out that the
interview gracefully negates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s previous denials (real, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freudian</ENAMEX>) of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s affairs, and might prevent her "vast right-wing conspiracy" sound
bites from being played ad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nauseum</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race. Aside from sheer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buzz</ENAMEX> (of which she's already got plenty), can you think of any other reason why
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, finally striking out on her own, is rehashing her marital
troubles?

            I also want to ask you for help in reading the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>'s
front-page account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Barton</ENAMEX>'s online-trading history. The story includes
a token caveat that "his actions can't be blamed just on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading," but then
recounts exactly how his deep losses led to the massacre. How are we supposed
to read a story containing a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-line disclaimer that contradicts its entire
narrative thrust? Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, I have been wondering if an unlucky gambler
has ever opened fire in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casino</ENAMEX>, or if any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockbrokers</ENAMEX> who
committed suicide in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'29</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'87</NUMEX> ever hurt anyone but themselves. Please let me
know if you've seen any stories that answer me.

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jodi</ENAMEX>

            P.S.: I love it when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> are deadpan. The terrific Times
biz-section story on the ad industry's all-too-sudden, profit-motivated
defection to the anti-smoking camp quotes an advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alex</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bogusky</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
