
   
   
      
         
            What Does W. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stand For</ENAMEX>?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> has
featured on its front page a new installment of a vast profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. The length of a short
book, the series has explored every nook and cranny of the presumptive
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>'s biography. We hear at length about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s childhood
reaction to his little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s death from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>, his pole vault over the
waiting list for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Air National Guard</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, and his conversion from
Wild <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cold Turkey</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. But as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (part <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>), we
have learned approximately nothing about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> thinks about
politics.

            This isn't just the fault of policy-averse,
personality-driven journalism (though it is partly that). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Visit George Bush</ENAMEX>'s
Web site, read his
speeches and statements, and you will remain unenlightened as to his views.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> offers conventional conservative's bromides about the economy and the
family and spends a lot of time talking about his signature idea: faith-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> programs. But if he has a political philosophy that goes beyond
pro-business pragmatism and personal concern for society's unfortunates, he's
hiding it awfully well.

            The problem here isn't simply the lack
of specifics--what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> disparages as "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-point plans." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of his brain
trust are working on position papers at this very moment, and they'll soon
provide the absent details. What's odd--and a bit worrying--is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has embarked on a presidential campaign lacking something even more basic:
the sort of world-view or approach that equips <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to formulate an
agenda in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.

            On the great issues of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> isn't a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pragmatist</ENAMEX>. He's a cipher. In an interview excerpt, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reporters
ask him whether it is true, as they heard from others, that during the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
War, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> argued on both sides of the issue. Here's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W.</ENAMEX>'s response: "I don't
remember debates. I don't think we spent a lot of time debating it. Maybe we
did, but I don't remember." This does not appear to be a convenient failure to
recall opinions that have since become unpopular or embarrassing. It's the
absence of any opinion at all. It's hard to believe, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">front-runner</ENAMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential race is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who can't remember what he thought--or if
in fact he thought at all--about the conflict that defined his
generation.

            In an article in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> offered a theory about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has neutralized the
religious right. Though he eschews most of the issues and themes dear to social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX>, such as actually trying to ban abortion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wears his
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> beliefs on his sleeve. You might say that he does something similar
with secularized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> as well, substituting his personal sense of compassion
for the kind of policies that could do something to help the poor. In a big
speech in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> singled out a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Texas</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> line up at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> for free
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dentistry</ENAMEX>. That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> cares about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> waiting outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> makes
you think he's a decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who can't afford to get their
teeth fixed don't need religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX>. They need dental
insurance.

            To say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is untainted by ideology does not
mean he lacks political instincts. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> did in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, he seems to
have a fine grasp on why so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are turned off by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> seems
prepared to spill some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> off the right side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX> in order to
get it upright again. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, it was reported that he had registered Internet
domain names for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX> potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> tickets: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush-Engler</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ridge</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All four</NUMEX> are centrist northern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>. This was
a powerful hint that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> intends to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Robertson</ENAMEX> to go play in traffic. I
predict that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> will soon find a moment to blast some marginal figure on the
right's ideological fringe, the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> dissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souljah</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            When your task is unifying a divided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, knowing
what views to reject, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> seems to, may be more important than knowing what
policies you support. Those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> with strong and consistent
ideological views--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Keyes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX>--can appeal only to
small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>. Others who are eager to serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> for
compromise look unprincipled because of their past records and comments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX>, for instance, has undergone a campaign conversion from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supply-sider</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pious</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>-values conservative. The result is that no one quite trusts
him.

            Not having a record on national issues makes it
easier to position oneself according to the current political wisdom. That's
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> generally make better presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>--they don't have congressional voting records to constrict their
evolution. Better still is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> who lacks even private opinions. He's a
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>'s perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX> doll. You can dress him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s
fashions. And no one will remember him wearing anything different.

         
      
   
