
   
   
      
         
            Talk: The Web Site!

            Omigodomigodomigodomigodomigodomigodomigod! Talk is out!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is so excited by the hype surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>--the most eagerly anticipated public document since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Report</ENAMEX>--that he wonders how he'll ever be able to actually sit down and
read the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Paris-Match-esque</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX>, which hits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsstands</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
(For a sampling of the newspaper coverage, see "
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>.")

            Amid all the hoopla, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> hasn't seen any attention lavished
on Talk's bold and imaginative Web site (which is not to be confused with the highly
entertaining Talk parody site posted prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mischievous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill's Content</ENAMEX> ; see "
Too <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Funny for Brill's Content "</ENAMEX>). The Talk Web site can
only be described as ... well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revolutionary</ENAMEX>. Chatterbox, who obviously doesn't
know how to think outside the box, figured the Talk Web site would
carry an article or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, and some information on how to
subscribe. How wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> was! The Talk Web site is actually an entirely black screen
with the Talk logo (white letters, lower-case "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">t</ENAMEX>" boxed in a red
rectangle with uneven <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX>--or does that make it a trapezoid?) smack in the
middle. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>--hidebound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX> that he was--clicked on the logo, expecting
to be transported into some magical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinaland</ENAMEX>. But no! You click on the logo and
nothing happens! The point of the Talk Web site isn't to spoon-feed you some
ready-made notion of what Talk is! It's an invitation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to
project his most elaborate fantasies onto what Talk could be!
It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st-century</TIMEX>! It's digital! It's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pokémon and A.M. Homes</ENAMEX> and day
trading and The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project and laser eye surgery and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX>'s bank account all rolled into one!!!!

         
      
   
