
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cocaine Straw</ENAMEX> Poll
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> tax-cut war. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s Talk
magazine interview. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> is campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>--including the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> straw
poll and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s refusal to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>-use rumors.

            The opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> grows increasingly pessimistic that a tax-cut compromise
will be reached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>--this despite assertions to the contrary by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
Majority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> (on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Sunday</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senators</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Voinovich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, and  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Santorum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pa.</ENAMEX> (on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s Late
Edition ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s veto threat is real, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> say, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> just
wants to use the tax issue as an electoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Gang</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox ; Fox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mara Liasson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Williams</ENAMEX>; Late

               Edition's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Gigot</NUMEX> points out that many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want to see the tax issue off the table, and that at least
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are willing to pass a bill, if not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> ones.
Late 
               Edition's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> points out that a do-nothing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> isn't a bad thing, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> thinks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> passed the tax cuts to
please campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>, not to campaign for. A few other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pundits</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Page</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Fund</ENAMEX> (both of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin Group</ENAMEX> )--think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> will compromise at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the 11th hour</TIMEX>,
as he did with welfare reform in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second week</TIMEX> in a row the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits slam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> for her comments in
Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. Some say her probable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> senate campaign is a
public exercise of  marital therapy ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> trots out a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> campaign video in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>--the same woman
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> seemed to blame in Talk . Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX>, such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Clift</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX>, admit
that the comments were unfortunate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> proposes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s interview was part of an elaborate fundraising strategy for her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senate</ENAMEX> campaign; the comments may hurt her politically, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morris</ENAMEX> reasons, but
defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> helps her curry favor with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Clift</NUMEX> points out that when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> story first broke, the
same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX> who now decry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s attempts at
psychoanalysis were enthusiastically probing the roots of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s "sex
addiction."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> are divided on the importance of the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> straw poll. Some,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Will</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s This 
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX> ,
think it genuinely tests a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s grassroots organizing ability. Others,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX>, argue that since voting in the straw poll costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> and is on a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">weekday</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> who can afford to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> and subsidize the most people
will win. Most agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> have
the most to lose. Some speculate that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> could make a surprisingly
strong showing.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>'s refusal to answer questions about
possible <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> use is untenable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>, and This

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s response indicates "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chink</ENAMEX> in the armor." Will notes that in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s Talk magazine interview
(separate from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> uses the f-word frequently and seems to poke
fun at a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">death-row prisoner</ENAMEX> to whom he refused clemency. Among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissenters</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> use is "an irrelevant question in politics,"
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Beirne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> say it won't matter because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s lead is too
strong.

            

               Why Not Just Use the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">B-Word</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>?
"This wasn't an accident, as some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> are
saying--[that] she just blurted it out. She is a very manipulative, conniving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>."
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Novak</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s marital revelations in Talk
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kid</ENAMEX>--I've Been There
"I mean, I've sat in these [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>] meetings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>. I know how it
works."
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, when another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> doubts his theory that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s Talk interview was an intentional fundraising strategy

            
               Last Word
"<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next week</TIMEX> we're going to find out she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-twelfth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX>."
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blankley</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s assertion that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
