
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oink</ENAMEX>!

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, as everyone knows, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that believes in the free market,
opposes big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and takes particular exception to welfare programs. But
then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> fall over each
other telling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hog</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> that the free market is unfair, that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> isn't doing enough to help them, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> should
support them when they fail to make money on their own.

            To be sure, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> do the same thing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> recently called for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 billion</NUMEX> in "emergency" aid and reversed his longtime opposition to
subsidies for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> derived from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> (his thoughtful explanation: "I
changed my mind"). Yet it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> who have taken ag-pandering to a
new level <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, in advance of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s straw poll in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX>. With the
exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, who opposes ethanol subsidies (and isn't
participating in the poll) all have adopted a blank-check approach to the farm
issue. Here's what the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> are offering as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-point program:

            

               Would work aggressively to open markets for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> products and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>.

               Would not use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> as a unilateral sanction or diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>.

               Emergency disaster relief, both through direct payments to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">reformed crop</ENAMEX> insurance.

               Tax incentives for use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>.

               Calls upon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> to accept findings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> and allow importation of genetically modified farm products.

            

            
               Comment : Very compassionate!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ag Stimulus Package</ENAMEX>."

            

               Tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX>, if you don't buy our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>, we won't buy your
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>.

               Double the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> market and raise the price of corn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 cents</NUMEX> a bushel by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">banning MTBE</ENAMEX>, the oil-based <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gasoline additive</ENAMEX>.

               Double export credit guarantees to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

               Double federal support for research at land grant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>.

               Repeal the inheritance tax for the sake of farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.

               Reduce the number of food sanctions.

            

            
               Comment : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pssst</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>--I don't think we buy their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Dole</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>-point farm program:

            

               Mandatory federal price reporting for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>.

               An increase in exports under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace</ENAMEX> program.

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> utilization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservation Reserve</ENAMEX> Program.

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> utilization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Export Enhancement Program</ENAMEX>.

               Increased promotion and use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX>.

               Enactment of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Fast Track</ENAMEX> trade-negotiating authority so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> can have
access to foreign markets.

               Allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s entry into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Organization</ENAMEX>.

               An immediate <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> tax deduction for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>' health insurance
premiums.

               Elimination of death taxes on family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX>.

               Helping rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> receive access to technology.

            

            
               Comment : The part about no inheritance taxes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> sounds
especially fair.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Family</ENAMEX> Farm <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill of Rights</ENAMEX>."

            

               Eliminate all inheritance and capital gains taxes.

               Insist that all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that trade with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> open access to their markets absent tariffs and quotas.

               Abolish the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> and end <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> bailouts of foreign competitors
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>.

               Review all embargoes and sanctions of foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that use food
exports as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>.

               Enforce existing antitrust laws to prevent mega-mergers.

               Require price disclosure.

               Support <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethanol</ENAMEX> production.

               Rewrite the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Endangered Species</ENAMEX> Act to require a vote of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> on every
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">species</ENAMEX> listed.

               Exempt family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OSHA</ENAMEX>.

               End the regulatory theft of property without just compensation.

            

            
               Comment : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pitchfork Pat</ENAMEX> is back!

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>' "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm Recovery Plan</ENAMEX>"

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> should ease its tight money policy and immediately reduce real
interest rates.

               Tear down trade barriers and bust open new markets.

               Help our foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> get back on their feet.

               Dramatically reduce the tax burden and abolish the death (a.k.a. "estate")
tax.

               Dramatically reduce the regulatory burden.

               Investigate potential anti-competitive practices.

            

            
               Comment : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX>: The only rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who thinks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> is doing a bad job.

         
      
   
