
   
   
      
         
            The Net: The Crack of the '90s
            

            It's painful to watch the demise of a city <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX>. We went through it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Mirror</ENAMEX> shut down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Newsday</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prematurely</ENAMEX>, I still
believe: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> had already broken even and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s economy would
probably be adding <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shareholders</ENAMEX>' profits.) On the
other side, I correctly predicted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> out of the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> deaths of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> .

            As you've indicated, newspaper competition is often better in theory than in
practice. I remember visiting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> who had
a front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> reproduced on her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> bulletin board.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> story was about marijuana consumption; another about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate</ENAMEX>. She had
written: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slowest</ENAMEX> news day of all time" on her copy, but from what you say it
sounds more like business as usual. Still, whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chronicles</ENAMEX>'s
weaknesses, it seems unlikely that eliminating competition will make them
better.

            As for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> , it's still kicking, and usually kicking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s front page: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WHAT HILLARY DIDN'T SAY/Author:</ENAMEX>
She skirted issue of sex addiction in interview."

            It seems entirely possible that anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> stories could take up
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">three-quarters</ENAMEX> of the front pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between now</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Election</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day 2000</TIMEX>, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> where the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-but-declared-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate first lady</ENAMEX> is
reasonably popular. That political truncheon gives you some idea of why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> keeps the money-losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> around. But then, since Fast
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s chief competition, maybe the less I say on
this subject the better.

            I can't say I liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuczynski</ENAMEX> piece much. The article quotes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Esquire editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Granger</ENAMEX> blaming, among other factors, the Internet
for the putative inability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> to engage in real debate. This <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX> my
theory that the Internet is becoming to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '90s</TIMEX> what crack was to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '80s</TIMEX>--a catchall explanation for everything that goes wrong in a
particular sector. Crime up? Must be crack. Circulation down? Must be the
Internet. Magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> don't have a clue about what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> really want?
Gotta be the Internet.

            I admire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger</ENAMEX> for turning his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> around somewhat when everyone else
was ready to apply embalming fluid. But for him to assert--and for the
Times to accept--a causal link between the Net's rise and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Esquire</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade-long</TIMEX> tumble is ridiculous. The decline of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general-interest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> has been with us for a lot longer than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuczynski</ENAMEX> or
Granger have had a login and password. Unfortunately, the reasons--increased
number of titles, declining newsstand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sell-through</ENAMEX>, etc.--are often very dull,
and so it's much easier just to blame the Net. (To be fair, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
piece does mention other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>, but I still find it an unambitious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mishmash</ENAMEX>.)

            Not that the Net doesn't change things. Just turn the page to find the story
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cisco Systems</ENAMEX> investing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a billion dollars</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KPMG</ENAMEX>, the accounting and
consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX> taking over the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Old: Now</ENAMEX>, there's a
story for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that wants to engage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
