
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rage</ENAMEX> Against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machine</ENAMEX>
            

            I heard about the workplace anger survey <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX>. If I
understand it correctly, this "study" was issued by a marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> whose
"research" consisted largely, or maybe entirely, of reading the results of a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallup</ENAMEX> poll. That strikes me as a shade less than clinically reliable; in
fact, it makes me angry!

            Still, I can relate to the anger-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-work <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>. It's silly to blame the
Internet, but I would argue that technology is a major factor. It's not just
the increasing complexity of technology, but our increased reliance on it. As
someone whose work life is largely "remote," I can testify to the frustration
at high-tech stuff that just doesn't function as it should. The simple process
of my filing a timely story for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>'s Web site can get
amazingly clogged. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editors</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> get in the habit of thinking that
properly working technology is a given; in fact, it's more like a best-case
scenario. Take their high expectations against shoddy machine or network
performance and you've got a sure-fire recipe for office rage.

            Did you see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Judge</ENAMEX> movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office Space</ENAMEX> ? Like all his work,
it's uneven. But my favorite scene is where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> disgruntled software
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> take a constantly malfunctioning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX> out to a field, and
proceed to kick the living toner out of the thing. It's all shot in slow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motion</ENAMEX>, like a mob pounding from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coen Brothers</ENAMEX> film, with a nasty rap
soundtrack.

            Kicking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">printer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
