
   
   
      
         
            Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX> Ever Use <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Cocaine</ENAMEX>?

            Don't get Chatterbox wrong. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> believes there are legitimate
"character issues" to raise about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. Even though most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s curiosity about the racial covenant on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s former
residence to be prurient and irresponsible, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> continues to desire a
fuller explanation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> about it. (See "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Bush</ENAMEX>'s Neighborhood.") <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has also been brooding a bit about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s mocking remarks to Talk's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX> about pleas for clemency
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karla Faye Tucker</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">axe-murderess</ENAMEX> who was executed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
(See "
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puff Patrol</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ballot Box</ENAMEX> for the ugly details.)

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thinks the media swarm surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s refusal
to say whether he's ever used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> is ridiculous and irresponsible. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> wrote recently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> (tragically, the article
isn't online), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> believes the sensible reportorial response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s
selective silence should be: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> probably used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> sometime in his
life; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) who cares? Yet the question keeps coming up--increasingly, swathed
in dispassionate meta-analysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> brings <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> pondering the media angle: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> sent a questionnaire to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> presidential candidates
asking whether they'd used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>. (Why didn't they just send a questionnaire
saying, "Is your name <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>?") <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eleven</NUMEX> denied they'd ever used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">The 12th</TIMEX> (heh, heh) refused to answer.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> decided the time had come to conduct a poll of his own, asking
various political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> who had written about this question,
or (more typically) had written or commented publicly about writing or
commenting publicly about this question, whether they'd ever used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>. Here
are the results:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howie Kurtz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> : "It would be hard for
me to claim to have a drug-free college education, but I'm not going to go into
the sordid details."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: Probable yes.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Burger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: Probable no.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeFrank</ENAMEX>, bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> : "
               No. I
went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas A&M</ENAMEX>, don't forget. I went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas A&M</ENAMEX> when it was all
male and all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: Almost certain no. (Full disclosure: Chatterbox
used to work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeFrank</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Joan Pollock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> : "You
know what? I am not gonna answer that question ... but I'm amused." (She said
this very good-naturedly.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: Probable yes. (Full disclosure: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> used to
work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollock</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> .)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX>, former campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'88</NUMEX>: "I think I'll
pass on this one--I go back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Ginsburg</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, and I passed then, on
the theory that we shouldn't be asking these questions ... and if we don't ask
them, we don't have to answer them." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ginsberg</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
appointment cratered after he admitted to having used marijuana long
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: Probable yes. (Full disclosure: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has
never met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estrich</ENAMEX>.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>, pundit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: Almost certain no. (This admission dents his
glamorous image. Besides, he got asked the same thing by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> when he went
to work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, and if he were lying now he'd have to fear being
ratted out by a disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G</ENAMEX>-man.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Brown</ENAMEX>, news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, WMUR: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No</ENAMEX>, I've not."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: Probable no.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cokie Roberts</ENAMEX>, pundit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX>: [Didn't return <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s phone
call.]
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> and a nice
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, almost certainly not.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lois Romano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
               
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">;</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Lardner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> : [Also didn't return <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s phone
calls.]
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: No idea. None of them appear to have been at their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Saletan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: Probable no.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No.</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: Probable no.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Stern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX>: "Yeah you big goofball.
But I did it with you! (Don't tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.)"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> concludes: Definitely lying.

            OK, OK, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> isn't lying. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> tried <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice about 20</NUMEX> years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. It was so wonderful that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> resolved never to try it again, and he
never has. The jurisdiction is none of your business.

            
               
                  Photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Slate Table of Contents</ENAMEX> by
Corbis/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ressmeyer</ENAMEX>.
               
            

         
      
   
