
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilded</ENAMEX> and the Unvarnished
            

            Good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>:

            What a glorious, air-conditioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            Even though my <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rotisserie</ENAMEX> baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nattering Nabobs</ENAMEX>) is mired in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> division, I began my reading rounds by checking the late <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>
box scores in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . My eyes then darted over to a comment by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Mariners</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Griffey Jr.</ENAMEX>, in response to press comments
reportedly made by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Griffey</ENAMEX>). Said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffey</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Younger</ENAMEX>: "My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s been in baseball how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>? He knows what to say
and what not to say."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Griffey</ENAMEX>'s remark conjured up the famous scene in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bull Durham</ENAMEX> in which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> instructs a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> in the art of answering all press
questions with innocuous sports cliches. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, as even toddlers learn how
to practice "spin," virtually everyone quoted in the news knows "what to say
and what not to say." That's why I'm going to devote <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> missive to
the handful of brave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX> who dared to tell truth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s papers.

            Hats off to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Budget Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Dominici</ENAMEX>, who is trying to
put the brakes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' heedless zeal to pass a tax-cut bill in
order to provoke a presidential veto they can then use in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> campaign. As
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> puts it, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dominici</ENAMEX> is concerned that the [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> may end up with an issue but no legislation." That, of course, is
exactly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s game plan. The danger lurking just offshore like a
surplus-eating <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> will ultimately agree to something
like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600-billion</NUMEX> tax cut in order to clear the decks for some sort of grand
compromise on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>.

            Buried inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Klain</ENAMEX>, has resigned to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Melvany & Myers</ENAMEX>. It had long been rumored that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klain</ENAMEX> was about to take
the fall for the snafus that have bedeviled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s campaign. Kudos to Katharine
Seelye, who didn't pull any punches on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klain</ENAMEX> ouster in her short piece in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . She quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> who recounted that in a recent
meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klain</ENAMEX> said he was "like a milk carton, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk cartons</ENAMEX> have an
expiration date." But in his on-the- record comments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klain</ENAMEX> gave a full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durham</ENAMEX> , claiming that "my heart said stay, but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> told me it was time
to move on."

            I was deeply saddened to read of the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Morris</ENAMEX>, someone I never
met but long admired. As a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1960s</TIMEX>, I remember how I
thrilled to read each issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morris</ENAMEX>' tenure as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Applebome</ENAMEX>, who wrote the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times obit</ENAMEX>, wins truth-telling points for
a paragraph that began, "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> drank too much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bourbon</ENAMEX> and red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, smoked
too many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Viceroys</ENAMEX>, stayed up too late and caroused too much."

            Now for some unfinished business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, I awoke still feeling the stab marks
from your last entry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. OK, my sentence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about day</TIMEX> trading being
emblematic of the "glitz-and-greed '90s" was not worthy of being included in my
collected works. But something weird is happening out there, which makes the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late '90s</TIMEX> different from the "junk-bond era and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas Strip</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro</ENAMEX> section of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> features a sad story
about the money woes and vituperative divorce proceedings of local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Moran</ENAMEX>. Court papers filed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Moran</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>'s
estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, allege that the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX> had a history of
"wasting the family assets on his stock market gambling." And the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> , returning to the perils of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading, begins a Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> with the tale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Harkness</ENAMEX>, a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthropology professor</ENAMEX>, who
"was seduced by the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gilded Age</ENAMEX>." Harkness, who used to safeguard her money
in thrift accounts, claims to have made money in the market. But, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> observes, "from cautious saver to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen speculator</ENAMEX> in just a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>--that's quite a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trek</ENAMEX> across the spectrum of financial risk."

            Anyway, it's time for me to make a trek of my own off to a newsstand in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quest</ENAMEX> of my very own inaugural issue of Talk . Something tells me that it
won't shimmer anything like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Morris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harper</ENAMEX>'s .

            Eagerly awaiting your epiphanies from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
