
   
   
      
         
            Armbands, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">But No Arms Banned</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the surrender to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">L.A. Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community center</ENAMEX> shootings, a development that off-leads at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
is fronted, (below the fold) at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads instead with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>'
decision to stop requiring the teaching of evolution as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
science curriculum. The decision also deletes most classroom references to the
big bang theory. One likely result observed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kansas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> will be unprepared for college admissions tests and college science
courses. The story is carried inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USAT</ENAMEX> leads with
the tornado that hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> (as far as
anyone can tell, the first tornado death in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>) and injuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tornado</ENAMEX> is also fronted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and is the top non-local story at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which leads with the worsening drought in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> shooting coverage reports that the subject of a nationwide manhunt,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buford Furrow</ENAMEX>, materialized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> unarmed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, and surrendered, telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> (in fact, say the
papers, he confessed to murdering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, but none of those
shot there have died) and that his purpose in committing the crime was to issue
"a wake-up call" for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to start killing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s end, Furrow
was brought back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> where <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> say, he will be charged
with attempted murder in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community center</ENAMEX> shootings and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> degree murder
in the death of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> letter carrier <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour later</TIMEX>.

            The papers report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furrow</ENAMEX> is speaking freely to the cops, particularly
helpful to them in the murder case for which there are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>. The
coverage includes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the de rigueur</TIMEX> interviews with shocked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>,
and depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Furrow</ENAMEX> as a neo-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> racist, who has been involved with each of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">white</ENAMEX> hate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front features a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furrow</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX>-style uniform.) And also as a troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">loser</ENAMEX>, who
after his prior arrest for pulling a knife on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> at a mental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, where he lived, told cops he often thought of killing others
and himself. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that several times he cut
himself with a knife, once, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> almost severing a finger.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furrow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arsenal</ENAMEX> included an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uzi</ENAMEX> assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> won't confirm this. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> wonders how a rabid
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Semite</ENAMEX> justifies or trusts using an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uzi</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX>.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story</ENAMEX> inside reporting that one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furrow</ENAMEX>'s weapons
was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">AR-15</ENAMEX> assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX>, apparently purchased piecemeal and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">custom</ENAMEX>-assembled. The central part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> was manufactured, says the
paper, by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> presided over by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who had been the state
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX> job became an issue. The
AR-15 possession wasn't legal, because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furrow</ENAMEX> is a convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX>, but easier
to do prior to the Brady Bill, the paper notes. The story also says that Furrow
told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> when arrested previously that in his glove compartment, he
always carried a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">9mm Taurus</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX>, a gun featured in an unrelated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-pager <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead editorial about the shooting makes a pitch for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
to do something serious about gun control. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead editorial says
that the event shows that hate crime laws are justified, that the criminal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX> system should keep better tabs on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furrow</ENAMEX>, and they should
be getting better access to psychiatric help. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> mystery the coverage doesn't
make much progress on is: How did <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Furrow</ENAMEX> come to target the day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> fascinates with the news that a tour <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of</ENAMEX>
Tolerance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furrow</ENAMEX> visited there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several weeks ago</TIMEX> and
attracted the attention of security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>  but disappeared before he could
be questioned.

            
               USAT fronts word that so far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have
died in hot <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. Papers should avoid inflicting this sort of information
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> sans context. For instance, how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have been killed in
car crashes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, or shot? The story doesn't say.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> dispatch relating the latest in a series of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goofball</ENAMEX> comments by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX>. While on a factory tour near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>, PP
saw a poorly wired fuse box and said, "It looks as though it was put in by an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>."

            Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>: Enough with the automatic full-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-name treatment of
heinous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>. That's a convention from Wanted posters that you should
adopt only if you also agree to run only front-and-profile pictures of
them.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Berke</ENAMEX>, picking up on and crediting a column by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> is considering running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>, a
longtime liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>, is unhappy about the failure of campaign finance
reform and tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> he's talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> instrumental in
previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> campaigns. Oddly, the story doesn't mention
Bulworth , nor does it mention a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>'s epidemic bimbonic
plague possibilities.

         
      
   
