
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox Rules</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Spiegelman</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Rall</ENAMEX>

            Consider this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> fight in world of big-time comics. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s
Village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Rall</ENAMEX> writes a vicious
takedown of the "<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">90,000-pound</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorilla</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> cartooning," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Art</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiegelman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rall</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiegelman</ENAMEX>, after winning a special <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>
for his graphic novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maus</ENAMEX> , became the de facto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the
sprawling world of "underground comix" and gained the kind of mainstream fame
and acceptance most cartoonists only dream of.

            Did he deserve it? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rall</ENAMEX> thinks not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiegelman</ENAMEX>'s notoriously provocative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> covers<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "Cheap and hollow." His role as the chosen cartoonist
of the intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>? A result of living "in a media <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
too busy to keep track of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> name per area of expertise." His
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer?</ENAMEX> "Winning a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize</ENAMEX> for a graphic novel is easy when you've
written the only graphic novel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour Topping</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>]
probably ever opened," not to mention that because it was a special citation
(and not in the cartooning category), he had no direct competition. For his
coup de grâce , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rall dismisses Spiegelman</ENAMEX>'s entire future career:
"Nothing on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX>'s résumé comes close to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maus</ENAMEX> in quality or concept. Even
some of his most ardent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> concede that he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX> of
cartooning, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with one great book in him."

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX>'s letters column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, cartoonists
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX> and small (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Pekar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Breen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Ware</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Millionaire</ENAMEX>, and
others) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chip Kidd</ENAMEX> take sides. Some praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rall</ENAMEX>'s courage for
taking on the untouchable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiegelman</ENAMEX>. Others say the article is overtly
personal and full of cheap shots from unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. Is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rall</ENAMEX> right, or is
this a case of sour <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grapes</ENAMEX> from a less successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>?

            Some of the attacks are unnecessary and untrue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiegelman</ENAMEX> has not ruined
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> cartooning world, and his promotion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby-boomer cronies</ENAMEX> to the
exclusion of younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> is no crime--everybody tries to give their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
a hand. In other respects, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rall</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> are right on.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiegelman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> covers are heavy-handed, with their
predictably inflammatory subjects. His obituary for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prohias</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> magazine was, for a tribute,
unbearably self-referential (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> paragraphs discussed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prohias</ENAMEX>, the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discussed Spiegelman</ENAMEX>). 

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rall</ENAMEX> also points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiegelman</ENAMEX> has developed a nice little monopoly on
the subject of cartooning in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> of note. Maybe now that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rall</ENAMEX> has stirred up the pot, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX> will choose somebody a little more interesting the next
time they want that kind of article--someone, perhaps, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Rall</ENAMEX>. Should
they? Read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> article, check out the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Rall</ENAMEX> and
Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiegelman</ENAMEX>, and let us know what you think.

         
      
   
