
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fat Catastrophe</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s forceful military reaction against
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insurgents</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dagestan</ENAMEX> (a story it fronted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>).
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Early Monday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> dismissed his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, creating
yet another political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> crisis for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, which faces a
parliamentary election at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> and a presidential one in the
middle of the next. Because of the development's late break, of the early
editions, only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> has it, in the form of a reefer box. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fronts Dagestan</ENAMEX>, but leads with further evidence of exponential political
inflation--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>'s quiet creation of an elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> stuffs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dagestan</ENAMEX> and goes instead with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>'s apparent loosening of its previous policy of automatically detaining
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with a story that gets front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s carrying of the fight over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> proposed
tax cuts to the national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>' meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told the state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>
the cuts could force deep cuts in domestic programs and raise interest rates.
Yet, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also said that he thought a smaller tax cut
could and should be passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Some of the coverage marks the continuing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> gravitization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX>. Front-page pictures from the meeting at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> show a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ventura</ENAMEX> talking,
very much equals, pictorially at least. (This represents a very conscious
choice by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>--after all, during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s appearance he no doubt appeared
at least briefly with nearly every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> has its own top fat
category requiring an individual contribution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350,000</NUMEX>, and goes on to
observe that if both parties meet their high-donor goals, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will
have raised twice as much money via this route as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. This is all
soft money, not governed by the rules for individual, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>, or corporate
campaign contributions, because it's collected for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>-building activities
and issue ads rather than for individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidacies</ENAMEX>, and the paper explains
that the new high levels of giving mean that the total amount of soft money collected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> could double the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> amount.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> illustration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> shift is the release <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who had been jailed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> because she was on
probation following a conviction for shoplifting clothes for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. And
the story provides no examples of obviously dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> snagged by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> under the old policy. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> goes on to admit that it's unclear how
many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> affected are like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and how many are
more serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King Abdullah</ENAMEX>, has in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX> twice gone out among his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> on undercover fact-finding missions, once pretending to be a
television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> (complete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>) and once an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">taxicab</ENAMEX>. Both stories (and isn't it curious that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> would
independently front such a soft feature?) note that there is a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab</ENAMEX>
tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> going out in mufti, with the overall feeling being that
this is a quaint feature of a veil- and robe-enmeshed culture. Neither story
notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> would also be a good way for an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to
find out what real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> put up with and what they actually think. If a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has a certain knack for, ahem, sneaking around, he might as well do
it for the public good.

            The LAT fronts a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10.5</NUMEX>
million lawsuit being brought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> by a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> mechanic against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for its failure to take
seriously racial harassment he suffered on the job. In a company <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, the lone black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew chief</ENAMEX> at his work space, discovered a depiction of
himself next to the words, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nigger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigger, Nigger</ENAMEX>." And then there was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hangman</ENAMEX>'s noose--not a drawing, an actual rope noose--hanging over a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">passageway</ENAMEX>. In a pre-trial deposition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> testified that he
thought displaying nooses could be offensive, but he did not think it was a
form of harassment. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> tried to retreat from this view after a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">23-minute</TIMEX>
break called by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is to be saluted for running
this story prominently, and if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> is smart it'll settle this case before
large numbers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX> daily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> decide there are plenty of
other morally sound ways to fly out of town.

            The papers nod toward the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">25th</NUMEX> anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s resignation. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager notes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> alive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> hadn't turned
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> yet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, if they were alive at all. And that a recent poll found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> thinking that there have been other political scandals
that were just as bad as <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rule of Law"</ENAMEX> column wonders how it can
be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> got invited to give the keynote address to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> was never so invited, and indeed was
ultimately disbarred. On the LAT op-ed page, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Reeves</ENAMEX>
digs up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben Franklin</ENAMEX>-style memo <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> wrote to himself, that he violated with
just about every waking breath: "Need to be good to do good. Need for joy,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">serenity</ENAMEX>, confidence, inspirational."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX>'s media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> reports there's grumbling in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">newsroom</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville Tennessean</ENAMEX> over the appearance in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
campaign video by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s. And indeed, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> has now said the appearance was a mistake. This is dumb. Isn't the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> allowed to also have a private role as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX>? And even in his public
role, there's an excellent chance his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> under his direction will
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">endorse Gore</ENAMEX>'s candidacy. So obviously, it's okay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to know what he
thinks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
