
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rage for Rage's Sake</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi Jim</ENAMEX>:

            As a fellow remote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>, I empathize with your rage against the machine,
although I am still not willing to concede that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">workplace rage</ENAMEX>" is a phenom
worth adding to the lexicon.

            I haven't seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office Space</ENAMEX> , but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Burning Man festival</ENAMEX>,
that annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> orgy of all things arty and survivalist held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>'s
Black <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rock Desert</ENAMEX>, I saw computer programmers gleefully blowing up old hard
drives and monitors just for fun. How's that for evidence of dependence on
technology breeding antipathy toward it, not to mention the self-evident
visceral pleasure of detonating expensive equipment that so quickly becomes
obsolete? Boom.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s media offer a nice corollary to your rage against the machine, in
the form of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Friedman</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Affairs</ENAMEX>" column "The Y2K <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Disease</ENAMEX>"
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . What's more annoying than technology that doesn't
work when you need it to? How about other's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s technology invading your
space? And the chilling implications of none of us ever really being logged
off? Technology is making the boundaries between work and play evaporate,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> worries, until there will be no downtime. Work, as the saying goes, is
expanding to fill all available time, now with the help of these handy
interruption devices--pager, cell phone, fax, handheld.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friedman</ENAMEX> declares that the real Y2K problem is overconnectedness. He
fantasizes about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> of the future with cell phone and no cell phone
sections. (Here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay Area</ENAMEX>, I've been to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> eating
establishment with signs explicitly forbidding the use of cell phones, but have
yet to see the appearance of phoning sections.)

            But guess what? This phenomenon of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">overconnectedness</ENAMEX> turns out to be just
another excuse to add <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more new rage to our list, which is growing seemingly
by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hour</TIMEX>, road rage, air rage, workplace rage, now "Y2K rage."

            "More and more I find myself reacting to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with cell phones the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> I react to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> smoking cigars at the dinner table next to me--violently.
I call it Y2K rage," he writes.

            I would like to discourse further on the changing nature of the relationship
between work and life as influenced by technology, but I'm seething about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rash</ENAMEX> of new rages in our midst. Am I suffering from rage rage?

            Send soothing words.
Katharine

         
      
   
