
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Hart Show</ENAMEX>

            The papers deliver a quiet, analysis-heavy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, with no overlap among the
front pages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
details vast wastefulness at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Administration</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times describes the legal defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>, the suspected Los
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alamos</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> mulls over the causes of partisan
divisiveness in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead indicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Administration</ENAMEX> for wasting over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> on maintaining unnecessary and underpopulated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. The
number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> is shrinking and the popularity of outpatient treatment is
growing, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX> stubbornly refuses to close its unneeded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>-- even
though, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report, the money saved could be better spent on
enhanced care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> view the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> as "a national
asset that must be preserved" and insist that they "have earned the right to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> offers a sneak preview of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>'s defense against
charges that he committed espionage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> will decide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming weeks</TIMEX> if and on what counts to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecute Lee</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> transferred classified
files to an unprotected local area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, he was merely making backups in
case the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">originals</ENAMEX> crashed. They also call the potential prosecution a result
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-Chinese</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">xenophobia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that despite their recent mergers and
triangulations into each other's ideological territory, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are unusually adverse to compromise. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
chose to risk a veto on their tax cut rather than settle for a smaller <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> refused to support light restrictions on gun control when their
stricter package was defeated. Potential causes for the inflexibility include
post-impeachment rancor, pre-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> election shadowboxing, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s waning
majority in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, normally an avid deal-cutter, may
prefer to let issues such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and gun control <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stall</ENAMEX>, in the hope that
they will later fuel the election of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager narrates how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> has already seduced
powerful trade group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>, who usually wait to lavish their money and
support until a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> is chosen. Specifically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has used the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> as a conduit to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX>. He has already registered donations
from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,542</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO types</ENAMEX>, as opposed to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">264</NUMEX> who have shelled out for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>.
The piece implies that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> is hypocritical: although it "aspires
to outside-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> populism," it has "eagerly exploited every advantage ...
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has to offer."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> a canny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> in the contest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> has consciously avoided the mistakes made by other
once-promising potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>. "We're <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> but we have money. ...
We're <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> but we know the rules," brags a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bradley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>. The story is the
latest in a spate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> pieces to feature a quote embarrassing to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> camp. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> asked me, 'Why are you saying all these
great things about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>? Why don't you say things about us?' " relays the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> piece inside the front section attests to why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forbes</ENAMEX> is a
sharp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>, if not a savvy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>. Despite his regular evisceration
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forbes</ENAMEX> rented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> names from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s subscription
list to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> camp. "We reach a desirable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>," explained a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX>
magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> are being widely cautioned to avoid
staring at the total solar eclipse that will take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11</TIMEX>. Watching the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX>'s emergence from lunar shadow could damage or even eradicate their vision.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Druids</ENAMEX> have other reasons for averting their eyes when the sun and the moon
merge. "A god and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goddess</ENAMEX> are making love," said an <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> moon worshipper.
"We have no right to look upon it."

         
      
   
