
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fined President</ENAMEX>

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the New York
Times lead with the shooting rampage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> killed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and then shot himself in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> as police
closed in. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , which runs the shootings top-of-the-page, leads instead with the
federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s announcement of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$488 billion</NUMEX> to be spent on mortgages and
apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> construction for moderate- and low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, a story
nobody else fronts. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, where jobs have zoomed but affordable housing
has not, will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84 billion</NUMEX> of the subsidy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headline
assumes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> already know quite a bit about the story: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ATLANTA GUNMAN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEAD</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> run the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> picture: a fit-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> followed
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in a suit, both hauling <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ass</ENAMEX> as shots are fired--a sort of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">post-modern Packer</ENAMEX> sweep.

            Besides the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> office building shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>'s suicide, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> found the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>. Also, the coverage notes that he was the prime
suspect, although never charged, in the beating deaths of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and
her mother. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says those occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, everybody else says
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.) There were notes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> found with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of the second
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> as saying
that they mentioned the murders of his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chemist</ENAMEX>-turned-day-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX> who had reportedly run up some
big losses, although the coverage points out that the murders of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> preceded by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a day Thursday</TIMEX>'s big market downturn. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> points out that the rampage combines <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s biggest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phenomena</ENAMEX>--mass shootings and the stock market boom. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> trots out a
quotation it got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the year</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the investment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> where killings took place, in which he compares day-trading to firing a
high-powered <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifle</ENAMEX>: "If you use it right, you will be able to hunt effectively
and bring down nice buck. But if you don't know what you're doing, you'll
probably blow your head off."

            The papers report that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who presided over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>
lawsuit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $90,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for giving false testimony about his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The sum is less than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> asked for, but more than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> offered. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> said that they will pay the money
without further legal protest. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> play the story
below the fold, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reefers it, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs it on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
This play, given the story's unprecedented content, signifies that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> have
just plain had it with the whole topic and are sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> feel
likewise.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has issued an arrest
warrant for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li Hongzhi</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the now-banned sect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falun</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gong</ENAMEX>, charging him with the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>. The papers
note that the warrant is much more political than legal, in that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> does
not have an extradition treaty with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that immediately after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>'s terrorist
bombing of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> detained
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>, only to angrily release them after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> conducted a cruise
missile strike against an alleged chemical weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>. Also, the
paper says, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> claim that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ignored their message that
they had suspects in the case in custody. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>'s
notification has been confirmed by some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s heat wave continues to get coverage, with for instance, a
WP front-pager under the cobwebby headline <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">SCORCHING HEAT WAVE WON'T LET</ENAMEX>
UP and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed reminding us that this is nothing compared to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> drought of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2180</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">B.C. But Today's Papers</ENAMEX> has the nagging feeling that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are pretty much just phoning this one in. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> weather map
shows, for instance, that it's hotter in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Billings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapid City</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> than it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>. So why is it that the latter
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> seem uniquely prone to heatstroke deaths? Is it something about building
construction, energy availability or local lifestyle? And did <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> die from heat in the current kinds of numbers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX>--when
there was no air conditioning? That is, have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> become less tolerant of
heat because of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">A</ENAMEX>/C? The papers don't address any of this. They should.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" notes that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, the jettisoning from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralston</ENAMEX> is viewed as a snub of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>,
which traditionally gets one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX>'s job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>
is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralston</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAF</ENAMEX>. The appointment, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>
legacy of the rise of air power over ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>. Incidentally, it turns out
that a recent column was absolutely wrong in saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> hadn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deigned</ENAMEX> to mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralston</ENAMEX>'s career stall was due to an adulterous affair
he'd been forced to own <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">up to</NUMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story in question, Gen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralston</ENAMEX>'s adultery was there right under <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX>'s nose and yet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers just didn't see it. The whole episode has left <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> feeling,
like, oh...like Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralston</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
