
   
   
      
         
            It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Empty Materialism</ENAMEX>, Stupid

            In bad times, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> run against the economic status quo. In
good times, it seems they strain to do exactly the same thing. Probably the
most distinct theme to emerge thus far among the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">challengers</ENAMEX> to
quasi-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">incumbent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> presidential race is that the material
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wealth of America</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> has brought with it a sense of spiritual
discontent.

            The official slogan of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prosperity With a</ENAMEX>
Purpose," which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> explains by pointing out that "prosperity alone is simple
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">materialism</ENAMEX>." In his "armies of compassion" address in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, he
elaborated a bit more. "The invisible hand works many miracles," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> said.
"But it cannot touch the human heart."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> has been saying essentially the same thing. On "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>"
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Russert</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> to identify the biggest problem confronting
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> cited <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> issues: race and the
lack of meaning. "There is something that's going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that is
widely felt, and that is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> searching for some meaning in their life that
is deeper than the material," he said. "I think that that is a profound
reaction to the materialism of our time and to the hollowness of life if you're
only interested in material things."

            It's hard to disagree with such sentiments, but it's even harder to
understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> are turning them into focuses of their
campaigns. Don't they remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>'s malaise speech? Don't they
remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "politics of meaning" fiasco? <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> tend to be
allergic to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>' dabbling in vague spiritual criticism, and for good
reason. We're electing someone to run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> to the
condition of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>.

            You also have to wonder just whose feelings these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are trying to voice.
Even in flush times like these, it's hard to imagine that a large segment of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX> feels burdened by the spiritual side effects of excessive
wealth. While presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> spend a good deal of time among people
with too much money on their hands (they're called thousand dollar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">contributors</ENAMEX>), this is surely not a significant voting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX>.

            But perhaps such comments are intended less for those who feel afflicted by
this particular form of ennui than for the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> capable of resenting
the rich. On this reading, denouncing the spiritual fallout of excess wealth is
a sophisticated variety of economic populism tailored to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of people
who fully hope to get rich themselves. Like greed, materialism is a vice that
tends to afflict those with more money than oneself. The problem isn't money.
It's the values of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have money. Here the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">multimillionaires</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> may have stumbled upon something rather clever: a kind of rich
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s class warfare. Shunning shallow materialism is a way to express
contempt for the upper class while being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the upper class.

            Still, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> are going to have trouble pulling this off. The last
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to benefit from class warfare was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Roosevelt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> could
do this not just because of his sense of noblesse oblige but because he had
policies to propose that would rein in the rich. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradley</ENAMEX> don't have
any practical suggestions. Instead of taxing and regulating the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">malefactors</ENAMEX> of
great wealth" into submission, they merely suggest we feel sorry for them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> hasn't said anything about empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">materialism</ENAMEX> yet, so he still may
have a chance to differentiate himself. If I were he, I think I'd respond by
saying that excessive prosperity is now a problem for just a few--and that the
next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> should see to it that it afflicts as many of us as possible.

         
      
   
