
   
   
      
         
            All Action and No Talk
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jodi</ENAMEX>,

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> may be the spawning ground of talking heads and the prime target
of right-wing talk radio, but when it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> remains a
no-talking zone. Wandering the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of this provincial backwater, I
discovered yet again that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is all action and no Talk . Not a
copy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> doorstop has arrived at any newsstand I checked. "Maybe
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>," said the only news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX> who had even heard of it.

            So about all I can do is wonder if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX>'s weary stare would have
been as weary if he reversed his word order and intoned, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Success</ENAMEX> is the pox of
celebrity." Or maybe, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Celebrity</ENAMEX> interviews are the pox of glossy magazine
journalism."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, is it possible that we're all supposed to return from our "hard
adventure" exploits with scabby knees? A full body cast seems more probable,
but that's one way to combine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> with
Talk's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hip List</ENAMEX>."

            Seriously, I think the dirty secret that helps explain the upsurge in
adventure travel and other forms of risk-taking is that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are bored
with prosperity. Where is the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> in politics when the only choices
on the table in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> are an unneeded tax cut or squirreling the surplus
away for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>' golden <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>? What's the point of getting rich and
flaunting your wealth through conspicuous consumption if everybody on your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> is collecting vintage <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wines</ENAMEX> and building oversize vacation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nantucket</ENAMEX>, according to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , is fast being despoiled by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parvenus</ENAMEX> who are tearing down historic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and replacing them with soulless
mansions because of loopholes in the local zoning laws.

            (Of course, as a recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">renter</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>, I represent a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">classic</ENAMEX> case of the raise-the-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">drawbridge</NUMEX>-we're-here syndrome.)

            In short, who wouldn't crave a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adventure</ENAMEX> in their lives at a time
when the political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are hellbent on giving us a
yawn-inducing electoral choice between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>? Which, of
course, brings us back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Klain</ENAMEX>'s departure from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
staff.

            A major reason the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign is so garrulous is that they are top-heavy
with armchair <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> who want to retain their credibility with the press in
case the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice-president</ENAMEX> loses. A parlor game among political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> is to see how many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half-dozen</NUMEX> "communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>" you can
name. In contrast, the lean and hungry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> campaign managed to keep
the biggest secret of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all last December</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dollar Bill</ENAMEX>'s surprise entry into the
presidential race.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> last nugget for the afternoon comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Grove</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable Source</ENAMEX>"
column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, it seems, has become an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
Powers fanatic, enlivening his contentless campaign travels with dead-on
imitations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>. But, according to campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mindy Tucker</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> is "more partial to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mini-Me</ENAMEX> than to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>." How fitting that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> the Younger so deeply identifies with the pint-size offspring of an
illustrious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.

            Happily yielding to you for the final word, I am already salivating over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s breakfast.

         
      
   
