
   
   
      
         
            Is the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Economy Over</ENAMEX>?
            

            For the really bad news, we'll have to wait until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, when the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> jobs report is released. (Actually, most of you reading this will probably
already have heard the bad news.) But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s news on the inflation front
was already dismaying. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Labor</ENAMEX> reported that nonfarm business
productivity rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 1.3 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second quarter</TIMEX>, after a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.6 percent</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leap</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. Along with that came news that unit labor costs leapt <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.8</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second quarter</TIMEX>, after a minuscule <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.8 percent</NUMEX> increase in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>.

            A rise in labor costs is, of course, a good thing for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, most
of whom are still seeing only slight increases in their real income. But a rise
in labor costs without a concomitant rise in labor productivity is generally
taken as a sign that inflationary pressures are in the offing. (If they're not,
then corporate profits are going to take a serious hit.) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s numbers were
not disastrous. But assuming that the jobs report is as good (or, rather, bad)
as is expected, meaning that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX> of new jobs were created in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> interest-rate hike now seems like a foregone
conclusion.

            Productivity is the key economic statistic, because only increases in
productivity can increase the ability of the economy to grow without the
artificial boost of inflation. The more output we get per worker<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-hour</TIMEX>, the more
income <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">per hour</NUMEX> each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> can earn. If productivity were to remain stagnant,
then the economy could grow only as fast as the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> grew.
But when, as in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX>, productivity increases at a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> rate, the limits of the economy are extended.

            Output per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> hour may seem slightly esoteric, but in fact it's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ideal</ENAMEX> measure of productivity because it makes explicit the heart of all
economic growth: the conversion of time, through labor, into value. The only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> an economy can become something more than a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> taking in each
other's washing, that is, the only way an economy can actually improve living
standards and increase the collective wealth, is when one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things
happens: Either <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more hours</TIMEX>, changing empty time into a product or
service, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> create more value with those <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">same hours</TIMEX>. In a booming
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> like this one, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do both.

            The slowdown in productivity, then, doesn't bode well for those who assumed
that the economy could keep growing at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> indefinitely without sparking
inflation. And yet it was striking that, confronted with this news, the bond
market, which is usually hypersensitive to the possibility of inflation, did
not sell off. In fact, bonds rallied, with yields dropping to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.04 percent</NUMEX>.

            You could say that this was just irrational. But when you look a little
deeper at the productivity numbers, the evidence for real inflationary
pressures starts to look rather sketchy. On a year-over-year basis (rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quarter-to-quarter</ENAMEX>), nonfarm productivity was up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.9 percent</NUMEX>, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.7</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first quarter</TIMEX>, and unit labor costs were up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">just 1.4 percent</NUMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Again</ENAMEX>, what's important is that increases in productivity outpace increases in
labor costs. Though not by too much.) So, from that perspective the economy
doesn't appear to be overheating.

            Still, the combination of this report and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Employment Cost Index</ENAMEX>
(which showed worker compensation rising faster than at any time since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>)
should throw at least a hint of caution into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Economy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, those
who are convinced that inflation is permanently dead and that the computer has
forever revolutionized the productivity equation. We're still in the middle of
a remarkable run. But a boom built on productivity improvements is real. A boom
built on easy money is not. And distinguishing betweeen the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> is the most
important thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> can do right now.

         
      
   
