
   
   
      
         
            Where Have You Gone, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jodi</ENAMEX>,

            I'm beginning to think that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> most loathsome words in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
language are "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> marriage." Regarding the conflict-of-interest
potential in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Franks</ENAMEX>' marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy- hater Bob Morganthau</ENAMEX>, all I can
add is that you don't have to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan DA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to get shivers over
the thought of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>. If elected, he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who's apt to send
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">slammer</ENAMEX> for griping about lost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> checks.

            I've been doing impromptu <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>-race polls around dinner tables filled with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">liberal New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. And I've yet to talk to anyone who can muster any
enthusiasm about the prospect of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
arouses far more positive electricity. Only the most hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX> say
they're planning to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. If there is a race that cries out for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Ventura</ENAMEX> (where is ex-mayoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>
when we need him?), it's this one.

            I had missed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> analysis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX>'s flawed poll
in my quick scan of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>." What I think is going on here with this obsession
with new emphasis on sex is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX> has figured out that it will soon
face a major membership crisis. Remember, this is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that loses
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> with the sureness of mortality tables. If they don't figure out a way
to quickly appeal to aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX>, they will cease to be a potent lobbying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. Any day now, I expect them to start an ad campaign that
proclaims: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX>--not your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s senior-citizen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>."

            Let's talk (no that's now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>'s word) ... er ... e-mail after lunch.

         
      
   
