
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Poverty</ENAMEX> of Theory
            

            The question "How much of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s vision of a post-industrial society has
come to pass?" is freighted in all sorts of subtle ways. Looking over your own
summary of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> projections of what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> society in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX> would
look like, one would say that they were, by and large, pretty prescient. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> himself disclaimed the role of futurologist. "I am writing," he said, "an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'as</ENAMEX> if,' a fiction, a logical construction of what could be, against
which the future social reality can be compared in order to see what intervened
to change society in the direction it did take." And what was his original
motivation in constructing this as-if scenario? He wanted to understand how
another sociological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> went wrong in predicting social change: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>.

            Though he is often (wrongly) lumped with the neocons <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> is in his
bones an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Old Left intellectual</ENAMEX>. (He joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Socialist Party</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 13</TIMEX>, and his first book, published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>, tried to explain
why no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxian</ENAMEX> socialist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> took root in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.) The
distressing thing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marxian</ENAMEX> bent is the failure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>'s
scenario for the collapse of capitalism (as presented in Volume I of
Capital ) to come true. What was the fatal flaw in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>'s scheme for
explaining structural changes in society as a consequence of increasing
conflict between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> classes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalists</ENAMEX> and the proletariat, whose
identities were determined by the industrial mode of production?

            The answer, it is generally thought, has something to do with the emergence
of a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> class--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technocrats</ENAMEX>, white collars, "symbolic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>," or whatever you want to call them--that is neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX> nor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">proletarian</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> (who actually made it through Volume <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">III</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capital</ENAMEX> !)
discovered that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> himself foresaw this possibility as he observed the growth
of an investment-banking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 19th century</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>
thought that the white-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> would eventually become "proletarianized"
because of the alienating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of office labor and the depreciation of
their value through free public education. He was wrong.

            How did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> propose to save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>? By "decoupling" (as he puts it) the two
dimensions of technology and social relations, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> had conceptually
unified. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>, changes in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> do not determine changes in the
other (for example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> was
collectivist, but both were industrial). So in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s sociology they are
treated as independent variables.

            I think that is why I find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> so much less interesting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>'s theory of social change was based on a simple and seemingly
powerful premise: The material mode of production determines everything else in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">society</ENAMEX>. History has falsified that premise. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> wants to salvage the theory
by introducing distinctions and complications. He insists that we talk about a
"techno-economic system ," a "political order ," a "cultural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sphere</ENAMEX> ," with an "axial principle" running through them all--the
"codificacation of theoretical knowledge."

            I find it very hard to see how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s forecasts about the future, prescient
as they may be, flow from this rather inert theory obtained by weakening that
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>. I understand what it means for a prediction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell's</ENAMEX> to be wrong
(like his prediction that inflation would become a permanent feature of the
post-industrial economy). But I wouldn't know how to go about falsifying his
theory of social change. It has too many degrees of freedom, as it were. It
seems to fail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Popper</ENAMEX>'s criterion for being scientific.

            And I seem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, to have completely evaded your very reasonable question,
"What part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s post-industrial society has come to pass?" Please steer me
back to the real world.

         
      
   
