
   
   
      
         
            Talk Party Talk

            If you stand directly in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX>--at once shorter and
kitschier yet at the same time somehow grander than you expect it to
be--there's a tree-dotted sward to the right, facing lower <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, of
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> football-field dimensions but kidney-shaped. In front of the
sward there's a promenade and a railing with a battery of those coin-operated
heavy-metal binoculars looking like silver alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> perched on metal stalks
and doing the usual truly mediocre job of magnifying things. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cataractic</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tunnel-visioned</ENAMEX>, those things are always disappointing, and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, with
the brilliant megalithic skyline laid out before you in even greater and
crisper grandeur than usual, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> blinking their bright-lighted way
toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LGA</ENAMEX>, with private and commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> plying the dark,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sparkling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York Harbor</ENAMEX>, you didn't need any kind of visual aid to
be impressed with the view.

            And when you turned around, to see the party--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>; you must give it
its due--you were nearly as impressed, in a different way. At least I was, and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the main ways I, being a meteorologically preoccupied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>, was
impressed was with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s climatological riskiness. I ran into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX>
Fielden, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , and he told me he was
doing a piece about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Isabelle</ENAMEX>.

            "What would have happened if it had rained<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" I asked him.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catastrophe</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> said.

            "So she just rolled the dice<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            "She just rolled the dice."

            She is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>, of course, and she rolled a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. It was a fabulous (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
would say fabbelus ) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, clear and warm, with a pleasant breeze
animating the multi-colored <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lanterns</ENAMEX> depending from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scantily</ENAMEX> dressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, most of them in black, and black-clad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> lay about
drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> on huge striped and solid-color <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cushions</ENAMEX> scattered about in
groupings of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX>, or sat at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30 or so</NUMEX> tables beneath
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. In the middle of each the tables was a huge picnic basket, in which,
under cloths folded over in a pastry-looking manner, were napkins, plates,
silverware, and plastic containers filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn salad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato salad</ENAMEX>, and
strolling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX> supplemented these dishes with platters of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lamb chops</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fried</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX>. Some tables featured big galvanized tubs filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and
bottles of white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>; columns of bottles of red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> stood in front of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tubs</ENAMEX>. A few of the tubs had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20 or 30</NUMEX> small bottles of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evian</ENAMEX> nestled in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. The
low, slate-topped wall of the promenade was covered by comfortable cushions,
and there were long bars in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> places. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> and temporary dance
floor had been constructed behind the statue. Generally, whatever "concept" Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabelle</ENAMEX> had for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> seemed to be working.

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,500</NUMEX> partygoers arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Ferry</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> on. The
statue was closed to the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, and only party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> were allowed on
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX> ferries that went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX> and came back
continuously <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I boarded the ferry at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 8:30</TIMEX>. It would
be foolish to drop names; they were as plentiful as the lights burning in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>, which presided over the proceedings like titanic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.
When we got off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>, we were ushered along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> by, well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ushers</ENAMEX>. A
lot of them had headsets on. Some motioned us on our way with
chartreuse-chimneyed flashlights. Made me feel like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">747</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> stood
stunningly on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier illuminated</ENAMEX> by camera lights in the gathering <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk</TIMEX> in a
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> and greeted some arrivees individually, causing a traffic jam and
throwing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">headset</ENAMEX>/flashlight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> into frenzied pleading: "This way, please.
If you'll just step this way." Oh, well, there's no way of avoiding the names:
In my small clot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dislodged swardward from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pier</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Newberg</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">escort</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newsman/artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Johnson</ENAMEX>;
illustrator/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane Smith</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buck Henry; Tony Schwartz</ENAMEX>; ???; ???;
???.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lane Smith</ENAMEX>, on rounding the bend in front of the statue and seeing the
multi-colored lanterns, said, "That works for me. I mean, they could have gone
with the fashionably neutral colors--white, gray, maybe tan. But this looks
good."

            And it really did. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> were chuckling about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Rome</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Decadence</ENAMEX>
effect of the big lawn bolster recliners. Numbers began wafting about on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breezes</ENAMEX>: "I'd say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least five</TIMEX>; it has got to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>." "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">750</NUMEX>, min." "Over a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mil</ENAMEX>--no question. Think of the one-night payroll alone, and renting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Liberty</ENAMEX>." "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> point <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. I heard that as known fact." These zephyr-borne
estimates went way up after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grucci</ENAMEX> fireworks barge floated between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX> and the skyline with an electric sign on it that said Talk (did I
forget to say that this was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> for her new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>,
Talk ?) and hurled into the black sky a literally earth-shaking barrage
of pyrotechnics. The first few were dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX>. "This one's for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Weinstein</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Plimpton</ENAMEX> said. He knew the names of each of these
single shot items: "A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>-flanged fleur-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de-lis</ENAMEX>," he said, or something like
that. "A <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12-inch</NUMEX> golden-dragon magnolia." The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> dedicated to what people
throughout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> kept noisomely referring to as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Liberty"</ENAMEX> (a moniker
on the same unacceptability level as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Big Apple"</ENAMEX>) came way down on the
list. She'd been privatized-for-<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a-night</TIMEX>, I guess. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plimpton</ENAMEX> got lost in his list
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, but despite referring to one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> to the display's
soundtrack as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecille Dion</ENAMEX>," he brought to the event his patrician sonorities
and his fabled familiarity with fireworks. The finale left no one in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> in any doubt as to the existence of his or her sternum and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ribcage</ENAMEX>.

            This fireworks' <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> was the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only 20 minutes</TIMEX> during which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25 to 35</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> was not talking to or hearing from someone who wasn't
with them. I mean, there was the headset <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, coordinating whatever it was
they had to coordinate, the security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, with their hearing-aid like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">devices</ENAMEX>, and the cell-phone set, talking to--whom? The mainland, one
guessed.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patton</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George C. Scott</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Patton</ENAMEX> looks over an imminent
battle scene and says something like "God help me--I do love it so!" Well, PFC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menaker</ENAMEX> is here to tell you, "God help me, I do love it so." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Friedman</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katrina van den Heuvel</ENAMEX> (her dress had literally no back; she looked
fabbelus !), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salman</ENAMEX> (you must say "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salman</ENAMEX>," I have heard, and how many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> have achieved <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-name status in our time? Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>, but not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas or Philip or William or John</ENAMEX>, as far as I can tell), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Jessica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce Brosnan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Solondz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Newman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Bacon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyra Sedgewick</ENAMEX>,
etc. I had a pen and a piece of paper ready to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latrell</ENAMEX> for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better</ENAMEX>
be careful not to get him angry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>"), but if he was there, I didn't see his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-name-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">sufficing</ENAMEX> self. These ingredients swirled around each other in a
dance of honest enjoyment and/or self-conscious shoulder-rubbing for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or
so before the toasts from the stage.

            Then came the toasts. Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latifah</ENAMEX> (featured in Talk's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">presided</ENAMEX>, asking that we "give it up for," among others, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Liberty</ENAMEX>." She
was accompanied by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grucci</ENAMEX>-worthy rap-bass on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX>-tall woofers,
and she called to the stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Galotti</ENAMEX>, who made some OK but forgettable
remarks, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teenster</ENAMEX> herself, who said, among other things, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Latifah</ENAMEX>
is the only queen I'll ever have to curtsy to. I mean, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--this is what it's all about." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> says "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">America</ENAMEX>" oddly--it's Ameriker
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amerrikeh</ENAMEX>, or something like that. She also said, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly a shriek</NUMEX>, that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Statue of Liberty</ENAMEX> was "awesome." She also thanked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Karan</ENAMEX> for the
dress, which she said she had to pour herself into. Her well-crafted remarks
also seemed ultimately dwarfed by the setting and by the event she herself had
caused to happen. One had to hand it to her--it was really fun. It was
undeniably Something. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>'s book is called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX> . For her, I
suspect, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Party</ENAMEX>'s a life.

            I left at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 11:30</TIMEX>, a little blotto. On the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Evans</ENAMEX>, who was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who hired me as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> and
who once demolished me in pingpong in between swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laps</ENAMEX> at his health
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">club</ENAMEX>--and I'm a pretty good ping pong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>--were spotted, saying hello or
goodbye to this luminary or that one. I got <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> face time with my
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>. "If I had a hat, it would be off to you," I said.

            "Have you seen it yet?" she asked, I like to think a little plaintively.

            "No, not yet."

            "Putting it to press had its nightmare moments," she said.

            "Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were telling me things about nervous breakdowns and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hospitalizations</ENAMEX>," I said. "But congratulations on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
breakthrough."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Franks</ENAMEX> worked very, very hard to get that," she said.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Well</ENAMEX>, it's a real coup."

            I felt a hand on my shoulder. "You'll have to swim over there, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,"
my other ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Evans</ENAMEX>, said, pointing toward the far shore. "Anyone
under <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">50</ENAMEX> has to swim. Could you swim that on a bet, do you suppose<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never</ENAMEX>," I said. "You're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swimmer</ENAMEX>. I'm about as good a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">swimmer</ENAMEX> as I am a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">ping pong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. By the way, congratulations."

            "On what? I haven't done anything."

            "Um, on your book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>" I said.

            "Oh, that. Well, yes, thanks."

            He hurried off to press a little more flesh. Speaking of which, "It doesn't
look to me like you had to pour yourself into that dress," I said to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cat</ENAMEX> just having left.

            She gave her eyes a bat or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. "Thank you, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dahn</ENAMEX>," she said. She can be a
terrible flirt, the "good <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>." 
(The "bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina"</ENAMEX> doesn't really belong in this festive setting.)

            Even knowing that most of this whole function was all for buzz and hype and
advertising and so on, I said, "This was so generous of you. Thank you for
inviting me."

            "Thanks for coming, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dahn</ENAMEX>. It is fabbelus, isn't it?"

            It was back onto the ferry, heading toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> into a still-warm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">breeze</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and I stood on the foredeck or whatever you call it. "This is
so romantic," she said. We smooched.

         
      
   
