
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Bell</ENAMEX>, the Once <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Famed New York Intellectual</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Bell</ENAMEX>, who recently turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX>, cuts an odd figure on the intellectual
landscape. Although he is generally considered to be the greatest living
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX>, surprisingly few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> have heard of him. (He is
probably better known in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.) There is no Bellian
school of sociological thought. He has been called "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sage</ENAMEX> without a
following." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>, when the book we are discussing was originally
published, he had a higher profile. One survey placed him among the "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> most
respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>." No doubt that had something to do with his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> volume of essays, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The End of Ideology</ENAMEX> , which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> himself once
called "the most cited and least read of books."

            Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> did not coin the term "post-industrial," it was his book that
launched it into the popular lexicon, where it was subsequently banalized by
untold mindless repetitions. That, of course, is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX>'s fault. Indeed, it
was with some excitement that I opened this new edition of The Coming of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Industrial Society</ENAMEX> , hoping to recover the rigorous and prescient
thinking behind the cliché. I was also curious to see how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>, in a newly
written foreword of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 80</NUMEX> pages, would retrospectively appraise the validity
of his theorizing and the accuracy of his predictions.

            I don't know about you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, but I was at first put off by the rather
unleavened prose, the endless morphological distinctions ("systems," "orders,"
"spheres," "situses," "axial principles," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"dimensions" ...</ENAMEX>), and the paragraphs
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of academic throat-clearing ("But the limitations of forecasting are also
evident. The further one reaches ahead in time with a set of forecasts, the
greater the margin for error, since the fan of projections widens")--not to
mention the typos, factual errors, and shoddy copy-editing of the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foreword</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> may have been one of the more sparkling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>
in his heyday; and he was also, of course, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Luce</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX> (and has even retained some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>-ese tics,
such as referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plato</ENAMEX> in a footnote as "the famed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> philosopher"). But
he has been, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic sociologist</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> (which
gave him a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">PhD</ENAMEX> after they hired him for his writings as a public intellectual)
and then, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologists</ENAMEX> cannot help generating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX>, sterile, abstract schematics to describe society.

            Curiously, if you look at the wonderful anthology of parodies that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macdonald</ENAMEX> put together long ago, you will find a burlesque of sociologese by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Bell</ENAMEX>, called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Parameters of Social Movements: A Formal Paradigm</ENAMEX>,"
which was allegedly a revision of an earlier scheme titled "The Configurative
Patterning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Movements</ENAMEX>." The parody is not all that funny. What is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hilarious</ENAMEX> is that a couple of sociological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> to whom he sent it
mistook it for the real thing. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them, he writes, "sent me back a serious
letter about some of the categories, while the other, not knowing whether it
was a spoof or not, wrote: 'You are too good a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> not to have created
something which itself is quite useful.' And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> asked me for a copy of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'earlier</ENAMEX> scheme.' "

            I seem to have left it to you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, to say just what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Bell</ENAMEX> means by
the "post-industrial" society. Forgive me.

         
      
   
