
   
   
      
         
            All <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chats Lead to Talk</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Walter</ENAMEX>,

            Of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Barton</ENAMEX>'s homicides didn't "stem from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading alone." I
meant that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> was far too offhand about the
non-digital factors that may have set him off. The story begins with some
general exposition about the sketchy details of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s past, but once the
narrative hits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> (right before the Internet boom!), it restricts itself to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s highs and lows as a day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>. That's why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s line
about trading not being the sole cause seemed so slapped-on and insufficient to
me. As you suggest, his killing spree may turn out to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> of policy
and business consequences: for gun control, regulation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading, the
online sector of the financial industry. So before we are asked to digest
proposals and reforms, I am hungry to know more about the other causes of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s rampage, and some real consideration of what, if anything, makes day
trading particularly nefarious.

            For example, the piece describes how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> used the extra-risky practice of
trading "on margin," or borrowing funds against the securities he already
owned, which he was required to back up with additional funds when the value of
those securities dropped. But the story doesn't tell us if trading on margin is
allowed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles Schwab</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan Stanley</ENAMEX>--in other words, if he could have
bet as riskily at a more established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> or away from a computer.

            You write that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>-trading career is emblematic of the
"glitz-and-greed '90s" and that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are "abandoning safe investments in
the quest for instant riches." I am chary of decade-long generalizations (I
thought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> were supposed to have been about "glitz-and-greed"). Your
statement is wide enough to span the gold rush, the junk-bond era, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Las</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vegas Strip</ENAMEX>. Sure, online investing is more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist</ENAMEX> and easily accessible than
panning for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> or high-risk bond trading, but you make it sound as if droves
of us are abandoning steady salaries for a home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, a modem, and a bunch of
trading accounts. So, tops on my list of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pieces I'd Like To Read</ENAMEX> remains a
solid analysis of the scope and specific dangers of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading, and how it
compares to more conventional forms of extracurricular investing.

            Perhaps, as you hypothesize, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> chose to air her woes in Talk
because it's a sympathetic forum. But so are lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> (remember the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX>'s recent rah-rah cover story?). I think she
chose it simply because it's the highest-profile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. Her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> candidacy is a direct reward for the crosses she's had to bear; before
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, her approval rating was too low to justify a run. What bothers me most
about the interview is that she seems to be trying to nourish her candidacy
with a new harvest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flytrap</ENAMEX>-induced sympathy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>, did you dis my offer of a Talk subscription. Your high-minded
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sneer</ENAMEX> leaves me crestfallen--does this mean you won't want to dish over it
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>? I have a copy in front of me, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> aside, it looks delicious.
I can't wait to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hannibal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Stoppard</ENAMEX> on his
newfound <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> heritage, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mimi Swartz</ENAMEX> on the legal revenge being exacted by
wronged <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>. But if you won't share with me, then at least my fellow F
train <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX> will.

            
               A demain ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jodi</ENAMEX>

            P.S.: No, I don't eat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>. But I could if I wanted to. A dirty
little secret: Like many of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s "quality of life"
prohibitions--including those on jaywalking and cursing--the no-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX> on the
subway rule is never, ever enforced.

         
      
   
