
   
   
      
         
            Death and Taxes

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Barton</ENAMEX>'s confessional notes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> front this story, and accompany it with profiles of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>, whose names were also released. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also front
coverage of the fallout: increased scrutiny of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ) and renewed clamoring in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> for tighter gun
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , reefered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LAT</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> approval of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$782 billion</NUMEX> tax cut plan. The bill
differs slightly from a counterpart <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> bill passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is all but certain to veto both. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s indictment by the state
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> on wiretapping charges is also fronted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>.

            Notes left by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> where his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
were found dead shed light on the motives behind his killing spree:
estrangement from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, recent massive day trading losses, and a strange
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allusion</ENAMEX> to a "fear" passed from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, to him, and ultimately to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>.
In the notes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> also pleads not guilty to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> murder of his first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> (he had been the prime suspect in the case), saying
"there's no reason for me to lie now." And though he pledges to destroy "those
who greedily sought his destruction," the only connection between him and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> appears to be a love of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>'s profile of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> runs under the subtle headline: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Victims</ENAMEX> were Drawn to their Deaths by
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lives in Day Trading</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> digs deep enough to report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s
photograph never appeared in his high-school yearbook, but neglects to mention
that he was investigated for molesting his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> after his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s death, a detail which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> includes.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mysteriously</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s notes make no explicit mention of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX> trading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploits</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> now have all the numbers---he lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$105,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 days</TIMEX>
of trading over an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-week</TIMEX> period. All of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> predict that tighter
day trading regulation, including a closer screening of aspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, is on
the way. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also mentions that criminal charges will likely be
filed against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, and points out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading's long odds--an
estimated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> end up net losers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that
Momentum, a day trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>, would ply its clients <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circus</ENAMEX>-style with free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> to keep them from leaving for lunch.
An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addictions</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> trading is
surpassing chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and pornography as the Internet jones of choice.

            Anticipating increased public pressure in the wake of the shootings, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> voted to appoint <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> to reach a compromise with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> on new
gun control measures. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> hope to pass laws
mandating background checks on gun show <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>, implementation of child
safety locks, and bans on large-capacity ammunition clips by the August
recess.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> tax cut bill differs slightly from that passed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX>. Instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> across-the-board rate cut,
it drops the only the lowest rate (from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent to 14 percent</NUMEX>), and makes
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> eligible for this rate. It also includes more measures to reduce
the marriage penalty and fewer to reduce the estate tax. It's similar to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> proposal in size (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$782 billion</NUMEX>), time of implementation (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>), and
likelihood of presidential veto (certain). The papers agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> is
using the bills mostly to define issues for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming</TIMEX> elections.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> faces <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> felony counts for taping her conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Taping conversations without the consent of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> is illegal
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>. Each of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s wiretapping violations
carries a maximum sentence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>, or both. But for her to do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> must prove that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> was aware of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>'s law against
unauthorized taping of calls. She (or, at least, her tapes and grand jury
testimony) may also be protected from state indictment under the broad federal
immunity deal she negotiated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX>.

            
               I've had lunch with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John John</ENAMEX>, I've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cocktails</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John John</ENAMEX>, and
you, Reverend, are no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John John</ENAMEX>: In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX>
takes aim at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> trying to bask in the glow of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX>'s celebrity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Isaacson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Alter</ENAMEX> are among
the many reprimanded for using the tragedy to boast of their own intimate meals
and conversations with the departed scion. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX> tells
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, "I'm admittedly much like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kennedy Jr.</ENAMEX> in that all my life ... I've
lived close to the edge."

         
      
   
