
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Scoops; Times</ENAMEX> Droops
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Katharine</ENAMEX>,

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the uglier things I've learned over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of close newspaper reading
is how deeply competitive jealousy affects news judgment, even on stories where
the importance is overwhelming. It's happening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> with the revelations
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in the federally owned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bomb factory</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paducah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, who
were unknowingly exposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plutonium</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
(which I know you don't read) broke this story in a front-page story on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>,
forcing the secretary of energy to launch an investigation, and all but admit
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> lied about this contamination for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. As you might
expect, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> has been struck with all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
There's a follow-up Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , profiling a worker
who died after a futile <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> of trying to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> to acknowledge his
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">illness</ENAMEX>. Belatedly--and to my mind revoltingly--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> now calls him
a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX>."

            If I were a national news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, I would use this horror story as a chance
to do a round-up of everything we now know about the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
involvement in nuclear contamination. Remind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> of the experiments done on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, get a reading on the other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bomb plants</ENAMEX>, etc. Instead, most of the big
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are giving this story a big ho-hum. As best I can tell, the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> hasn't run an article at all; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times couldn't spare <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> words, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> did
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> with virtually no reporting in it.

            I guarantee you that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> will put its series, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joby Warrick</ENAMEX>,
up for a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>, and I wouldn't be surprised if it wins. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, of
course, will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> from the very papers who are now ignoring the
story.

            On an arguably brighter note, there is a milestone obituary in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Paterson</ENAMEX>, one of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Fat Ladies</ENAMEX>" of
cooking show fame. If you've ever seen the program, which debuted on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, you know how bizarre it is: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> enormous, motorcycle-riding eccentrics
offering some of the unhealthiest meals imaginable. (I'm sort of a conceptual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>: The show itself I find unwatchable.) Anyway, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> obit is
written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enid Nemy</ENAMEX>, who does not normally grace the death announcement page,
and she notes that no less a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles "</ENAMEX>sent a gift of homemade
organic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomato soup</ENAMEX> and vanilla <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> to Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paterson</ENAMEX> after she disclosed
her illness <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>." The story also discloses that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food Network</ENAMEX> is
planning <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a two-hour</TIMEX> tribute to Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paterson</ENAMEX>, who is survived by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>." This may be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a specific
television broadcast has been plugged in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> obituary.

            Sorry to be so grim <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. I lost a sizable sum of money in a poker
game last night, and it may be affecting my mood.

         
      
   
