
   
   
      
         
            More on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> and Psychotherapy

            Writing previously about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX>'s wildly hyped book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shadow</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Presidents</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Legacy of Watergate</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> criticized a passage that ended a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> excerpt and seemed designed to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> with the
impression that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> were in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> therapy. (See "
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward Positions Himself</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> Couple.") If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was
seeing a shrink, that struck <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> as big news. (Clearly, he should
be seeing a shrink.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> wrote the passage in an annoying way that
didn't really establish whether he was or he wasn't seeing a shrink, and seemed
designed mostly to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> to take credit for the scoop if some other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">drudge</ENAMEX> came along and actually nailed it, while also covering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>'s ass if
it turned out not to be true.

            Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s wildly hyped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, Talk , has taken up
the issue again in its much-discussed profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>. The profile
itself is pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX>, and has caused a big dust-up over whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did or should have indulged in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-shrinking speculation of her
own about the source of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s sexual compulsions. The possibility that
the connection is the result of some misleading quote-juxtaposition by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franks</ENAMEX> herself is explored by 
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s previous Chatterbox
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Kaus</ENAMEX>, on his excellent new Web site, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kausfiles</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. (Full
disclosure: The item also includes some very sensible praise of Mrs.
Chatterbox, a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> and sometime 
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">writer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie Williams</ENAMEX>. And you might as well also know that: a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaus</ENAMEX> for close to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>; b) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaus</ENAMEX> co-edited an
anthology of neoliberal writings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX> that never got published;
c) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaus</ENAMEX> attended the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>, though at different
times; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaus</ENAMEX> apprenticed at the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> , though at different times; e) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> first met the future
Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaus</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> apartment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>; f) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaus</ENAMEX> was an usher at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> nuptials in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">g</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaus</ENAMEX> worked at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> at the same time, though in different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, during the late
1980s; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">h</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has probably neglected to cite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> additional
conflicts of interest, but figures he has to leave something for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brill</ENAMEX>'s
Content to expose.)

            Anyway, setting aside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s own alleged dime-store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">psychologizing</ENAMEX> about
why her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is a womanizer, let's look at what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franks</ENAMEX> writes about whether
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is in psychotherapy:

            

               
                  Public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has prevented the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> from seeking therapy, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> told me they expect him to after leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            This was misreported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> as "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
statement in the article that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would seek therapy when he left the
Presidency." As you can see, the statement is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franks</ENAMEX>' own, based on what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> "told me," a point that seemed to be fully grasped by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who asked about it at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 2</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> briefing. Is it true the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is not seeing a
shrink? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> thought so. It quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
Lockhart as saying, "My understanding is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> continues to deal with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> that he talked about at the outset. I can't tell you about the
details of that because they are private. But he has sought to work with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> who he is close with and friendly with, and that's the extent of
it."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lockhart</ENAMEX> left a little wiggle room that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> didn't mention.
Here's a follow-up from the briefing:

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> have degrees in other areas, like
psychological--well, psychology degrees. Is he dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> who have
psychology degrees and deal on other issues--
               

               A: I don't have the slightest idea. I know who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> are. I don't
have the slightest idea what degrees--

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Q</ENAMEX>: Can you tell us who they are?

               A: No, because this is something that's private. Although--although at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them has not made a secret of the fact that he's talked to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. [This last is a dig at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX>.]

            

            In other words, it's possible (though probably unlikely) that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
is in psychotherapy under the guise of seeking "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX>" from a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychotherapist</ENAMEX> who's also an ordained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
