
   
   
      
         
            Weatherbox: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Part II</ENAMEX>

            Chatterbox slightly mangled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s "
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weatherbox</ENAMEX>" item the meaning of the "hottest-ever" weather data available
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOAA</ENAMEX>. Chatterbox, wanting to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to quit whining about the
heat wave, used the data to point out that it's been a lot hotter, which it
has. The data itself (including the hottest-ever temperature recorded
officially<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">--136 degrees Farenheit</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Azizia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13, 1922</TIMEX>--and
the hottest-ever temperature recorded officially in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>--134 degrees in
Death <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10, 1913</TIMEX>) were correct. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>, his mind
clearly addled by the heat (it's much cooler now) misinterpreted the
rankings below "hottest-ever" of both worldwide temperatures and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
temperatures. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thanks the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who wrote in to inform him of
his error.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOAA</ENAMEX> data show the hottest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> ever recorded on various continents, in
declining order. Therefore, it's rash to conclude (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> did) that the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-hottest temperature in known human history was the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">134 degrees</NUMEX>
recorded in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Death Valley</ENAMEX>--cited by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOAA</ENAMEX> as the hottest-ever temperature in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North America</ENAMEX>, and as a temperature hotter than any other recorded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOAA</ENAMEX> for
any continent that isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. More likely, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-hottest day in
known human history probably occurred somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>, where somebody
probably measured a temperature of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">135 degrees Farenheit</NUMEX>. But this would
not be included on the NOAA chart because <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>'s record is the
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">136 degrees</NUMEX> figure for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Azizia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox's</ENAMEX> rankings
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> were similarly skewed, since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOAA</ENAMEX>'s chart listed all-time highs for individual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>; hence the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-hottest day in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> was probably not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, when it hit <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">128 degrees</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake Havasu City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ariz.</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">125 degrees</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fahrenheit</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laughlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nev.</ENAMEX> Rather, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-hottest day probably
occurred in the same location as the hottest day, i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Death Valley</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, which is really, really hot. Indeed, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dinesh Desai</ENAMEX>
claims to have recorded a temperature of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">129</NUMEX>
degrees while walking across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Death Valley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1998</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s
rankings for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> hottest, <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> hottest, etc., are, of course, similarly
botched.)

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> e-mailed Chatterbox some intriguing evidence that the temperature
may have lately spiked past <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Azizia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX>'s, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1922</TIMEX> world record of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">136</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">degrees Farenheit</ENAMEX>--though not, of course, anywhere near these shores. Sgt.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Comiskey</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>, who since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> has been stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX>,
claims that it hit <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">142 degrees</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> out on the live fire range. "I
fought in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Comiskey</ENAMEX>, "and I can tell you this is the worst
heat I have ever felt." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> were given T-shirts that say
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">142</ENAMEX>" in order to commemorate the event. This is not an officially sanctioned
figure, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> trusts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> to handle a thermometer.

            None of these qualifications negates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s message that it can get a
lot hotter than it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Certainly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> means
no disrespect to the (mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who died in the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> heat
wave. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> finds himself wondering why this heat wave, which
stretched across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>, killed so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> , a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> in a relatively northern latitude that is reputed to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windy</ENAMEX> and situated on a very big lake. (By now it's cooled down to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">83 degrees</NUMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Midway Airport</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX>'s weather Web page.
Click here for links to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX>'s coverage of the heat
wave.) According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2.7</NUMEX> heat deaths per
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, "a higher rate of these fatalities than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>," which tend to be hotter.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason, apparently, is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> doesn't have enough air conditioners
for low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Quoth the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> :

            

               
                  Air conditioning is not standard equipment in low-income housing here,
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Forman</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> and environmental sciences at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Illinois</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> ... <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only four</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Housing</ENAMEX>
Authority <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> for senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> have air conditioning in every <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Bates</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CHA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Jackson</ENAMEX> and Mayor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard M. Daley</ENAMEX> have made it a goal to increase the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> that
provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> with air conditioning, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacquelyn Heard</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            Interestingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s deaths and power outages came "despite a citywide
emergency plan" that was implemented after an even worse heat wave in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, and
despite the fact that forecasts "accurately predicted record-scraping
temperatures" (this again, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> ). However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cook County</ENAMEX>'s heat-wave death
toll--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19</TIMEX> (out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 185</NUMEX> nationwide)--isn't as bad as in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribune</ENAMEX> attributes this to the emergency plan, which
had police ferrying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without air conditioning or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> to
"cooling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>."

            Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't remember hearing before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s unusual number of heat-related deaths. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> phoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
Klinenberg, a Ph.D. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> in sociology at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX>, who's writing a book
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the 1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> heat wave, to dig deeper. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klinenberg</ENAMEX> says the phenomenon
is partly related to the recent decline of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>. As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sociologist William Julius Wilson</ENAMEX> points out in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">When Work Disappears</ENAMEX> , this decline has led to a lot of
black migration out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>. But when that happens, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klinenberg</ENAMEX> says, a lot
of old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> stay put, and are therefore cut off from family support networks.
Much the same is happening with white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klinenberg</ENAMEX> says. As it happens,
the heat-related deaths are concentrated among the white and black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>--and largely bypassing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s sizable <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. That's
mainly because "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Latinos</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> are in a different migration cycle. Their
numbers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> have been increasing. ... They're newer arrivals and
they're continuing to come in." In other words, the young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are
situated near the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>, and can help them escape the heat. (To read
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klinenberg</ENAMEX>'s article, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Autopsie d'un été</ENAMEX> meurtrier à <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>," in Le Monde
Diplomatique, click here. Warning: As the title suggests, it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>.)

         
      
   
