
   
   
      
         
            Who's Afraid of The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has a terrible confession to make: He went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Blair</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witch Project</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and, despite trying very, very hard to be
scared, wasn't. What's puzzling is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> scares very easily. Loud,
sudden noises make him jump. The sight of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> makes him blanch. A staircase
creak in a dark old <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> makes him shiver. Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is always saying
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is preposterously easy prey for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s cheapest effects.
This raises the troubling question: Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> too much of a philistine to
be scared by the tonier, more abstract terrors served up in The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX>
Project ? Is Chatterbox incapable of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Art House Fright</ENAMEX>?

            This possibility occurred to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> when he rented the
classic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> thriller <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wages of Fear</ENAMEX> , which has for its can't-lose
premise the transport by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> of highly explosive material through bumpy
jungle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> (and, it must be said, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>) lost patience
with the extremely tedious exposition leading up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Big Event</ENAMEX> and shut it
off. (This even though the film starred a young, extremely suave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yves Montand</ENAMEX>.)
Chatterbox dimly recalls admiring the novels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Brockden Brown</ENAMEX>, whose depiction of supernatural
events occurring in broad daylight somewhat resembles the
terror-of-everyday-life technique behind The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project , when
he read them in college. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't particularly recall being
scared by them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> really thought he was going to like The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX>
Project . For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first half-hour</TIMEX> or so, he marveled at the film's deft,
improvisational style. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student filmmakers</ENAMEX> depicted in the movie, who
present themselves in home videos and snippets of their planned black-and-white
"documentary," seemed like real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> they go to, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> missed any reference to
it in the actual movie--is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery College</ENAMEX>, situated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about eight</NUMEX> blocks from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>.) "Aha!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> told himself. "Ever so gradually, the
ordinariness of the film's events will give way to terror, making everyday life
seem absolutely terrifying!" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> looked forward to being spooked by what

<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX> termed "the nameless evil just beyond the video camera's little
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX> of light." Chatterbox was still looking forward to this thrill an hour
into the film as he gazed upon various pagan-looking piles of rocks and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bales</NUMEX>
of twigs. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Ten minutes</TIMEX> before the movie ended, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> realized that the
terror just wasn't going to happen, and his feelings of pleasurable
anticipation quickly gave way to feelings of inadequacy.

            Perhaps, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> thought, he was probing the wrong medium. He logged onto
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Web
site. But it required a plug-in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> didn't have on his desktop,
and he lost patience. One parody site called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair Bitch Project</ENAMEX> and
another called The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch Ate My Balls</ENAMEX> were also disappointments. Finally,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> looked up some real folklore from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Burkittsville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Md.</ENAMEX>, where The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair Witch Project</ENAMEX> is set. There's a legend about a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Spook</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>," where ghosts supposedly help push your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to the summit, and one about
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Confederate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> dumped in a well, and one about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mythical beast</ENAMEX> called
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snallygaster</ENAMEX>--part reptile, part bird, part octopus, with "huge jaws" and
"razor sharp teeth." These didn't scare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> either.

         
      
   
