
   
   
      
         
            Hot Air

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
lead with the ongoing heat wave and resultant drought--though the heat is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">abating</ENAMEX>, the situation is dire for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> front (and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reefers) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s comments on her marriage in the premiere issue of Talk
magazine. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with a story on increasing reuse of disposable
medical equipment. Such reuse, though potentially disastrous, is largely
unregulated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads
with the latest woes of the waning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Coalition</ENAMEX>--reports of falsified
lists of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also front the
beginnings of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> presidential primary.

            Extreme heat has caused <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 180</NUMEX> heat-related deaths nationwide. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Glickman</ENAMEX>, touring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, may
recommend declaring a state of emergency. Nonetheless, given the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rainfall</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heartland</ENAMEX> has had, yields there should be sufficient to prevent nationwide food
shortages or price hikes. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>
may be on the verge of another crisis, brought on by low prices in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and
depressed markets abroad.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s inaugural issue of Talk, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> blames her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s infidelities on psychological "abuse" he suffered as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>,
particularly the fallout from a conflict between his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> (but not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ) actually describe the
conflict: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> petitioned for custody of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4-year-old</TIMEX> when
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia Kelley</ENAMEX>, decided to wed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Clinton</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> his
grandmother deemed unsuitable. (He turned out to be an abusive alcoholic.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "elaborate rationale" ( WP ) for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s behavior also
involves viewing his lies as "sins of weakness" designed to protect his loved
ones. Talk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> tells USAT that the timing of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> had nothing to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> senatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>. But the WP
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Franks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX>, claimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> agreed to
the interview to "defuse the issue in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> politics." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>
wouldn't comment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>'s motives. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> helpfully reminds
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that Talk is "powered in part by corporate synergy."

            To cut costs, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> process items like
angioplasty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">balloons</ENAMEX> or biopsy needles for reuse. A growing number farm out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reprocessing</ENAMEX> to cheaper third-party <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> marked for
"single use" are reprocessed, sometimes with horrific results--a reprocessed
cardiac catheter, for example, broke off in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s heart during treatment.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, citing a lack of information, exercises little regulatory control on
reprocessing, but a ban on third-party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">reprocessing</ENAMEX> is likely. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> abuse such a
ban won't fix: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> changing the status of formerly reusable items to
"single use" merely to boost sales.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that even at the height of its influence, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX> kept <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>, duplicate names, and wrong
addresses on its lists of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. They also hired temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to
provide the press with images of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">bustling</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>. Even their current claims of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> rely on one-time petition signers and erroneous
addresses. Now that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX>'s plea for tax-exempt status has been
rejected, it may split into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX>: a tax-exempt voter education <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> and
a political action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that would endorse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and donate to
campaigns.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional Revolutionary Party</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRI</ENAMEX>), which has ruled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">70 years</TIMEX>, kicked off its first presidential primary. In the past,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> has simply hand-picked his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> primary are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Interior Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Labastida Ochoa</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Madrazo Pintado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tabasco</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> say Labastida
could unite the technocratic and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist factions</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, polls show
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madrazo</ENAMEX> to be the early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, despite longstanding fraud allegations and
campaign funds of dubious origin.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> was punished for criticizing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s use of an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anthrax</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>. Her letter to the military newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stars and Stripes</ENAMEX> , which included a request that "numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
ask the questions" about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>'s possible side effects, was viewed by her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">superiors</ENAMEX> as a possible incitement to insurrection. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX> is the first
attempt to protect the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military against a germ warfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 Acres</NUMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Windows Upgrade</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times /CBS News</ENAMEX>
telephone poll shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s approval rating with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> is down to
"relationship theory" of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Business School</ENAMEX> associate professor, further
trouble may be on the way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Consumers</ENAMEX> view their relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-child," and their relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> as "childhood
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buddy</ENAMEX>." But their relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>? "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Master-slave</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX>
agrees: Now get back to work.

         
      
   
