
   
   
      
         
            Arresting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hose</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> approval of
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX> tax cut (dispensed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
having dedicated much front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX> to the emerging cut, runs
a front page "news analysis" piece on the politics of the vote but leads
instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>'s abandonment of its longstanding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>-per-market
ownership rule, a story nobody else fronts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times stuffs the tax cuts on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> and leads with the likelihood that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> will not be awarded an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> franchise any time soon. The LAT
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front</ENAMEX>'s top non-local story is a new bipartisan <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> report finding that
federal counterintelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> badly bungled their investigation into
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> nuclear espionage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe probe</ENAMEX> is also fronted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes that the narrow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">221-206</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-49</NUMEX>) votes
mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s promised veto of the bill (because he says it
squanders an historic opportunity to retire a substantial portion of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> debt) is unlikely to be overridden. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> gets at the high
quality of the economic analysis evident in the floor debate with its
observation that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point during a discussion of the bill's tax credit for
producing energy from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry waste</ENAMEX>, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ozens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> seated in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chamber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clucked</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chickens</ENAMEX> ..."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains the gist of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> ruling: If a market has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least eight</NUMEX> independently
owned TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>, then one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. This is a condition, the
Times notes, met by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s largest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> suspects
that a likely result of the ruling is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> will quickly try to
snatch up available <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> where they already own <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> have exuberant reaction quotes from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAX TV</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> wins with, "If we're going into the duopoly game,
we're the prettiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">du</ENAMEX>-op dance." It would have been nice however,
if the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> had spent a sentence or two explaining how such a momentous
market decision gets to be made, not by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, but by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> spying stories all point out that there was a multi-year delay in
investigating the contents of suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>'s computer--caused by
wrangling between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> which wanted a warrant to do so, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>, which
found the evidence for doing so less than compelling. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> report says
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> also focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> too much, ignoring other
possible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spies</ENAMEX> and other possible sites for their espionage. The coverage notes
however that the report discloses for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> was fired last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> after he failed a polygraph test in which he was asked if he ever
passed computer information on miniaturized nukes to unauthorized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            The WP front reports on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>'s new drought-driven water-use regulations. It
seems that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> just can't abide by such rules but that their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>
do a fine job of turning them in to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> for such now-criminal
violations as <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawn sprinkling</ENAMEX>. (You can use a hose though--but you have to hold
it.) And yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> were actually sent out on some calls. The story sallies
forth under a truly wonderful headline: PUT THE <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SPRINKLER DOWN SLOWLY</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> files on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Harvey Oswald</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> gave to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> became available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Archives</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has a look. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX> pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> is less
voluminous than the total <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald</ENAMEX> file as described by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> district
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> who once was shown a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">4-foot</NUMEX> stack by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The only really
new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> in the file about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald</ENAMEX>: An allowance and a housing subsidy paid
to him in addition to his factory job salary were decreed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
Party's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Committee</ENAMEX>. Also at the achives, says the paper, there's a
previously released tidbit revealing that on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> hunting trip while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, he "shot very badly."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbers</ENAMEX> indicating that
the Internet IPO boom is bust. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">156</NUMEX> Internet IPOs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37 percent</NUMEX>
are now below their offering price, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">68 percent</NUMEX> are below their first
trading price.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> also files what could be the first mention of a
revolutionary change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> plans to start
producing finished <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> of receiving a customer order.
Currently, says the story, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about 17-18 days</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler-Daimler</ENAMEX> takes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-12</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> to get the quickie treatment will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Camry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solara</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just a week</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> day <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trader</ENAMEX> murders took over the front pages,
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> workplace shooting fails to crack them. What are the newspapers
thinking with that? Is it the lower <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> count ("only" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>)? The lower-rent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vocations</ENAMEX> involved (plumbing and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> supplies)? Or that since it happened
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> already, it isn't really "news" now? And the answer is (envelope,
please): Yes.

         
      
   
