
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rudy: The Coming Mud Bath</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jodi</ENAMEX>,

            I came back from lunch in such a merry mood (and, no, the lunch wasn't the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-martini kind), brimming over with joy that we live in a land so bountiful
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can give away <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX>. Then I got your
e-mail and my heart sank. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, do you really find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> a "complex and
appealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>"? Are all your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> really hyper for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>--thrilled that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> will bless the lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> with her divine
presence?

            Maybe I should have sensed the warning signs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> when you partially
praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s
there-will-be-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">public-information</NUMEX>-given-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the</NUMEX>-press-while-I'm-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> media
strategy. Now, I will admit that I voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> mayoral election
based on the premise that the drastic improvement of life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
outweighed his obvious personality flaws. But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, surely you will agree with
me that temperament alone (not to mention his future vote to re-elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lott</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority leader</ENAMEX>) makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> cosmically ill-suited to serve
in a legislative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, especially since he would be required to work and play
well with others.

            You also find me jaded because I fail to grasp the "promise" of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary-Rudy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, do you really expect a high-minded debate on
public housing and the plight of upstate dairy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
campaign would be fought out on your TV screen with dueling negative ads about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> billing records and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> brutality. Such a down-and-dirty contest
would make <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumer-D'Amato</ENAMEX> mud bath seem like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Periclean Athens</ENAMEX> in
comparison.

            What politically would interest me? How about a presidential race between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>? As a political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, I desperately long to
watch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> with enough self-confidence and authenticity to resist the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prefabricated</ENAMEX> political dictates of the campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>.

            For all my apparent grumpiness, one of the joys of this e-mail
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">correspondence</ENAMEX> is that you find things in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> that I had missed, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Apple</ENAMEX>'s succulent tribute to cookbook <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Olney</ENAMEX>. But as
someone who, alas, had to compose one of those formulaic Times death
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">notices</ENAMEX>, let me provide a bit of explanation. The problem is not the
Times , which I think would print anything that wasn't obscene or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">libelous</ENAMEX> in these paid notices, but the bereaved themselves. As you look at
this sad-eyed page of agate type amidst your grief, you find yourself deciding
that this is not a moment for creative writing.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, please write me back with joyous tidings on happier topics.

         
      
   
