
   
   
      
         
            Looking Backward
            

            I'm going to sidestep your question of whether the information revolution
has changed the nature of the "good life," and point out that your description
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> as a "conservative in culture" clarifies some of what seemed so cloudy
in The Coming of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Industrial Society</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s fleeting discussion of
the "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX>" cultural events--so in the foreground of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life circa
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>--is somewhat startling with hindsight. After all, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>
standing between the last hurrah of an industrial age (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '50s</TIMEX>), and the
ascendance of a service-centered economy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> (with all the doubts that
came along with it--like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> manufacturing eroding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy; an assessment that reflected suspicion of an economy's
ability to thrive on building services rather than things). As an early
indicator of what the post-industrial world might look like (Woodstock <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>?),
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> would have been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good decade</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX> to examine in this book. Yet
he's far more interested in, say, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>, and the goings-on inside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>,
than what was happening on some upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>. Your description of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s cultural conservatism makes me wonder whether his decision to ignore the
cultural effects of post-industrial society had to do with his personal
distaste for the "counterculture" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> freaknik thing I've seen in old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">newsreels</ENAMEX>.

            It's an unfortunate omission because it's precisely this cultural
"information revolution" that has changed our world and defined our
post-industrial society--the same information revolution that allowed amplified
music to be synchronized with lights using "feedback" (i.e. information about
the system) to produce a psychedelic experience. Or the information embedded on
plastic films that allowed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>-track tapes to alter the way one experienced a day
on the beach. The entire <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> thing was a product of an information
revolution--one that initially empowered everyday <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to personalize their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> diet, eroding the principle of mass experiences through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, and
enhancing tribal impulses to identify with your clique. By not discussing these
aspects of the "post-industrial society," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> left us with a book whose value
is more for what it says about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX> than about the
21st . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell</ENAMEX>'s basically best on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX>, and if that's of interest to
you in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, then you'll enjoy reading The Coming of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post-Industrial</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>--I'm told by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith</ENAMEX> that this is to be our last installment on this
book. It's been lovely corresponding with you. I hope you've been writing your
messages from the beach ... Next time around, we'll see if we can discern how
the information revolution may have "changed the nature of the good life," as
you put it, for better or worse.

         
      
   
