
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day Trading Is for Suckers</ENAMEX>
            

            In the wake of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s shootings at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two day</TIMEX> trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> for one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> said that these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> did a good job of
warning prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> of the risks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading entails and added that if
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> followed the rules the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> laid out, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading was both easy and
profitable. Now, easy it may be, although spending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six and a half hours</TIMEX> staring
at a computer screen isn't my idea of fun. (Which makes you wonder why I'm a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>.) But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">profitable day</TIMEX> trading certainly isn't, and the current mania for
it is less a reflection of the moneymaking opportunities it offers than of the
allure of easy credit and the seemingly unstoppable conviction of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX>
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> can be beaten.

            The numbers are by this point well known, but they're no less staggering for
all that. Most estimates suggest that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 to 90 percent</NUMEX> of all day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> lose
money. And that's in absolute terms: These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> leave <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their day</TIMEX> trading
careers with less money than they had when they started. Those statistics say
nothing about how many day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> lose money in relative terms, which is to
say underperform the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">S&P 500</ENAMEX>. (If you do worse than an index fund, you're
effectively losing money, because you can invest in an index fund with no labor
or opportunity cost at all.) It's probably safe to say that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 5 percent</NUMEX>
of day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> are successful, even without considering the opportunity cost of
all the time and energy they have to put into their trading.

            This is not, needless to say, surprising. Day trading is predicated on a
fundamental misconception about the nature of stock prices, namely that they
are somehow persistent and predictable. Now, some interesting academic studies
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> have called into question the idea that stock prices move only
in a pure random walk (i.e., they're as likely to go up as go down at any one
moment). But the walk is effectively random, in the sense that patterns are
incredibly hard to discern and basically impossible to take advantage of with
any regularity. In order to succeed as a day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX> over time, you have to be
one thing: incredibly lucky.

            The media sort of gets this. But the attacks on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading have gotten too
mixed up with concerns about the impact of online <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brokerages</ENAMEX>, the rise of
individual investing, and the mania for Net stocks. These are distinct
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phenomena</ENAMEX>, and have nothing to do with what's wrong with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading. In the
long run, the impact of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading on stock prices is negligible, and although
the rise of the Net has facilitated day trading, in fact day trading as it's
done at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">All-Tech</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Momentum</ENAMEX> looks more like old investing than
new investing, in this sense: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who profit from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading are not
the day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> that reap huge commissions from all the trading,
just as old-line <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> tended to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to trade to increase churn
in their accounts and boost commissions.

            The thing that is most remarkable <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about day</TIMEX> trading, though, is the almost
complete absence of a coherent investment theory that could justify the
practice. If you read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Buffett</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lynch</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Burr Williams</ENAMEX>, you
get a clear sense of the principles that guide their investing. But if you talk
to day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and try to figure out why they believe they can beat the market,
you don't get any real ideas. You just get a host of anecdotes about great
trades. The press has exacerbated this problem by including in every article
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about day</TIMEX> trading at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> who says he's made <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of dollars. How he did it and why he doesn't get up from the table
and walk away always remain unexplained. Let's face it. If you go into any
casino, there's going to be someone there who's up many <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX>.
That may help us understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> keep gambling. It doesn't help explain
what gambling really means economically.

            Finally, it's crucial to remember that day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> have the dubious
advantage of playing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX>'s money, since most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> will lend them up
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of their existing capital to buy more stocks with. That has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
consequences: It increases risk, and it makes day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>' performance even
less impressive. If you're wagering <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150 percent</NUMEX> as much money as you have, the
profits when you succeed will be greater than otherwise. But so will be your
losses. What day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> need to ask themselves is: If I had put <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150 percent</NUMEX> of
my money in an index fund, what would my returns have been? But if they could
ask themselves that question, they wouldn't be day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
