
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News We Disapprove Of</ENAMEX>
            

            Good morning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>,

            I love evergreen headlines, those perpetually blooming stories that could
run in any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any year</TIMEX> (an example: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Jersey Official Indicted</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ties Alleged"</ENAMEX>). Well, the front page of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> provides
an all-time classic of the genre: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pediatricians Urge Limiting TV Watching</ENAMEX>."
Stop the presses! No, on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> thought, didn't I read that same story in the
Times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>? Or was it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>?

            Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX>, like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979 or 1959</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> editorial page was
the repository of the conventional wisdom written in a uniquely ponderous style
that combined voice-of-God self-confidence and the bromides of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX>-backed task-force report. All that has mercifully changed as the
edit page has been transformed under the editorship of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howell Raines</ENAMEX>. But every
so often, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> goes completely retro with a return to
yes-but-on-the-other-hand prose. Today, the edit page finally weighed in on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s Talk interview, devoting infinitely more space to the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intimate Hillary</ENAMEX>" than was deemed appropriate by the news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX>. (I have
long thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> should handle hot-potato stories like this
with a special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> page called: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">News We Disapprove Of</ENAMEX>.") But the
Times editorial concluded with a sentence so pompous and so
non-committal that it should be immediately be added to the syllabus in
journalism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, parse this one if you dare: "In a contest involving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> personalities
as distinctive as Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Guiliani</ENAMEX>, the potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX>, every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> will have to reach a decision that balances
all aspects of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s abilities, issue positions and personal
qualities."

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX> I was overjoyed to snag the last copy of the New York
Post at my little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> newsstand. That's where I learned of the
latest circulation-boosting gambit by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Maturity</ENAMEX> , that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up</NUMEX>-with-aging <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> published by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX>. The big story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> on the
senior circuit is an exclusive listing of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50</TIMEX> "sexiest" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> who are
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years old</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gere</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sarandon</ENAMEX> ("steam
heat"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Christie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Selleck</ENAMEX> ("anytime sexy"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Karan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rukeyser</ENAMEX> ("sexy in suits") and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Bacall</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Newman</ENAMEX> ("vintage
sexy").

            I'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52 years old</TIMEX>, balding, well-rounded, and doomed to always misplace my
reading glasses. But I'm also old enough to know that sexual allure does not
necessarily dim with age. (At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> anniversary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gala</ENAMEX>, I found myself positively tongue-tied, embarrassingly adolescent in my
awkwardness, on being introduced to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Bacall</ENAMEX>.) So why does the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX>
Maturity" spread leave me so uncomfortable? Would I feel different if this sexy
plus-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cavalcade</ENAMEX> appeared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>?

            My guess--and let's not delve too deeply into my psyche--is that I'm
offended by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX>'s role in sponsoring this silliness. There's something
about this middle-aged spread (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s, not mine) that suggests a
desperate need to join the self-esteem movement. It all seems, well,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Viagra-esque.</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, any reaction from a younger and fitter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
