
   
   
      
         
            Times Hits, Runs
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Katharine</ENAMEX>,

            Before you do anything else <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, grab the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and
read the front-page profile of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Brown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>. It's a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masterpiece on Brown</ENAMEX>'s transformation from reform-driven eco-visionary into
pragmatic city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pol</ENAMEX>. In an overly felicitous phrase that I nonetheless wish I'd
written, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Waldman</ENAMEX> says: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moonbeam</ENAMEX> has become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pothole</ENAMEX>." Gone is
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> limit on campaign contributions, gone are the denunciations of the
prison-industrial complex. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> boasts of his crackdown on crime, and
says: "I don't talk about sustainable development. I talk about downtown
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>." I confess to harboring some soft sentiments for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, though my
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have always said he's easier to admire from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">3,000 miles</NUMEX>
away.

            And now for a rant, combining my old energy as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> press
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> with my new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Industry Standard</ENAMEX> obsessions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times prominently published a story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> was
playing footsie with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America Online</ENAMEX>. This is important because as faster,
so-called broadband Internet access becomes more widespread, there will be a
fierce battle to control both the data pipes that come into our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and the
content that goes through them. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite@Home</ENAMEX>--which is now largely owned by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>--is sort of an early experiment in what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> might look like if
they combine an Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite</ENAMEX>) with a broadband service (@<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home</ENAMEX>).
Trouble is, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are kind of small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>. Hence, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> will want to ease out
of its deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excite</ENAMEX>, and move toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>. (I
didn't bring this story up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in part out of modesty: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> of mine published a story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months ago</TIMEX> suggesting that an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AT&T</ENAMEX>/AOL
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alliance</ENAMEX> was practically inevitable.)

            So OK: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> prints the story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> saying these talks are under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> and, not surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite@Home</ENAMEX>'s stock price drops like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">poll</ENAMEX> numbers; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> figure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite@Home</ENAMEX> will be the unwanted third
wheel. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite@Home</ENAMEX> issue statements
saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will honor their exclusive agreements through
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>.

            If you're the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , you're ideally suited--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journalistically</ENAMEX> obligated--to publish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a second day</TIMEX> story. You've moved
markets, and forced denials from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> major communications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. But in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ... there's nothing at all. It's as if the whole thing
never happened. Even though these are huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, there seems to be the
attitude that "it's just the Internet." I'll bet you'd never get this kind of
sketchy coverage if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> in question were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citibank</ENAMEX>. And while
of course we know that institutional jealousy is never a factor, it's
interesting to note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excite@Home</ENAMEX> has a market capitalization of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $9.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>, which contrasts intriguingly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>.

            Yours,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
