
   
   
      
         
            A Non-Profit IPO?
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq Stock Market</ENAMEX> are considering
plans to become for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and to issue stock. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will
be very valuable. Who gets the shares?

            Although both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> are non-profits (meaning that earnings are
not distributed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>), their ownership structures are clear. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX> is
owned by its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,366</NUMEX> seatholders--brokerage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> that have paid for the right
to trade on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>--the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly 6,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> securities. 

            As with any IPO, shares would be issued representing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of the
value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.  Current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> would get some of these shares: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> would exchange their seats for stock, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and listed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> would be able to purchase shares before any public offering. The
remaining shares would be issued to the public. Money from the initial sale
would go into the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' treasuries. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> say they need the
money to expand and compete with upstart high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>.  Once they are
normal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> can issue more stock or bonds at any time; it
is much harder for a non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX> to raise money. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> may also
distribute shares to its listed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, as a reward and incentive for
listing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX>. Shares that are sold or given away would, of course,
reduce the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>' share of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.

            Nevertheless, their ownership interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> may turn out to be
quite valuable. Estimates of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX>'s potential market capitalization (total
stock value) range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $15 billion</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,366</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYSE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $100,000 and $2.5 million</NUMEX> for their seats. But a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/1,366</NUMEX> share of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.4 million</NUMEX>.

            Why don't more non-profits make the switch? For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, most non-profit
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> are not actually profit-making <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> are
salivating for a piece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Stock Exchange</ENAMEX>. But even in the current
IPO frenzy, there wouldn't be much of a market for shares in, say, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX> or
your local soup <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX>, most non-profits (particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX>) are
not owned by anybody. In fact, this is a requirement for a non-profit that also
wishes to be tax-exempt: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s assets must be dedicated
permanently to charitable purposes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trustees</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum</ENAMEX>
could turn it into a for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> if they wanted to, but first they would
have to give away all its artwork, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, and endowment. Unlike the stock
exchange <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, they would not get any of the shares themselves. And if the
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> made a profit, it would have to pay taxes.

         
      
   
