
   
   
      
         
            Sympathy for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the worst features of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> politics is the way we treat decent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who fail to win elections. Examples include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>
and, yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George H.W. Bush</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            Now the press is starting to administer this public shaming in advance. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX> on the receiving end <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar Alexander</ENAMEX>, widely depicted as a
wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> awaiting his coup de grace in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ames</ENAMEX> straw poll on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX> have been flocking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s campaign like crows to
road-kill. Recent articles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> death-watch for pathos. Despite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of campaigning,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Iowans</ENAMEX> don't know who he is. He's broke. He can't get the air-conditioning in
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to work! The collective message: What a pathetic loser!

            I myself had some harsh words about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> campaign. I didn't
like the way he sold out his own legacy of decent, moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republicanism</ENAMEX> for
an ersatz, anti-government populism. But since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> went the way of
all political flesh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> has returned to his sounder instincts. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, he
has been espousing the kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">centrist positions</ENAMEX> he took when he served as a
(very fine) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> and later as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of education. On the
environment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> calls himself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Roosevelt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> who advocates
spending more on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Parks</ENAMEX>. On education, he has backed away from the
conservative panacea of vouchers and focused on the more realistic reform of
charter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> is short on novelty and excitement but long on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> and dedication, as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his six years</TIMEX> of futile campaigning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> show. He flopped this time, but not because of any defect in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.

            Assuming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>'s campaign does come to an end <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> as predicted, we
must ask why it never got off the ground. I think the reason is fairly obvious.
Another moderate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> with a famous name and far more money squashed him
like a bug. By offering "electability" as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> selling point, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexander</ENAMEX>
helped make the case for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX> redundant. But that's no reason
to despise a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> who tried hard, played fair, and will surely make a
gracious exit.

         
      
   
