
   
   
      
         
            Can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville Be Sued</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>?
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>--angered
by alleged misinterpretations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lady</ENAMEX>'s interview in Talk --was
going to put classified ads in the paper promising <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> "to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
who can show me that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> linked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s sexual misconduct
with his childhood." Is a promise like that legally enforceable?

            A promise is only legally binding if it is part of a contract. But a
contract needn't be a written document or even an oral agreement. If a
reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would conclude that a serious offer was being made, and
fulfills the terms, it can be considered a binding contract. If you put up
signs around the neighborhood saying, "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> for the return of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>," and I
spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> searching before finding and delivering your beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">tabby</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> will make you pay up. If you have gained no benefit and I have incurred
no cost, and it's a non-business situation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> will probably say it was
unreasonable for me to take you seriously. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX> would be harmed, not
helped, by someone proving him wrong about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>--and that someone would
enjoy vindication rather than enduring any cost. On the other hand, Carville
benefits both commercially and politically from his stagy promise itself, so
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> might hold him to it.

            In a recent case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimba Wood</ENAMEX> ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX> did not have to make
good on an advertisement suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> could redeem <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">700,000</NUMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi</ENAMEX>
Points" for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23 million</NUMEX> Harrier <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter jet</ENAMEX>. No reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> would
believe it, she said. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee, Haley Barbour</ENAMEX>, promised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> to any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who proved that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> budget proposal did not increase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> spending by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 50 percent</NUMEX>.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> filed breach of contract suits. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">A dozen</NUMEX> are still litigating.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNC</ENAMEX> has already settled with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> claimant for an undisclosed amount. Last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> talking-head <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph DiGenova</ENAMEX> got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> to fork up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldo Rivera</ENAMEX> broadcasted an offer of that amount to anyone who could cite a
case where a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was convicted of perjury for lying about sex.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville's Post</ENAMEX> quote was not an offer--it was a statement of
intent to make an offer. (Since he said he intended to publish an offer, no
reasonable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> could believe he intended his statement itself to be a
binding offer.) And on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> show <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next morning</TIMEX>, he announced
that he had decided not to publish the offer after all. He also said that the
ad he wasn't running would have promised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana State</ENAMEX>
University alumni <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX>, not to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> who proved him wrong. That means
even if he had made a legally binding promise, it would be hard for anyone but
his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX> to sue him if he failed to make good.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Explainer</ENAMEX> plans to offer <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> to any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who can show her that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX> made a legally enforceable offer.

            (As for the question raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carville</ENAMEX>'s non-offer, see this literary
analysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Kaus</ENAMEX>.)

            Next question?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Explainer</ENAMEX> thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX> contracts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Ayres</ENAMEX> for his invaluable
assistance.
            

         
      
   
