
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Pastor Prays</ENAMEX> and Tells

            Chatterbox jumped to an unfair conclusion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> when he said that the
following remark by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Lockhart</ENAMEX> was a dig at Jesse
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>: "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least one</NUMEX> of [the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has consulted about his
marital infidelity] has not made a secret of the fact that he's talked to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>." (See "
More on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychotherapy</ENAMEX>.") A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> has informed Chatterbox
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Philip Wogaman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pastor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundry United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, has written a whole book about ministering to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> during
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From the Eye of the Storm</ENAMEX> . It was published in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> to coincide with the impeachment hoopla. Chatterbox can't bring himself
to take a look at this book, but here's a snippet from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wogaman</ENAMEX>'s own rather
Uriah Heep-esque description of it on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>:

            

               
                  The book's subtitle is, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Pastor to the President Speaks Out</ENAMEX>," but I
hasten to say that it does not betray pastoral confidences. [Oh, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX>,
you're such a tease!] I also want it understood that book royalties go to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> because I do not believe it is right to profit by this national
tragedy. I hope it will help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> understand the deeper implications of the
presidential impeachment controversy ... I have sometimes felt I truly was in
the "eye of the storm." The book draws upon that experience, although it does
not invade private pastoral conversations. I have taken up issues related to
love and sex, repentance and forgiveness, and the relationship between personal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and public responsibility in political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>.
               

            

            Clearly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> is nowhere near being the biggest and most
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">sanctimonious</ENAMEX> self-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s inner circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX>/marriage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counselors</ENAMEX>. Incidentally, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> advantage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would enjoy if he were seeing a
secular psychotherapist would be a professional code of ethics that would come
down much harder on anyone who pulled this sort of stunt. A more cynical
possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> can't bring himself to believe is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
actually encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wogaman</ENAMEX> to write this book to help keep his poll
numbers up.

         
      
   
