
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax Chat and Tina Talk</ENAMEX>
            

            Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> is tax cuts. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> is the presidential campaign. Issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy</ENAMEX>.

            There's very little consensus on what the tax debate holds. For example, on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>, says it
would be best to just forget cutting taxes and go home. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, says he would just as soon wait on a tax cut until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX>
becomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. And on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">This Week</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX> says even a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700 billion</NUMEX> cut is too small, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> really
ought to scuttle tax cuts, pay off the national debt, and hike military
spending.

            Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> agree that the fate of a tax cut <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> will not be known
until after a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> recess. For now, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> are digging in rather than
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compromising</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> fall into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> camps. Those who argue that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
will compromise--i.e., sign a tax cut greater than the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 billion</NUMEX> ceiling he
now demands--point to several signs, such as (a) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s release of a modest
tax cut proposal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, (b) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s desire to make a deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> on
entitlement reform, and (c) the eagerness of some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to be seen
as tax-cutters before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election time</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol Gang</ENAMEX> ;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Page</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Carlson</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> ; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gigot</ENAMEX>,
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NewsHour With Jim Lehrer</ENAMEX> ).

            Pundits predicting a stalemate point out that (a) in an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">off-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
won't be as eager to compromise as he was on welfare in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, and (b) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> think a stalemate will work against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s
congressional elections ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Gang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hunt</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NewsHour</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Shields</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Late Edition</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Roberts</ENAMEX>; and This

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX>).

            On the campaign front, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> continue to express pity for the bumbling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and awe at the seemingly invincible <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> Some programs replay a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX> ad now running in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> which indirectly attacks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for his runaway
fund-raising. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>--such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gigot</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shields</ENAMEX>--think the ad
is ineffective because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W.</ENAMEX> raised all his money from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">under-$1,000</NUMEX>
contributions and seemingly without improper influence. The opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mafia</ENAMEX>
agrees that the remaining mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>--are in free-fall and must win big in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> straw
poll.

            On <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX> says that race will be the focus of
his campaign. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later that</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Edition</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>
agree that the race issue is a non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starter</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX> says it will pull
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> to the left, preventing him from having a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souljah</ENAMEX> moment." On
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Group</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX> make fun of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> and
agree that his campaign is still faltering.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> feast on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s revealing interview in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forthcoming</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, Talk . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s affair
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> stemmed from an "abusive" home environment and that his
mistakes don't negate his other accomplishments. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Week</TIMEX> even opens
its show with a special roundtable just on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>. (To her credit, Cokie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> does mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> is owned by the same parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> as
Talk .) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristol</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheshire</ENAMEX> grin on his face, calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s remarks
"the epitome of modern liberal psychobabble," a sentiment shared by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pundits</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX>--think it will hurt her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
chances. Meanwhile, the commentariat is divided over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tongue-in-cheek</ENAMEX> campaign trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Page</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zuckerman</ENAMEX> approve, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McLaughlin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Huffington</ENAMEX> disapprove).

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX>, Child of the '60s
After inveighing against the raping and pillaging at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Woodstock '99</NUMEX> (a video
segment of concert-goers is captioned "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Attendees & Hopped-Up</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Psychos</ENAMEX>"), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John McLaughlin</ENAMEX> finds himself waxing nostalgic for the hippies of
yesteryear: "At the first <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Woodstock</ENAMEX> there was [also] heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>, there were
[also] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> standing around [under a hot sun], there were long lines for
food, but they were respectable."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Winners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Losers</ENAMEX>
When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Novak</ENAMEX> notes that even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Toricelli</ENAMEX> voted for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s tax cut, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> calls
Toricelli a rich-coddling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poseur</ENAMEX>--"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> [of] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman Sachs</ENAMEX>."
"His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> is partly you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>," she says. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novak</ENAMEX> responds: "The winners
of society, I hope."

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Last Word</ENAMEX>
"It works out to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about 5 cents</NUMEX> per lie."
--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Webber Wright</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX> fine of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
