
   
   
      
         
            Going <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day-Trader</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jodi</ENAMEX>,

            A personal confession is in order after your vivid portrayal of your normal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Breakfast Table</ENAMEX> routines aboard the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>. (I trust that you don't actually
partake of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverage</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>, since in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s New York
that's a "quality of life" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> that makes you eligible for an
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all-expenses-paid night</TIMEX> in the lockup on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rikers Island</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, while you were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">luxuriously</ENAMEX> riding to work in air-conditioned comfort aboard the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX>, I was
among the downtrodden scanning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> in a steamy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>. (At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conroy's Pharmacy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Tisbury</ENAMEX>, I have a reputation as a
wild-and-crazy big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spender</ENAMEX> because I reserve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> a day--the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">York</ENAMEX> 
               Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
papers, plus the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , where I hold
a day job as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>.)

            I haven't yet read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s wagging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tongue</ENAMEX>, though <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this evening</TIMEX> I will be headed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> in quest of the calming
breezes of a window air conditioner. But I suspect that would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had been searching for a nurturing and safe interview in which to
discuss the purported real reasons that she plays "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stand By Your Man</ENAMEX>."
(Remember, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX> wrote a gushy paean to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "sex appeal" in
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> .) I do find it telling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s latest theory about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>'s "abuse" as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is the kind of psychological claptrap that gives
liberalism a bad name. About the only mystery left is the psychological roots
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s compulsion to lie under oath.

            As for your bet that the actual Talk interview will prove a
disappointment, it seems so self-evident that I will resist the offer of a free
Talk subscription. After all, as we have learned from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
scandals, talk is cheap.

            I too was fascinated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Barton</ENAMEX>'s day
trading. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> "going day <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trader</ENAMEX>" replace the already dated "going postal" in
our lexicon?) Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> murders occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s paper was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chance to weigh in with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive Barton</ENAMEX> piece. I loved the small authoritative details like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>
"hunched in silence over his usual cafeteria-lunch fare of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey burger</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fries</ENAMEX>." (Writing for news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> is where I learned the trick of detailing
what was eaten during noteworthy meals. Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, there was an
expression on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>, "Get out your menus, here comes
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> .)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, I think you're a little hard on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s offhanded
admission that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>'s actions don't stem from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading alone. He was,
after all, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who had apparently already murdered his prior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
The sentence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> story that spoke volumes to me was the one
that read: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About 1990</ENAMEX>, [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX>] started out focusing on no-load mutual funds
he had selected by doing research in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ." That,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alas</ENAMEX>, is the odyssey that so many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have followed in the
glitz-and-greed '90s--abandoning safe investments in the quest for instant
riches.

            What was sorely missing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> recap was the aggressive
stance that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> has taken in trying to regulate day trading. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> stated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> has emerged as the
industry's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nemesis</ENAMEX>.") And my new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>
Galvin, said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> , "If there's one thing this whole
thing points out, it's that there is a dire need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> to clearly
identify this [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trading] as a problem."

            But it's only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, so it's early for us to right all the wrongs of a
world gone mad. So with my fingers black with newsprint, this seems like the
perfect moment to take a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late-afternoon</TIMEX> swim.

            See you at breakfast tomorrow

         
      
   
