
   
   
      
         
            Hilary'd Out
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jodi</ENAMEX>,

            As a proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> neighborhood that I pray will always be
called the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper West Side</ENAMEX> and as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> who has never deigned
to look at "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Circuits</ENAMEX>," I'm afraid that I don't have much to add to your clever
insights from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX>.

            The story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s papers that caused me to mentally brake to a halt was a
front-page piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Sipress</ENAMEX> about how the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos National Laboratory</ENAMEX> is now busily researching traffic patterns.
Since we have all marveled (maybe grumbled might be a better word) at the way
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bottlenecks</ENAMEX> appear and disappear with no apparent cause, I sped through the
story in hopes of discovering a telling insight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, all that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> seem to have come up with is a series of new
metaphors to describe traffic jams. Are they like "water molecules freezing
into ice"? Or is traffic movement akin to "the remarkable darting motion of a
school of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>"? The article, though, did have one memorable bit of deadpan
humor. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Barrett</ENAMEX>, is described as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> "who convinced Los
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alamos</ENAMEX> that traffic was a matter of grave national security." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unmentioned</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Eisenhower</ENAMEX> used the same flimsy
national-security excuse to build the interstate highway system.

            I'm indebted to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maven</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rich Galen</ENAMEX> and his e-mail
newsletter "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mullings</ENAMEX>" for putting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> interview in its proper context:
It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> story," an overhyped journalistic frenzy designed to
cover the fact that when the shrinks go on vacation, there is virtually no real
news. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galen</ENAMEX>, who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, makes his insights available to the world at
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mullings</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.) A typical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> story, which I remember from my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early days</TIMEX>
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ," was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> democracy-in-peril scandal called
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debategate</ENAMEX>." There were breathless charges, never fully proved as I recall,
that someone from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> had swiped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>'s debate
notebook.

            I realize that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in my haste to wrap up our correspondence in a
timely fashion, I never got a chance to explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race makes
me so uncomfortable. Let me count the ways:

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). After an impeachment-tinged year in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> marriage drowned
out all other news (admittedly with a generous assist from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s decision to run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trek</ENAMEX> yet again through that tiresome swamp. Maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> wants
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vindication</ENAMEX>, but as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> I simply crave relief from this entire
topic.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Yes, running for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> while serving as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> does trouble
me in ways that go beyond legalistic questions of whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> funds are
used for her travel and campaign expenses. The law, for example, does not
require reimbursement for the extensive costs of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> protection when
she campaigns. Nor is there a way to wall her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> off from all
political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, of course, has the same problem. But, at least,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> was elected to his current post.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Despite being the crucible of the feminist movement, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ranks, I
believe, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">49th</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> being elected to public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> history has ever been elected to a statewide post more
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">august</TIMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenant governor</ENAMEX>. So why don't I hail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s candidacy as an
important feminist breakthrough? Because like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liddy Dole</ENAMEX>--and in sharp contrast
to, say, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dianne Feinstein</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> owes her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> solely
to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s political career. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> will never develop its own cadre of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Congresswoman Nita Lowey</ENAMEX> are shut out of
the glamour races.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>). As a baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, I was appalled by the cynicism with which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
suddenly declared her secret yen for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>. Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, I had a lengthy
discussion with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>. In all her rhapsodies about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> never mentioned any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American League</ENAMEX> allegiance to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>). I do have some lingering problems with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpetbagger</ENAMEX> issue. As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teen-ager</ENAMEX>, I was in my jejune fashion totally opposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Kennedy</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> candidacy. And I certainly didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">cotton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>-transplant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckley</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> victory on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservative</ENAMEX> ballot line.

            That said, I am now officially <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'d out.

            Over to you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>,

         
      
   
