
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Complex</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Sex</ENAMEX>
            

            Good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Walter</ENAMEX>,

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> shouldn't bother expounding on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX>
That's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unfit To Print</ENAMEX>. That's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>'s job, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> she shows us why.
Dowd nails the exact reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s Talk interview is
distasteful. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, because in it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> publicly savages her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>- and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>-in-laws. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>, because in it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> compares herself to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>. And
most importantly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s profiler, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Franks</ENAMEX>, is
married to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.A.</ENAMEX> and longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nemesis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Morgenthau</ENAMEX>. The
Times editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, I'm sure, would make this ethical boo-boo bleed
with ink. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> refrains from any pontification on the conflict-of-interest;
she trusts her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to spot a moral problem when they see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            I'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than half</NUMEX> your age, so it will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a few years</TIMEX> before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AARP</ENAMEX> starts to flirt with me. But like you, I doubt that a come-on as blatant
as the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Maturity</ENAMEX> cover would stir my subscription, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX>,
or vote.

            The list you mention is part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Maturity</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September-October</TIMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Great Sex</ENAMEX>" issue, which proposes that older <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are just as lusty as
their younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> the magazine hyped the issue with a study
supposedly proving that older <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> bonk more frequently than anyone
previously knew. The stats have already garnered a ton of attention: "If you're
under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age of 40</TIMEX> and you go to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>, make sure you knock on
the door first!" a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> anchor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gaily</ENAMEX> warned me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>.

            But a great story on the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> reveals some blatant miscounting behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> blitz. It turns out that
the study's sampling began at the ripe old age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX>, and that it used <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45-to-60</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-olds</TIMEX> as its largest polling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The mean age of those polled is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>,
even though the average AARP <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX>. So the study isn't only insulting
... it's also misleading.

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jodi</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
