
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax-Cutting Folly</ENAMEX>
            

            Sometimes you find yourself having to say the obvious. So here goes: There
is no good economic or social motive for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$792 billion</NUMEX> tax cuts just
passed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Representatives</ENAMEX>. The justification
for the cuts rests upon a misapprehension of the lessons of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX>, a
foolishly optimistic view of the certainty of economic forecasts, a confusion
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private goods, and an almost willful averting of the eyes from
the realities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. I know the cuts were dead on arrival. But
it's still amazing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> passed them.

            Last things first. Tax cuts, in good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Keynesian</ENAMEX> fashion, stimulate the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. But the economy is already running at or near its productive capacity.
Bond yields have soared above <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> on fears of inflation, and an
interest-rate hike by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> meeting now seems a foregone
conclusion. In this environment, tax cuts serve only to overheat an already
racing economy. And increased consumption is hardly what the economy needs. An
argument can be made that spending on education and infrastructure would help
boost the economy's productivity in the long run. Certainly spending down the
debt, reducing government borrowing, would have that effect by encouraging more
productive uses of capital. It's hard to imagine that a cut in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s hardly
confiscatory tax rates would do the same, especially when the major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of both bills would be the wealthy, who have already reaped
enormous benefits from the boom.

            But perhaps, as we've been told time and again by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Archer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX>, we should trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to spend their own money. Of course we
should. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Frank</ENAMEX>, who's worried that we're buying too many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expeditions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boxsters</ENAMEX>, I don't really care what particular private goods
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> consume. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> should also be able to spend their money on
public goods such as public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">stealth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX>, and they
can't do that if the share of the federal budget devoted to discretionary
spending keeps getting smaller and smaller. No matter how much I'd like to, I
can't get together with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> and pay for road improvements on the
Interstate, or invest in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>. I know the obviousness of this point is
staggering, but so too is the disingenuousness of the rhetoric surrounding tax
cuts. The money's going to be spent in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place or another. It's just a
question of where, not a question of trusting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or not.

            A centerpiece of both tax cuts is a severe trimming of the capital-gains
tax, which seems like a very odd decision at a time when short-term investing
is on the rise and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are having absolutely no trouble raising capital.
Here again, the benefits of this cut will flow almost entirely to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wealthiest</ENAMEX>, and will solve a problem that currently does not exist (that is,
capital scarcity). And although any capital tax distorts capital allocation,
isn't encouraging long-term investing a distortion that recent events in the
global economy suggest might not be such a bad thing?

            Most important, it's essential to remember that all of these tax cuts and
spending plans are predicated on the idea that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> can
make meaningful predictions about economic growth, tax revenues, and budget
surpluses <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15 years</TIMEX> out. They can't. The record of economic
forecasting is an abysmal one, not because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forecasters</ENAMEX> are stupid or biased
but because the economy is just too complex to predict with any accuracy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm</ENAMEX> did generously say that if the surpluses don't materialize, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
could just raise taxes to make up the difference. He also said that he had some
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> swampland, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brooklyn Bridge</ENAMEX>, and a couple of hot Internet IPOs he
wanted to sell us.

         
      
   
