
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> as Urban Planner
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello Walter</ENAMEX>,

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> built a neighborhood again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            A "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">House & Home</ENAMEX>" section story announced that the previously
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">indeterminate area</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 23rd</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">42nd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Side</ENAMEX> should now be referred to as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NoMad</ENAMEX>, for north of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Park</ENAMEX>. (In
this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, one sure mark of a commercial-turned-residential neighborhood is a
syllabic acronym. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soho</ENAMEX> stands for south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribeca</ENAMEX> is the triangle
below <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Dumbo</ENAMEX> is down under the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Manhattan Bridge</ENAMEX>). The story does not
reveal how many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorkers</ENAMEX> have rented or bought <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NoMad</ENAMEX> recently.
Instead, it features a few fashion industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> who moved there
in search of stately <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prewar buildings</ENAMEX>, fantastic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, and affordable
housing prices. The fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, for example, pays
a mere <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> a month in rent.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> does this at least once a year. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> it instructed us
to start calling a desolate stretch on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Side TunJav</ENAMEX> (the area is
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Tunnel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Javitz</ENAMEX> convention center). The name
never took off, and neither did the neighborhood.

            And when will the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lay the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Circuits</ENAMEX>" section to rest? When it
stops bringing in so many ads, I guess. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Technology Journal</ENAMEX>" section
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is trying to steal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s dial-up business by offering the same service for little or no money. AOL
currently has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21.95</NUMEX> per month they pay for the
service generates <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s revenue. So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> could soon join <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> price-cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mausoleum</ENAMEX>. In contrast, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Circuits</ENAMEX>"
prints stories on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> working in tech-oriented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> jobs and on
password proliferation. OK, so the section isn't devoted to hard tech news. But
it makes digital culture seem so dull that it's probably keeping a couple
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thousand Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> offline.

            I see I've turned this message into a harangue against my beloved
Times . I feel guilty, like I've just publicly insulted my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Jodi</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
