
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch Bitch</ENAMEX>

            No self-respecting cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> could resist a potshot at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> for putting The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project on their
covers--even though it is the best movie showing at the moment. So here
goes: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> are right to hype this movie, but they're hyping it for the
wrong reasons. They're playing it as a breakthrough-in-marketing
story--small-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> hit on 
big-time strategy--when it's actually the oldest marketing story in the
history of culture: scaring and delighting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> and making oneself rich
and famous by pushing back the boundaries of what is commonly thought of as
realistic.

            This would be a fairly obvious thought to have if you saw the movie, as I
did, in the eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Catskills</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> away from the outlandish
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moorish</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olana</ENAMEX>, built by the richest and most famous (in
his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson River</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">School</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Edwin Church</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1826-1900</TIMEX>). On the one hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> was as much of a marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX> are said to be. His best-known painting is a
giant canvas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ecuadorian mountains</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heart</ENAMEX> of the Andes
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1859</TIMEX>) , which he displayed as if it were a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> of the real unto
itself. He had it framed by heavy curtains, surrounded by semicircular benches,
and lit by gaslight, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could sit and stare at it at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, as if in
attendance at a play. He charged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX> and handed out opera
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">glasses</ENAMEX> or special metal tubes, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> could pick out this detail and that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. This was a whole new way to exhibit art, and it made him not only the most
notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>--but also
the first mere <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> who could afford to build a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> on what was then the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superritzy Hudson</ENAMEX>.

            The painting that makes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> worth remembering, though, came <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
earlier, when he took the most overrepresented theme in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art to date,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niagara Falls</ENAMEX>, and convinced everybody they'd never seen it before. In
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retrospect</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>'s style doesn't seem realistic at all, at least as we tend
to mean the word <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. He left out the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> that lined the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the tourist trap, as well as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> who
rubbernecked there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>. But his painting felt more real than what had
come before it, because it was bigger and wider and more maniacally detailed,
and because every <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">brushstroke</ENAMEX> contributed to the general sense of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>'s
ferocious power as it rushed to the edge. Coming as it did not long after the
invention of photography, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niagara Falls</ENAMEX> exploited that reigning
convention of "the real" to communicate a sense of what lay beyond reality--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">divine</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> just under the surface of things, there for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> to harness on
its way to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Manifest Destiny</ENAMEX>.

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair Witch</ENAMEX> Project is more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niagara Falls</ENAMEX> than
Heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andes</ENAMEX> . The reason it's so scary is that it feels so real,
even though, being a work of  supernaturalism, it breaks all the rules of
so-called reality. The reason it feels so real is because it uses the latest
signifier of realism--home video--and not just because it's the style of the
moment (the reason most music video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> employ the technique) but because
it's the best way to get across the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gothic</ENAMEX> vision of the world just
outside your door--the nameless evil just beyond the video camera's little pool
of light. Oddly, as visions go, it's not depressing in the least. What's
depressing is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who celebrate a movie like this for its commercial,
rather than its aesthetic, triumphs. 

         
      
   
