
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Election</ENAMEX> on the Web

            Ask a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> schoolchild to
name his favorite political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and you might be surprised. Instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Dem</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tory</ENAMEX>, you might hear, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Loony</ENAMEX>."

            Yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Loonies</ENAMEX> are an
official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> and a Web site. The only problem is that, just
as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Britain</ENAMEX>'s elections approach their climax, it's been down. That's
because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loony Webmaster</ENAMEX> fell ill. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>, all you'd find at The
Official <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monster</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Raving Loony Party Site</ENAMEX> was a picture of some strange-looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and a
promise the site will be "back online very shortly."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Loonies</ENAMEX> are far from the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> to invade the Internet. As the
political eyes of the world turn to watch whether the heavily favored, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Party</ENAMEX> trounce the long-ruling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stiff Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Major</ENAMEX>, some snazzy Web sites
are waiting to show them what's really going on.

            While the proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> with Internet access is much
smaller than in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> seem to be somewhat
ahead of their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> in using the Net to communicate with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>. They are eager to participate in online forums, such as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citizens Online</ENAMEX>
Democracy, to reach out to young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>.

            What they said in that forum
wasn't much different from what you'd hear in a televised <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> debate. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Major showed a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> acerbity. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>'s manifesto," he wrote,
"was more revealing for what it left out. It didn't say that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> they
would sell out to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> they would raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of pounds</NUMEX>
in tax in their emergency <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> budget. And in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX> they would hand more
power back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and start the process that could lead to the break-up
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>."

            By
contrast, the "media savvy" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s responses, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> in the
subsequent online discussion noted, "only seemed to be an advert for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labour</ENAMEX>
manifesto ... whereas all the other replies seem to have taken some time in
their approach to the questions." (Perhaps, suggested another, that's because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blair</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisers</ENAMEX> "had probably moved him onto something they thought more
urgent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> way through the piece, like buying [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX> a drink, and
someone else finished it off!")

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, to be sure, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 50</NUMEX> of the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">641</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> have e-mail. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 80</NUMEX>
percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> had Web pages by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. But in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> votes
are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> for the individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. Perhaps as a result, the
sites maintained by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>'s major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> tend to be far more
interactive and user-friendly than the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> party sites, which were little
better than electronic billboards.

            In addition, powerful
independent political sites--similar to the now-defunct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PoliticsNow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s
AllPolitics over here--churn out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsbriefs</ENAMEX>, analysis, and information.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> are outstanding: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
Election <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">97 and Election 97</TIMEX>.

            GE97, in addition to polls,
rundowns of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, backgrounders on salient issues, events calendars,
chat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and a wrap up of current betting odds, allows you to build your
own "party manifesto." The site will then compare your choices on the issues
with those of the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> (also displayed) and tell you which comes
closest to what you want. Or you can play the games of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Trivial Politics</ENAMEX>" and
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mystery Margins</ENAMEX>."

            Election
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">97</ENAMEX> uses a new <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Virtual Reality Modeling Language</ENAMEX> technology to provide 3-D maps
that give <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> a better understanding of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituencies</ENAMEX> are
spread throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and where the critical districts lie. It also
provides an extensive set of links to other political sites, including those
maintained by many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            As in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> offer a wide
variety of information to Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> funded the general election sites that everyone used--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathered</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PoliticsNow</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> sired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AllPolitics</ENAMEX> -- and most major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and TV
channels, notably the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>, had election pages. But, except on election
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, these were a relatively small part of their Web sites, let alone their
overall news. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, however, major news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are spending
heavily to make their election sites the main focus of their overall Web sites.
For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> has its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.K. Elections</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'97</NUMEX> page with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guides</ENAMEX>, polls, and an election share-price index. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observer</ENAMEX> have a broad site packed with information. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC</ENAMEX>, which
is adding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-person Web operation, plans to provide live
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">audio</ENAMEX> and video streams on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.

            Early in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> heralded the Year of the Internet--to be climaxed by a
presidential election in which the Internet would make a significant
difference. It didn't happen. But a post-election poll by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wirthlin Group</ENAMEX>
showed one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> claimed the Internet "influenced" the way they voted.
And on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> saw their ratings drop while
Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> flooded election-oriented sites in record numbers.

            Already <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> have been predicting that the Internet will
make a difference in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> elections. To watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> fawn over online
tools and techniques, many might think so. There is, however, one thing for
sure. On <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> political Web sites will be flooded by
enthusiastic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">users</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> will crash. There will be delays in getting
returns. And more than likely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> will point to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1</TIMEX> election as
the political dawn of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Great Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age</ENAMEX> of the Internet.

             

         
      
   
