
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Downsizing the Mob</ENAMEX>

            When, after an absence of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Pacino</ENAMEX> returned to the screen in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea of Love</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>),
he looked like a human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">filament</ENAMEX>: all dark, burning eyes that never seemed to
blink. His intensity was startling, but you couldn't be sure how to take him.
Always an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> of moods, his timing had become even more capricious. He didn't
speak his lines, he distended them: He never seemed to want to let them out of
his mouth. At once manic and zoned-out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pacino</ENAMEX> acted in a hambone universe of
his own, and when he was rewarded with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> for his grandstanding in
Scent of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woman</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>)--well, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> in his new film,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX> , might say, "Fuh- get about it."

            In
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donnie Brasco , Pacino</ENAMEX> has been cast as a sad little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-rater
named "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty" Ruggiero</ENAMEX>, who boasts repeatedly of having "clipped" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, yet
is always passed over for promotions within the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>." With his gold chains
and fur collars, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX> is a howlingly tacky parody of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX>, and Pacino
uses all his blowhard insecurities, along with his patented air of electrified
stupor, to elicit from us an astounding degree of sympathy. Nothing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX> says
or does comes out right--especially his adoption of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">protégé</ENAMEX>, a young jewel
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thief</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX>) who turns out, of course, to be an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undercover FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.

            The miracle of the film, which is based on a memoir by the
real "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brasco</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph D. Pistone</ENAMEX> (in collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Woodley</ENAMEX>), is
that with so many layers of irony, it's so emotionally pure--and so wrenching.
Partly this comes from the tension between the snappy, driving screenplay by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Attanasio</ENAMEX> and the elegiac tone of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Newell</ENAMEX>
(along with his magnificent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Doyle</ENAMEX>). And partly it comes from
Pacino, whose epic self-absorption, in this context, makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX> seem
heartbreakingly vulnerable, even while he's blowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> off. It's
hard to think of another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX> with this range of moods: satirical,
sometimes hilarious, yet suffused with a sense of loss and riddled with the
kind of violence that makes you recoil and lean forward simultaneously.

            I knew the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screenwriter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Attanasio</ENAMEX>, in college and later, when he was the chief film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . Watching Donnie

               Brasco , I remembered that he loved to quote from a relatively obscure
scene in The 
               Godfather , the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by the stove in the Corleone
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clemenza</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard S. Castellano</ENAMEX>) discoursed on the art of
frying sausages and peppers for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacino</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loose</ENAMEX> and giddy, a
relief from all the gore and gravitas, the scene made even more explicit the
movie's theme of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>," both real and extended. As nightmarish as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corleones</ENAMEX>' lives came to be, there was still something seductive about being
taken under the wings of expansive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> figures with few uncertainties about
what they were put on this earth to do. What a kick to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pacino</ENAMEX>, 25 years
later, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clemenza</ENAMEX> role, demonstrating for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Donnie</ENAMEX>" how to make coq au
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vin</ENAMEX> . This time, though, the scene has an undercurrent of shame. Pistone
knows that he's exploiting the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s best, most fatherly instincts, and
it tears him up. Later, there's a tiny but significant moment when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX>
wonders how "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Donnie</ENAMEX>" could be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traitor</ENAMEX> when he's been a guest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>--when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX> has cooked for him.

            
Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Godfather , Donnie</ENAMEX> Brasco
revolves around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, except that they're now the source of guilt instead
of reassurance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX> seems drawn to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Donnie</ENAMEX>" because he bears a physical
resemblance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangster</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkie</ENAMEX> who keeps his distance. So
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX>'s exhortations on the subject of wise-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> etiquette--carry your money in
a wad, not a wallet, lose the facial hair--have an unusual zeal: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX> is
looking for another shot at fatherhood. Pistone, who dislikes the officious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>," boasts of having his hooks in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX>, but comes
to dread (and delay) the moment when he'll be pulled out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operation</ENAMEX> Donnie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brasco</ENAMEX> and called upon to bring about his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>'s demise. There's another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tortured</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, too: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pistone</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, who languish in the
absence of a steady <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.

            I wasn't
looking forward to the scenes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX>, because the
stick-in-the-mud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> has become such a cliché--although I was curious to see
what the vivid young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Heche</ENAMEX> could do with a role in which she
didn't have to shed her clothes. As written and played, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX>'s
scenes are intrusions in the best sense: They gnaw on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pistone</ENAMEX> from another
angle; they add a point to the film's complex geometry. Heche, who played Demi
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed doctor girlfriend</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Juror</ENAMEX> , brings a wounded poetry
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX>'s bedragglement. Sagging under the weight of running a household--and
of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>' unspoken but persistent disappointment--she has no vocabulary
to convey to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> what she's going through. She can't share his work or
know his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> (sometimes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>) whereabouts, and you can see how the
powerlessness eats at her. When she finally takes action--changing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s
phone number without informing him--her justification has a scary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Now I</ENAMEX>
know how it feels to be in control."

            On the evidence of his book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pistone</ENAMEX> was truly torn up
about having abandoned his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> it took him to infiltrate the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mob</ENAMEX>, but he didn't lose as much sleep over what he was doing to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>
family. That's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>'s conceit. And the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX> seems to have
had much less stature. (The part <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pacino</ENAMEX> plays is a fusion of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX> and the
nobler aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang leader</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Black</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Napolitano</ENAMEX>--whom the film reduces
to a remorseless hothead, played by the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of movie bullies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madsen</ENAMEX>.) The story has been fictionalized, but it hasn't been <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>-ized.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX> gives us a novel perspective on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX>--as the bottom
feeders of capitalism. Underlings huddle in the cold outside a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Little Italy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>, waiting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, who emerges from a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX> with a fat
cigar in his mouth. Most of the time, these shabby "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>" just sit around
and rack their (small) brains for new schemes, worried that if profits fall too
low, they're going to find themselves "clipped" or "whacked." They're like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesmen</ENAMEX> who have to meet their quotas or they're out--downsized, only
literally, into small pieces.

            Scenes
like the ones in the social <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> have a real comic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX>, an "animal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>," reclines on a ghastly blue-green lounge
chair in a red sweat suit, watching videotapes of gazelles being pounced on and
devoured by <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX>. (He longs to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>, but he ends up as the gazelle.) He
can't even mount a competent search of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pistone</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobile</ENAMEX> for a "wire,"
finally giving up with the stereo in a shambles and offering to buy another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. ("You want a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DeVille?</ENAMEX>") Sprawled on a motel sofa, fielding awestruck
questions from a couple of junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pistone</ENAMEX> expounds on the meaning
of the phrase "Fuh-get about it" (which, depending on one's inflection, can
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> fatalistic acceptance, doomed resignation, murderous rage, enthusiastic
agreement, or nothing in particular) in a speech that will live long in the
hearts of gangster-movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mavens</ENAMEX>. Apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX>'s last line in the film,
which is moving but also way too pat, there isn't a single element on which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attanasio</ENAMEX> hasn't put a fresh spin.

            
Nor is there a moment when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newell</ENAMEX> takes the
easy way out. I've always found his films ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance With a Stranger , The</ENAMEX>
Good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Weddings</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funeral</ENAMEX> ) a little obvious, but his
work here has an authentic sense of place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX> feels rooted.
More important, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newell</ENAMEX> molds these disparate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> into a tightly knit
family of their own. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depp</ENAMEX> does fine, believable work. His "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Donnie</ENAMEX>" is cagey and
recessive, and when he reverts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Pistone</ENAMEX>, he doesn't relax--he gets wiry,
as if he needs to discharge all his tension. If there's a problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depp</ENAMEX>'s
acting in general, it's that he's so serious, so concentrated, so unplayful;
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> almost never have more than a single dimension at a time.

            But these are quibbles:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX> is everything it needs to be. It might not have the scope
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Godfather or The Godfather Part II</ENAMEX> , yet among all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gangster</ENAMEX> pictures since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s epic, it has no peer. ( Goodfellas ?
Fuh-get about it.) Exploring a more mundane milieu, it serves as the missing
link between us and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Godfather</ENAMEX> --a gangster movie for a mingier, more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cynical</ENAMEX> era, when even doing good comes with a terrible cost, and where every
family tie is a snap of the wrist away from a garrote.

            
               "Fuh-get about it":
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX>) with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Blake Nelson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giamatti</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

            
               A domestic spat: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne Heche</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pistone</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depp</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

            
               Dreams of the future:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lefty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Pacino</ENAMEX>) and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Brasco</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depp</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

         
      
   
