
   
   
      
         
            The Happy Pornographers

            I suppose it sounds strange
to call <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> yet another drama of family values. The film
follows a well-hung stud in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> porn-flick industry, and it doesn't
shy away from recounting his lewder adventures. It even invites us to love him
and all his scummy, sinning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Wahlberg</ENAMEX>--but this
sounds all wrong, you still want to call him Marky <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>), is recruited into the
world of porn in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, when he is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>. This happens because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie</ENAMEX> still lives at
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with his awful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>; a wimpy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and a drunken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, who runs
around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> calling him stupid. He dreams vaguely of stardom, but for the
time being works as a dishwasher in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">One night</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burt Reynolds</ENAMEX>), who happens to be a porn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, spots talent beneath
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie</ENAMEX>'s bulging zipper. Back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> asks him to pull out his love
gun. His suspicions are confirmed, and he tells <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie</ENAMEX> to call him about getting
into the business. We know we should be horrified, but we're not. We've seen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>. We know how badly he needs a pat on the back. Against our better
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">instincts</ENAMEX>, we think, "Go with this nice older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Thomas Anderson</ENAMEX>, waits awhile
before playing his cards. The early scenes unfold with a patience that's rare
in movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>. Like a kinder, gentler <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Altman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> takes time
to introduce us to his underground drifters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie</ENAMEX> goes for his audition, which
turns out to be sex on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> with a pretty but inappropriately cheerful
runaway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollergirl</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Graham</ENAMEX>), so named because she lives her whole life
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">skates</TIMEX>. Soon he's shooting his debut movie under the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk Diggler</ENAMEX>.
His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first day</TIMEX> on the set is a classic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice</ENAMEX>-in-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> scene, except that
the logistics of the shoot involve the cleansing of vaginas and polite
whispered negotiations about where to ejaculate. The atmosphere is supportive,
even wholesome, until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> finally stirs in some sicko stuff. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX> party <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ODs</ENAMEX>. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, who is married, has sex with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">driveway</ENAMEX> while <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> stand around watching. Slowly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anderson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX> up
a simultaneously lighthearted and sinister mood, as if this were a thriller set
at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp.

            He seems to be saying that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> to every
situation, and he's helped out immensely by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wahlberg</ENAMEX>'s charismatic and subtle
performance as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie</ENAMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk</ENAMEX>. This is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> to whom it would be easy
to condescend, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wahlberg</ENAMEX> captures his nobility without skimping on his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stupidity</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie</ENAMEX> starts out, he thinks of sex as a calling, a gift he can
give to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wahlberg</ENAMEX> is heartbreakingly natural as this ignorant naif; he
cries out to be protected, like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX> whose paws and ears are still
disproportionately large. He's vulnerable without the narcissism that has
characterized so much vulnerable-male acting since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brando</ENAMEX>. I suppose it's
central to his appeal that his looks even shift from macho to feminine: At
different points his tiny eyes and wide, thin-lipped mouth reminded me of the
preppy convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Kelly</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genevieve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bujold</ENAMEX>.

            
               Boogie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nights</ENAMEX> follows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, when promiscuity was still socially
acceptable and porn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> still dreamed of being recognized as legitimate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, by which time a combination of Reagan-era values and the
rise of low-quality video has brought the industry crashing back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. It's
an ambitiously wide time span to take on, especially since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is
likely to know it intimately, but for the most part, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> gets the tight
shirts and the light-blue eye <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX> and the fake wood paneling right. There
are scratches on the veneer of authenticity, though. The soundtrack is less
evocative than hyperactive: It runs the gamut from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Burdon</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spill The Wine</ENAMEX>" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Springfield</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>," and the songs are
usually heard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years later</TIMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in real life would have listened
to them. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rollergirl</ENAMEX> should have thrown out her skates long before the movie
ended in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>. As I recall it, the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '80s</TIMEX> in a
seizure of revulsion over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late '70s</TIMEX>, and the brief disco-era roller-skating
fad placed a close <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> in terms of national shame. There's an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indiscriminateness</ENAMEX> to these lapses, an overconfidence. In the press kit,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying, with amazing chutzpah, that he called on his
"very specific memories of the way <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> looked and felt" to re-create
the period. The press kit also informs us that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>, which means that
what we're seeing is based on the memories of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a 6-year-old</TIMEX>.

            
In a way, this sloppy handling of the retro
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> is refreshing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> is young enough to be post-hip and
post-ironic, if such terms are possible (can anything still be post-anything
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonironically</ENAMEX>?). He's got a sense of humor, but he's more interested in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and motivation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Horner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entourage</ENAMEX> is explicitly presented as a
dysfunctional makeshift <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>: Besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollergirl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk</ENAMEX>
finds a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> figure in the porn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Waves</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianne Moore</ENAMEX>, who does
a good job of looking beautiful in one scene and puffy in the next), and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> in the ugly, dumb, good-natured hack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed Rothchild</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reilly</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk</ENAMEX> and this group slowly isolate themselves from the world. They
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">shield</ENAMEX> and indulge each other; they snort <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coke</ENAMEX> together the way a regular
family might grill hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. And as a shrink might say, they lack boundaries.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amber</ENAMEX> is sad because she has a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> she's no longer allowed to see. So
she tells <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk</ENAMEX> that she loves him as if he were her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, and then she seduces
him. Their strong feelings for each other are real, but they are also
astonishing feats of denial, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anderson</ENAMEX> acts as both sympathizer and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>.

            The idea that wherever we
are, we need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, is interesting, up to a point. It was the main conceit
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s first film, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Eight</ENAMEX> , a neo-noir set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nev.</ENAMEX>,
about an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> who takes on an imbecile <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">protégé</ENAMEX> and loves him like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>.
But like any idea, it gets simplistic when carried too far, and late in
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> it explodes into cheap melodrama. Without a good role
model to guide him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk</ENAMEX> snorts so much coke that his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> poops
out. He slides downhill and gets beaten up--punished, essentially, for having
gone too far with this fantasy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and having lost his grip on reality. And
in an extremely sadistic overlapping scene, we see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollergirl</ENAMEX> momentarily burst
out of her passive bubble and brutalize <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> jerk for all the abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have
subjected her to over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. Without guidance, she's lost all morals and
turned into a cauldron of rage. These late scenes are over the top, as mean and
reductive as editorials in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX>, and they nearly extinguish the moral
subtlety of what's gone before. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> even hopes they are insincere, an attempt
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> to stay in step with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Promise Keepers</ENAMEX>. It would be a shame if someone this talented meant them in
earnest.

            
               "She's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to all
those who need love."--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diggler</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wahlberg</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reynolds</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waves</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>)
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX>
                (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">41 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chocolate love"--Buck</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swope</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Cheadle</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky Barnett</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Ari Parker</ENAMEX>) discuss style in
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights</ENAMEX>
                (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">37 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

         
      
   
