
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mysteries</ENAMEX>

            Writing about the
mysteriesyou can't quite say what they were.Sacrifices? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fasting</ENAMEX>? walking
belowor sprinkling drops of water nearthe marriage bed where the celebrants
laybriefly with the sacred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beforethe</ENAMEX> raising up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX>?You, the writer
separated from herby <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX>, know only that later she'llreappear sometimes
on vases ...Hell was invented about this time;later <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> aren't
reliable.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aristotle</ENAMEX> writes that
you'll sufferover the mysteries but will learnnothing new. The past slips into
you finally.<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Generations</ENAMEX> kept these secrets.Islands fell asleep looking at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX>.The one who ruled you above will rule youbelow, taking you down to show you
the cut part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX>.Probably she was <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>, your hunger was beautiful,her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hunger</ENAMEX> was beautiful,but what do you really know?

            Much was enacted, much was
shown,the burning one is soughtas an emblem; just once you will lie downbetween
her legs. The ritualgoes on with its potions,its implied promises; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>
goes onwith his combs, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>,the exhausted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> held up--you try in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vain</ENAMEX>, and after your researchamong the transcripts of the institutionwhat gives
you immortal life turns out to be the breath of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> ...

            Belief in
the subterranean roomshas haunted you. Not finding themisn't it the same as if
you had?We know you through your writingsand your complaints. Of courseshe
found you, though you believedshe loved you less than she should have--your
short smile, your long tears,your fingers exiting the page,the chords of your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mysteriesabsolute</ENAMEX> and wild and brief--

         
      
   
