
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bogus Nights</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence Rafferty</ENAMEX>
has a sensible column in the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GQ</ENAMEX> on the vapidity of independent
film. "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafferty</ENAMEX> writes, "independent movie after independent movie
arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> on waves of critical admiration, and moviegoers
unaccustomed to the peculiar moral universe of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">indie-ness</ENAMEX> must have emerged
from these experiences deeply perplexed: wondering, perhaps, how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>
who carped about studio films like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">majestic</ENAMEX>, flawed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amistad</ENAMEX> could embrace wholeheartedly stuff as dubious as
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deconstructing Harry , The Sweet Hereafter , Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> ,
[and] <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Company of Men</ENAMEX> ." Rafferty correctly identifies indie film's
"air of smugness." Because its supposed anti-commercial values are pre-approved
by a youngish, left-of-center <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, indie filmmakers are encouraged to be
"less rigorous with themselves--to accept limitations that they'd be better off
trying to correct or transcend."

            This is a
familiar debate, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafferty</ENAMEX> turns the usual cant around. It's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypercapitalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> mentality that is usually deemed corrupt. Independent
films, no matter how incompetent, are thought to be well-meaning. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rafferty</ENAMEX>
passes over obvious chances to criticize the indies in technical terms--no
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">review of Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> prepared me for what a patchy, tedious film it
was--and instead finds something morally defective in them. He has in
mind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Minghella</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The English Patient</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil LaBute</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Company of Men</ENAMEX> ), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX>. This rather disparate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> is tied together by a desire to resist the strictures of studio
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmaking</ENAMEX> and to advertise that resistance to a discerning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. So
instead of uplifting stories we get studiously downbeat ones; instead of good
vs. evil we get calculated ambiguity; instead of violence as plot device we get
violence as happenstance; and instead of a corporate worldview we get
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-expression</ENAMEX> and self-regard.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rafferty</ENAMEX> uses the word "moral" quite pointedly. He thinks
that these movies are destructive, that they enjoy degradation. I think he's
mostly right. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarantino</ENAMEX>, notably, manipulates our capacity to be aroused by
death. No less offensive, however, is the automatic presumption of quality in
work that defines itself merely by its choice of subject matter and mannerism.
Because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX> epigone named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Thomas Anderson</ENAMEX> announced a film
on the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> porn--because he promised to show some dick--he was
celebrated as a poetic chronicler of subcultures. Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">better-than-average</ENAMEX> studio films--I'd name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Titanic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Devil</ENAMEX>'s
Advocate --are picked apart by highbrow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, even by those who admitted
enjoying them. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Gilroy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Lemkin</ENAMEX>'s script for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Devil</ENAMEX>'s
Advocate was witty and literate; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">for Boogie Nights</ENAMEX> was
not.)

            Most
freethinking filmgoers will admit the existence of morally repugnant indie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poseurs</ENAMEX>. But what does that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> have in common with the almost universally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">admired Coen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>? This writing-directing-producing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Coen</ENAMEX>
directs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Coen</ENAMEX> produces, both write--has cannily outlasted the cyclical
faddishness of indie-dom. Their movies-- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blood Simple , Raising</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crossing , Barton Fink , The Hudsucker</ENAMEX>
Proxy , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX>, and now The Big Lebowski --have been eccentric
in the best sense, avoiding both mainstream studio practices and the indie
mentality that mindlessly reacts against them. And yet something is not
working. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Coen opus after Blood Simple</ENAMEX> has, in one way or another,
fallen flat.

            
I don't subscribe to the standard critique of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX>--that they are too cool and too clever by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>, that they care more
for wordplay than for flesh-and-blood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. In fact, they have a
tremendous gift for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. They can write a role, and find an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> for it,
in a way that creates a small myth on the screen. I'm thinking in particular of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances McDormand</ENAMEX>'s unflappable pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Turturro</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton Fink</ENAMEX>, the mediocre leftist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> who tries to go <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>; and in
the new film, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bridges</ENAMEX>' incarnation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Lebowski</ENAMEX>, a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the Dude</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">amiable stoner</ENAMEX> who is drawn into a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Sleep</ENAMEX> -inspired kidnap scheme.
What these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have in common is an instantly plausible blend of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">idiosyncrasy</ENAMEX> and stereotype. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dude</ENAMEX> is burdened with all the clichés of his
kind, but he also shows pleasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eccentricities</ENAMEX>, such as an eye for interior
decor. ("That rug really tied the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> together," he says, after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> urinates on it.) His bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> and co-conspirators--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Goodman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, a gun-toting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vet</ENAMEX> with an intellectual streak, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buscemi's</ENAMEX>, a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who's always <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step behind--are also neatly drawn. As
long as they are simply chatting together at the bowling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>, the film is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">charming</ENAMEX> and alive.

            The
trouble starts with the plot. The great flaw in most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX>' work is,
surprisingly, an inability to sustain a plot over a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">span</ENAMEX>. I say
surprising because their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blood Simple</ENAMEX> , came so close to
perfection. Its plot really was simple--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> hires hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to kill philandering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>--and appeared complicated only to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in the film. The plot of
Lebowski , on the other hand, is a mystery to all. It has to do with the
kidnapping of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX> (also named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lebowski</ENAMEX>) and debts
owed to a porn impresario. I won't describe it in more detail because it
crumbles to nothing long before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>. Careless plotting first cropped up in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX>' murky gangster picture <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crossing</ENAMEX> , and it hurt
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX> , the best of their recent films. (If a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> buries a suitcase
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of money, we should find out what happens to it.) In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebowski</ENAMEX> , we
lose track not only of plot devices but of whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, who come and go
without finding a reason to be. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turturro</ENAMEX> is wasted as a bowler named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, a
convicted pedophile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spandex</ENAMEX>. He is an amazing creation, but he has no
function.

            The crux of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX>' plot problem is climax. Over and
over, they have imposed an artificial resolution on a sequence of brilliant
character studies. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton Fink</ENAMEX> , for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fink</ENAMEX>'s adventures in
'30s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> lead him through a splendid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> of vintage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX>--a madcap studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gin</ENAMEX>-soaked <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Faulkneresque</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>, a
seemingly ordinary insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodman</ENAMEX> again) who makes strange noises
in the hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> next door. Then what? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX> put a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fink</ENAMEX>'s
bed and set fire to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX> , the kidnapping-turned-murder
scheme never finds a satisfying <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> act, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX> create an illusion of
climax only by having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> kill another in a giant geyser of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>. In
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Lebowski</ENAMEX> , the climax is so farcically arbitrary--one character
drops dead of a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX>--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX> seem to be laughing at their own
inability to wrap things up. Anyone who's tried to write a screenplay knows the
difficulty of writing a climax. The process is always artificial. The art is in
hiding the artifice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX> shrug off that task with annoying arrogance.

            Do these
enormously talented filmmakers show a moral failing in the sense that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafferty</ENAMEX> developed in his piece? I think they do. Their sin is pride. The Coens
have reached a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> where they no longer question their ideas or flesh them
out. You can catch them in the act, as it were, by comparing a shooting script
with the final product. I have such a script for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fink</ENAMEX> .
(The "shooting script" is the script as it stands before filming begins; the
script that you can buy in book form is a "continuity script," which has been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">edited</ENAMEX> to match the film.) The degree to which the shooting script matches the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> is astonishing. Page after page has been shot word for word. This,
needless to say, is unusual; even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> who write their own scripts very
often make major changes during production. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX> had shot everything
verbatim, right down to unfinished sentences ("I don't know ... I mean--") and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hesitations</ENAMEX> ("uh," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"er"</ENAMEX>). If the script were airtight, such faithfulness to
self would be admirable. But when the script is flawed ...

            
The moral is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coens</ENAMEX> might actually be
able to make further artistic advances if they shackled themselves to the evil
studio system. Someone needs to speak to them in time-tested studio
platitudes--to say that the script goes nowhere in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> act or that there
are too many marginal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. They might also profit from filming others'
scripts. But the hype that greeted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blood Simple</ENAMEX> appears to have
convinced them that they are sufficient unto themselves. They've reserved an
independence they haven't earned.

         
      
   
