
   
   
      
         
            Dream <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pun on "Single Man</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Before Marrying Again</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ryan</ENAMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>; to be composted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Feb. 12</TIMEX>)
            

            To hear
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dream Pun</ENAMEX>," click or on the title.

            I don't know how I knewthe
signalman was the signalman.His fuzzy red-brown hair the color of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>? I
knewhe wasn't just a waiter carrying a traywhen he pushed through the
rathskellerdoing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> salute--not straight upSieg <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heil</ENAMEX> but the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lateral</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>,elbow-fulcrum on his shoulder's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>,hand (made into blade) starting at
his heartsweeping the quadrant in front of himas if only to clear a paththrough
the jolly, blocked aisle.

            You weren't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> at the
tall tableI was sitting with,where we eat together most of the timewatching the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sky</ENAMEX> change at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">sunset</ENAMEX> and talking about our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> from each other's
livesflickering ghostlike through that gorgeous air)--nor was I speaking to her
when he pushed through doing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> salutethat meant run right then to save
myself.There wasn't time for a word to her.The bomb exploded as I got out the
door.

            You know what it was like in
there.You've listened to me so many hoursdepicting aftermaths of my blunt
shame.The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">place</ENAMEX> had been jammed, everyone drunk,the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar</ENAMEX> had kept the
explosion in--pillowed, muffled, a brief hot thudwithin thick earth-sunk
concrete walls.But oh my God what it had done.I crawled back into the
rubblesearching for her, until I sawthe work I had to do now.What had happened
had happened,I'd never know how. I had to help withthe wounded and haul out the
dead.

         
      
   
