
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web Weather Today</ENAMEX> 

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few nights ago</TIMEX>, I turned
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel 4</ENAMEX> to watch the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> weather forecast. Or rather, I turned on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Channel 4</ENAMEX> to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meteorologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Ryan</ENAMEX>. It was a deeply satisfying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s brow was furrowed; his jaw was tense. A cold front, he warned,
had "gathered strength in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rockies</ENAMEX>" and "cut a swath across the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>." It was now "bearing down on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>],
threatening to wallop the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> area with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 to 8 inches</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX>."
Then his mouth relaxed slightly. He said that a high-pressure system was
"<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in the Southeast" and would shoot a "blast of warm air" up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic</ENAMEX> coast. Would it reach us in time to fend off the snow? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> was
hopeful.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
weather <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forecasters</ENAMEX> like to say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has the most exciting
weather in the world. It's biblical--from hurricanes to blizzards, droughts to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">floods</ENAMEX>, and the occasional plague of locusts for good measure. I don't know if
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> does have the most exciting weather, but it certainly has the
most exciting weather forecasts. They, too, are biblical. The ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greeks</ENAMEX>
ascribed lightning to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zeus</ENAMEX>; we haven't made much progress. The weather forecast
is still an epic, a story of God's war with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Hot and cold air masses
"clash," storms "strike," and sweeping "fronts" ravage the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. The forecast
is a tale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX> (the noble high-pressure system), savage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurricane Andrew</ENAMEX>), and omnipotent, inexplicable deities (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Niño</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jet</ENAMEX>
Stream). I'm sure I'm not the only one who feels a frisson when a
forecaster announces that a cold front is "descending" from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>--as if some
malevolent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic</ENAMEX> god were coming to exact revenge for the sins of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.

            Weather, in short, is a crackling good story, infused with
enough drama to sustain local news broadcasts, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of water-cooler
conversations, and an entire cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>. So imagine my excitement when I
stumbled upon the Web weather industry. Here was a world of
weather--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>-<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>-a-day weather, personalized weather, global weather, fishing
weather, flying weather, farming weather, e-mail weather, graphics weather,
text weather. Its breadth boggles the mind. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> forecasts day
and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> on its snazzy weather site. So do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Weather Channel</ENAMEX> (which has claimed the best weather address
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>). Other Web <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forecasters</ENAMEX> include weatherOnline, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTELLICAST</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WeatherNet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TVWeather</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AccuWeather, Geocities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Weather Network</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC Weather</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Weather</ENAMEX>
Service--to name only the mainstream sites.

            
There is, of course, something obviously ironic
about all this Web weather: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> doesn't have any weather (unless you count
the hot air that envelops most newsgroups). In fact, you could argue that the
entire point of cyberspace is to have no weather, to liberate us from
the mundane and inconvenient physical world. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> will have
weather, weather or not.

            Indeed,
Web weather technology is as sophisticated as it gets. The sites make
television's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Weather Channel</ENAMEX> look amateurish (or rather, even more amateurish
than it already looks). All the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are constantly updated. You never have to
wait for a forecast. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are both easy to navigate and comprehensive. On
most, a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse clicks</ENAMEX> will retrieve the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-day</TIMEX> forecast for any ZIP code,
any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>--complete with smiling sun/frowning raindrop
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">animations</ENAMEX>. You like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> photos? The Web lets you download current
satellite images of any corner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>. (On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, you can string
together <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few hours</TIMEX> of satellite photos into a cloud movie.) Are you
big on ground radar? Most sites offer pictures from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dopplers</ENAMEX>.
Many will let you monitor earthquake activity, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> levels, humidity, and
flood threats.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> rely on essentially the same package of NWS
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">data</ENAMEX>, satellite photos, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doppler</ENAMEX> images, so they do have a certain
laundry-detergent quality: same <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">powder</ENAMEX>, different box. (This monotony is
reminiscent of sports Web sites, which also draw from a single well of data.)
So sites strive desperately to build brand identity. Some make <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-day</TIMEX>
forecasts instead of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-day</TIMEX> forecasts. Some dispense with jaunty graphics,
delivering temperatures in sober gray text. Some niche-market to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sailors</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Weather Channel</ENAMEX> supply a weather newswire
("<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Light</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> dusts the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dakotas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West</ENAMEX> is dry"). An illustrated weather
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">encyclopedia</ENAMEX> accompanies <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's site. And weatherOnline reviews
weather media and will soon launch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Adventures of Weatherboy</ENAMEX> , a
cartoon based on the exploits (such as they are) of a real-life teen weather
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forecaster</ENAMEX>. The grand prize for gimmickry goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AccuWeather</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. It devotes an entire Web page to the most
important weather in the world: <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">password works</ENAMEX> (which is
rarely), I can view "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal AccuWeather TM</ENAMEX> ." This
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX> has my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-day</TIMEX> forecast (well, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s), a chart of
my current weather conditions (actually <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Airport</ENAMEX>'s); and a radar
map centered over my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sterling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Va.</ENAMEX>, but who's counting). It's
exactly the same information available on all the other Web weather sites, but
it's got my name on it.

            At this
point, I am supposed to pause to pay homage to the miraculous Internet. Web
weather, I should say, displays all the medium's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">virtues: Efficiency</ENAMEX>!
Convenience! <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Personalized</ENAMEX> service! A rich supply--no, a surfeit --of
useful information! How extremely useful it is!

            
Too useful, actually. Even the best Web weather
sites-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INTELLICAST</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Weather Channel</ENAMEX>--manage to do what I
thought was impossible: They make weather boring. Following weather on the Web
is like following baseball by reading scorecards. The weather forecast is more
than "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>." You must also hear the story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>. Where is it coming from?
Whose fault is it? <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s? The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Lakes</ENAMEX>'? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bermuda High</ENAMEX>'s? What kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rain</ENAMEX> is it? When it will arrive? Will the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jet Stream</ENAMEX> protect us from it? Is it
"much-needed" or "unwelcome"? You do need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weatherman</ENAMEX> to know which way
the wind blows.

            But the
Web dispenses with all that. The cyberforecast is purely mechanical and purely
boring. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s supposed innovation--individualized forecasts--is
depressing. We no longer make common cause against the weather god. Now I have
my weather--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal AccuWeather TM</ENAMEX> --and you have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yours</ENAMEX>.

            Fortunately, not all Web weather is such a drag. Commercial
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> comprise only a fraction of online meteorology. Just as it has for New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey Nets</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> conspiracists and foot fetishists, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> has
also given birth to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">weather fanatics</ENAMEX>. Granted, theirs is a most
peculiar <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>. It feels almost exactly like a normal place--you can shop,
travel, talk, learn, watch movies--except there is only one subject:
weather.

            Amateur
meteorologists, for example, make chitchat at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Usenet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsgroups</ENAMEX> devoted to
general weather (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sci</ENAMEX>.geo.meteorology and uk.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sci</ENAMEX>.weather). True <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> talk
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shop</ENAMEX> at even more specialized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, such as one on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Northeastern</ENAMEX> weather
(ne.weather), whose recent conversation topics included the great blizzard of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978 and the freak</TIMEX> snowstorm of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1977</TIMEX>. Weather obsessives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> on the Web.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX>--count 'em--online weather <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WeatherStore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX>
meteorological gizmos. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Favorite gizmo</ENAMEX>: the weather
radio, which is tuned permanently to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Weather Service</ENAMEX> broadcasts.)
You can plan a weather <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX>, including
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cloud 9</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Tours</ENAMEX>, sell "storm-chasing tours" online. (Designed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who've
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">watched Twister</ENAMEX> too many times, these "vacations" consist of spending
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> driving a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> around the bleakest parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> hunting for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tornadoes</ENAMEX>.) Weather voyeurs can sneak a glance at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> weather cameras
filming the skies in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. Weather games, weather videos, weather
prizes--they have all found their way to the Web. There is even weather
identity politics: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Women in Weather</ENAMEX>" profiles female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">meteorologists</ENAMEX> and hosts
discussions about topics female and meteorological ("We're both meteorologists
... how will we both get jobs in the same place?").

            It may be the disaster sites that best capture the spirit
of the weather Web. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Dozens</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of sites, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eye</ENAMEX> on the
World, celebrate tsunamis, typhoons, hurricanes, droughts, and--of
course--tornadoes. Most are illustrated with brutal photos of beached
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ships</ENAMEX>, downed <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and shattered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are, I think, the
meteorological equivalent of snuff films. They prove that even when all you
care about is weather, the Web still has plenty of dirty pictures to show
you.

         
      
   
