
   
   
      
         
            False Notes

            It was a disconcerting
experience, waiting to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One True Thing</ENAMEX> . The
earlier screening was ending, and out came one woman after another with tears
streaming down her face or eyes bloodshot from weeping. "I cried during the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> scene and never stopped crying," said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to another, then joined the
long line for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. Later, watching the movie, I found myself
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly sobbing</NUMEX>, too, except from boredom. One <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">True Thing</ENAMEX> isn't a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">snickerfest</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beaches</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>), and it isn't as emotionally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pornographic</ENAMEX> as parts of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">As Good as It Gets</ENAMEX> . It's pretty
much inert. But my benumbed responses don't account for all those weepers
leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> or for the snuffling and nose blowing I heard during my own
screening. No, the movie's themes are enormously resonant, which makes its
doddering tastefulness that much more frustrating.

            
               One
True Thing is based on a decent, understated novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Quindlen</ENAMEX>, the
story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Gulden</ENAMEX>, an ambitious young magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who moves from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> back to her small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> to care for her <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>-ridden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.
Never close to this unassuming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homemaker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> returns reluctantly, at the
behest of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>, an imposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of literature at a small,
middling college who maintains that he's too busy to tend to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. In the
course of the book, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> learns that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s life, while ostensibly rich
in literary-philosophical meaning, is a sham, while the real meaning--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bravery</ENAMEX>--can be found in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s household and community rituals and in
how she faces death. In the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> pages, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> goes on trial for her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>'s mercy killing and only then manages to remove herself, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bitterness</ENAMEX>, from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s constellation.

            The film, directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Franklin</ENAMEX> from a script by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
Croner, throws most of its weight onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> relationship, which
wouldn't be a problem if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Croner</ENAMEX> knew how to dramatize it. The novel includes a
scene in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>, is too weak to prepare an elaborate luncheon
for a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, so her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> dons the apron and, under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX>'s
direction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX> a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX>. In the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX>) passes
out on the sofa while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renée Zellweger</ENAMEX>) comically botches whatever she
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">touches</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> goes for cheap laughs with shots of burning chicken
paillards, a smoldering chocolate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX>, and plates on which the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> has been
left uneaten. Think of the possibilities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Quindlen</ENAMEX>'s original--the rapport
that might have developed as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen sautés</ENAMEX> and mixes and bakes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX> offers
her expertise. That could have been the core of the picture, right there, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Croner</ENAMEX> toss it into the trash. When, later, the newly domesticated
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> whips up a masterful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> dinner, her skills have arrived out of
nowhere.

            
               One
True Thing taps into the same yearnings as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field of Dreams</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>),
only for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>. That earlier work,
impossibly fraudulent on every level, dramatized the ways in which baby
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX>, who came of age with the counterculture, rejected their daddies along
with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddies</ENAMEX>' conservative values, only to be left with an emptiness
filled only by, gulp, a supernatural <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game. One <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">True Thing</ENAMEX>
doesn't employ fantasy (at least not overtly) but tries to stir similar regrets
about the feminist dismissal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewives</ENAMEX>: You moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and the
heartless magazine world, you dressed in black, you rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>. But look how
you barely knew her! How she held your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> together! Look at how it was
her--not otherwise engaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX>--who gave your life its true foundation!

            
This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> is embodied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep</ENAMEX>, who
might be the biggest reason the film goes wrong. The central fact of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX> is
that she's an invisible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>--always taken for granted, in the background,
doing things but never really registering. Employing an accent that's straight
out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep</ENAMEX> clucks and flutters and sighs and acts so
ostentatiously industrious that it's hard to imagine anyone not noticing (or
not wanting to bludgeon) her. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> whose face you should want to
scrutinize for hints of a larger awareness, but I found it hard to look at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep</ENAMEX>, who's always busy radiating virtue. Later, ash faced with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, she's
paradoxically easier to watch (she does less), and she hits some convincing
notes of pain. But when she finds her tongue and protests the injustices of
literature, in which "clever" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are always depicted as superior to merely
"good" ones, she's pathetically unconvincing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dots</ENAMEX> remain unconnected. As
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hurt</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> at appearing to think deep
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thoughts</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s groggy pretentiousness and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>'s merge
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uncomfortably</ENAMEX>. Hurt plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> from the movie's point of view instead of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">character's</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>'s self-absorption and obliviousness are so apparent
from the start that it's a wonder he could ever have fooled anyone.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of marvelous thrillers such as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">One False Move</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Dress</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), and of the intricate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> miniseries
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurel Avenue</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>), must have taken on this project to prove that an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmaker</ENAMEX> can bring a fresh perspective to the white-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX>
tale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> in snowy <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>. He does bring his customary
leisurely pacing and attention to place, especially in the lovingly coordinated
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, flowered wallpaper, chintz) family <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">homestead</ENAMEX>. What he doesn't provide
is a pulse. The film unfolds in flashbacks, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> is interviewed by a
district <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> about the circumstances of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s death, but the
framing device doesn't generate any suspense, and the linking scenes are so
clumsily overwritten that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> might be talking to her therapist.

            What holds the film together is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zellweger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX>, and not
because of anything she does but because she's the only major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> who seems
to be listening. I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zellweger</ENAMEX> as a hot pants hell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">raiser</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miserable Tarantino</ENAMEX> knockoff called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">.45</NUMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). She was
exuberant, as she was in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>-making turn in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Maguire</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>)
and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX>'s superb, largely overlooked drama The Whole Wide
World . Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep</ENAMEX>, she slips easily into her roles, revealing her
disparate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> not through epidemic tics but in how she reacts to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around her. Through her eyes, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streep</ENAMEX> looks halfway human.

            So why do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cry at <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One True Thing</ENAMEX> ? It might be that even an ordinary
relationship between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is so fraught--with so much left
unspoken--that any film that hammers so relentlessly on that spot will hit a
nerve. It might be, too, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>'s unhurried tempos give us plenty of
time to look back on our own lives and loved ones and to think about the people
whose labors we didn't register until they were gone. One <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">True Thing</ENAMEX>
prompted me to call my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> when I got home. Of course, AT&T
commercials do that, too, and they get the same point across in under a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>.

            
In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pecker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Waters</ENAMEX> seems to wonder
aloud if you can ever go home again, especially when your success, like his
own, has transformed that home from something authentically tacky into
something ironically chic. His eponymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Furlong</ENAMEX>) is a boyish,
happy-go-lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> whose pictures of urban grotesques--from
fornicating <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX> to lesbian strippers to homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exhibitionists</ENAMEX>--renders
them objects of beauty and wonderment. Acclaimed as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Arbus</ENAMEX>" by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lili Taylor</ENAMEX>) and assorted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pompous critics</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pecker</ENAMEX> finds his haunts suddenly withering under the attention, his
subjects demanding model fees, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Ricci</ENAMEX>), the
compulsively by-the-book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proprietor</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">laundromat</ENAMEX>, fleeing his wealthy new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cohorts</ENAMEX> for the safety of her suds.

            This is
the subversively lovable <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Waters of Hairspray</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>) rather than the
in-your-face deformity maven of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pink Flamingos</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>) and the more
mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cry Baby</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1990) and Serial Mom</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>). Pecker
is a breezy, agreeable picture--a charmer, thumbs-up, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>--but there's
something disappointing about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Waters</ENAMEX> film that's so evenhanded and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-embracing, even if its sunniness is "ironic." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waters</ENAMEX> seems to be trapped in
an ironic loop, making movies that look more and more like love-ins, in which
name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> go slumming and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Hearst</ENAMEX> show up for
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">nudge-nudge-wink-wink cameos.</ENAMEX> He must know that no one can be shocked when
everyone's in on the joke, but he doesn't seem to want (or to be able) to step
outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp aesthetic</ENAMEX> and play anything "straight." There's nothing in
Pecker that isn't done more brilliantly--and more subversively--every
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Judge</ENAMEX>'s inspired cartoon series King of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Hour</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> real <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Chan</ENAMEX> picture crafted for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> market, is a terrific piece of junk filmmaking. The plot is by the
numbers, and you can't help but notice that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX> has more stunt doubles these
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, but the movie has been photographed (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Greenberg</ENAMEX>) and
staged (by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brett Ratner</ENAMEX>) with unusual polish, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX> has been paired
with the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Tucker</ENAMEX>, who's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Murphy</ENAMEX> on helium. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucker</ENAMEX>
can be trying when the script isn't good, but he's a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foil</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX>--physically gung-ho and with supersonic timing. The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> consul is kidnapped, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX> is summoned from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> saddle him with wild man <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> ("My own
mama ashamed of me, she tell everyone I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>!") to keep him out of
their way. Of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> ends up in the middle of every conflagration.
The fights are riotous slapstick set pieces: In the art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> finale, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX>
fends off hordes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassins</ENAMEX> while catching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX>, priceless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ming</ENAMEX> vases as
they tumble from their pedestals. As he demonstrates in picture after picture,
he's willing to be stomped for art's sake.

         
      
   
