
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hams</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Winter</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexandre Dumas</ENAMEX>-inspired
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">swashbuckler The Man in the Iron Mask</ENAMEX> is thoroughly second-rate--which
is to say that it waddles when it ought to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX>, clanks when it strives for
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">cornball</ENAMEX> poetry, and transforms its august <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> into something akin to a manic
dinner-theater <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troupe</ENAMEX>. Nevertheless, armed with a tub of popcorn, a Three
Musketeers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, and an industrial-size <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Diet Coke</ENAMEX> (with free refills), I liked
it better than the other, more artful pictures I saw <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. Here's an
example of why: In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Twilight</ENAMEX> , aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gumshoe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Newman</ENAMEX> regards glamorous
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sarandon</ENAMEX> with anguished eyes, his longing for her at war with
his loyalty to her <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>-ridden <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Hackman</ENAMEX>). It's terribly tasteful
and grown-up, but not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as compelling as musketeer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Byrne</ENAMEX>'s fervid
declaration to foxy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Queen Mother Anne Parillaud</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Man</ENAMEX> in the Iron
Mask : "To love you is a treason against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>--not to love you a treason
against my heart." To love a line like that is a treason against my high
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aesthetics</ENAMEX>--not to love it a treason against my even higher propensity for
florid kitsch.

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> in the Iron Mask features <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEO</ENAMEX>!!! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LEO IS DA BOMB</ENAMEX>! I
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LOVE YOU LEO</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LEO OH GOD PLEASE READ THIS</ENAMEX>!!! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LEO IS GAY</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEO</ENAMEX> IS NOT GAY YOU'RE
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JEALOUS</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LEO IS A BEAUTIFUL HUMAN BEING WHO LOVES WOMEN</ENAMEX>!!! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEO PLEASE MARRY</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ME</ENAMEX>!!!!) in the dual role of the overweening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> king
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and his twin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philippe</ENAMEX>, who was first spirited away at
birth by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> fearful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">internecine</ENAMEX> struggles and subsequently locked in
the bowels of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bastille</ENAMEX>, his features concealed by the eponymous iron
mask.

            That would have been all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>, were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX> not a complete
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schmuck</ENAMEX> who capriciously drains the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX>'s coffers with foreign wars,
starves a lot of smudgy faced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX> (who hurl rotten <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> at his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>), and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">falls</ENAMEX> on whatever beauteous wench strikes his royal fancy. When he royally
fancies the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> love (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Godrèche</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Sarsgaard</ENAMEX>) of former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">musketeer Athos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX>) and orders the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> shipped off to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">battle</ENAMEX>, it's time for the aging <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Three Musketeers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Athos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aramis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Irons</ENAMEX>),
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porthos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gérard Depardieu</ENAMEX>)--to haul their uniforms out of mothballs and
prove once again that they're more than the stuff of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chocolate bars</ENAMEX>.

            This is
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> feature directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Wallace</ENAMEX>, who wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braveheart</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX> manages to bellow "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FREEDOM</ENAMEX>!" shortly before his
upper and lower halves are cleft in twain--thereby liberating <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> from
hordes of slumming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Shakespeare Co.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> has a thing for men
who die with their boots on. ("This is the death I have always wanted," gasps
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> in this picture's lachrymose climax.) He also digs resplendent
brocades, alarums, male choirs, and handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> on horseback saying things
like: "Then God be with you. For we shall not." He apparently has no taste for
pacing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, who are left to police their own histrionic impulses--which
is like leaving our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to police his libidinous ones.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byrne</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>'Artagnan, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth musketeer</TIMEX>,
torn between his loyalty to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> and to his all-for-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>/<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-for-all
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compatriots</ENAMEX>, has the most complicated role and carries it off with real dignity
and discernment (which means, of course, that he's just a teeny bit
dull). Depardieu, meanwhile, demonstrates that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gallic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> is fattier than its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX> bring to the picture <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> distinct styles
of prissiness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irons</ENAMEX> is the upper-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet priss</ENAMEX>, locking liquid eyes
on his co-stars and gravely over-enunciating. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Malkovitch</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Method</ENAMEX>
priss, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">feyly</ENAMEX> dragging out his words and democratically abolishing all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">punctuation</ENAMEX>. (As his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarsgaard</ENAMEX> does a brilliant--and
respectful--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovitch</ENAMEX> impersonation that's maybe the best thing in the
movie.)

            At first
it seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">LEO DESERVED A NOMINATION</ENAMEX>!!!) will be another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contestant</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> juvenile falling on his face doing period European
drama contest. (The reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keanu Reeves</ENAMEX>.) Playing the swinish
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">king</ENAMEX>, his performance begins badly, and the long hair doesn't flatter his wide,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">doughy</ENAMEX> face and compressed brow. But once the nice twin enters the movie,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DiCaprio</ENAMEX> can use his expressive eyes (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEO</ENAMEX>!!! READ THIS!!!) and his halting
sweetness to win us back into his good graces. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OH MY GOD LEO IS THE GREATEST</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AHHHHH</ENAMEX>!!!)

            It isn't nice to beat up on senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, which must be
why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Benton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twilight</ENAMEX> has received such respectful reviews. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">third-rate</ENAMEX> mystery tricked out with a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> and some tony cinematography,
the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unspools</ENAMEX> like an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s swan song--a bitter,
late-Romantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">threnody</ENAMEX> for the lost integrity of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">archetype</ENAMEX>,
co-opted by the evils of a shabbily materialistic culture.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benton</ENAMEX>
isn't an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--he only directs like one. This is essentially a twilit remake
of his wonderful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> thriller, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Late Show</ENAMEX> , in which a senior citizen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shamus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Carney</ENAMEX>) wrestles with both a brutal murder and the innumerable
humiliations of aging (they're connected), happily assisted by a New Age flake
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily Tomlin</ENAMEX>, in her most exuberant screen performance). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twilight</ENAMEX> is
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Late Show</ENAMEX> without the spitfire, and it succumbs to the paralysis it
means to portray. As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newman</ENAMEX> lets his voice go raspy to express
world-weariness. His mournful performance ennobles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton</ENAMEX>'s conception without
enlivening it. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton</ENAMEX>, aging evidently means forgetting everything you once
knew about drama.

            
More enlivening by far is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love and Death on</ENAMEX>
Long <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX> , in which another aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hurt</ENAMEX>), a clubby
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> poignantly out of touch with modern society, goes on another
soulful quest, developing an obsession with a beautiful teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Priestley</ENAMEX>) whom he accidentally sees on-screen in a film called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hot Pants</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College 2</ENAMEX> . First-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Kwietniowski</ENAMEX> has fun with the
collision of high and low culture, and he does elegant work. But his mistake is
the opposite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Twilight</ENAMEX> . Where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton</ENAMEX> couldn't distance
himself enough from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> to generate a comic perspective,
Kwietniowski can't keep from satirizing his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>'s passion. Emotionally, the
picture plays it safe, hugging the shore.

            Hurt's face is so deeply
lined that he now resembles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Karloff</ENAMEX>'s mummy--not flesh and blood but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">flakes</ENAMEX> and embalming fluid. But if Hurt has the kind of visage we normally
associate with dissipation, few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> are able to combine such bleariness with
such (oxymoronic) concentration. This is a gentle tour de force by one of our
greatest comic miniaturists.

         
      
   
