
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">End of the World as We Know It</ENAMEX>?

            It cannot be said too often
that the principal job of a modern mainstream movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> is to distinguish
smart formula crap from dumb formula crap. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> extreme are The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>

               Show and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX> , at the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> and the dire
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six Days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nights</ENAMEX> , which squanders a plucky, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carole</ENAMEX>
Lombardish turn by the scrumptious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Heche</ENAMEX>. There's an especially virulent
subdivision of the above: smart formula crap that makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> dumb.
To this category can be assigned the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> , a
blow-you-out-of-your-seat blockbuster that's sure to make you laugh, cry, thump
your chest like an ape, and call your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> to buy shares of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> stock.
Count on lethal asteroids to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">UFOs</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist Watch</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Buscemi</ENAMEX>'s asking price to triple; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Bruckheimer</ENAMEX> to end
up back where he was in the era of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top Gun</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), before his dead
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Simpson</ENAMEX>, blew the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">duo</ENAMEX>'s credibility on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, and call
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">girls</ENAMEX>. How dumb did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> render this reviewer? So dumb that he's
giving it a good review.

            With
reservations, of course. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruckheimer</ENAMEX> movies (the spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX>
hangs over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruckheimer</ENAMEX> products like a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemical</ENAMEX> spill) push every button
pushable, including some you never knew you had. The aim is to get you pumped,
bellowing, pogoing backward up the aisle playing air guitar. Armageddon
is one killer climax after another. Will <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> survive the shower of
meteors that launches the picture (spectacularly)? Will deep-core driller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX> murder smarmy sidekick <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck</ENAMEX> when he discovers the lout in bed
with his dishy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liv Tyler</ENAMEX>)? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Willis</ENAMEX> accept the job proffered by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Bob Thornton</ENAMEX> to rocket to the incoming asteroid (the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>),
drill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> feet beneath its crust, drop an A-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, and get the hell out of
there? Will his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> make it off the ramshackle <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mir</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> piece?
Will both <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttles</ENAMEX> manage to land on the asteroid through a shower of (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3-D,</ENAMEX>
surround-sound) debris? Will their drills penetrate the iron surface? Will they
stop the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> from detonating the nuke before they reach <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">800 feet</NUMEX>? In the
tradition of screenplay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert McKee</ENAMEX>, the stakes in every act are
ratcheted up. Where there's a cliff, there's a hanger.

            Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armageddon</ENAMEX> worked for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lab rat</ENAMEX>. The
electrodes were cannily placed, the jolts administered at regular intervals.
Along with the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, I jumped when I was meant to jump, laughed
when I was meant to laugh, and swallowed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> in my throat when I was meant
to feel moved. It's true, little irritants kept creeping in. It gets harder and
harder to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affleck</ENAMEX>, especially when he plays dumb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> by putting every
line in the same generic, working-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> italics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liv Tyler</ENAMEX> is a lollipop for the
eyes but doesn't speak, dress, or move like someone raised on a deep-sea oil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">derrick</ENAMEX>. (Of course, after getting away with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly McGillis</ENAMEX>' flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top Gun</ENAMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX>'s brain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Days</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thunder</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruckheimer</ENAMEX> can probably be forgiven a certain cockiness.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-coital Affleck</ENAMEX> dancing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> cracker on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX>'s bare middle recalls
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> dancing a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet</ENAMEX>'N Low packet on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kidman</ENAMEX>'s bare thigh: See the naked
starlet, buy the product. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trident missiles</ENAMEX> in this lefty's side:
knee-jerk invocations of God and Flag; jabs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenpeace</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>
delivering the clenched-teeth opening narration; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>' climactic exhortation
to "Chew this iron bitch up!" Still, there are few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> as apolitical as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">giant</ENAMEX> asteroid. We can all agree that it would indeed be a good thing to chew
that iron bitch up.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael Bay</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rock</ENAMEX> ) has whiplash comic timing, and he can certainly
do spectacle: The opening bombardment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> is riotously well edited,
and so is ... well, without giving too much away, we won't always have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>.
It's too bad that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bay</ENAMEX> has to hard-sell every shot. His pacing is strictly for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ritalin</ENAMEX> generation, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>-commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositions</ENAMEX> make the movie seem
even more synthetic. The asteroid itself is disappointingly undercharacterized,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay</ENAMEX> compensates by turning every frame into a blur of motion. You can't
really see what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drillers</ENAMEX> are doing--not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maverick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affleck</ENAMEX>, in his big
"I can drill this!" number. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armageddon</ENAMEX> is awesome, dude, but it's, like,
short on awe.

            
Still, I can't dislike a picture in which, when
all seems lost, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> turns to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission Control</ENAMEX> camera and says, "Prepare
the world for bad news." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX> has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of doing nothing, of
finding just the right (and most noncommittal) combination of facetiousness and
sincerity. He can deliver <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">zingers</ENAMEX>, and he can also invoke the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Almighty</ENAMEX>. He can
call himself a "third-generation driller," add that "drilling is not a science,
it's an art," and not be laughed off the screen. He's the perfect mascot for a
have-it-both-ways hip/square disaster epic, which parodies The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right</ENAMEX>
Stuff machismo and wants you to buy into it at the same time (which is
true, come to think of it, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Right Stuff</ENAMEX> itself). The yucks come
thick and fast until the motley, comic-relief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> starts getting blown away in
the line of duty, and then it's time to get patriotic.

            In the
end, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buscemi</ENAMEX>'s movie. As the horniest, most sardonic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX>, he has the funniest lines, and his wormy, dyspeptic grin sits on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s most ingratiating skull <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buscemi</ENAMEX> knows how to act on the fly,
which is essential in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael Bay</ENAMEX> picture if you want to be more than a
splotch on the screen. As streakers go, he makes more of an impact than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">asteroid</ENAMEX>.

            Out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sight</ENAMEX> is slick in all the right ways. It starts with
a disorienting series of shock cuts, during which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX> tears off his
tie, marches through traffic into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and, without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> or a plan, pulls
off a charmingly effortless robbery foiled only by a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">starter</ENAMEX> on his wreck
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>. By now (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only 10 minutes</TIMEX> into the picture), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soderbergh</ENAMEX> ( sex, lies, and 
               videotape ), has the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> in a
happy, receptive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>--not quite knowing what to expect and delighted to find
itself in such clever hands. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>, whimsical novels of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmore Leonard</ENAMEX> have
been all too put-downable, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soderbergh</ENAMEX> contrives the perfect voice for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard</ENAMEX>'s prose--laid-back and grooving when it needs to be, but also taut,
with the eerie foreboding of violence about to erupt. He has evolved into a
first-rate commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>.

            The movie's zigs and zags are
too entertaining to divulge, but it's permissible to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clooney</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Lopez</ENAMEX>, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshal</ENAMEX>, meet cute: She gets shut
up with him in the trunk of a getaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and is hostage to his chatter about
movies, a life of crime, and how he wishes he had met her in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> so he could
have picked her up. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clooney</ENAMEX> is a handsome rogue and knows it. He's starting to
go to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX>, though, which makes him vulnerable--especially to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lopez</ENAMEX>, a smart,
ripely beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> who projects a disarmingly high opinion of herself. No
phony demureness here: She acts as if she came of age telling an endless parade
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> where to put it. When she succumbs to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clooney's Irish allure</ENAMEX>, you
know there's going to be a "but."

            Produced by the same team
that made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leonard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Get Shorty , Out of Sight</ENAMEX> is stuffed with
amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, among them <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ving Rhames</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clooney's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Cheadle</ENAMEX> as a
mercurial psychopath and, in unbilled cameos, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Keaton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson Jr. Best</ENAMEX> of all is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Brooks</ENAMEX> as a multimillionaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> who
meets up with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clooney</ENAMEX> when he's thrown in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for felony fraud. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX> studs
his familiar, sad-sack persona with hard shards of ruthlessness and
opportunism. Like this terrific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confection</ENAMEX>, he never melts.

         
      
   
