
   
   
      
         
            Apocalypse Then

            How do you portray violence
in movies nowadays so that it isn't a turn-on? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nearly 30 years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sam</ENAMEX>
Peckinpah devised a massacre at the climax of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wild Bunch</ENAMEX> that he
thought would take the casualness out of killing. He lingered on it, slowed it
down, fastened on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>-spurting bodies as they hurtled through the air--and
ended up making it lyrical, aestheticizing it, distancing it. Less
well-intentioned filmmakers followed in the wake of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloody Sam</ENAMEX>," turning
carnage into spectacle, even into rock 'n' roll. What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> has
accomplished in Saving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> is to make violence terrible again.
Nothing in the movie's melodramatic narrative can diminish the shocking
immediacy of its combat scenes.

            The
opening battle might be the most visceral ever put on film. After a solemn but
predictable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">modern-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prologue</ENAMEX>--an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and his extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> trudge out
to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cemetery</ENAMEX> to view row upon row of white crosses--there's a shock cut to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> surging toward <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha Beach</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Normandy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. It's
D<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-Day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>. Trembling hands open a canteen. They belong to a familiar
star--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>--but everything that follows is alien. The camera is down in
the surf, pitching, as young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> pray and vomit. They've barely beached before
the first bullets come--before these smooth-faced, overgrown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> begin to get
blown through. We don't see the enemy <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine guns</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX>, but we hear the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pops</ENAMEX> and the ceaseless whine of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX>, and we watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> as their chests
and heads explode. Some drop underwater, but still the bullets come in near
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">silence</ENAMEX>, producing squalls of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>; above the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, the din resumes with a
vengeance.

            The images are supersharp, as if viewed through too-strong
glasses, yet they streak and pixilate--break into shards--as the camera jerks
wildly left, then right. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color</ENAMEX> has been drained from the frame: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">greens</ENAMEX> of
uniforms and browns of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> are muted, the sky rendered a neutral gray.
Against this monochromatic palette, the brackish blood leaps out of the screen.
That <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> is everywhere. A helmet full of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seawater</ENAMEX> turns out to be full of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sloshing gore</ENAMEX>; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> with a gushing arm socket picks up his severed limb
and staggers aimlessly; a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with his intestines on the outside wails through
a last, protracted hemorrhage. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>'s helmet stops a bullet with a clank;
he removes it in wonder; his brains are then blown out.

            For nearly
half <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>, the horrors come <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> upon another, unaccompanied by music and
unrelieved by any point of view except that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> in the middle of
the slaughter. There are no objective, "establishing" shots and no possibility
for emotional distance. Nauseated, I fixed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX> because I knew the star
would survive until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at least the last reel.</TIMEX> But even that reassurance seemed
precarious. In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> , death can come at any instant, from
any direction. For the rest of the film's running time (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nearly three hours</TIMEX>,
total), each action--even a small <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, such as the eating of an apple--is thick
with potential finality.

            
This is not the work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> we've
come to know. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaws</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Close Encounters of the Third</ENAMEX>
Kind (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>), he could afford to build any set, throw money at any creative
problem. His mise en scène became increasingly synthetic: He seemed to
lose touch with the texture of life. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s List (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>) edged
into the movie-ish. Deciding to shoot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> as if it were
a war documentary gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s art a new orientation. Or rather, a new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disorientation</ENAMEX>. He shoots battles so that we can't always see what's happening,
our vantage is frighteningly restricted, and the world of combat is reduced to
pure sensation. This isn't about "bravery" or "heroism" but getting from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Point</ENAMEX>
A to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Point B</ENAMEX> without being torn apart by bullets.

            
               Saving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> , from a script by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rodat</ENAMEX>, doesn't remain as feverishly
abstract as its imagery, but at its best, early on, it feels
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">undiagramed</ENAMEX>--unmapped. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squadron</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Capt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanks</ENAMEX>), is sent behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> lines to find one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pvt. Ryan</ENAMEX>, whose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>
have been killed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> in separate battles. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> under
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX> are furious with what they see as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> mission and a
misallocation of military resources; they can't believe they're risking their
lives to rescue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> anonymous private. But we in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> know that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> is more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>--that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harve Presnell</ENAMEX>, sounding like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>) has ordered it out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincolnesque</ENAMEX> compassion for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
ripped apart by war. Freighted with such symbolism, the odyssey cannot help but
amount to something .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miller</ENAMEX>'s journey into the bowels of the war--through
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">rubbled</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> and fields strewn with rotting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX>--attains the surreal
intensity that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Ford Coppola strove for in Apocalypse Now</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>),
except without the self-conscious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Bough</ENAMEX> stabs at myth-making.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> stages an agonizingly prolonged encounter with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sniper</ENAMEX> in a
mounting drizzle, the life of a wounded, exposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> streaming out of his
body with the rainwater. The next assault is different, an attack on a concrete
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> "pillbox" that's barely glimpsed through the thick smoke, the action
viewed through the eyes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squadron</ENAMEX>'s skinny, bookish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davies</ENAMEX>). After the shooting subsides, the tenderfoot hurries ahead to discover
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s medic (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giovanni Ribisi</ENAMEX>) mortally wounded, being ministered to by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squadron mates</ENAMEX> hysterically pressing the dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for instructions on how to
stop his bleeding. It's no wonder that, later, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> go through piles of dog
tags taken off dead <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> with little more than numb irritation and that
when they finally stumble on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pvt. Ryan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX>), they can barely contain
their hostility.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX>
in war movies are usually undercharacterized--it comes with the territory. But
these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> register. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vin Diesel</ENAMEX>'s loping charisma made me sad to see
him blown away so early, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barry Pepper</ENAMEX> gives a stock part--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sniper</ENAMEX> who
prays fervently before he kills--a monomaniac concentration. Mellish, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>'s nervy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>, who can't keep from taunting captured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> with his
religious identity, is a study in aggression, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groucho</ENAMEX> without punch lines.
There are stellar turns by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ribisi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Sizemore</ENAMEX> as a plodding but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">good-hearted</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Burns</ENAMEX>, whose acting is less mannered when
removed from his own movies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>' efforts to submerge his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moody</ENAMEX>-wise-guy
personality dovetails movingly with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s struggle to keep his
humanity in check. I find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>'s proletarian integrity deeply suspect but must
admit that he holds the camera like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> and that finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pvt. Ryan</ENAMEX> is not an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anticlimax</ENAMEX>.

            
The battles in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Private Ryan make</ENAMEX>
most <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> pictures seem like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> stuff--even the bleak,
"existential" ones like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Fuller</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steel Helmet</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hell Is for Heroes</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>). These sequences carry a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">post-Vietnam</ENAMEX>
aura of futility, and the scenes between the skirmishes are similarly modern,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of rambling talk and post- Godot waiting around. But the movie's
overall vision is surprisingly old-fashioned. In most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> films, authority
is insane. Here, orders from on high bring meaning, a glimpse of a more divine
purpose. The mission has the opposite end of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apocalypse Now</ENAMEX> :
not the war's heart of darkness but its heart of light.

            There's
another, more virulent way in which the movie is old-fashioned. In the course
of the endless massacre of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha Beach</ENAMEX>, I wrote in my notebook,
"No one who experiences this scene will ever cheer for a war again." But when
the tide of the battle turned and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> started getting their heads blown
off, I wrote "YES!!!!" And when a pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, fresh from
witnessing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies being</ENAMEX> blown to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">bits</NUMEX>, shot several pleading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>
rather than take them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>, I didn't applaud the act, but I didn't feel
much like grieving, either.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX> are faceless with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> exception: a captured
pillbox <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> who babbles and cajoles for his life, sings <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthems</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">extols Betty Grable</ENAMEX>'s gams, and screams "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fuck Hitler</ENAMEX>!" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reiben</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mellish</ENAMEX> want to blow him away, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX>--who has almost never fired a
gun--protests vigorously that such an act would be a war crime and that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> must be taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> or freed. It would be wrong to give away what
happens next, but the consequence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">squadron</ENAMEX>'s action is <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX>-handedly
predictable and, morally speaking, takes the picture down a peg. Too bad.

            It goes without saying,
however, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> makes the case that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>' morals explode like land
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mines</ENAMEX> amid the terrors of war. This is not, after all, where they live. It's
hard to recall a more chilling stretch in modern movies than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before the
last big battle, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>, surrounded by the debris of a
devastated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, listen to the echoey, piped-in strains of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Piaf</ENAMEX>
recording--and then hear the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> low rumbles of approaching <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX>,
each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> alone in the shared knowledge that this foreign music will likely be
the last they'll hear.

         
      
   
