
   
   
      
         
            Jailbirds

            Having risked appearing
foolish in the cause of his art; having tackled his parts with demented,
hyperbolic integrity, letting the madness of his roles infuse him and carry him
into the ether; having snagged an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> for his besotted, bebop melancholia in
Leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX> has now set out to prove that he can be
as much of an overmuscled jackass as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX>. For an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> so gifted
this was no easy feat. It took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of labor with a personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX> to
develop both a beefcake physique and that distinctive deadness-behind-the-eyes
of the practiced bodybuilder. And it took a project of rare slickness and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vacuity</ENAMEX> to help him blot out all traces of his hitherto peculiar but attractive
personality. It took <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Con Air</ENAMEX> .

            This is a
film that disdains prosaic time and space. The action is hooked to a backbeat.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> float, abstractly, in the frame, lit so that their muscles have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">luster</ENAMEX>. None of the images breathe; the details are fixed as in cement. In this
airless setting, nothing seems truly at stake--with the possible exception of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>'s artistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, which has been sold to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Bruckheimer</ENAMEX>, the surviving
half of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that brought you <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Flashdance</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top Gun</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>), and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>'s The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock</ENAMEX> . Here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>, a noble convict,
swollen pectorals pumping as he runs from an exploding airplane <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hangar</ENAMEX> in slow
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motion</ENAMEX>, looking every bit as credible as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Lou Ferrigno's Incredible Hulk</ENAMEX>. Here
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>, brawny arms hugging a bullet-pierced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> who rasps that there is no
God--to which he answers, without a whisper of irony, "I'm gonna prove to you
that God does exist!" breaking up their pPieta to trash a planeload of drooling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sociopaths</ENAMEX> while electric guitars squeal their hosannas.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX> has been incarcerated, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rambo</ENAMEX>-like, for killing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-defense</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paroled</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and with a yearning to see his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
and loyal blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Potter</ENAMEX>, the apotheosis of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>), he has
the bum luck to land on a prison transport flight described--in one of those
testosterone-laden lines that can be comfortably transplanted to coming
attractions--as "a planeload of pure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX>." These include serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>,
massrapists, cannibals, and a "poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> for the criminally insane" called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus</ENAMEX> "the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Virus</ENAMEX>," played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX>, who recycles his carnivorous Bugs
Bunny act from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In The Line of Fire</ENAMEX> .

            Once the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> stage their inevitable coup, blow away a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>, and install
their own wild<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-man pilot</ENAMEX>, the movie gives them little to do except fly the
unfriendly skies. Really, their ambitions are shockingly limited for a
planeload of pure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predators</ENAMEX>. They don't rob <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Knox</ENAMEX>, attempt to wipe out the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern seaboard</ENAMEX>, or even molest the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mormon Tabernacle Choir</ENAMEX>. They just wing
it, leaving plenty of time for softy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cusack</ENAMEX> and meany <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> Colm
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meaney</ENAMEX> to debate the merits of shooting the jailbirds out of the sky. (Cusack
seems to have a psychic bond with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>, perhaps because he's playing the part
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX> would have played in his pre-hunk, pre-lobotomized era.) Bystander
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX> doesn't side with the escaped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, as you wouldn't if you had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
who looked like that waiting for you. He's also pissed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX>, who is
insufficiently concerned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> bud needs a shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> bad.
Yes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Rosenberg</ENAMEX>'s empty opportunistic script can't even generate
believable conflict among convicts.

            Apart from a cunningly tasteless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in an empty
swimming <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX> featuring a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahmer</ENAMEX>-like mass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Buscemi</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Con Air</ENAMEX> is boring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX>. It's much less
entertaining than The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock</ENAMEX> , which had a genuine comic snap in the scenes
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX>, back when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX> wasn't striking heartthrob poses
(except for those amusing occasions when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> were striking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heartthrob</ENAMEX> poses). Is there any death more conclusive for an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> than putting
on a muscle shirt and walking around in slow motion?

            Movies as synthetic as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Con Air</ENAMEX> make me wonder if my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> wouldn't be more enjoyably spent watching a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>. Let me explain. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill McKibben</ENAMEX> begins his meditation on television and nature, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Age</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missing Information</ENAMEX> , by describing a duck gliding around a pond,
contrasting a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> spent watching its languorous motion with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>-tat-tat
of images and data on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> cable TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>--images that, he argues,
carry far less information about the way the world works than the
back-and-forth of that lone quacker. (I'm oversimplifying, but that's the
gist.) My old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKibben</ENAMEX>'s aesthetic is not the same as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> (his favorite
movie is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gandhi</ENAMEX> ), but since reading his book I pay closer attention to
the temporal aspects of film, convinced that even, say, a successful formula
thriller like Breakdown derives much of its power from its simulation of
real time.

            From that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">angle</ENAMEX>, the starkest counterpoint imaginable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Con Air</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulee</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gold</ENAMEX> , which begins with a leisurely scene of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulee Jackson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Fonda</ENAMEX>), a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">traumatized Vietnam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX>, aside a swamp, tending impassively to his tupelo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">honeybees</ENAMEX>. In the film, which opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beekeeping</ENAMEX> is a mark of spiritual purity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulee</ENAMEX> might have cut have himself off
from the emotional hurly-burly of life, but he's deeply in tune with the
natural world. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bees</ENAMEX> and I have an understanding," he announces, stoic in
his denims. "I take care of them, they take care of me."

            
Judging from his films, among them A Flash
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and writer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Nu単ez</ENAMEX> believes it's improper to let events unfold in anything other than
real time. There always seems to be plenty of it, along with the chance to
study the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, even when there's not a great deal going on
in them. (In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby</ENAMEX> , the face on display was a nice and interesting one,
belonging to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Judd</ENAMEX>, so this wasn't a problem.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold</ENAMEX> does
evolve into a sort of thriller, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> runs afoul of his convict
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">son</ENAMEX>'s ex-partners in crime. But even during the climax, it is possible to look
up and count the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Exit</ENAMEX> signs, or the tiles on the ceiling. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nu単ez</ENAMEX>'s movies go
places, but with no acceleration, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> on the pond.

            Lacking the compression of
the greatest movie making, the realism of films like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold</ENAMEX> leaves
me slightly yawny. The unassuming way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nu単ez</ENAMEX> tells a story assumes, in fact, an
enormous amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> indulgence. Nonetheless, there are compensations.
Consider a scene in an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Orlando</ENAMEX> hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulee</ENAMEX> meets with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eddie</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Flynn) and Ferris</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dewey Weber</ENAMEX>), the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX> who wish to extract from
him a hidden stash of loot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynn</ENAMEX> speaks politely, deliberately, in no hurry to
press his point and yet unwilling to let his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX> off the hook, persisting
in the pleasantries well past the point of pleasantness. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> crawl,
and, as they do, you realize that the immobile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obsequious</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie</ENAMEX> is infinitely
more terrifying than any of the slobbering, muscle-flexing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>-wielding
psychopaths of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Con Air</ENAMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Bruckheimer</ENAMEX> blockbuster can't waste a
beat simulating a real human exchange. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Nu単ez</ENAMEX> has all the time in the
world.

             

            Clips info
TKTK

             

         
      
   
