
   
   
      
         
            Locus Politicus

            
               A campaign junkie rates
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>.
            

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Cooper</ENAMEX>

            
               (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,163</NUMEX> words; posted
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 23</TIMEX>; to be composted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 30</TIMEX>)
            

            I've seen the future, and
it's hurting my back. I'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, my body contorted,
my laptop balanced on my knee. I'm watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> and using my computer. This
is how they hyped this new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and yet, I wonder: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surely</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> did
not want me going to a chiropractor. My eyes flicker between screens close and
far, making me wonder whether I'll need bifocals. More annoying, my mind whips
between the laid-back, have-a-beer feeling of watching TV and (at least for
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice</ENAMEX> anyway) the intensity of operating a computer. "It's time to get
connected," they say in the ads for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>. Yet the only interactivity open to
me is to write a question to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, who is being interviewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX>. I can't do this, though, because I didn't submit an "Ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>"
question at an appropriate time. (Besides, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 8,000</NUMEX> questions came <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, so I wasn't really going to get in on the action.) There are glitches.
Every time my browser goes to the page, it hits some sound file that belts out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX>'s booming baritone: "This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX>. ..." I can't make it stop.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is supposed to be
manna for me, a news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hound</ENAMEX> who devours <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, who watches <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> on
vacation, and who occasionally tries to fall asleep by counting senators
instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straining</ENAMEX> to remember <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX>'s backbenchers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Craig</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk Kempthorne</ENAMEX>, usually does the trick.) But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is not succor. It is
often technically frustrating, as was evinced by my wrestling with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brokaw</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            Yet, there are things I've
come to love about the Web in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the couple of months</TIMEX> since I got on it. For me,
the best thing about political Web sites--and by that I mean stuff put up by
everybody from major media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>--is that they can get me where
I would have gone anyway, only much more quickly. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> often on the
road, I can now get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> , <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> indispensable papers for news
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">junkies</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>, are well-designed and ready <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> appears, the better to find out what my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> have that I
don't. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Cisneros</ENAMEX>, the secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Urban Development</ENAMEX>,
came to my magazine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> for an editorial lunch, I was able to prep up
quickly at his Web site.

            
Unfortunately, much of what is on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is diatribe or propaganda, foaming
with hate or boosterism, irrelevant either way. "There's this explosion of
information, and much of it is crap," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Riley</ENAMEX>, executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of
AllPolitics, the
site maintained by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . This makes sites like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley</ENAMEX>'s
especially valuable because they become, basically, reliable brand names in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sea</ENAMEX> of muck. Along with its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PoliticsNowa</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joint venture</ENAMEX> of several news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>,
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Journal</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AllPolitics</ENAMEX> remains a place where you can get lots of
political news and know that it's quality journalism, as opposed to some guy
blowing steam. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> andNewsweek each
site revels in the narcissism of small differences. PoliticsNow fancies itself
more insiderish; and, indeed, some of its features, like a regular column
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The</ENAMEX>
Buzz are meant for true aficionados. Over at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AllPolitics</ENAMEX>, they pride
themselves on being more beyond-the-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX>. In fact, the chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>, filled
with regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX>, are the most popular parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AllPolitics</ENAMEX>. "They do more
business than any bulletin boards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">onPathfinder</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley</ENAMEX>, "including the sex boards, which gives me
pause." Both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are good bets.

            Ican't say the same for sites maintained by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.
When the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>
campaign opened their Web site <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this summer</TIMEX>, they treated it like a
major event, even bringing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> over to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> to tout the
site. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> proves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> wrong," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> said, sounding like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confucius</ENAMEX>. The veep meant, of course, that computers will allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team Clinton</ENAMEX> to
respond quickly to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> attacks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>'s siteis equally turbo-charged. And while most candidate
Web <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are rich in position papers and press releases and sound clips and
applets, they're the cyberequivalent of a table set up at a campaign rally
where you can pick up brochures. They are too biased to help you think clearly
about which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> is better. Perhaps this will change. For the moment,
though, campaigns reach most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>, not the Web. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX> remains
more a gimmick, a way to signal to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blahblah</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of the
future.

            By contrast, I get a
visceral thrill surfing over to various political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> page
may be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s face to the world, but opening it still feels like getting to
eavesdrop on a conversation. Visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> site and read all about <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Second Amendment</ENAMEX> rights, described in
the hysterical, "the<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-liberals</ENAMEX>-are-coming!" tone that you would expect from, and
which is echoed throughout, libertarian-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> on the Web. There's also
an odd universal cheeriness to political Web sites, many of which I was guided
to by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>'s terrific Internet correspondentMary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynn</ENAMEX> "Be sure to visit theSinn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fein</ENAMEX> Web
site says a line in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Captive Voice</ENAMEX>
magazine written by IRA "political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>." It's hard to imagine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Luther King</ENAMEX> writing the "Letter from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birmingham Jail With Hotlinks</ENAMEX>."
There is a strange moral equivalence to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, too. Each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> pops up and
makes its claim, regardless of any relation to the truth. One can call up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serb Action Web</ENAMEX>
site and find out how to order books like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Eradication</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-1993</TIMEX> . This may come as news to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarajevo</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Srebrenica</ENAMEX>. (Less slick is the home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>-Herzegovina
embassyin <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>) There is an incongruous pride in technical
prowess. Go to an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX> and it has that funky icon boasting of being in "the
top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of all Web sites." How shall I visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mecca</ENAMEX>, I wonder? With
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netscape</ENAMEX> or Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer</ENAMEX>?

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing that
political sites can't replicate is the smell of politics, the feeling of being
at a campaign. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this year</TIMEX>, I was at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> rally in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omaha</ENAMEX>. I loved
everything about it: talking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who schlepped there on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>; the comic effect of having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> dressed like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGruff</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crime Dog</ENAMEX>
from public service ads, standing behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. I loved leafleting when I was in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX>, handing out flyers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passers-by</ENAMEX>. Not everyone, of course, can get to
a rally. But there are political meetings and activities in every neighborhood.
There's plenty of reason to be out on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, instead of sitting in the
basement.

         
      
   
