
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Noise</ENAMEX>

            To hear "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Noise</ENAMEX>" read by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>, click here or
on the title.

            Then he died.And they
said: Another soul 
               free .

            Which was the wrong way to
see it, I thought, having been there,having lain down beside him untilhis body
became rigid with what I believewas not the stiffening of deathbut of surprise,
the initialunbelief of the suddenly ex-slave hearing

            
               Rest; let it fall now,
this burden.
            

            The proof most commonly
put forth for the soulas a thing that exists and weighssomething is thatthe
body weighs something less, after death--

            a clean fact.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Miraculous</ENAMEX>
Translation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bodyof Saint Catherine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sinai</ENAMEX> the number
of angels required to bear the bodyall that way through the aircomes to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>,which tells us nothing about weight, or the lack of it, sincethe angels
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">depictedare</ENAMEX> clearly those for whom

            the only business is hard
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX>,

            the work angels, you can
tell:the musculature;the resigned way they wear clothes.

            Beyond them in rank,in the
actual presence of God,the seraphim stand naked, ever-burning,

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-winged: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to fly
with,in back; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> at the face to withstandthe impossible winds thatare God;

            and a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX>--for
modesty,for the covering of sex.

            A greatnoise is said to
alwaysattend them:less the humming of wings thanthe grinding you'd expect

            from the hitching of what
is hot,destructive,and all devotion

            to the highest, brightest
star.

         
      
   
