
   
   
      
         
            Ravioli Bartoli

            Connoisseurs of singing
rarely hold moderate opinions, and there is hardly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> who elicits more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adulation</ENAMEX> and disapproval at the same time than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mezzo-soprano</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecilia Bartoli</ENAMEX>,
who opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 16</TIMEX> in a new, made-to-order production of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossini</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
Cenerentola at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX>.

            Bartoli
is more than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>: She is a marvel of marketing. She sells out any house
she appears in and moves enough CDs to qualify as a pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.3 million</NUMEX> since
her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> recording appeared in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. Her recordings outsell those of every
other classical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano Pavarotti</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31</NUMEX>, she has already had
more ad hoc laurels lavished on her than many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legends</ENAMEX> receive even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">posthumously</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> has created "Ravioli
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chunnel</ENAMEX> trains that link <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> is called the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecilia Bartoli</ENAMEX>." There is a spate of worshipful Web sites devoted to her, and
a breathless and wildly premature biography by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Chernin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renate Stendhal</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cecilia Bartoli: The Passion of Song</ENAMEX> , which describes her as "a
sensuous, embodied angel, standing quietly on a concert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> as she report[s]
back to God about the mysterious joys and sorrows of human existence." Another
book about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> is being written by Manuela
Hoelterhoff, the former opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , who is
now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of its editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.

            Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartoli</ENAMEX> live up to the hype? She is certainly a fine
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> who never sacrifices passion to precision. Listen to her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">roulades</ENAMEX>--virtuosic runs of notes on a single syllable--and you'll hear each
note as a distinct link in a long, twirling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> and each word being accorded
its proper weight. Her new CD, An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Songbook</ENAMEX> , for instance, opens
with one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of settings <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossini</ENAMEX> made of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> short verses by the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pietro Metastasio</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mi</ENAMEX> lagnerò tacendo" ("I will
complain silently"). It is a jovial anthology of trills, runs, grace notes,
mordents, and melismas, with a section of operatic recrimination. Bartoli
finesses the tension between glum words and sprightly notes right up to the
end, when the music's exuberance finally overwhelms self-pity.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> have argued that her voice is too petite to reach the outer spaces of
the cathedral-like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> and that her repertoire is too narrow, fusty, and
obscure. She has sung no more than a handful of operatic roles onstage, mostly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossini</ENAMEX>, and she has made a specialty of the songs that kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossini</ENAMEX>
busy after his opera-composing career had ended. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX>'s style of fussing
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every</TIMEX> syllable has been called twitchy, belabored, and self-consciously
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adorable</ENAMEX>. Critics also draw ominous comparisons to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Battle</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soprano</ENAMEX>
whose gifts have been eroded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> by an uncontrollable tendency to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">simper</ENAMEX>. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX> has allowed her stage manner to become downright
weird. On the video of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Cenerentola</ENAMEX> , from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, her eyes pop
out, her dimples deepen, her chin recedes unflatteringly against her neck, her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> springs forward and back from her shoulders as if she were doing the Funky
Chicken. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX> does not have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">diva</ENAMEX>'s sense of dignity.

            
After years of disarming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>-next-door
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">normalcy</ENAMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX> may have begun indulging in the clichés of diva
naughtiness, such as a habit of canceling appearances, including a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">much-publicized Battle</ENAMEX>-like spat with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX>'s general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Volpe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX> has consistently said she is just protecting her health.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoelterhoff</ENAMEX> recently told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> that at least some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cancellations</ENAMEX> had to do with the condition of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriele</ENAMEX>, who
has had surgery for a brain tumor.

            There is
a certain irony to the accusation that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX>'s voice and repertoire lack
substance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX> has said that she finds the wry humor of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX> more modern than the grandiloquence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verdi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puccini</ENAMEX>. Her voice
matches her sensibility: It is better suited to the human-scaled works she
sings than to the colossal operas that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s colossal <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> were built for.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> have long been designed to be one-size-fits-all, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossini</ENAMEX>'s
domestic comedies inevitably seem dwarfed by a stage ample enough to contain
the struggles in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valhalla</ENAMEX>. It is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartoli</ENAMEX>'s voice but the operas
themselves that are too small for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>--or rather, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> is
too big for all but the grandest of grand opera. Under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Levine</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>
has barely dabbled in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bel canto</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">finespun singer vehicles</ENAMEX> of the early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX>, favoring instead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX> of opera. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cenerentola</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossini</ENAMEX>'s version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinderella</ENAMEX> story--has made it to the
Met for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s history, it is only because Bartoli
brought it there.

            For now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> seem willing to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX> to perform
repertoire that would otherwise seem destined for the remainder bin. She has
championed the music of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Viardot-Garcia</ENAMEX>, herself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossini</ENAMEX> mezzo-soprano
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19 th century</TIMEX>, and led a campaign to rehabilitate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haydn</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost</NUMEX>-mythological cantata <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arianna</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naxos</ENAMEX> and his virtually unknown
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opera Orfeo ed Euridice</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason she can get away with this is that
she is a dazzlingly expressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>, guiding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX> through the
emotional landscape of a piece with every small push of her voice. She colors
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> recitative in her recording of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haydn</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orfeo ed Euridice</ENAMEX> with
more brilliant hues of grief than I've ever heard before. "Sventurata! "
she cries (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Unhappy me</ENAMEX>!") in a voice full of pain. "A thousand dismal
thoughts"--her tone darkens--"constantly cloud my mind," and the notes acquire
a ravishing mistiness that is partly unsung air.

            To my
mind, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX>'s breathiness is central to her appeal. She can command a full,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chesty</ENAMEX> holler when she needs to, but in quiet passages she tends to produce a
gentle haze of breath around each focused note. This hiss, the noise level in
her voice, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Gould</ENAMEX>'s humming as he played the piano or the squeaking
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrés Segovia</ENAMEX>'s fingers on the strings of his guitar, makes her unusual
today, when most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> are trained in the discipline of steely perfection and
when our ears have become accustomed to the sharp-edged sounds of a compact
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disc</ENAMEX>, surrounded by undiluted digital silence. It is as if, by this deliberate
smudging, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bartoli</ENAMEX> were giving old songs an antique timbre.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX>'s effort to cast herself as an
anti-diva, at least in her stage performances, has worked. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scandalized</ENAMEX>, but more were charmed, when she made her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> debut <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two seasons</TIMEX> ago
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Despina</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant girl</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> wheel to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> malicious and befuddled
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lovers in Mozart</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Così</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> tutte . She did not enter down a curving
staircase, but rather toting a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on a rope like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">barge</ENAMEX>--and made it
immediately clear that she was carrying the whole production.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX> is a wildly popular
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">singer</ENAMEX> of relatively unpopular music, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> who could probably fill
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadiums</ENAMEX>, but prefers to keep her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> at close <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, she
opted to give a recital in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Center</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Tully Hall</ENAMEX>, rather than in
the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Avery Fisher Hall</ENAMEX> (to the chagrin of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presenter</ENAMEX>). She has been
leaning on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> to find a more intimate venue for her projects. She has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gravitated</ENAMEX> toward the stripped-down aesthetic of original-instrument <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ensembles</ENAMEX>.
While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pavarotti</ENAMEX> and his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sidekick tenors have been turning opera into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX>-appeal juggernaut, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bartoli</ENAMEX> has been trying to shrink a bloated genre.
That's the effort for which she really deserves megastardom.

         
      
   
