
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Laundry</ENAMEX>

            Now and then, a documentary
film comes along that makes us re-examine the rules that unofficially govern
the genre: Can there be a middle ground between fiction and fact? Can a
documentary use scripted scenes and yet remain ontologically authentic? How
much can you stylize material before you alter the reality that you're
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">striving</ENAMEX>, at least in theory, to capture?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unmade Beds</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barker</ENAMEX>'s " 'real life' feature film," has proudly worn its mongrel status as a
"directed" documentary of single life in the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, employing, in the face
of criticism, what amounts to a cackling-punk defiance. The movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> four
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">aging New Yorkers</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>--through their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX> dating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rituals</ENAMEX>, in
the process depicting a universe of lusty, coupled-up haves and downcast,
excluded have-nots, all viewed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rear Window</ENAMEX> -style through rectangular
openings in the massive apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in which they reside.

            This is
not cinema 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vérité</ENAMEX> , and nothing has been left to chance. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> selected his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">many hundreds</NUMEX> of potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>,
followed them around for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, and then scripted their monologues and
dialogues to reflect what he says he saw. Calling his own film "an exercise in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mendacity</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barker</ENAMEX> goes on, "I'm quite happy to tell lies about my characters
and even collude with their self-delusions if it enables me to communicate
larger dramatic truths."

            Spurned by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unmade Beds</ENAMEX> opened <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks ago</TIMEX> in a small screening <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, where it proceeded
to set box office records and generate lots of (largely favorable) press. In
part due to smart publicity, which has bannered some of the bad reviews and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">commentary</ENAMEX> ("I have to tell you that this film upset me so much that I really
don't want to have anything to do with it"--a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publicist</ENAMEX>), it threatens
to become a cause 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">célèbre</ENAMEX> --and to be coming soon to a theater
near you. It's always nice to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX> proved wrong about the merits of
"difficult" films, but in this case I think they did the decent thing.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unmade Beds</ENAMEX> isn't just bad--it's obnoxiously, noxiously bad, a freak
show for the empathetically challenged. The outrage it has prompted isn't the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puritan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kind</ENAMEX>; it's more like legitimate revulsion at watching a blowhard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pervert people</ENAMEX>'s lives in the name of "larger dramatic truths."

            Those
truths are large, all right. Take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-year-old</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 foot 4 inch</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely guy</ENAMEX> who has been looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost two decades</TIMEX>. If you were
to walk past him on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, you might think that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of his small stature
might have some trouble getting dates and be rather bitter about it. The larger
dramatic truth is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> has lots of trouble getting dates and is
very bitter about it. Just in case you feel too sorry for him, however,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barker</ENAMEX> is careful to include a homophobic monologue in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> complains
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who waste their lives hanging out with effeminate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX> turns out to be the film's most
sympathetic subject--by a wide margin. At least he's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikey</ENAMEX>, a paunchy
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54-year-old</TIMEX> who writes but can't sell screenplays and who always flees blind
dates, because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> he gets fixed up with are "<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mutts</ENAMEX>." Sounding like one
of the low-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangsters</ENAMEX> who posture like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kingpins</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mikey</ENAMEX> talks a lot about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mutts</ENAMEX>. He also reminisces about that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hour</TIMEX> period in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'70s</NUMEX> when he managed to sleep with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, whose
pictures he shows off. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">These days</TIMEX>, all he meets are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mutts</ENAMEX>. He comes off as a
pathetic little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser</ENAMEX>--a mutt.

            Aimee, on
the other hand, is a pathetic big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">loser</ENAMEX>, weighing in at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">225</NUMEX> pounds.
Determined to get married before she turns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30</TIMEX>, she generally is filmed beside
bags of groceries and assorted junk <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX>. She cries about her situation to her
thin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie</ENAMEX>, who, in one scene, gently mentions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aimee</ENAMEX>'s weight. Clearly
the scene is scripted, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aimee</ENAMEX> does a good job acting taken aback. She has
always been fat--and she's "OK with it," and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> just has to accept it. This
is followed by more talk about how you attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Will they respect you if
you call them back? If you express too much interest? "Or," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> thinks,
"if you're <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">225 pounds</NUMEX>?"

            The only natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX> here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda</ENAMEX>, a garrulous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exhibitionist</ENAMEX> who blossoms with the camera on her--she could have a career as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny Marshall</ENAMEX>-style <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character actress</ENAMEX>. Divorced and aging, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda</ENAMEX> needs money
and is willing to charge for her sexual services. It shouldn't be too
difficult, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are always showing her their dicks ("I'm up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dicks
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>"). They meet her and, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> later, they show her their dicks.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weird</ENAMEX>, huh? What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barker</ENAMEX> leaves out (it's in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> article)
is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda</ENAMEX>, a former lap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX>, works in marketing at a strip joint.
Presumably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> standing next to her in line at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> don't show her their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dicks</ENAMEX>. Nor, presumably, does she show them her breasts--although she bares them
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barker</ENAMEX>'s camera, jabbering about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> while she doffs her clothes and
steps into the shower and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soaps</ENAMEX> up.

            Barker
might have crafted his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>' monologues from their own words, but he has
robbed them of their spontaneity--and, thus, of their essence. They aren't
thinking or trying to come to grips with their situations in front of your
eyes, because they already know what they're going to say: They've been fixed
like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX> on the ends of pins and held up for voyeuristic inspection.
The scenes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and confidantes have a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>, programmatic purpose. You
can imagine the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> composing a shot (the shots are tightly composed and
elaborately lighted) and reminding them, "In this scene she points out that you
should lose weight and you get shocked and defensive. Ready ... Action."

            
Call me square, but I find this antithetical to
the documentary spirit. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX> who trained as an anthropologist before
going to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBC Television</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barker</ENAMEX> clearly made up his mind about his
material before his cameras began to roll--so it's no surprise that it feels
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prechewed</ENAMEX> and predigested. When reality interfered (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda</ENAMEX> apparently did not
go through with a marriage to an immigrant in search of a green card for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>, as she does on-screen), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barker</ENAMEX> brushed the truth aside as immaterial,
following her up the steps of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Hall</ENAMEX> in her wedding dress because it was
"true to her character." But what separates documentary from fiction is that
real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are often more complicated, and more conflicted, than finished
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>--as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda</ENAMEX> proved to be more (or, at least, other) than the sum of
her parts. That's the kind of truth that reveals itself to documentary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmakers</ENAMEX> after the fact, when they go over footage and discover unexpected
patterns, dissonances, glimmers of a universe that's richer and messier than
the one they set out to portray.

            So what are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barker</ENAMEX>'s "larger
dramatic truths"? Single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> can be desperate. Single people
fear they're going to die alone--unloved and unloving. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are judged and,
in turn, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> others by how they look. Big news. One could argue, charitably,
that the movie is meant to be prescriptive, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barker</ENAMEX> intends for us to
regard the ways in which his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> delude themselves and thereby learn to
see through our own self-delusions. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barker</ENAMEX> hasn't concocted a larger
dramatic structure that would hold those larger dramatic truths together
and help us comprehend where these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> went wrong. He dramatizes right up to
the point where a dramatist would be expected to provide some insight--and
then, hey, he's a documentarian.

            
               Unmade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beds</ENAMEX> might make a good date movie. There's little to argue about in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>' personalities--both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> will find them repulsive--and
the picture the film <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">paints</ENAMEX> of single life in the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is so bleak that
you'll probably want to jump into bed with whoever is sitting next to you.
Anything to keep from turning into one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slums</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> also walks a line between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genres</ENAMEX>, in this case coming-of-age sex comedy and autobiographical monologue.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamara Jenkins</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, has an eye for absurd
juxtapositions that was obviously sharpened by the pain of her nomadic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">upbringing</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natasha Lyonne</ENAMEX>) spends her teen-age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> being
shuttled with her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> from one cheap dive to another in the <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">90210 ZIP</ENAMEX>
code, all because her egregiously unsuccessful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Arkin</ENAMEX>) wants them
to be educated in the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furniture</ENAMEX>'s temporary; education is
permanent.") It's a major omission, then, that we never see those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' interaction with their stable, well-to-do <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>.
We can't tell if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> is, on some weird level, justified in his fervor,
or whether he's screwing up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>--subjecting them to humiliation and
robbing them of a sense of permanence--for no reason. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> hasn't quite
figured out how to shape her narrative, which is full of episodes that are
there because they actually happened but that don't have a payoff. I almost
wish she'd included more voice-over narration, more commentary on the things
that, as a filmmaker, she hasn't learned to bring out.

            
               The
Slums of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> never gels, but it has a likable spirit, and it's
exceedingly easy on the eye, with lots of pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and wry evocations of
'70s fashions and decor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, to obtain financial support from his
wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Reiner</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> to take in his vaguely schizzy,
dipsomaniacal niece (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marisa Tomei</ENAMEX>). She and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> compare breasts, play
with vibrators, and talk in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pig Latinish gibberish</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> never lets the
proceedings get too sentimental: The whimsy is always cut with an acidic
awareness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s desperation. "Are we middle-class now?" ask the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, hopefully, before another crisis sends them back into their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>,
cruising past the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX>, in the mean <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hills</ENAMEX>.

            
Grading on the steep curve established by
summer blockbuster <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons past</TIMEX>, these have turned out to be a pretty good few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> at the movies. Even the commercial swill ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deep Impact</ENAMEX> ,
Armageddon , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Mask of Zorro , Small Soldiers , Snake</ENAMEX>
Eyes , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">H20</ENAMEX> ) has been of a high grade, and Saving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> and Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> were Vitalis slaps in the kisser
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> woozy from all the warm weather escapism. Out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sight</ENAMEX> was
tender and charming, as was, in its gross-out way, There's Something About
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> . And, on the indie front, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Opposite of Sex</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66</TIMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pi</ENAMEX> have proved that there's still commercial life after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundance</ENAMEX>. Sure, we had stinkers, but even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Godzilla</ENAMEX> was fun to jeer at.
And there's something reassuring about the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Avengers</ENAMEX> is so
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rotten</ENAMEX>: proof yet again that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with piles of money can hire wizard
production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> but can't fake class.

            I don't know who the
credited <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don MacPherson</ENAMEX>, is, but it's unlikely that he has ever
seen an episode of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avengers</ENAMEX> , let alone sussed out the source of
its appeal. Opening with a slapstick sequence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Steed</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiennes</ENAMEX>) doing kung fu, the film shifts to a scene in which he meets Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peel</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uma Thurman</ENAMEX>) while sitting naked in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sauna</ENAMEX> with only a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> to cover his
private parts. The series was erotic in a way only prim <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> humor can be:
The Old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Steed</ENAMEX> was capable of throwing a punch and bonking someone with his
bowler, but he left the karate kicking to his liberated, leather-suited distaff
associate. Here their roles have been witlessly muddled, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacPherson</ENAMEX>'s idea
of banter is to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pair</ENAMEX> complete each other's clichés.

            Whereas the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steed</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Macnee</ENAMEX>, was to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English Men's Club</ENAMEX> born, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiennes</ENAMEX> is an eternal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">caddie</ENAMEX>. The willowy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurman</ENAMEX> looks great in her outfits, but it's ever more
apparent that she isn't much of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>--at least, not a trained one--and
her attempts at insouciance are embarrassingly arch. As the eccentric master
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villain</ENAMEX> who controls the weather, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> is flat-out terrible,
acting high on the hog. To think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connery</ENAMEX> once found the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond</ENAMEX> films so far
beneath him! When he sputters lines like "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> to die!" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">imagines</ENAMEX> Dr. No,
Goldfinger, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blofeld</ENAMEX> snickering in the wings.

         
      
   
