
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naked Eye</ENAMEX>

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naked Eye</ENAMEX>," click or on the title.

            The small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> he's
sitting snug against is radiantas an operating table on which the naked
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dancerdoubled</ENAMEX> in the mirrored backdrop dances before himsimultaneously from
both sides at once, blond crotchAnd jiggling ass, nipple and churning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shoulderblade</ENAMEX>.

            If he's aware of us at
all, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and I,in a back <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> farthest from the stage, what are webut
the proverbial rubes, sight-seeing frat boyson a sleazy lark, too loud, too
talkative, gigglinguneasy ironies about being where we'd never go alone.

            If we annoy him, the
annoyance must be somehow necessary to his pleasure, the rising of it
sweeterfor the last tug of a defeated gravity--as feeblenow, as faraway, as
being anybody's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.For he seems all gaze, nudging a dollar toward
her.

            And she, her back to him,
seems only what she shows as she bends over, reaching between her splayed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legsto</ENAMEX> pick it up, her face a moment upside down beneath her crotch, her pink
tongue flickering levelwith the face she watches watching her, the face
void

            of expression, dense as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stone</ENAMEX>, clinical as light,unmoved, as if the fantasy is that there isn't
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>,that she isn't dancing any gesture of what sheimagines he imagines she
would feel like if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hewere</ENAMEX> doing to her what she pretends he does.

            The fantasy is wholly of
the eye. The eye is his.The eye is lordly. Only imagine it as thinking: Let
the frat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> hoard how her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fingertips</ENAMEX> have eased the hidden lips back to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">moist</ENAMEX> interior, let <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">themsmuggle home</ENAMEX> to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> pale simulations
            

            
               of themselves still
outside watching what they onlyenter in the dark, what in the dark they only
feel --Only imagine it, and it is yours, your eye, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>,no less
imperiously moving over him as his movesover the places in her she has never
seen.

            It is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seer</ENAMEX>'s eye moving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lordly</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>,over all of us its rapture cool, so otherworldly,who
here can deny that hidden craving is abroad,and that the cure lies in the body
spread before usthat the eye alone is shrewd enough to read.

         
      
   
