
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher Hypothesis</ENAMEX>

            I staggered out of a showing
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Square</ENAMEX>. The world looked evil and sad.
The sun was sinking out of sight at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 43</TIMEX> rd Street, where
signs no longer read "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">43 rd Street</ENAMEX>" but instead "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX> rd
Street: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolph S. Ochs Street</ENAMEX>," in tongue-twisting homage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriarch</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six neon-striped</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">storefronts</ENAMEX> seem to have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sprouted</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five or six days</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Complex</ENAMEX> now has a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Store</ENAMEX>, not to mention a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>. Billboards high above <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> nd
Street advertise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Amsterdam Beer</ENAMEX>; fake movie marquees draw attention to them
with chortling messages like "Don't Look Up." Those fake marquees first
appeared during the filming of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> bomb Last Action
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Hero</ENAMEX> . Afterward they bore pseudo-provocative art-slogan messages of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenny Holzer</ENAMEX> variety. So we're looking at fake ads parodying fake slogans
parodying fake movie titles. I wish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> would come back now and blow
everything up again. I went into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>, hoping to find solace in an order
of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super-Size Fries</ENAMEX>. They were stale. Where can you go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> for decent
trash?

            When I
say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batman & Robin</ENAMEX> is a punishing ordeal, I want you to know
where I'm coming from. I have an appetite for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blockbusters</ENAMEX> of the
sort that some literate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> consider big and dumb. I thought the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX> Bros. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Burton</ENAMEX>'s pulp opera, had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> in it. It
invented a huge movie world in which the eyes could go dreaming. It also had
the wit to set a menacing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> against a merrymaking villain--the line between
good and evil grew scribbly. The last <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Schumacher</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman Forever</ENAMEX> , was nowhere near as cool, but it was clean, campy fun
from beginning to end, and it rode high on a maliciously <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>
performance. I was also lucky to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman Forever</ENAMEX> in more pleasant
surroundings than the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Times Square</ENAMEX>--in a high-modern movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palace</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helsinki</ENAMEX>, with an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of hip <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finns</ENAMEX> who giggled at subtitles that seemed to
go their own way from the script. (At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX> text made some
kind of joke about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chevy Chase</ENAMEX>. No one was saying "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chevy Chase</ENAMEX>" on-screen, or
possibly could have been.)

            Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher</ENAMEX> is not a talentless filmmaker. Indeed, a
sophistical argument could be made that his films, while meretricious, are
always at least mildly entertaining. If your next dinner party threatens to
turn dull, you might try antagonizing sophisticates with a Revisionist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher Hypothesis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Elmo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fire</ENAMEX> ? An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">unflinching</ENAMEX> descent into the
shallowness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brat Pack</ENAMEX>, notable for the discovery of the brooding
dramatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demi Moore</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lost Boys</ENAMEX> ? An innocently homoerotic
vampire spoof, notable for the discovery of the brooding dramatic craft of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jason Patric</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flatliners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dying Young</ENAMEX> ? Best passed over in
silence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX> is found not to be a tragedian. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dying Young</ENAMEX> was
really notable as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big whoosh of air out of the balloon of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">megastardom</ENAMEX>.) Falling Down ? A descent into white-male, white-collar
vigilante fantasies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX> diptych, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Client and A Time to</ENAMEX>
Kill ? Bad movies done in style. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher</ENAMEX> is once again the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maestro</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">8 by10s</ENAMEX>, unveiling the teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Renfro</ENAMEX> and twentysomething dreamboat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew McConaughey</ENAMEX>.

            "But this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher</ENAMEX> is a pompous idiot," your dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> sputter. "He once said on
The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Rose</ENAMEX> 
               Show that he made 'commercial' pictures
like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> so he could afford 'idea' pictures like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Time</ENAMEX> to
Kill !?!" All too true. But let's at least admit his flair for trash. At his
best he offers an empty but internally consistent flamboyance. He is skilled at
evoking places: Falling Down captured with precision what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
looks like on a vicious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer day</TIMEX>. He is also good with faces, particularly
male faces. This is not to make assumptions about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s sexuality--he might
just happen to be as gifted a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of slow-witted male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> as, say,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Cukor</ENAMEX> was of fast-witted female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>. I enjoy this aspect of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher</ENAMEX>'s work, although I wonder, in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Time to Kill</ENAMEX> ,
whether he worried about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McConaughey</ENAMEX>'s inability to enunciate or to assume
different facial expressions. The acting is not always an embarrassment; in
Falling Down , the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher</ENAMEX> film that threatened to be decent,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Douglas</ENAMEX> delivered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the creepiest slow burns of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batman & Robin quashes the Schumacher</ENAMEX>
Hypothesis for the time being. (I will have to return to my old contrarian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">standby</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unsung Greatness</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>.) It has none of the minor
virtues of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher</ENAMEX>'s other films. It looks bad: cluttered surfaces,
production design reminiscent of overblown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> musicals, editing too fast
for the eye to catch up, poor staging of fast action. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">first few minutes</TIMEX> are
particularly trying--direction seems to have been handed over to a fractious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> of prepubescent speed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX>. And while this kind of movie doesn't
cry out for a coherent plot, it does need surprises. Most of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX> 's clichés were parodied in advance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Powers</ENAMEX> . (When
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> shows up on a TV monitor warning that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeze</ENAMEX> has taken
over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gotham Museum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> will think fondly of the plot-spewing
monologues of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Basil Exposition</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smirky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX> has no screen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">charisma</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris O'Donnell</ENAMEX>'s strutting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>-cut <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX> is a superfluous second
superhero, indistinct from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uma Thurman</ENAMEX> tries to interject some
vampish style as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poison Ivy</ENAMEX>, but the inanity of her character--environmentalist
turned plant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>?--has the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> snickering against her. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Alicia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silverstone</ENAMEX>, as a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> turned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Batgirl</ENAMEX>, purses her lips
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uncertainly</ENAMEX>.

            With so
much wrong on every front, it's hard to single out a basic flaw. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> has to take the blame for providing no immoral <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> to the
Batman world. Each of the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> films had a sly, spry
villainous turn, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Nicholson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny DeVito</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX> dancing
through their roles. Schwarzenegger slowly and methodically munches his way
through reams of cardboard zingers. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winter</ENAMEX> has come!" "Everyone chill!" "The
Iceman cometh!" etc. He's Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeze</ENAMEX> , see? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX> has regressed to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ultraprimitive Conan</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbarian</ENAMEX> manner, except that, in this case,
not even his big frame adds much to a waddling-icicle role.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the movie's few redeeming features is partially
wiped out by one of its worst excesses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliot Goldenthal</ENAMEX>, the best film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> now working, has written typically imaginative music, rich in jagged
harmony and deft scoring. That eerie wailing at the end of the title theme is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> of trilling horns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schumacher</ENAMEX>'s regard for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>--he used him also
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Time to Kill</ENAMEX> --is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sign of latent tastefulness. In movies like
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Interview With the Vampire and Heat</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldenthal</ENAMEX> returned the
obsolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX> to some of its old glory. But in the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Batman</ENAMEX> , the score was apparently deemed insufficient. It's repeatedly
blotted out by the sound effects that erupt in tandem with every move or twitch
on-screen. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whip</ENAMEX> of a cape sounds like a rocket blasting off. An actual
rocket blasting off--yes, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeze</ENAMEX> escapes in a rocket, just
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil in Austin Powers</ENAMEX> --sounds like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> going to work on
your ear. This indiscriminate racket, more than anything, sent me out into
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Square</ENAMEX> with the feeling of having been roughed up. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> hasn't
changed so much after all.

            
               Chill out: Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeze</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Donnell</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

            
               Batspat: Batgirl
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silverstone</ENAMEX>) vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poison Ivy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurman</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

         
      
   
