
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop Technology</ENAMEX>

            That Star Wars
should turn out to be a kind of cultural touchstone for many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is likely
to be mysterious to the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for whom it is not a cultural touchstone.
It's tempting to assume that its appeal, like the appeal of most popular
entertainment, is simply a function of how old you were when you were first
exposed to it. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fourteen</NUMEX> seems to be the age of prime vulnerability for these
things--a time of life when the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">clay</ENAMEX> is soft enough to take an impression and
firm enough to retain it. If you were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> flourished, you are
probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles fan</ENAMEX> for life. If you were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> was on
television, you are (God help you) probably a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trekkie</ENAMEX>.

            No doubt some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> of the re-released Star Wars is therefore owed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> born
circa <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>. But they can't take all the credit. This is a movie that, although
it had been available on videotape for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, grossed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36.2 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>
it was re-released. To put those dollars in perspective, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Maguire</ENAMEX> ,
the second-highest-grossing movie that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>, took in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.6 million</NUMEX>.
Gridlock'd , the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">No. 1</ENAMEX>, made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.2 million</NUMEX>. Star Wars did
better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first weekend</TIMEX> in re-release than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission</ENAMEX>: Impossible --and it
recouped its production costs long, long ago.

            
Things this profitable require explanation.
here is the big screen/little screen thesis: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Videotape</ENAMEX> is inadequate for a
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">like Star Wars</ENAMEX> , which is famous for its epic scale and special
effects, so that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who know the story by heart are happy to plunk
down <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> to get the full <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> mm experience. This seems the weakest
explanation. The movie has been buffed up a bit--a remixed soundtrack, some new
computer-generated images, and so forth. But as pure big-screen experience, it
still feels light-years behind a contemporary state-of-the-art spectacular like
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Independence Day</ENAMEX> . The quaintness of the movie is probably more appealing
than the new--and, to someone who hadn't seen the film in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>, practically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imperceptible</ENAMEX>--special effects.
       The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> answer, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> preferred by the film's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lucas</ENAMEX>, is the myth-and-archetype explanation--timeless themes, classic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, basic elements of universal human nature, etc. This argument
probably needs to be parsed into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>. The original Star Wars
spun off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more movies (the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of which, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Return of the Jedi</ENAMEX> ,
actually out-performed the original at the box office), a line of books (many
of them best sellers), and a number of other licensed products, to the total
tune of something like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.3 billion</NUMEX>. This is, in other words, a story that
occupies a substantial amount of turf in the popular culture. Everyone in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> knows "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> the force be with you" and what a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wookiee</ENAMEX> is, just as
everyone knows "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yabba</ENAMEX> dabba doo!" and what a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flintstone</ENAMEX> is.

            
Whether this translates into myth, any more
than The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flintstones</ENAMEX> translates into myth, is
another matter. Star Wars is stuffed with "mythemes"--the atomic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>, so to speak, of mythic material. The movie reminds you of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
stories you already know, and it thus cashes in--brilliantly, it must be
said--on the secret formula of all art, which is: If it worked once, it will
again. But most of the elements didn't come out of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Golden Bough</ENAMEX> .
They came out of all the other successful pseudo-mythical contrivances of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> popular culture--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Westerns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flash Gordon</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Godfather</ENAMEX> ,
and so on. The basic template seems to be an amalgam of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wizard of Oz</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Days</ENAMEX> : The relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luke</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Hamill</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Han</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX>) is just the relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richie</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fonz</ENAMEX>; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wookiee</ENAMEX> is cloned directly from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowardly Lion</ENAMEX>; and the scene in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">C-</ENAMEX>3PO
is dismembered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sand People</ENAMEX> is completely appropriated from the scene in
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scarecrow</ENAMEX> is dismembered by flying <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wizard of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oz</ENAMEX> . It is true that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wizard</ENAMEX> is a story implanted deep in the
memory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the viewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>--but it is a stretch to call <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Wars ' appeal atavistic.
       The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> explanation for the success of the Star Wars re-release
is just that they marketed the hell out of it. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> in the entertainment
business, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">land</ENAMEX> lies fallow. The big <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> movies have mostly played out
their pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> runs; the television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> is already old; <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> is
finished, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> is still <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">midseason</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> off. It is
not a bad time to promote a product. The Star Wars re-release got play
in almost every conceivable outlet. And when you start seeing, even before the
movie opens, detailed press accounts of the process by which the new
computer-generated images were designed and inserted into the picture, you know
that the publicity wheels have already been turning on this one for a very long
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.

            
Still, the key to a successful entertainment
phenomenon usually isn't the what or the how. It's the when. Before everything
else that was significant about them, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> were what came along after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>. Their differences from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> (more literate and lovable, less slick and
racially ambiguous) were what made their similarities with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> (purveyors of
courtship music for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX>, a scandal to grown-ups) work.
       The Star Wars <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odyssey</ENAMEX> , a movie that combined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> attraction with intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretension</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> is a science-fiction movie that takes science extremely
seriously. Its message is that the advanced technological future--what we now
call the age of digitalization--will transform the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> into a new,
probably soulless <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, just as apes once became <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> by the invention of
the tool. Computers in particular--the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">HAL</ENAMEX>, whose acronym is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> one
letter removed--are represented as the models of what this superior being will
have to be like. It was all in keeping with the general pop imagery of computer
technology: automation, a brave-new-world technocracy, white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> in white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coats</ENAMEX>--a universe without affect and with some sort of cosmic inevitability
about it.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> tar Wars changed all that. It was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spoofy</ENAMEX> and pop rather than gnomic and portentous (or, indeed, "mythic," which
is what popular entertainment becomes when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have made too much money from
it). And it associated technology with fun and adventure. The movie didn't just
suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who fly around in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spaceships</ENAMEX> will be just as swashbuckling,
funny, romantic, and--in a word--human as ever. It was itself an advertisement,
through its special-effects wizardry, for the new unthreatening entertainment.
The movie coincided with a complete makeover in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX> of the imagery
of advanced technology, the most notable examples of which were the emergence
of the video game and the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> advertisements for the PC that featured
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Chaplin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tramp</ENAMEX>. Computers aren't soul-destroying <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of
technocratic efficiency, these images said. They're interactive and fun; anyone
can use them (even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tramp</ENAMEX>); and they should be associated not with the idea
of labor, but with the idea of play. The computer is the toy that will keep us
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human</ENAMEX>.
       The digital age that has now arrived is almost exactly in the image that
Star Wars prophesied, so that celebrating the movie is a way of honoring
its prescience. (If the digital age seemed soulless and technocratic, we would
probably be watching a re-released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> .) Computers got into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX> when they stopped being thought of as needlessly expensive and vaguely
inhuman ways to balance your checkbook, and started being sold as devices for
your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to play "educational" games on. And a computer network devised on the
grim old <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> technological rationale--as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX> scheme--has
become a play land for ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> with modems. High tech is now
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with creativity, democracy, and spending more time with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
It is because we had Star Wars that we have SLATE.

            
Of course, it is because we had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
Wars that the movies changed, and not for the better. In making the digital
world fun, we somehow made fun merely digital. In the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> movies,
screen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> have become tiny figurines--droids, almost--manipulated in front
of colossal computer-generated <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">spaceships</ENAMEX>, fireballs, tornadoes, and volcanic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eruptions</ENAMEX>. The sensual essence of the movies used to be the human face; now
it's just light and sound. The real world has become a blue screen, and the
human being is a prop. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>'s blockbuster <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twister</ENAMEX> , the amazing
virtual noise of the amazing virtual tornadoes was so deafening that there were
long stretches in which, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> were apparently shouting at
one another at the top of their lungs, no dialogue was audible. If you listened
very carefully, though, you realized that there actually was no dialogue; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> were obviously aware that their voices were not going to be heard. So
they were just repeating the same line over and over in every tornado scene.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come on</ENAMEX>!" they kept yelling. "Let's get out of here!" The impulse was
understandable. But where were they going to go?

         
      
   
