
   
   
      
         
            Sound of Mind

            Professional music-making
works along the principle best defined by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chevy Chase</ENAMEX> when he opened
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live 's "Weekend Update</ENAMEX>" with the portentous phrase, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chevy Chase</ENAMEX>. And you're not." Whether they play rock or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
classical music or jazz, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> are engaged in a conversation with one
another, and with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>. The rest of us are listening in, although
there have always been some who don't like feeling forced into silence. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Poet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adrienne Rich</ENAMEX>, for example, called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beethoven</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth</ENAMEX> "music of the
entirely/ isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>/ yelling at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> of the ego/ music
without the ghost/ of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in it."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tod Machover</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>
based at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Lab</ENAMEX>, thinks computers will bring the isolation of the
musical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> to an end. In this he is partly influenced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media Lab</ENAMEX>, which
champions the idea that a seamless global web of information will soon blur the
line between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listener</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Machover</ENAMEX> also likes
to quote late <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pianist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Gould</ENAMEX>, who said that the "best of all possible
worlds" is one in which "art would be unnecessary. ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> would be
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and their life would be art."

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machover</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brain Opera</ENAMEX> is a performance-cum-interactive stunt. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Roughly</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> long, it was presented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> times a day over the course of several
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Center Festival</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (it closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 3</TIMEX>). In it,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Machover</ENAMEX> weds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gould</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitmanesque</ENAMEX> vision to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cage</ENAMEX>'s Zen-inspired idea that
music is not sounds chosen by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>, but a quality of awareness about what
you're hearing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> for all this is the expensive, complicated, and
most un-Zen-like apparatus of computerized electronic music. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brain Opera</ENAMEX>
supplies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> with a variety of strange-looking digital
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">instruments</ENAMEX> and asks that they play around with them. We not only get to
explore a cool new technology; we get to collaborate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>. We move
toward being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, our lives, the art. In theory, anyway.

            
               B
               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">></ENAMEX>rain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> begins in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Julliard School</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, which has
been transformed into a thicket of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics molded</ENAMEX> into shapes suggestive of
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruits</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, or maybe cells. We <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mill</ENAMEX> around in the dark among the
machines, some of which emit fanfares, drumrolls, or gusts of melody, so that
between the bumbling and waiting-to-try and noise, we feel much as we might in
a video arcade. The games, though, are more interesting.

            The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gesture Wall</ENAMEX>," for instance, puts a little zip of electricity through you,
which makes you intelligible to some sensors in front of you, which means you
can "play" snippets of music and sound by gesticulating. (My fillings vibrated
a little; though that could have been caused by the ambient noise.) There are
also dirigible-shaped pods about the size of beach balls that, depending on how
hard you hit the nubby pads that stick out of them, cause nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> to
spit out percussive clicks and bops. Another device is called "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Speaking</ENAMEX>
Tree"; it engages you in conversation about music. You can have any type of
discussion you want, provided it's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machover</ENAMEX> expected. ("What is your
favorite piece of music?" asks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Tree</ENAMEX>. "I don't know," say you. "When you
hear it, what do you feel?" asks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Tree</ENAMEX>.)

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Machover</ENAMEX> wanted the experience to feel like "walking into
somebody's brain while a piece of music is being created," because, as the name
suggests, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brain Opera</ENAMEX> is about the nature of mind. It is based on the
theories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin Minsky</ENAMEX>, an artificial intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> who holds
that consciousness is built up of loosely connected separate processes. What I
think of as "me," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minsky</ENAMEX>, is actually a pattern that emerges as a lot of
components of my brain go about their business of seeing or hearing or eating
or whatever it is they do----much the way a traffic pattern emerges out of the
actions of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>, or an opera performance out of the actions of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">musicians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conductor</ENAMEX>, and a stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brain Opera</ENAMEX> both
presents and enacts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minsky</ENAMEX>'s theories: The music emerges in part out of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noodling</ENAMEX> around with the gizmos right before we go in to hear it.

            After a
half hour or so in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX>, we're led into the recital <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX>, where Machover
appears and explains that "some <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of the piece is in place before, and
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> will be created at this performance." He and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> take
their seats; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machover's</ENAMEX> is inside a more professional version of the "Gesture
Wall." He ignites <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brain Opera</ENAMEX> with a sequence of chopping hand motions
and vigorous leanings in his chair (picture the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX> under attack); this
brings forth a sonic crash from the computer. We hear a lot of musical
quotations--from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Igor Stravinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rite of Spring</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Bernstein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Candide</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke Ellington</ENAMEX>--that bounce around a theme from
the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ricercare" of Bach's Musical Offering</ENAMEX> . Images that would work well
on album covers fly by on big screens --the moon, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>, the great red spot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jupiter</ENAMEX>. We hear a comment or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Speaking Trees</ENAMEX> ("I think it has to
do with the electrons in the air"; "music changes your mood very definitely").
The words of the libretto zip past on the screens. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prerecorded</ENAMEX> voices sing it
to New Age melodies. A red <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">square</ENAMEX> appears, signifying, apparently, that people
logged on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brain Opera Web</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> who are participating in the piece
on "virtual instruments" are now being sampled and folded into the work.

            
               I >t is all quite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lively</ENAMEX>, and far from dull. But by the end I feel a little glazed and tired,
much as I might feel after too much time spent on the Web or reading somebody's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hypertextual</ENAMEX> "novel." There's the same sense of scope and technical mastery,
and absence at the core. I missed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> voice, the unique and
compelling emotional timbre, of the sort that characterizes less interactive
music--including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machover</ENAMEX>'s own, when he's not trying to bring the whole world
into it. Also performed at the festival, for example, were his works for
"hyperinstruments," electronic versions of a cello, viola, and violin, which he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invented</ENAMEX> himself. Each of these compositions suggested the powerful currents of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>'s anguish, jauntiness, fragile serenity. But Brain 
               Opera
is swamped by the sound of Whatever, of Nothing in Particular.

            Giving up his musical
individuality, it turns out, has not paid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Machover</ENAMEX> back with a glimpse of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gould</ENAMEX>'s perfect world. From the moment we are guided into the play arcade, each
alone, each face to face with technology designed and controlled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX>, we are
maneuvered along paths laid down for us. We are no more collaborating than a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lab mouse collaborates</ENAMEX> with a medical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brain Opera</ENAMEX> is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opera</ENAMEX>, and we are not.

         
      
   
