
   
   
      
         
            Beyond Good and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>

            A lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> have plastic
features, the kind that mold and remold themselves according to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' moods; others--primarily <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX>--have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Rushmore</ENAMEX>-esque features whose lack of plasticity is
meant to betoken strength. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Duvall</ENAMEX>, uniquely, has a face that manages to
be both granitelike and plastic. In repose, it is a chiseled mask, with avian
eyes that give away little; then, swamped by feeling, those features wiggle and
crack and loosen from their moorings. Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duvall</ENAMEX> have a screw loose? I
sometimes think so. His volcanic rages don't have the put-on quality of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post- Raging Bull Robert De Niro</ENAMEX> or the preening self-consciousness of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacino</ENAMEX>; nor is he a simple-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully boy</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Keitel</ENAMEX>. On-screen,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX>'s madness has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">divine purity</ENAMEX>. No <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> has ever brought the kind of
belief to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelist</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX> brings to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>, the tormented protagonist
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Apostle</ENAMEX> . And no one else could have created a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> who stirs
in the film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> such disparate responses: He's magnificent, he's
dangerously crazy, he's magnificent and he's dangerously crazy.

            The fact
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX> gives such a glorious performance in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle</ENAMEX> is likely
to distract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from the fact that he has also written and directed a
glorious movie--the most vivid and radiantly made of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. (The film opened
briefly at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of last year</TIMEX> to qualify for various awards; it goes into
general release <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle</ENAMEX> has a laid-back intimacy that
reminds me, mutatis mutandis, of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jean Renoir</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">documentarian</ENAMEX>'s penchant
for letting events play out at their own sweet speed. And if, as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX> gets drunk on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>'s megalomania, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> he keeps the character
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">soberly</ENAMEX> in focus, so that we're simultaneously swept up in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>'s good while
recoiling from his evil, agog at his purity while giggling at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hamminess</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX> introduces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> as a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, being led by an
immense black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> through the swinging doors of a back-country <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>,
where the restless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is mesmerized by a gospel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX>. In no time, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grown-up Sonny</ENAMEX> is perorating before congregations black, white, and mixed.
Happening with his mama (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> Carter Cash) past a multicar collision, he seizes
his <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> and marches through a field to the worst-injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> leans
into the window, places his hand on the shoulder of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with gelid eyes
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood trickling</ENAMEX> from one ear, and exhorts him to live , live .
He says that there are angels in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, that the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has nothing to
fear if he accepts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX> as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX>--and, miraculously, the young man
manages to thank him. We never learn if he or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with him
survive (We see her stir), but we know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>'s prayers have got through to
them. And we believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> when he says, almost laughing in amazement at his
own gifts, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mama</ENAMEX>, we made news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in heaven."

            But
frequently the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> makes is of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> variety. Thanks in part
to his "wandering eye and wickie-wickie ways," he has lost his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, Jessie
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrah Fawcett</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (he calls them his "beauties") to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Allen</ENAMEX>), a gentle, callow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> who seems to be, in every way, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>'s
opposite. Civil and friendly toward his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> can turn
suddenly, scarily <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX>--pounding on their door in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> and
throwing a baseball through their window. When the anxious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessie</ENAMEX> has him voted
out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> church that they founded together, something ruptures:
Unable to comprehend his banishment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> spends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mama</ENAMEX>'s
attic railing at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>. ("I've always called you 'Jesus,' you've always called
me 'Sonny.' ") Primed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liquor</ENAMEX>, he commits a shocking act of violence, then
flees <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> for a new life--sinking his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in a swamp and baptizing himself
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle E.F.</ENAMEX>"

            
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The next 90 minutes</TIMEX> of The Apostle
recount that new life, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle E.F.</ENAMEX> builds from scratch in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ramshackle Louisiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. In almost no time, he has secured a position as
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">auto</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mechanic</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">good-hearted grease monkey</ENAMEX> (Walton
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goggins</ENAMEX>). More important, he has sought out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brother Blackwell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Beasley</ENAMEX>), a
retired black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> whose fervor once generated several <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attacks</ENAMEX> and
who now reposes with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackwell</ENAMEX> doesn't
know if this self-dubbed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle</ENAMEX> has been sent by God or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Satan</ENAMEX> (nor do we), but
he trusts that the former will soon make that plain; in the meantime, he sets
about helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.F.</ENAMEX> to establish a parish.

            Surveying
a broken-down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> by the side of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interstate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> murmurs,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Resurrection time</ENAMEX> ... resurrection time. ... Yes, sir." He concludes, "I could
do some shouting in here." He checks out the space the way a jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>
checks out a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub</ENAMEX> in which he's about to perform. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle</ENAMEX>'s preachings
(one can hardly call them "sermons") are marvelous production numbers,
alternately plangent and syncopated; they make everyone--even those of us in
the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> predisposed to find a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelist</ENAMEX> threatening--feel
welcome. I'm not sure what he says in those numbers, only that I
couldn't take my eyes off him or stop myself from nodding when his congregants
said, "Amen." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX> has an abysmal singing voice--gargling and off-key--but
his speaking voice, his presence, is insistently musical. His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle E.F.</ENAMEX> is
utterly certain of what he's doing; and--even knowing what we know about his
past--we can't help sharing his conviction that something momentous is taking
place in this small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>.

            Where other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> have tried to assert that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">showmanship</ENAMEX> somehow precludes belief, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duvall</ENAMEX> demonstrates how showmanship and
belief can reinforce and even galvanize each other, the former driving the
latter to transcendental heights. (The roof of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E.F.</ENAMEX>'s church features a neon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">arrow</ENAMEX> pointing skyward and the words "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Way Road to Heaven</ENAMEX>.") "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Ghost</ENAMEX>
power !!" might sound like something out of a used-car commercial--and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX> is as clear-eyed on the capitalism-evangelism correlation as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marxist-leaning Antony Thomas</ENAMEX> in his skeptical 1980s documentary <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thy Kingdom</ENAMEX>
Come <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">...Thy Will Be Done</ENAMEX> . But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duvall</ENAMEX> also subscribes to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
dramatic tradition (which can be discerned in works as various as The Iceman
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cometh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Music Man</ENAMEX> ) that says that any fervent belief, even
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> based on uncertain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">premises</ENAMEX> and fueled by an impure source, can give life,
the way a placebo can be an authentic remedy if it empowers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> to heal
itself. Who cares if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle E.F.</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">madman</ENAMEX> if he can make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s
spirits soar this high? And who's to say he's a villain if he doesn't violate
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parishioners</ENAMEX> have placed in him?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>
doesn't seem to have nefarious political aims; he simply wants to create a warm
and nurturing community with himself at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>. He spearheads food drives,
and disarms a racist "troublemaker" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Bob Thornton</ENAMEX>) with show-stopping
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bravura</ENAMEX>. At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX> doesn't go soft on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> never
shows a hint of remorse for the crime he committed. And when he courts the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">receptionist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miranda Richardson</ENAMEX>, never so girlishly charming) at a radio
station where he preaches, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> gives off glints both of his "wickie-wickie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>" and the concomitant jealousy that drove him to become a fugitive. He's
still one scary dude--jittery and, in some fundamental way, unformed.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle</ENAMEX> is not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duvall</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> directorial
effort. Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, he made an oddity called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Angelo My Love</ENAMEX> , a
semi-improvised account of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> coming of age among the gypsies. Watching that
movie, I found myself simultaneously attracted to and repulsed by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> in ways that left me confused (and also impressed). At times, Duvall
seemed to be sentimentalizing the gypsies; at others, he seemed to be rubbing
our noses in their ugliness and duplicity--or was that just my racism? It was
hard to know. The same kind of tension exists in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">The Apostle</ENAMEX> , but these
are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and here he seems fully in control of our responses. The
performances, down to the smallest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">congregant</ENAMEX>, could not be richer. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX> is both in our face and yet tantalizingly out of reach,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infantile</ENAMEX> and of amazing stature. We wish we could be like him, and we thank
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord Almighty</ENAMEX> that we're not.

         
      
   
