
   
   
      
         
            He Got Balls

            Basketball! It's played amid
the cornfields of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> by lanky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> with flaxen hair and 'twixt the
housing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> by the troubled shores of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coney Island</ENAMEX>, where otherwise
powerless young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> bestride the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> like colossi. Basketball!
The young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gods swivel</ENAMEX>, unwind, suspend themselves in air, the orange <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">orb</ENAMEX> that
spins from their fingers as splendid for an instant as the sun, until it
drops--swish!--through nets like filigree to the earth from whence it sprung.
Basketball! So lyrically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> you can almost hear the dissonant yearnings
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Copland</ENAMEX>. Wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a minute</TIMEX>, that is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Copland</ENAMEX>--a gay, white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX>
on the soundtrack of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee</ENAMEX> movie! The opening montage of He Got
Game leaves no doubt as to the mythopoetic intentions of its fiercely
enterprising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Basketball</ENAMEX>, not baseball, is the pastime of the nation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> inhabits. And He Got <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Game</ENAMEX> is poised to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">African-American Myth</ENAMEX>, a tale that encompasses the tragedies of the past, the
turbulence of the present, the messianic longings of the future.

            So much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ambition</ENAMEX>, dynamism, visual energy, bullshit. I confess: I come to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee</ENAMEX>
"joint" with suspicion, prepared to fight off the propaganda, to sort through
the messages and scrutinize the codes. The hope is always there, though, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> will transcend his anger and egotism and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> and make a film that
feels organic--that doesn't add up to another sterling specimen of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX>
That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man Cook</ENAMEX>!" school of movie making, in which razzle-dazzle outshines
content and the auteur upstages his own work. It's a testament to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s talent
that, hobbled as he is by a chip on his shoulder the size of a planet and
aspirations often laughably outsized, he has managed to make a film as
entertaining as He Got <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Game</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uneven</ENAMEX>, ludicrous, but--oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>!--fun to
watch. He got balls.

            The picture has one of the oldest pulp plots in the
business, last used to rousing effect in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Escape From New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>): A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict</ENAMEX> is sprung from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, promised liberty by an
untrustworthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in return for accomplishing a morally ambiguous task
that no one else can do, given a strict deadline, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ruthlessly</ENAMEX> monitored by
his ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">captors</ENAMEX>. Here the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Shuttlesworth</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denzel Washington</ENAMEX>), and
his mission is to go into the projects of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coney Island</ENAMEX>, where his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>
(played by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee Bucks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Allen</ENAMEX>) is a high-school
basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> of near divine abilities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake</ENAMEX> must convince his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to sign
a letter of intent that he'll enroll in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big State University</ENAMEX>, the state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX>, however, are formidable. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is
currently under siege by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, and their unsavory minions, all of
whom proffer money, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>, sex, and sundry other illegal inducements to sign
with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> or professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>. More of an obstacle still is the
relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, which has been poisoned by the death of
the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> under circumstances that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> keeps cunningly under wraps
until the movie's galvanic climax, in which the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> go mano a mano
on the basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.

            This is
sure-fire material, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> structures it deftly, leaving us in the dark until
the end as to why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake</ENAMEX>--a manifestly decent, soft-spoken, cagey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>,
gorgeously underplayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>--ended up in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place.
Meanwhile, He Got Game teems with ... stuff. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>'s syntax can be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legitimately</ENAMEX> labeled Brechtian. The narrative is incessantly interrupted by
cinematic placards, exhortations, lectures about staying in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> (in the form
of letters from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lonette McKee</ENAMEX>), and inserts
depicting the evils of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are photographed
iconically, as in an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eisenstein</ENAMEX> film: the spiritually crippled black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> with
his modest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afro</ENAMEX> against the weather-beaten relic of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coney Island</ENAMEX> ride, for
example. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>, who has started his own advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> and is noted for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hyperbolic Nike</ENAMEX> commercials, is always selling something (I pat myself on the
back for titling my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986 first</TIMEX> feature,
She's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gotta Have It</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birth of a Salesman</ENAMEX>"), and his work is never
sharper than when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are selling something, too--delivering some
kind of spiel as if their very existences depended on it. (Some of the spielers
here include real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX>, along with a hilarious mock-religious
turn by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Turturro</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supersensitive</ENAMEX> to criticism <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> has
built in all kinds of protections against charges of racism and misogyny. A
preening <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian-American</ENAMEX> sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Palagonia</ENAMEX>) declares that he has no
mob ties and that he resents being stereotyped, shortly before delivering a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stereotypical</ENAMEX> (and very funny, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>-esque) recitation of the luxuries
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraris, Rolexes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansions</ENAMEX>) that await <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> if he signs on the dotted line.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lala Bonilla</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosario Dawson</ENAMEX>), the amusingly named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delilah</ENAMEX> dispatched to seduce
the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, gets a monologue near the end in which she justifies her
actions on socioeconomic grounds. And, as a counterpoint to all the luscious,
bare-breasted white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> used to tempt the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> into playing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man</ENAMEX>,
there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hooker</ENAMEX> (the model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Milla Jovovich</ENAMEX>, the film's most unlikely bit of
casting, made to look like a near albino) who's exploited and knocked around by
a jittery black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pimp</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson Byrd</ENAMEX>) so sadistic that if this film had
been made by a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> he'd have been cited (most likely by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>) as a
flagrant racist outrage. As on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, the seams of the movie show.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crouch</ENAMEX> (who gleefully refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> as "the diminutive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>") has pointed
out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> resembles the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preston Sturges' Sullivan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travels</ENAMEX> ,
a lightweight who strives to make an unwieldy epic called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">O Brother, Where</ENAMEX>
Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Thou</ENAMEX>? (Actually, this joke was first made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Max Frye</ENAMEX> in his
underrated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> farce <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amos</ENAMEX> & 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX> , in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike</ENAMEX>-like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playwright</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> hit called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Yo Brother, Where</ENAMEX> 
               Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Thou</ENAMEX>? )
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>'s use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copland</ENAMEX> pieces such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln Portrait</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Rodeo</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appalachian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring</ENAMEX>," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fanfare for the Common Man</ENAMEX>" too transparently pump up the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">picture</ENAMEX>'s already pumped-up visuals, and his b-ball variation on the
religioso finale of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lars von Triers</ENAMEX>' Breaking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waves</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>) is
as daft as it was in the original.

            What transforms He Got <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Game</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s love for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sport</ENAMEX> and his intimacy with its nuances. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike</ENAMEX> knows basketball. He filmed in
and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">High</ENAMEX>, which is also the setting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darcy Frey</ENAMEX>'s
superb book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Shot: City Streets, Basketball Dreams</ENAMEX> , an equally
panoramic but more grounded portrait of the game's meaning to the denizens of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coney Island</ENAMEX> projects. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> might view the sport as a metaphor--as both a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> out and a trap for young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX>--but he never lets the metaphor
gum up the realities of the game. On the contrary, the metaphor intensifies the
action on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, which can seem kinetic to the point of spontaneous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">combustion</ENAMEX>, as pressure to perform tears <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> up and turns black man
against black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. If, on occasion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s serpentine camera seems more active
than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> he's shooting, he knows just when to speed the play up, when
to slow it down, and when to let it unfold in real time. And he gets a charming
performance from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>, who, in his acting debut, occupies his pedestal with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grace</ENAMEX> and diffidence. The "diminutive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>" never evinces more stature than
when he's looking up in awe.

         
      
   
