
   
   
      
         
            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Company of Men</ENAMEX>

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, while writing a
review of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX>'s grotesque rabble-rouser <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rocky IV</ENAMEX> , I went
back and watched the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX> to see if--to borrow the controlling
metaphor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ingmar Bergman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Serpent's Egg --</ENAMEX>"through the thin
membranes you [could] clearly discern the already perfect reptile." In other
words, was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s egotism always this monstrous? Maybe not. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX> ,
which is basically a comedy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> is treated as a lumbering sad sack. Most
striking is the camera placement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Avildsen</ENAMEX>, keeps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>
small in the frame, as dwarfed by his desolate environment as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chaplin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tramp</ENAMEX>. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sly</ENAMEX> became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX>, he seized creative control of his films
and moved the camera way up close, so that his heavy-lidded nobility and his
musculature loomed large. (In interviews, he said that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> remarked on
the puniness of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rocky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">physique</ENAMEX>, a dig that clearly goaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>
into pumping himself up, in all senses.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> has certainly had his
blockbusters over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, but he has also turned himself into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goliath</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camp</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cop</ENAMEX>
Land , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freddy Heflin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loser sheriff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garrison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>,
just across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George Washington Bridge</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>. I use the word "loser"
so casually because the film virtually brands it on his forehead. He is
discovered in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, playing a desultory game of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pinball</ENAMEX> beside <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX>
empty beer bottles. Running short of quarters, the soft, flabby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddy</ENAMEX> staggers
outside, unlocks a parking <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meter</NUMEX>, and spills the coins all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalk</ENAMEX>.
Driving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> loaded, he glances longingly across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> at the big city
where he once dreamed of being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>, and then, swerving to avoid a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deer</ENAMEX>,
plunges off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> into a tree, totaling his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and putting a huge gash on
the bridge of his nose. The hardened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> who live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garrison</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> enclave--treat him like a pet. He's there to give speeding tickets. In
his shabby <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, he listens to the blue-collar wail of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Springsteen</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX> through and through.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>, whom a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associate</ENAMEX> of his once described to
me as "the most frightened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>," had to hold a press conference to
announce that he was going to gain weight for the part of a not-so-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super hero</ENAMEX>
in a small movie. (From his vantage, I guess, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> makes small movies.)
Where normally <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> would over-project his potency, in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cop Land</ENAMEX> he
telegraphs his impotence. It isn't just the paunch. It's the bleary, hangdog
demeanor; the watery eyes; the shambling gait; the passiveness that borders on
the stereotypically feminine. He's like a white <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stepin Fetchit</ENAMEX>. And yet, as
obvious as this performance is, it's more deeply felt than anything <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>
has done since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX> --and is close, I suspect, to how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> really
sees himself. He's never more winning than when he projects loserdom.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cop</ENAMEX>
Land shares its leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s slow-wittedness, but also his likability. It
tries hard. It's formulaic, but it sticks to a classic Western formula instead
of a cartoonish blockbuster <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Noon</ENAMEX> by way of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX>,
with a touch of Peyton Place . (I could also cite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Franklin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">One</ENAMEX>
False Move and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Richardson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Border</ENAMEX> --but the list of
influences would run as long as this review.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mangold</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heavy</ENAMEX> ), labors mightily to establish a sense of place--he never
stops setting the scene. At the start, the camera glides over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> into
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> while a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX>, who turns out to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal</ENAMEX>
Affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mo Tilden</ENAMEX>) informs us that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> have
always dreamed of living outside the metropolis itself, "where the shit
couldn't touch 'em," and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garrison</ENAMEX> was such a refuge--a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> on a hill,
with a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of cops, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>, and almost no crime.

            
Of course, the hill the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> sits on is a heap
of corruption, a pile of lies as high as the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palisades</ENAMEX>. Everything emanates
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Donlan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Keitel</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-</ENAMEX>connected <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> who presides
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garrison</ENAMEX> like the old-style movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss-men</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Akim Tamiroff</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward G.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> has a problem. While driving drunk back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX>, his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nephew</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babitch</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Rapaport</ENAMEX>), gets sideswiped on the bridge
by a couple of stoned rastas. Thinking they fired on him, he blows them away.
(I thought they fired on him, too, but the point is murky--no gun is found in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>.) For some reason, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> fears that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> will spill his guts to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Affairs</ENAMEX>, so he takes radical (and, quite frankly, moronic) measures to
keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Babitch</ENAMEX> from seeing the inside of an interrogation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.

            Mangold
and his cinematographer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Alan Edwards</ENAMEX>, can't get enough of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garrison</ENAMEX>'s
terraced cliffs above the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>, and they rarely lose sight of the imposing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> skyline. It's a constant reminder to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freddy</ENAMEX> of the time when, as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teen-ager</ENAMEX>, he saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> beauty (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annabella Sciorra</ENAMEX>) from drowning when her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> went off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX>, in the process mangling one ear and leaving himself
unfit for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD</ENAMEX>. We learn all this from flashbacks and from a strange oracle
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gary "Figgs</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figgis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Liotta</ENAMEX>), who, when drunk, can't seem to stop
himself from spewing exposition. ("You saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> beauty from drowning and
made yourself deaf in one ear so that you couldn't be a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>, and then
she married some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>--you have a right to be jealous!" Or words to that
effect.)

            In the labyrinthine plot, everyone has something to hide.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathy Moriarty</ENAMEX>) is having an affair with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Berg</ENAMEX>),
who's married to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddy</ENAMEX>'s old heartthrob (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sciorra</ENAMEX>). Assorted police
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">goons</ENAMEX>--among them the dependable heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Vincent</ENAMEX> and the blue-eyed, blankly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">malevolent Robert Patrick</ENAMEX>, the lethal shape-shifter of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Terminator 2</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judgment Day</ENAMEX> --let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX> know he'd better turn his deaf ear on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chicanery</ENAMEX>. For most of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cop Land</ENAMEX> , we watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> get bullied and
stared down by everyone in the large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, while we wait for him to awaken from
his stupor and start blowing bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> away--which you know he has to do or he
would never have accepted the role. Of course, the formula dictates that all
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> must abandon him so he can march down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, wielding a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shotgun</ENAMEX>, bleeding but with the iron back in his spine, to prove to those city
cops what he's really made of. "Everybody in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>," he says, "is gonna
tell the truth."

            Since the
film moves in such a leisurely fashion, with lots of talk, there's plenty of
time to be distracted by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>. Oh, there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathy Moriarty</ENAMEX>,
married to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvey Keitel</ENAMEX>--hmmm: Weren't they in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bull</ENAMEX> together?
No, that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Pesci</ENAMEX>. Where's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Pesci</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Moriarty</ENAMEX> have any scenes with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Niro</ENAMEX>, her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bull</ENAMEX> co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Keitel</ENAMEX> have more scenes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niro</ENAMEX>? Have they acted together since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi Driver</ENAMEX> ? Liotta, he and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX>
were both in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GoodFellas</ENAMEX> --was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keitel</ENAMEX> in that? No, that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pesci</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorraine Bracco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keitel</ENAMEX>'s ex, played <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liotta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Liotta</ENAMEX> have any scenes
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX>? Wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Vincent</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bull</ENAMEX> ? And
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GoodFellas</ENAMEX> ? And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino</ENAMEX> ? Where's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Pesci</ENAMEX>?

            
All these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scorsese types</ENAMEX> are in there pitching,
doing their damnedest to legitimize the movie and its wayward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. Under a
curly black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thatch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX> coasts along, giving an offhand but confidently
weird performance. "I look at you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sheriff</ENAMEX>," he says, "and I see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who's
waiting for something to do." The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>-deliberate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">diction</ENAMEX> lets you know that he
knows the line is a cliché but that he thinks it's entertaining anyway. The
character is playing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freddy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX> is playing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>. "I
could take you blindfolded, both hands tied behind my back," he seems to say,
the heavyweight towering over the bantamweight. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>, bless him,
endures it like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.

            
               The beginning of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Babitch</ENAMEX>'s troubles (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rapaport</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">58 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

            
               "I've got a sticky
problem." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mo Tilden</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De Niro</ENAMEX>) explains the situation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff Freddy Heflin</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">51 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

         
      
   
