
   
   
      
         
            As <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Slime Goes By</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigourney Weaver</ENAMEX>, who plays
an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX>-blooded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Ripley clone in Alien Resurrection</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
installment of the gory Alien "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>," has made a career out of
putting herself into ridiculous situations and managing never to look
ridiculous. Her immersion in her roles commands respect and awe: She surges
past embarrassment, past fear, and even when she makes a misstep, she lands
catlike on her feet. That strong, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brandoesque</ENAMEX> jaw gives her a pugilistic
cast--laugh at her and she'd slug you. No one giggled at her when she communed
with apes in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gorillas in the Mist</ENAMEX> , and no one will giggle at her in this
epic oddity, even when she's writhing around in a mucousy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pit</ENAMEX> of alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viscera</ENAMEX>,
communing with the queen and its unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>--an image so strange that it goes
beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jungian</ENAMEX> vampiric phalluses and womblike hatchways of earlier
Alien films into what is possibly the collective unconscious of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extraterrestrials</ENAMEX>.

            When we
last encountered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ripley</ENAMEX>, she was doing a backward swan dive into a pit of
molten lead with a bewildered baby alien <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">erupting</ENAMEX> from her chest. That kind of
finale pretty much rules out another one with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigourney</ENAMEX>, right? Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackman</ENAMEX> once described how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poseidon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adventure producers</ENAMEX> wanted him
back for a sequel, and when he pointed out that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> had been
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">incinerated</ENAMEX> (in a pit of molten lead, coincidentally), they said he could greet
the previous film's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> as they exited the upside-down <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vessel</ENAMEX> with the
line: "Did my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> make it?" Now, thanks to the rise of cloning in the
popular imagination, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> are necessary.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alien Resurrection</ENAMEX> , we meet a set of conceited,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sadistic scientists</ENAMEX>--the kind of dangerously hubristic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prometheans</ENAMEX> who are
convinced that they can harness the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> for the good of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>. ("Once
we've tamed the ..." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">etc.</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two hundred years</TIMEX> after the events of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alien</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> , they obtain a vial of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley</ENAMEX>'s alien-infected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and grow her--and
the creature that she was carrying to term--in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX>. They lock Ripley
in a futuristic gothic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> and proceed with their hopeful experiments, while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>, their elongated black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">helmet-heads</ENAMEX> glistening with goo, regard
their would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trainers</ENAMEX> (among them <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.E. Freeman</ENAMEX> and the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Dourif</ENAMEX>)
with a mixture of rage and amusement, the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX> looks at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">punks</ENAMEX> who momentarily have the upper hand but who he knows will be a bloody
pulp in a matter of moments.

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">milieu</ENAMEX> isn't much of a stretch for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Pierre Jeunet</ENAMEX>, who
(with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Caro</ENAMEX>) made the squishy horror picture <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delicatessen</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>) and
City <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of Lost Children</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>), a surreal hybrid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Gilliam</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX>. Though brownish, the new picture is less monochromatic than the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two</TIMEX>, and the giant space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> in which it takes place is both steely
and drippy, with the techno-organic feel of the belly of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">beast</ENAMEX>. The aliens
themselves have never been animated with more virtuosity. You get to see one
swim: It whips itself forward with its tail at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a hundred miles an hour</NUMEX>.
There's also a scene in which an alien gets slowly sucked out of a hole into
space, a process that makes a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> grinder look merciful. The movie's other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wagnerian</ENAMEX> set piece features the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley</ENAMEX> clone--who has an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">8</ENAMEX>" stenciled on her
arm--coming upon a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> that contains the previous <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> attempts to bring her
back. This there-but-for-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the</NUMEX>-grace-of-God sequence almost justifies the movie's
absurd premise.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alien Resurrection</ENAMEX> is reasonably entertaining,
but it's the unwieldy product of what I call the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Romans Syndrome</ENAMEX>," based
on the experience of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who worked on the soap opera <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Days of</ENAMEX>
Our Lives . Briefly (or semibriefly), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> was married to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlena</ENAMEX>, who was
played by one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soapdom</ENAMEX>'s divas. When she decided to leave the show, her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> got killed in a plane crash, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> decamped, too,
to be replaced by another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> younger, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six inches</NUMEX> taller, and
built like the ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> that he was. Except that when the diva
rejoined the show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years later</TIMEX>--it turns out her character didn't die in
that plane crash but had amnesia ,etc.--she said, "Wouldn't it be wonderful to
work with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> again?" And they said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Er</ENAMEX>, there's another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> here
now, and he's really popular." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">diva</ENAMEX> said, "Work it out." So in wanders
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman</ENAMEX> I to announce that he has been held <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> on an island for the last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> and--wait a minute, who's this other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zounds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roman II</ENAMEX> doesn't
know either! It took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> to execute a plot--involving mad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and
personality transplants and amnesia and plastic surgery--to account for what
was, in essence, the idiotic whim of some diva.

            I digress
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Romans Syndrome</ENAMEX> out of sympathy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joss Whedon</ENAMEX>.
Because once you immolate your leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>, you have to execute some mighty
violent narrative contortions to bring her back, and by the time you've
explained what she's doing there and why, half the movie is gone. And what's
left--despite all the offal--feels inorganic. In addition to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ripley</ENAMEX> coping with
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personhood</ENAMEX>/alienhood, you have a setup out of The Poseidon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adventure</ENAMEX> , with a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to push their way through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">watery</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> to reach their little ship, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after another getting
gobbled down by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> at regular intervals.

            Aside from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weaver</ENAMEX>, there's another wild card--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winona Ryder</ENAMEX>
as an enigmatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Annalee Call</ENAMEX>, who comes on board the station
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of smugglers and an agenda of her own. It's possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX>
gets worse the harder she tries to act. Her scenes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weaver</ENAMEX> are sad: She
doesn't have the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>'s histrionic resources, plastic physique, or
energy. And she's playing a role that would likely confound the most able minds
of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weaver</ENAMEX> have
exchanges as stilted as anything in <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Plan 9</ENAMEX> From Outer
Space --surprisingly, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whedon</ENAMEX> (who wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffy</ENAMEX> the Vampire
Slayer , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toy Story</ENAMEX> , and did the uncredited rewrite of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speed</ENAMEX> )
has a pretty good ear. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> actually snarls, "I am not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with
whom to fuck.") But even with her stinko lines, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weaver</ENAMEX> has never been as
flabbergastingly gorgeous and charismatic. She's tall and lean and meteor-hard,
and you can almost believe there's really acid in her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, and that no alien
in its right mind would mess with her. Her skin has an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">unearthly</ENAMEX> glow, which
might be the work of the brilliant cinematographer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darius Khondji</ENAMEX>, of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Seven</NUMEX> ) or--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weaver</ENAMEX> being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weaver</ENAMEX>--might just be coming from within.

         
      
   
