
   
   
      
         
            Trigonometry

            Imagine a long lighted fuse
that snakes down <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">corridors</ENAMEX>, winds around corners, slithers up and down stairs,
doubles back on itself, and finally arrives at an impressive-looking explosive
device. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaboom</ENAMEX>? No. Out comes a tiny flag with a sign reading, "Bang!" So goes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian De Palma</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Snake Eyes</ENAMEX> , a thriller of serpentine excitement all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> up to that dud of a climax. The preview <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> left muttering darkly, and
no one at the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> joint next-door could say enough nasty things. But I'll bet
that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 minutes</TIMEX> earlier those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were entranced. I was. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX> is like a
single-minded physics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wizard</ENAMEX> who, with every new picture, sets out to
demonstrate a different spatial/temporal theorem. The way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX> scrawls
breathlessly on a chalkboard in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Will Hunting</ENAMEX> --that's the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">De</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palma</ENAMEX> makes a thriller, piling on angles, variables, fractions, exponents. Now
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX> needs to learn that the kind of payoff that dazzles a math <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>
doesn't always give an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that ultimate, explosive charge.

            The
movie's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX> is its premise--its mathematical "given." It's a
single, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minute</TIMEX> tracking shot that holds on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Detective</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santoro</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX>) as he bounds around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> that's the site of a
heavyweight championship fight. Sporting a loud orange rayon jacket with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> shirt, the brazenly corrupt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santoro</ENAMEX> pummels a bookie (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Guzmán</ENAMEX>) and
extorts a wad of cash, hollers encouragement to the rabbit-punching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shaw</ENAMEX>), and gives high-fives to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">righteous-dude buddy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cmdr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Dunne</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Sinise</ENAMEX>), assigned to protect the visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fabiani</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX> holds on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santoro</ENAMEX> even when the bout begins and the crowd
goes nuts at what they see (but we can't)--and even when shots ring out and
blood begins to gush from the secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>'s throat.

            All the details <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX> withholds in that first showoff
sequence he provides in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the next hour</TIMEX>: the fight, which a video replay suggests
was "thrown"; the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>'s barely heard conversation with a blond
"bystander" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla Gugino</ENAMEX>) who has glancingly caught one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX>; and
the comings and goings of a mysterious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> with red hair and lots of cleavage
and a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with a radio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earpiece</ENAMEX> who shouts at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX> that he's going
down, he's going down. The more perspectives the sleazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santoro</ENAMEX> gets, the more
he understands what actually happened "before his very eyes"--and the more
unhinged he becomes at the prospect of having to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>.

            
               Snake
Eyes takes place more or less in real time, and in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> giant megastructure:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> is attached to a hotel and casino, and outside rages a hurricane
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jezebel</ENAMEX>) that keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> indoors. This gives the movie an
astonishing concentration. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> is a hothouse maze: The tacky décor is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oppressive</ENAMEX>, the images shot a little too close, the camera angles skewed to
induce <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vertigo</ENAMEX>.

            
Here's an example of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX> works: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">villain</ENAMEX> is searching for a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gugino</ENAMEX>), who, trapped in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel-casino</ENAMEX>, has pretended to be a whore, latched onto a fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at a gaming
table, and disappeared with him into his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The villain knows she's on the
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">35 th</NUMEX> floor, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX> tracks with him down a long, tacky corridor
as he moves from door to door, listening for her voice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> cuts to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>, riding up in an elevator, talking to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> in security. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> is
screening a videotape of the fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at the gaming table and zeroing in on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">guy</ENAMEX>'s wallet, trying to read his name, so that he can call the desk and find
out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> number and tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX> so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX> can get there before the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">villain</ENAMEX> gets there. Now it's back to the villain, who stands outside another
door, listening. Hot-dog that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX> is, he cuts to an overhead shot, and his
camera begins to move, gazing down at the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the corridor and then the
inside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> he's in front of (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> is fooling around) and then the
room after that (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is sleeping) and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> after that--which holds,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">voilà</ENAMEX> , the fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. But there's another variable, another
time <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>: The fat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> expects sex, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> doesn't want to give it to him,
and he's trying to throw her out despite her protests that her life is in
danger. Now the elevator door opens and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX> arrives at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
floor--and now he and the villain are moving in opposite directions down the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">corridor</ENAMEX>, converging on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> where the increasingly frantic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is being
pushed toward certain doom ...

            Yes, it's mechanical, even
metronomical, but thrillers are built out of wheels and pulleys and ticking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clocks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX>'s machines are more intricate than anyone's since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchcock</ENAMEX>. And just when you think that he has run out of variables--that he
can't possibly introduce another element, another angle--he'll suddenly split
the screen and present you with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tumultuous frames instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. The
score, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryuichi Sakamoto</ENAMEX>, is full of post-Romantic film noir gloom, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sakamoto</ENAMEX> also introduces a more modern, free-floating anxiety, a New Age dread
that deepens the horror--that takes it out of the whodunit class and into the
"Can we ever believe what we see?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">league of Rashomon</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snake Eyes</ENAMEX> could have
been another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX> masterpiece instead of a bummer on the order of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission</ENAMEX>: Impossible (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>). But it never transcends its (glorious)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santoro</ENAMEX>'s high-tech odyssey and the movie's themes don't intersect as
they did in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blow Out</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>), and the climax doesn't unify the movie's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">visuals</ENAMEX>--the way the angled escalators in the shootout of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlito's Way</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>) were like a grand, trigonometric punch line. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koepp</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carlito's Way</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jurassic Park</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>]) gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX> what
he wants but no more--a blueprint, and not an especially witty or resourceful
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. That leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>, who in contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Koepp</ENAMEX> gives everything he has and
then some, humanizing the film with his trademark goofy exuberance. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Betrayed,</ENAMEX>
humiliated, beaten to a pulp, he limps along a snakelike corridor toward that
final confrontation with the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>--and then a deus ex machina robs
him of his <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">finest hour</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX> leaves him all bloodied up with no place to
go.

         
      
   
