
   
   
      
         
            Where on the Web Is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>?

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica's Place</ENAMEX>," the Web
site of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica S. Lewinsky</ENAMEX>" (whose <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> Online profile declared, "Oh, What
a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tangled Web We Weave</ENAMEX>"), was spotted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>. It linked
to sites like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenpeace</ENAMEX> and included declarations such as
"This is My 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> , its [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] located in the most
incredible <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> in the world." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> quickly identified the site as a hoax and
pulled it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 22</TIMEX>. "It seemed designed to deceive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> said.

            Indeed,
it already had. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 22</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>
News reported, "Web page gives insight to intern." The paper quoted lines
from the page that did not shed a lot of light on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>. "The
White 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> , This is where I used to work. ... Of course when I
am not working I am usually watching my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> ." Home page <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> came
across as banal at best, empty-headed at worst. And a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 23</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> piece noted that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica's Place"</ENAMEX> "sure
looked like the real home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>" (though it didn't say why)
before acknowledging that it "could have been a hoax. Of course, the whole
thing could be a hoax."

            The more we hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, the further removed
from reality she becomes. She's been transformed into a prototypical lovesick
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">teen</ENAMEX> (even if she's in her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20s</NUMEX>), a vulnerable ingénue, a slightly clueless
betrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and, most recently, a deranged hussy. Each "identity" is fully
developed on Web sites devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, which essentially take news
accounts and reflect upon them in a deeply silly manner.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lovesick Teen: A</ENAMEX> "photo analysis" page (part of a site called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cary's Crap</ENAMEX>)
examines shots from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> tape of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s postelection hug,
noting the "ecstasy look on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s face" as she and the president
embrace--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here Monica</ENAMEX> is obviously giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Fuck Me</ENAMEX>' stare. If
she hasn't been, she wants to start. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Notice the</ENAMEX> chick to the right with the
similar expression. She's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Presidentialy</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plump"</ENAMEX>--and her wistful
expression as he moves off through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is obviously out of her
mind with lust." A site pretending
to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s home page (this one isn't out to deceive a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>) makes her a
total <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX> teen, whose favorite TV show is "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">BEVERLY HILLS</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90210</NUMEX> (WHAT ELSE? - <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">BRANDON IS SOOOOO CUTE</ENAMEX>!!) ."

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vulnerable Ingénue</ENAMEX>: "Your [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ]
young and were taken advantage of as far as I see it. I know you will do the
right thing. I know you fear for your safety but be brave and do the right
thing," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> concerned supporter in the letters section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky Online</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fan Club</ENAMEX>.

            

               Slightly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clueless Betrayed Friend</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan club</ENAMEX>, whose support is
clearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 100</NUMEX>-percent sincere--"Don't worry about the blown job with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revlon</ENAMEX> ..."--includes a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>" section, which attacks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> in no uncertain
terms but also portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> as a dupe:

            What kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> tape
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" without them knowing it? What if this "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" then uses
these tapes to put you in the international spotlight, facing federal criminal
charges, as well as ensuring your place in the history books as the penultimate
stupid bimbo?

            Why, that is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> at
all! Better pick better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> next time, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>, especially in the big
city!

            The site
then imagines what might have become of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> hadn't tattled:

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ou</ENAMEX> would probably be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">traipsing</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> right now, enjoying many misadventures, like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">latter-day Ann Marie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlo Thomas</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966-1971</TIMEX> TV sitcom
That <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> . Why, there is even a resemblance!

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> to
the page to see what they mean.)

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fan Page</ENAMEX> has a set
of good links about the affair and a message <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, too, though on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX> visit,
it was no longer available. It will no doubt return soon.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deranged Hussy</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Messages</ENAMEX> posted to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fan Club</ENAMEX>" span
the range of opinion on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Here's one
typical posting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from Jan. 29</TIMEX>:

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> is nothing but a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bit BIMBO</ENAMEX>. She's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>, has lied her whole life and will lie to her grave.
Anyone who puts a valentine message in a news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] on her own
free will for a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has got tom [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] be a sicko stalking bimbo.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thats</ENAMEX> [ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> belong together, like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peas</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pod</ENAMEX>.

            Postings
on the scandal can be found in any number of newsgroups and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zipper Gate</ENAMEX> is one
place to go for some even cruder entries. At the "I Love
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>" site, a gentleman with a powerful crush pleads with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX> nude spread:

            Do this
nude layout for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX>. See, it's all I have. IT'S <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ALL I HAVE</ENAMEX>!!!! I have
nothing but you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, please hear my cries. You know a little about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obsession</ENAMEX>, don't you?

            
And yet, we also have everything we're supposed
to need to construct our own vision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">résumé</ENAMEX>, courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>, and photographs (some
from her high-school yearbook), which are being displayed all over television
and the Internet. None of us would want judgments formed about our character on
the basis of high-school-yearbook pictures, but it is worth noting that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">high-school Lewinsky</ENAMEX> seems fairly heavy and does not look happy. From her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">résumé</ENAMEX>, we learn that she worked in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s tie shop for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. The
document is also marked with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">résumése</ENAMEX>, some of which now takes on an
unfortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, given the scandal: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excellent</ENAMEX> interpersonal ... skills." Her
e-mail and
former work addresses have been uploaded--not to encourage harassment, of
course, but "simply ... to point out how useful the Net has become in gathering
personal information." Her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX> can be visited, as can her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX>. She has yet to suffer the fate of having school
papers, personal letters, or other artifacts put on the Web by "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>" or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foes</ENAMEX>, but don't dismiss this possibility. Meanwhile, the site that has claimed
her name for its domain, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monicalewinsky</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, says it's reserved "For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinksy</ENAMEX>
[ <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sic</ENAMEX> ] to use to convey to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TRUE Story of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Incident</ENAMEX>."

            Then
there's the pornography--not of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> herself, though someone has posted a
fairly ubiquitous fake picture of a nude <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> under the header "She had to go run her mouth." There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a dozen</NUMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> sites" that capitalize on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>' interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to entice them
toward more profitable pleasures. Search for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>," and you may find a
site that reads "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MONICA LEWINSKY NUDES FREE MONICA LEWINSKY NUDES FREE MONICA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">LEWINKSKY</ENAMEX> ..." At <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> glance, this scans as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Free Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>," but it
probably isn't meant as a political statement. (Let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> out of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX>!) A link that promises "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica Lewinsky News Updated every 14 Minutes</ENAMEX>" delivers
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SexKing</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky Profile</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX> ends up taking you to the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hard-core</ENAMEX> site, counting on the fact that you will click on the link marked
"naked photos." Oh, and if you inadvertently type ".<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>" after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
instead of ".<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gov</ENAMEX>," you'll find a very different sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>. It's not
just XXX sites that are up to this trick; see, for instance, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>,
we hereby invite you to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Auction</ENAMEX>." "Need money to pay for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>? We
guess that you will ..."

            Finally we come to the sites about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> that are too
sick or crazed to categorize. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica Lewinsky Ate My Balls</ENAMEX> boasts that it is the
"original" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica Lewinsky Ate My Balls</ENAMEX> page, a claim that presumably will be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hotly</ENAMEX> contested. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ate My Balls</ENAMEX> "joke," however, is not an original concept.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MLAMB</ENAMEX> is one of a series of sites (created by different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>) based on the
premise that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">famous person</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> has eaten balls or likes to eat them.
Generally, there are photos and captions to this effect. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahoo</ENAMEX> has helpfully
collected the series. A "photo
lab" does fun-house-mirror tricks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>' face. Another site
manipulates her mouth. It also lets you stimulate the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">penis</ENAMEX>" with your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX>, producing predictable results.

            Because you can count on a
proliferation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>-related <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> to come, you may want to
bookmark this one, which compiles <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> links ranging from news reports
to idiotic jokes.

            We can't really expect
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> sites to define the "real" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Nor would we want them to
reflect a grassroots campaign of unwavering support. There's something about
typing the name "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>" into your search engine that forbids the
raising of serious expectations. But we might have hoped for a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX>-cultural imagination, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> sites to exhibit some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>--a
"drag personality," at least, that could make light of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s situation
without slandering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> herself. If nothing else, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s a
twentysomething pitted against middle-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>, Lucianne
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. We'd quixotically hoped that she could
turn to the Web in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> and find herself becoming a hip
cultural icon. At latest search, though, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> has let her down.

         
      
   
