
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Informing Dynamics</ENAMEX>

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Informing Dynamics</ENAMEX>," click .

            We don't live near a
stream, but now we do:the water slipping down the side of the street

            would shame many a river
with a big nameinscribed on space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX>, with a history, with

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">inches</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> and more coming: a flotation medium rising in the

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">basement</ENAMEX>, alas, a mop and
bucket my squeezingremedy: and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis</ENAMEX> off at a funeral:

            put down in this much
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, one could drown;at least, get wet: but what does the body

            care that has no spirit in
it: it has alreadydrowned in a medium sleep pales before: and

            the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>, even: it was
just a bit of electricity firing off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joints</ENAMEX> and nets: off,

            it isn't there anymore:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, though, isbut it has taken on the temperature of the

            ground and sees no
difference in itself: oh,but the difference to some! a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX>'s

            worth of getting on with
life: it is just thatquick cut between getting our monographs

            published about horse
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fever</ENAMEX> and keeping the drainfree below the rainspout and putting a little

            aside for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> and--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOP</ENAMEX>--gone:I have so much trouble with that edge: the

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">day-to-day</ENAMEX> plunged into
eternity: the look back then from eternity to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX>:

            what was it all about,
what was the use, howdid we get so interested, so worried, so

            anxious: I say, meaning
cannot be criticizedby time: where does time get off: while there

            is meaning: when anything
has served its purposeit might as well be abandoned, even meaning:

            but meaning
is really good while it lasts: toobad you can't store it up anywhere for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">download</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
