
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phat Head</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX> is legendary
for possessing both a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>'s promiscuity and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX>'s wariness of
genuine commitment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> are lured into developing projects with him for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> at a time until--unable to decide whether to go ahead or not--he stops
returning their phone calls. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> does commit, his insecurities present
formidable obstacles. It's said that one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> was driven nearly to homicide
after being forced to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six hours</TIMEX> lighting each shot (and, allegedly, to
employ a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> whose sole job it was to hold a cardboard triangle next to
a light so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>'s jowls would be covered by a shadow).

            
Professional wishy-washiness has had unhappy consequences for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> himself,
most recently in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love Affair</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), the best-forgotten remake of An
Affair to Remember --a listless vanity production with the impact of
something viewed through the wrong end of a telescope. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s politics might
be those of a hipster, but his aesthetics since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shampoo</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>) have been
those of a fuddy-duddy.

            I recount <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s history in this gossipy way to suggest
why his latest movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulworth</ENAMEX> , has been praised as such a radical
departure for its star-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and why, in some ways, it is. A screwball
political satire about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>) who loses his senses and
begins to babble the truth on the stump, the film has a kamikaze comic spirit
that's spectacularly disarming, particularly coming from its hitherto
overcautious auteur--not to mention a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> owned by right-of-Attila
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>. Puffy features on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> in various (non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murdoch</ENAMEX>) magazines and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>, which was contractually obligated to make
and release <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulworth</ENAMEX> , has tried to bury the picture, thus ensuring its
status as a cause <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">célèbre</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> who'd love to stick it to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert</ENAMEX>, even if that means enriching his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Right</ENAMEX> on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>! Give it
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man</ENAMEX>! ) And while <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog and Primary Colors</ENAMEX> have
taken disrespect for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> to levels undreamed of since the
nose-thumbing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the counterculture, political satire is still a rare
enough bird in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for a sighting to be cause for joy.

            I don't
want to rain too hard on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bulworth 's parade</ENAMEX>--only drizzle a little. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> is fun, but it's also thin, repetitive, and intoxicated with its own
outrageousness, and it's as familiar in its leftist-paranoid way as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oliver</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> picture. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> doesn't spend much time setting up the premise--or making
it psychologically plausible--and the opening plays like choppy notes for what
follows: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulworth</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> up for re-election, is weary of
the mealy-mouthed speeches and fund raising. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleepless</ENAMEX> and depressed and in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">loveless</ENAMEX> marriage, he takes out a contract on his own life.

            Being aware of his imminent assassination makes Bulworth
politically reckless. Before an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Central</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, he discards his feel-good paean to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new millennium</TIMEX> and tells
his stunned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that he hasn't returned to their neighborhood since the
riots because the photo op has passed and that no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> will ever pay
attention to them because they don't give any money to campaigns. Charged up by
the rhythms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, his newfound candor, and the sight of a dishy,
dreadlocked young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halle Berry</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> embarks on a hallucinatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">odyssey</ENAMEX> that includes a stop at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Fried Chicken</ENAMEX>; a fund-raiser at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mogul</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX>, at which he lectures the appalled "big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>" on their greed
and the lousiness of their movies; and a visit to the bowels of the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>,
where he placates <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>-toting black juveniles by buying them <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> and
standing up to the white cops who stop to harass them. Along the way, he dons
hip-hop garb and employs rabidly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populist raps</ENAMEX> to say the sort of things that
... well, you just don't say if you want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> (and PACs) to give you
money to run for office. This being a satire, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX>'s campaign is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reborn</ENAMEX>--and suddenly he's not so eager to be shot.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> double talk have primed us all for
Bulworth , but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> is peddling his own less flagrant brand of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bull</ENAMEX>. He
has used this template in the past. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> is enamored with martyrdom--with
the fantasy of reclaiming his potency, seducing the unseducible, and getting
blown away at the height of his prowess by an intolerant society. Variations
can be found in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Parallax View</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bugsy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>), but the real precursor to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> is Heaven Can 
               Wait (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>), in which the soul of a
young buck enters the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of a square old white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, who wins over skeptics
and then is cruelly cut down. This time, the square old white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> becomes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Negro</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> for the homies, who stare at him in amazement and
nod their heads as if to say: "Yes, this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> gets it."
The fantasy comes within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an inch</NUMEX> of seeming pathetic, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> (who co-wrote
the script with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Pikser</ENAMEX>) is savvy enough to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> a coked-up
campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> (the brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Platt</ENAMEX>) whose jittery attempts at black
slang throw the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> soulful conversion into relief. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX> might
be white, but at heart he's supposed to be a real nigger . The movie's
satirical vision never extends to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Beatty</ENAMEX>
pounds us over and over with his one joke and with slapsticky cuts to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX>'s would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX>, until the movie arrives at a bad, pretentiously
mystical ending. What's striking, though, is how superbly he maintains the
movie's comic momentum even when he runs out of ideas. The normally tentative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">filmmaker</ENAMEX> clearly draws strength from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s go-for-broke mindset. His
camera becomes increasingly energized, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulworth</ENAMEX>'s gung-ho tastelessness
takes on an exhilarating life of its own. "Everybody's gotta fuck everybody
until we're all the same color!" he rants. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> might be making up for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reds</ENAMEX> , where, out of fear of alienating his Reagan-era <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, he kept
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Reed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> ideology under wraps.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watching Bulworth</ENAMEX> , you can see what
turns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> on about campaigning. You get a glimpse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> who taught
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hart</ENAMEX> to talk politics out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of his mouth and pick up babes out
of the other. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> was to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Richards</ENAMEX> was to rock
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stars</ENAMEX>--those who tried to imitate him ended up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OD'ing</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX>'s glee in
seducing us with language overrides the movie's shaky construction and
embarrassing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> worship. If you didn't know better--and I hope you do!--you'd
be tempted to give him your vote.

         
      
   
