
   
   
      
         
            Choose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX>' movie of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primary Colors</ENAMEX> is the most massive cinematic harpoon ever buried in the
flank of a sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Even omitting some of the best-selling
novel's more scandalous episodes (such as the future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> jumping into
bed with the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>), the picture cheerfully out-leers, out-winks, and
out-nudges the book by the notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anonymous</ENAMEX>, a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Klein</ENAMEX>, transforming
bumptious clown show and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible dummies</ENAMEX>. The film is an
outrage all right, but not in the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> intended. The
outrage is how smug and empty of insight it is, and how rhapsodic its reviews
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who ought to know better.

            The novel
may be fast, but it ain't cheap. It's actually a crackerjack piece of work, its
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> sweeping you up in the momentum of a national campaign, its prose
imparting a buzz. Then, as the sordidness and opportunism of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> become apparent, the writing turns somber and dirgelike and full of
easy moralizing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> is never more penetrating than in the book's first
scene, in which the ingenuous black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Burton</ENAMEX>, marvels at the way
in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Stanton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>,
listens intently to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of an urban literacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, grasps their hands,
recounts the experiences of his own poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, and leaves them feeling heard,
understood, and moved. That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX> ices his triumph by having sex with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> who runs the program is troublesome but almost fitting: The tryst is
another kind of conquest, another way to make his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> feel special.

            The weird thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX>'s real-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> is
that when he speaks, even when I'm pretty sure he's obfuscating, dissembling
(OK, lying ), I believe him. I believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sincerely</ENAMEX> lying. I think that he has fully justified to himself what
he's saying, and his certainty radiates out and envelops his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX>. After
the canned, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B-movie</ENAMEX> sloganeering of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> and the slapstick linguistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">pratfalls of the Hollow Man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, it was (and is) a thrill to watch a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> who not only thinks magnificently on his feet but gets a near-sexual
charge out of doing so. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has amazing stature--more than any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of my lifetime. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> at projecting mastery, he's even physically
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outsized</ENAMEX>, with a bulbous nose that's like a touch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dogpatch</ENAMEX> populism and a
voice that rasps with conviction--that risks the shredding of its cords for the
sake of moving its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. Previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administrations</ENAMEX> have featured mostly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">faceless</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s cast of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> is endlessly compelling.
Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX> should get some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Emmy</ENAMEX> for the performance she gave
on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> : Whether or not she was telling the truth, she was
quivering with pleasure at her own histrionics; that was acting , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>.
What great drama!

            It's
certainly more entertaining than anything in Primary Colors . In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s first scene, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> holds for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> on a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> telling the
sad story of his illiteracy--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> rubbing your face in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nobility</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>, barely listens, and when he
speaks, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travolta</ENAMEX> telegraphs like crazy that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX> doesn't believe a word he's
saying. He and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> give the game away in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 10 minutes</TIMEX>, so it's hard
to understand the increasing disillusionment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Lester</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Lester</ENAMEX>
is a lean and well-spoken and handsome young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, a convincing preppy. But
he's an unbelievable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>. Sprawled on his motel bed watching the end of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shane</ENAMEX> , he mutters, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Come</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">back</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shane</ENAMEX>, run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," and that's the
whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>: He's always staring into the distance, scanning the horizon
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. That he believes even for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> in the movie's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX> makes him
seem like an idiot.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travolta</ENAMEX> is one of the most likable and
instinctive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> in movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, but no one who has met him would describe
him as a "brain." Not being an intellectual is not necessarily a hindrance to
an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, of course--unless the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> is playing an intellectual and needs to
give a credible account of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> thinking. (Thinking in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is more
difficult than it looks; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brando</ENAMEX> can do it better than anyone, which is why he's
fascinating in even his laziest performances.) As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travolta</ENAMEX> furrows his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brow</ENAMEX>, but he's not thinking. He does a surprisingly skillful nightclub
impersonation, but he doesn't get this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> isn't the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> to guide him. Before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had even taken <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, animator and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cartoonist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Alan Stamaty</ENAMEX> dubbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cram-a-lot</ENAMEX>," and no
phrase has ever caught as hilariously that combination of prodigious
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wonkishness</ENAMEX> and naked aspiration (and, arguably, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> inspiration). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who hungers for minutiae, who can toss off reams of data like some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Trek</ENAMEX> techie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> and make it even more theatrically compelling.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travolta's Stanton</ENAMEX> is just a double-talker. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year-old</TIMEX> could see through
him.

            Travolta
doesn't get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s famous <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">temper tantrums</ENAMEX>, either. The one he throws is a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hissy</ENAMEX> fit that's so spurious he even loses his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> accent--he turns into a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travolta</ENAMEX> has no rapport with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma Thompson</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> begins
disastrously, throwing her own tantrum on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runway</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> plays her cards close to the vest; she might have a temper, but she
would never carry on in public in front of perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX>.) The performance
improves in its quieter passages, and at times <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> seems to manifest a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Brockian</ENAMEX> sympathy for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, who is frequently caught between her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s unchecked libido and her own fierce ambition--between a boner and a
hard place.

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Carville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Bob Thornton</ENAMEX> does his
familiar rancid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hick</ENAMEX> act. He's fun to watch, but he's not the performer
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carville</ENAMEX> is--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carville</ENAMEX>, who comes through in the documentary <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">The War Room</ENAMEX>
as a titanic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX>, a barker whose appetite for politics is mesmerizing to
the point of messianism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thornton</ENAMEX> never cuts loose, never runs away with the
movie. But who could? There are no happy accidents in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX> film--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is too slick, too in control of what he does to let real life bleed
through. There are a few great performances. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caroline Aaron</ENAMEX>'s vulgar <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucille</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaufman</ENAMEX> (modeled on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Thomases</ENAMEX>) is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astonishingly</ENAMEX> lived-in portrait, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fine</ENAMEX>, too, in lesser roles are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Guilfoyle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Shalhoub</ENAMEX>, and the comedian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Klein</ENAMEX>. As the flawed, haunted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> who steps in to run against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Hagman</ENAMEX> proves once more that he can be a preternaturally
sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>. And, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby Holden</ENAMEX>, the campaign's self-proclaimed "dust
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buster</ENAMEX>," the manic-depressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX> who accepts as her mission the
elimination of all <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Bates</ENAMEX> is a dyke tornado.

            Marvelous
as these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> are, they never transcend the limited conception of their
roles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> trashes them all--he'll trash anyone--for cheap laughs. He has a
nervous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer</ENAMEX> at campaign headquarters remove his yarmulke for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, the way you'd take off your hat for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>; it doesn't matter
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> that no <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jew</ENAMEX> would ever do something like that.

            
It's hard for me fully to express how deeply
rotten I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primary Colors</ENAMEX> is. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Adjectives</ENAMEX> like "glib," "coarse," and
"sour" don't fully do it. I found it so oppressively smug that I had to get up
and pace the aisles <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> times, and I'd have bolted if I hadn't been
duty bound to stick it out. It's hard to believe that this movie has received
the press that it has--actually, not so hard if you know the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>
has glad-handed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> in positions of power. He's positively Clintonesque
in his attentions. "Opinion-makers" have been going to screenings for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> ensured he'd be championed by the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry King</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie</ENAMEX>
Rose by casting them both in the movie.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primary Colors</ENAMEX> has
already got rave reviews, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> could conceivably respond to it, too:
They've been living with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> saga for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legitimately hungering</ENAMEX> to see it dramatized--and to be told what to think about
it all. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> is eager to tell you what to think. The least thoughtful people
always are.

         
      
   
