
   
   
      
         
            Eros Turannos

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">22</NUMEX>)
            

            To hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eros Turannos</ENAMEX>," click .

            The woman
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> writes about in this poem must choose between a disastrous love affair
and no love affair at all. She chooses the calamity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> is like that
of much <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> country music--this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheatin</ENAMEX>' song, in its way, and also a
song about small-town life, the way gossip about an extraordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can
somehow elevate both the locale and that heroic figure. Story becomes myth in
that communal whispering, an effect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> imitates with his amazing rhymes,
a kind of hyper-ballad. It's worth noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> knew small-town life
and also suffering; he was destitute until <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> by one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to a book of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robinson's</ENAMEX>, created a
government job for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>
            

            She fears
him, and will always ask          What fated her to choose him;She meets in his
engaging mask          All reasons to refuse him;But what she meets and what
she fearsAre less than are the downward yearsDrawn slowly to the foamless weirs
         Of age, were she to lose him.

            Between a
blurred sagacity          That once had power to sound him,<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And Love</ENAMEX>, that will
not let him be          <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Judas</ENAMEX> that she found him,Her pride assuages her
almost,As if it were alone the cost.He sees that he will not be lost,         
And waits and looks around him.

            A sense
of ocean and old <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees          Envelops</ENAMEX> and allures him;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tradition</ENAMEX>, touching
all he sees,          <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beguiles</ENAMEX> and reassures him;And all her doubts of what he
saysAre dimmed with what she knows of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>--Till even prejudice delays,        
 And fades, and she secures him.

            The
falling leaf inaugurates          The reign of her confusion;The pounding wave
reverberates          The dirge of her illusion;And <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, where passion lived
and died,Becomes a place where she can hide,While all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and harbor side 
        Vibrate with her seclusion.

            We tell
you, tapping on our brows,          The story as it should be,As if the story
of a house          Were told, or ever could be;We'll have no kindly veil
betweenHer visions and those we have seen,As if we guessed what hers have been,
         Or what they are or would be.

            Meanwhile
we do no harm; for they          That with a god have striven,Not hearing much
of what we say,          Take what the god has given;Though like waves breaking
it may be,Or like a changed familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>,Or like a stairway to the sea        
 Where down the blind are driven.

         
      
   
