
   
   
      
         
            Where the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk Ends</ENAMEX>

            Before I
indentured myself to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> and its stock options, I worked for a
publication called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington City Paper</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Paper</ENAMEX> is
what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> pretentiously call an "alternative <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX>" and what everyone
else calls a "rag." It's a free paper, full of listings and reviews, that can
be picked up from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> evenings, and from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gutters</ENAMEX> and trash piles on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. When I started working at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
Paper , I assumed that the only reason anyone ever took a copy was its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">listings</ENAMEX>, which were comprehensive and quirky. But after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> I realized
that I had it wrong. The listings are secondary. Washingtonians read <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
Paper because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Paper</ENAMEX> cares so intensely about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washingtonians</ENAMEX>--their local art, their local politics, their local
controversies. Like any decent local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, it views the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as the place of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s highest achievement, of clashing ideas, power struggles, great ambitions.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Paper</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> are obsessed with their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Whenever there was a
movie with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> scenes, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> invariably devoted the bulk of his
review to nit-picking about the film's bogus geography. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Paper</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> are both fiercely loyal and fierce: Every week the letters column fills
with complaints from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been mortally offended. Almost every city
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has a publication like this, a paper that is parochial in the best
possible way.

            I thought about this recently as I was surfing through
online city guides, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s latest <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next Big Thing</ENAMEX>. Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX> have a
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> for urban journalism, and it's an ambitious <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Online city guides
are meant to be category <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>, a challenge to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>, alternative
papers, city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow Pages</ENAMEX>, and even ticket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX>. Online
listings and reviews are going be more comprehensive, searchable,
personalizable, and up-to-date than those in any print publication. Their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> want you to plan your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">entire weekend</TIMEX> from your computer--read movie
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> reviews, find the closest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> and show times, book reservations,
buy tickets, and even print a map to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>
alone, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CitySearch</ENAMEX>, a
well-capitalized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Calif.</ENAMEX>, has opened sites for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> North
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, and more are on the way. Its chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, has
launched its city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twin Cities</ENAMEX>, and
has plans to expand. Yahoo! and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital City</ENAMEX> cover most major metro
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX> and alternative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> are striking deals with the Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New York Sidewalk</ENAMEX>, for example, buys listings from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> , while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CitySearch</ENAMEX> has made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> .) The print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> are also competing
with their own cyberpartners. So the industry is crowded. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> alone,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CitySearch</ENAMEX>, Total <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> Now, Yahoo!, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
Out (registration required), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paper</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H/X</ENAMEX>
are battling for online supremacy.

            (I
mentioned <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>. Pause for full disclosure. I have embarrassingly large
conflicts of interest in this story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> publishes both <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>, and pays my salary. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sidewalk and Slate</ENAMEX> are headquartered in the same
part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> campus in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redmond</ENAMEX>. I also have a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who works
for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. Oh, and I interviewed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s job at
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington Sidewalk</ENAMEX>.)

            
Give credit where it's due. The utility of the
online <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> is high. The best of the guides--<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk and CitySearch in New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>--are very useful. Their listings are extensive enough to sate even the
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jaded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manhattanite</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurants</ENAMEX> are catalogued by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, and
reviewed, competently, by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>. Essentially all movies, plays,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">concerts</ENAMEX>, exhibits, readings, performances, and sports contests in the New York
area are listed. All events get the basics (time, cost, location), most are
accompanied by a brief description, and a hefty chunk are capsule-reviewed.
Maps and directions are plentiful. The search engines are a breeze. You want to
see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force One</ENAMEX> ? A few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> clicks locate the closest theater, show
times, and a review. The most obscure events are found easily: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surfing</ENAMEX> turned up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gastronomical</ENAMEX> walking tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinatown</ENAMEX>, a place to rent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> for a lunch-hour sail, and a recitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beowulf</ENAMEX> , accompanied by
medieval harp. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidewalk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CitySearch</ENAMEX> are customizable: You tell them your
preferences--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> opera, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, action movies, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pablo Picasso</ENAMEX>--and
they'll send e-mail about events you'd like.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CitySearch</ENAMEX> aren't flawless, though. They shortchange the outer boroughs. I
queried both for kosher <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">238,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> and
many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>--and turned up only a single eatery, a kosher
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> place. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are mildly buggy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>'s maps tend to crash or
load without street names. The greatest annoyance: Neither site enables you to
buy tickets or make reservations online. But these technical glitches will be
solved. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CitySearch</ENAMEX> is about to start selling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ticketmaster</ENAMEX> tickets on its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, is engaged in a nasty legal battle with
Ticketmaster, and probably won't be able to strike a similar deal.) The
personalization software will improve. And as computers get faster and smaller,
the online guides will be as convenient as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>.

            And yet something is missing from this new city
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>--namely, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The online <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are mass-market <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>, and
they are infected with an inoffensive corporate blandness. They ignore
politics. The editorial content is limited to capsule reviews and short,
cheerleading columns about yuppiedom. The city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> are untouched by the grit
and idiosyncrasy that define urban living. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sidewalk</ENAMEX>'s movie reviews are pablum
provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinemania</ENAMEX>, for God's sake. Couldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> afford a local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reviewer</ENAMEX>?) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sidewalks of New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twin Cities</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> even
look exactly the same, stamped out by a cookie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cutter</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York CitySearch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New York Sidewalk</ENAMEX> are based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>,
but they could have been prepared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redmond</ENAMEX> for all that they feel
like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Apple</ENAMEX>.

            The online guides, in search
of the largest, richest, entertainment-hungriest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, have an image of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that is deeply depressing. Alternative and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> conceive of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as a place of controversy and passion. The online guides see it
strictly as a place of consumption. What is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>? The receptacle for your
disposable income. The only urban problem to which the online guides have the
answer is: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Where</ENAMEX> should we eat dinner?"

         
      
   
