
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Net</ENAMEX> Net

            I was jittery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.
Would he play or wouldn't he? Would he or wouldn't he?

            By "he,"
I mean, of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Kentucky</ENAMEX> basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Anderson</ENAMEX>, who
blew out a knee <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">NCAA championship</ENAMEX> tournament had started,
so I needed to know: Would <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Pitino</ENAMEX> let <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> return to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All day</TIMEX>, I combed sports Web sites for a rumor, a hint, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> leaf
to read. The more I looked, the gloomier I got. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsTicker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s rehabbed knee was stronger than his
undamaged one. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sporting News</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> had gone to practice. Then
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Network</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pitino</ENAMEX> as saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> had played better
in practice than anyone else on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. Finally, bingo! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitino</ENAMEX> announced he
wouldn't risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s pro career for the sake of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s tournament.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> frenzy might make sense if I were, say, a
compulsive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gambler</ENAMEX> who'd pawned his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX>'s engagement ring to wager against
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>. But I have just <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> riding on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> tournament pool. The only
explanations I can muster are that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) I hate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> basketball--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Pitino</ENAMEX>
is so smooth it's creepy and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) this is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> tournament, the be-all and
end-all for sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fanatics</ENAMEX>, an event in which no fine point is too fine, no
minutia too minute.

            Where does
this madness come from? I could try to justify my tournament obsession as the
natural extension of my romance with college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>. I could sing hymns to
the majesty of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Game: the monochromatic</ENAMEX>, never-say-die <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>; the band
trumpeting out the tuneful college song; the slap of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather</ENAMEX> against pine
...

            
But that would be a lie. I feel the same way
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA Finals</ENAMEX>, the pennant race, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Masters</ENAMEX>. Sports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX> hoard trivia for the same reason political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX> lock their remotes
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C-SPAN</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> obsessives salivate over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Awards</ENAMEX> pre-game
show: Power. Trivia allows the junkie to master a small (by definition trivial)
corner of the universe. We can explain the tournament, you can't.
We speak a private language--The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big Dance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTP</ENAMEX>, zone press, subregionals--and
you don't. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">junkie</ENAMEX> watches a tournament game entirely differently than the
casual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>. For the casual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, the game is art, an aesthetic delight. For the
junkie, it's science.

            All
sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junkies</ENAMEX> bore their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with stories of their astounding predictions.
To this day, I congratulate myself for picking low-seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>, out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, to win the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">NCAA</ENAMEX> title. I knew that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denny Crum</ENAMEX> was a great
tournament <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pervis Ellison</ENAMEX> could dominate, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>'s
competition was weak. What I rarely mention is that I failed to guess the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">champion</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next eight</TIMEX> tournaments. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Junkiedom</ENAMEX> does not require knowledge
so much as it requires the pretense of knowledge. To really understand
college ball, you would need to spend most of the fall and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sky</ENAMEX> conference games on satellite television and reading back issues of
Inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro Conference Basketball</ENAMEX> .

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, being an <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">NCAA-</ENAMEX>tournament devotee was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harmless</ENAMEX>. Read the sports section, watch early-round games until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 a.m.</TIMEX>,
videotape the highlights on the local news, and fill out an entry for the pool.
Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> sports section came along, adding to the load. Soon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX> arrived, and cable became a must. But now the sports Web has arrived. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> has become crack.

            I
discovered this innocently on the opening day of the tournament. I logged on to
Yahoo! to search
for scores. I found a mind-boggling array of sports Web sites. Among commercial
sites alone, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPNET SportsZone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsLine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SI Online</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sporting News</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nando</ENAMEX>.net, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
MadNET, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alleyoop</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com,</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Network</ENAMEX>, and Yahoo! itself were covering <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">March Madness</ENAMEX>. (This is not to
mention the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX>'s
excellent site and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX> pages maintained by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>, and local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>.)

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ihave</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two weeks</TIMEX> surfing the Net,
and I must report it is magnificent. Sports Web sites are one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s few
financial success stories, and deservedly so. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> tournament is chaos: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> play <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">32</TIMEX> opening-round games at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">arenas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX>. The frenzy
overwhelms traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> satisfy themselves with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10-inch</NUMEX>
stories and box scores. TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sportscasters</ENAMEX> rush through a highlight or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sports Web</ENAMEX> brings order to the anarchy. Unrestricted by space, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> run
more articles and statistics than any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and deliver more audio and
video clips than any TV show. Their online tournament <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> operate better than
any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> pool ever could, and their fantasy sports leagues outshine any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonelectronic</ENAMEX> sports game. Sports Web sites are category <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>.

            ESPNET
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsZone</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolls-Royce of the Web</ENAMEX>. (Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolls-Royce</ENAMEX>, it costs: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.95</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>. If you
don't want to pay, you can view some of the site free.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsZone</ENAMEX> does not
cover the tournament so much as carpet-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> it. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21</TIMEX>, for example, I
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">visited SportsZone</ENAMEX> to learn who won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa State</ENAMEX> round-of-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> game, which
had ended too late to make the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>. I immediately found a wire story
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UCLA</ENAMEX>'s overtime win. That led me easily to a box score, photographs, a
game summary, half-a-dozen audio clips of post-game interviews, a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10-second</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">QuickTime</ENAMEX> movie of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruins</ENAMEX> running a fast break, a comprehensive scouting
report on both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, and an online chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> were whooping
it up. And every tournament game receives this treatment. Nothing
succeeds like excess.

            Other sports sites pale next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SportsZone</ENAMEX>, but they still
demolish print and TV. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sporting News</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SportsLine</ENAMEX> (the other site that charges <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX>) mirror
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>'s format, but serve less: less multimedia, fewer columns, fewer stats.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today, and Yahoo! behave more like wire services than the full-service sites.
They post loads of newspaper articles--Yahoo! had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 50</NUMEX> for one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">second-round</ENAMEX> game--but skimp a little on photos and gizmos. Sports
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Illustrated</ENAMEX> , by far the best-written sports print <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, is more
disappointing online. It prints too little original content and relies heavily
on poorly written wire copy. (I also found it slow-loading and buggy.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports</ENAMEX>
Network probably attracts more attention than it deserves. It's slow, ugly,
and text-heavy, but it delivers the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> key morsel the big sports <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> won't:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vegas</ENAMEX> line. SportsZone, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsLine, et al</ENAMEX> practice the anti-gambling
puritanism of TV, which dumped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its oddsmakers years ago</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Network</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">posts Vegas</ENAMEX> odds, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stardust</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirage</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>, no less. It also advertises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intertops</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> online bookmaker. In the spirit of unfettered investigative
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>, I tried to place a bet on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intertops</ENAMEX>, but was completely flummoxed
by its complicated log-on.

            Still, the gambling-free
sites are entertaining enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Fantasy basketball</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, and football
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">leagues</ENAMEX> are thriving on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsLine, SportsZone</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sporting News</ENAMEX> .
At least half-a-dozen sites, including all the major ones, hosted free online
tournament pools. They were a breeze to enter--a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse clicks</ENAMEX> and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">password</ENAMEX>. I signed up for all of them. But instead of achieving power and
domination, I suffered a mammoth blow to my junkie ego. Entering Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Four</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">weekend</ENAMEX>, I rank no higher than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">12,277 th</NUMEX> place in any of them.

         
      
   
