
   
   
      
         
            Dark and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stormy Nights</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> into The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingerbread Man</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Altman</ENAMEX> thriller based on a story by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Grisham, I found myself scribbling in my notebook, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Altman</ENAMEX> is God!!"
Here, amid the seemingly aimless hubbub, the muddy narrative, the loose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">framing</ENAMEX>, and the faraway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, a sense of place--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savannah</ENAMEX>--had begun to
emerge, and also a free-floating anxiety: No one knows what's under the surface
of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>; no one knows anything . The scary side of the city
featured in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midnight in the Garden of Good</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> has never been
captured with such brusque poetry, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> seems to pull the portrait out of
his hat.

            At the
precise moment that I was declaring (really revisiting) my reverence for the
great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, the elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> sitting next to me was grumbling:

            "I can't understand a word
they're saying. Can you understand a word they're saying?""I don't know what's
going on.""Stupid movie." "What's going on?" "Do you want to go?"

            I stifled
an urge to whisper, "If you leave now, you can catch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matlock</ENAMEX>
rerun"--which would have been snotty but not completely off the point.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matlock</ENAMEX> is what they expected, and what they got was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matlock</ENAMEX> : the same sort of sub-noir story line but with the camera moved
back a clinical distance and the soundtrack rendered clangorous, disharmonic.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingerbread Man is to Matlock</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rite of Spring</ENAMEX>
is to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockettes</ENAMEX>.

            It's also, to be honest, only a fair-to-middling mystery. I
guessed the ending--not just the major revelations, but who would live and who
would die--in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first half-hour</TIMEX>, and I'm no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matlock</ENAMEX>. But the movie is still a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">delight</ENAMEX>, a fascinatingly strange and chaotic ballet set to familiar noir
motifs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> had me hooked from the credits, in which the camera cruises high
above an eerie topography--both parched and veined with swamps--while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Isham</ENAMEX>, serves up off-the-beat thumps and hollow brass gongs, and
fragments of cell-phone conversations remain just on the far side of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">audibility</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> makes you work to pick up dialogue, to follow the threads,
to figure out--always after the fact--just what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s motivations were. His
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">framing</ENAMEX> is the least insistent of any major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, which is especially
radical in a genre where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> are accustomed to having their gaze
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> seem caught on the fly; they give performances that don't
seem like performances, and are the richer for it.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branagh</ENAMEX> has never been finer, and that's saying something. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Magruder</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savannah</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> famed for keeping scum bags out of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, he's a
strutting cock, a chain-smoking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hothead</ENAMEX> who thinks with his pecker. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> stays remote and self-involved and a bit of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fool</ENAMEX>, and because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branagh</ENAMEX> never asks for sympathy, I found myself giving him plenty, much as I've
given my sympathy to another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> peckerhead with spotty morals who's been
in the news of late. Anyway, it's hard to tsk-tsk the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> when his chief
motivation is bedding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Embeth Davidtz</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mallory Doss</ENAMEX>), a dark-eyed,
neurasthenic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enigma</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>'s most willowy gams. Seemingly terrorized by
her hooting-mad, derelict <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Duvall</ENAMEX>, in a hilarious cameo), Doss
doffs her duds at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> opportunity and promptly has the hapless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attorney</ENAMEX>
on a very tight retainer. The brilliant cinematographer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Changwei Gu</ENAMEX>,
shoots her nude through a doorway of hanging beads, and in close-up through a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fogged</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>-drizzled windshield; he keeps her simultaneously naked and veiled,
and the effect is both alluring and unnerving.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actors</ENAMEX> are reborn in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> movies. That's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daryl Hannah</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branagh</ENAMEX>'s associate, sporting dark hair, thick glasses, and a
sensibly reticent demeanor. In one stroke, this underrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> takes
herself out of the blond-airhead class. As a dissolute, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>-hearty private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Downey Jr.</ENAMEX> seizes his drug-addled image--and dances with
it. He's wonderful and he's worrisome. A lot of big-deal movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> could walk
into an open manhole and our lives would not be appreciably poorer. But
whatever must be done to keep this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> alive and working--regularly scheduled
rehabs, full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minders</ENAMEX>, a religious conversion--should be done, and done
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploits Downey</ENAMEX>'s image like the cold SOB he probably is. There's something
arrogant about this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s refusal to pander--but it's a splendid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">arrogance</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> film is like a box of chocolates: You never know what
you're gonna get--nougat or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">arsenic</ENAMEX>. So you stay braced, alert. Unlike most
contemporary cinema, you don't leave an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> movie feeling dumber than when
you went in.

            Where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> keeps you at a distance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-born
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonso Cuar처n</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Little Princess</ENAMEX> ) pulls you deep inside his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' heads. Already, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuar처n</ENAMEX> is one of the most accomplished subjective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> alive. Through his camera, the external world becomes transfigured
by emotion, so that everything--even what might not be literally true--seems
real . What better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> to film a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> novel? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuar처n</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
Expectations , which has been updated to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf Coast Florida</ENAMEX> and the New York
art world of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX> and given a rock 'n' roll backbeat, is fluid and lyrical
and thoroughly transporting. I've read the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> original over and over and
seen all the previous adaptations, yet I didn't for an instant yearn for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>--at least, not until the movie had ended, when I
was scratching my head over why it finally seemed so un-Dickensianly
miniature.

            The good
stuff <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> is no longer <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pip</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX>, who is frolicking in the waves
among the gulls when a shackled and bloodied escaped killer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX>)
erupts from the water and forces him to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and drink and a tool for
cutting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX> returns, the scene has <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an eye-popping</NUMEX> storybook
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terror</ENAMEX>, with its cocked frames, its sharp reeds standing out from the deep
black night sky, and with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Niro</ENAMEX> giving the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that patented
sour-stomach-bogeyman grimace.

            
After the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict overture</ENAMEX>, we learn that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX>--who has a gift for drawing and painting--lives with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Dickens</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Cooper</ENAMEX>) in a ramshackle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">gulf</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> catches <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX> gets laid by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>--and splits. What
happens then is an enchanting blend of old and new, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX> is summoned to the
manse of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Dinsmoor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne Bancroft</ENAMEX>), a filthy-rich ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">socialite</ENAMEX> driven mad
by her abandonment, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades earlier</TIMEX>, by a wayward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiance</ENAMEX>. But it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dinsmoor</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">niece</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estella</ENAMEX>, who becomes the focus of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX>'s fantasy life--and art.

            The
little blonde is pretty but no enchantress--she's too glum and snooty. Growing
up to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX> makes her more bewitching but no less blank. Paltrow,
as ever, is inhumanly gorgeous, like some <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Close Encounters of the Third</ENAMEX>
Kind <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>, with that elongated neck and those stringy limbs, that big
face with its faintly mocking beatitude. I can't decide if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">actress</ENAMEX>, since she's able to get by so easily without doing all that much.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paltrow</ENAMEX> certainly doesn't appear to have suffered for her art: Unlike other
screen beauties--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Pfeiffer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Lange</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Stowe</ENAMEX>--she doesn't
seem to have any interesting neuroses to ply. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Expectations</ENAMEX> , she
never makes the leap from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">erotic</ENAMEX> object to flesh-and-blood human, and that's
not just the fault of the script and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. We're told of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Estella</ENAMEX>'s inner
struggle--of the tug of war between the punishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cock-tease</ENAMEX> that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> has
engineered her to be and her inherent decency--but the conflict isn't palpable
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paltrow</ENAMEX>'s paltry performance.

            Nor does the grown-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Hawke</ENAMEX>) develop much
stature. When an anonymous benefactor provides him with the means to travel to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and show his paintings at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SoHo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>, he goes somewhat mulishly.
He never becomes absorbed into the art world and its black-clad poseurs, always
remaining a glassy-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX>'s awkwardness keeps him inoffensive, but
it thoroughly obviates the dramatic arc that's the whole point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>'
novel: If success doesn't change <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX> for the worse, then his rejection of the
high life doesn't entail the same kind of sacrifices--or come as a consequence
of some harrowing epiphany. And so the movie, after a miniclimax or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, just
comes to an end, suddenly smaller than the sum of its parts.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
Expectations is magical anyway--just this side of surreal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finn</ENAMEX> tells us
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dinsmoor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> "smelled like dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat piss</ENAMEX>," and I mean no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disrespect</ENAMEX> when I say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bancroft</ENAMEX>'s performance evokes those same aromas.
Those dreading a standard-issue, musty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss Havisham</ENAMEX> will be delighted by this
flamboyantly posturing, pantsuit-clad crone with her face <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> and
"chica-boom" slang. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bancroft</ENAMEX> is so spectacularly abrasive that it's scandalous
that she doesn't get the incendiary comeuppance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>' novel--that
objective-correlative finale in which the seething, dried-out harridan
spontaneously combusts.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> hoping for spontaneous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">combustion</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> debut of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Chow Yun-Fat</ENAMEX> might want to turn
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>. On the evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Replacement</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Killers</ENAMEX> , they seem bent on turning the most galvanic figure of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
action <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> into a pallid family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>--domesticating him in all senses. Chow,
for those who haven't caught his act in any number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Woo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ringo Lam</ENAMEX>
shoot-'em-ups, is one of those poker-faced, can't-catch-me, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">artillery</ENAMEX>-wielding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supermarksmen</ENAMEX> who can blow away <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> without removing his sunglasses or
the toothpick from his mouth. He strikes poses reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve McQueen</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX>, but his tiny smile lets you know he's having a blast, and he
seems more human than all his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> action models put together.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Replacement</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Killers</ENAMEX> , he's a decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX>, devoted to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, forced by
an underworld <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingpin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth Tsang</ENAMEX>) to travel to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to
assassinate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The saintly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX> draws the line at shooting a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boy</ENAMEX>, however, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingpin</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J체rgen Prochnow</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> with
scarred-in-hell faces, comes after him with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uzis</ENAMEX>, rocket-launchers, and so on.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antoine Fuqua</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Coolio</ENAMEX> music videos, does a passable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">slow-motion Woo</ENAMEX> imitation (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woo</ENAMEX> is one of the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>), but the plot
and dialogue are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brand X</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chow</ENAMEX>--by turns courtly, worried, and earnest--has
nothing of the rock 'n' roll bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that put him on the map. He's likable, but
he only comes alive with a gun in each hand, spinning round and round, firing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front</ENAMEX> and back, the tails of his jacket flapping.

            The movie's chief pleasure
is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mira Sorvino</ENAMEX> as a wise-ass passport <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forger</ENAMEX> who can detonate an insult with
throaty, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bacall</ENAMEX>-like precision and then leap into gun battles with
hell-for-leather abandon. Her part makes no sense, but watching those long
limbs flying through the air, I never felt like complaining. Davidtz, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paltrow</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sorvino</ENAMEX>--it's a banner month for leg <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
