
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vine</ENAMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24</TIMEX>)
            

            To hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX> read
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Vine</ENAMEX>," click .

            The term "phallocentric"
finds <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of its more ludicrously explicit instances in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Herrick</ENAMEX>'s funny
little poem about a wet dream. In contrast to contemporary writing about sex,
however, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrick</ENAMEX> does not really put the male
organ--or any organ--at the center of his poem; for him, imagination--both
erotic imagination and literary imagination--is central. He smiles a little
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mockingly</ENAMEX>, but affectionately, at his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. The helplessness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucia</ENAMEX> in
this fantasy, and the idea of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bacchus</ENAMEX> ravisht by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>," may make us uneasy
on feminist grounds; but the corrective reality of the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX>--the physical
fact of the helpless erection--corrects and undermines the imagination's unreal
fantasy of domination. The reality sunnily undermines the preposterous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">fantasy</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrick</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poem</ENAMEX> is a loose translation of a piece by the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anacreon</ENAMEX>. The
quality of civilization--and civilization accepting that it is made of and by
the human body, laughing at that body fondly, putting it in its place--is part
of what makes the poem interesting and appealing.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>
            

            I dream'd
this mortal part of mineWas Metamorphoz'd to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Vine</ENAMEX>;Which crawling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and
every wayEnthralled my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dainty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucia</ENAMEX> .Me thought, her long small legs
& thighsI with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tendrils</ENAMEX> did surprize;<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her Belly, Buttocks</ENAMEX>, and her
WasteBy my soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Nerv</ENAMEX>'lits were embrac'd :About her head I writhing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hung</ENAMEX>,And with rich clusters (hid amongThe leaves) her temples I behung:So that
my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucia</ENAMEX> seem'd to meYoung <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bacchus</ENAMEX> ravisht by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.My curles
about her neck did craule,And armes and hands they did enthrall;So that she
could not freely stir,(All parts there made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>.)But when I crept with
leaves to hideThose parts, which maids keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unespy'd</ENAMEX>,Such fleeting pleasures
there I took,That with the fancie I awook;And found (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ah me</ENAMEX>!) this flesh of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mineMore</ENAMEX> like a Stock , than like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Vine</ENAMEX> .

         
      
   
