
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brave Sparrow</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Collier

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave Sparrow</ENAMEX>," click .

            whose <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is in the
strawand bailing twine threadedin the slots of a roof vent

            who <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> a tiny
ledgeagainst the starlingsthat cruise the neighborhood

            whose heart is smallerthan
a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart</ENAMEX> should be,whose feathers stiffen

            like an arrow fret to
quickenthe hydraulics of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wings</ENAMEX>,stay there on the metal

            ledge, widen your
alarmingbeak, but do not flee as others haveto the black walnut vaulting

            overhead. Do not move
outsidethe world you've madefrom bailing twine and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX>.

            The isolated starling
fearsthe crows, the crows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> upto rout a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX>

            is cold. And <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cold</ENAMEX> is whata
larger heart maintains.The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">owl</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk and dawn</TIMEX>,

            far off, unseen, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">audible</ENAMEX>,repeats <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its syncopated</TIMEX> intervals,a song that's not a cry

            but a whisper rising from
concentricrings of water spreading out acrossthe surface of a catchment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pond</ENAMEX>.

            It asks, "Who are you?
Whoare you?" but no one knows.Stay where you are, nervous, jittery.

            Move your small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> a
hundredways, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> times, keeppaying attention to the terrifying

            world. And if you see the
Robinsin their dirty orange vestspatrolling the yard like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thugs</ENAMEX>,

            forget about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">worm</ENAMEX>.
Starveyourself, or from the air inhalethe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> you may need, digest

            the dust. And what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promiscuouscat</ENAMEX> and jaybirds do, let themdo it, let them dart and snipe,

            let them sound like
others.They sleep when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">owl</ENAMEX> sendsout its encircling question.

            Stay where
you are, you lit fuse,you dull spark of saltpeter and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
