
   
   
      
         
            Getting <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Here to</ENAMEX> There

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Hollander</ENAMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Getting From Here to</ENAMEX> There," click .

            After the issues raised
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> by the dawnHad been considered for a while and (darnIt!) lost their
appeal, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> of the darkStabbed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> as if with a dirkThe
disappearance of the sun's red diskIn a sea of golden dust brought us to
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">dusk</ENAMEX>

            An unseen term, after the
after-birth,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emerges</ENAMEX>: We're delivered of our dearth,As when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you rose from
bed, warm hearth,Promising kettle, desire's best of health:In the gray distance
over a bare heathYou discerned, striding toward you, someone's death.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> hears such stories
with one's eyes unwet:She woke up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TetOffensive</ENAMEX> had
left her widowed with a totWho broke her heart as if it were a toy.Luck having
given her one so-so try,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wrung</ENAMEX> out her life and left her bones to dry.

            How many other questions
hide in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">how?</ENAMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Writers</ENAMEX> should make a deep, unwitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vowNever</ENAMEX> to think about
such questions. (Wow!I wish I could!) Rather than try to wooAnswers into the
mind's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, dream of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who,Where</ENAMEX>, What they were wearing then, and Why.

            She took him to her place
at half-past oneHer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom windows</ENAMEX> bordered by caca <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">d'oie Chintz</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">draperies</ENAMEX>--not nice--but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lust</ENAMEX> says fieTo nice, for which it does not give a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fig</ENAMEX>.He'd gone there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, just for a quick fixAnd didn't get back home till
after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>.

            Wisdom's long weary
journey from the eastCeased when it halted once to take its easeIn some oasis
with a book, a vaseOf <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX>, love in a valeOf silken-covered
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sand</ENAMEX>, no weathervaneClattering, ostentatious, giving ventTo windy thoughts, yet
knowing where it wentThe overgoing of the sad, late west.

            He
misdirected us, and so we came By a long route, which took us through a
caveFilled with the lapping of a distant wave.Our confidence already on the
waneWe wandered, wondering, ever more in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">wantOf</ENAMEX> knowing where the true way
really went.

         
      
   
