
   
   
      
         
            Cheer

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>
Plumly

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 10</TIMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read this
poem, click .

            Like the waxwings in the
juniper,<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> at a time, divided, paired,passing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">berries</ENAMEX> back and forth,
and bynightfall, wobbling, piping, wounded with joy.

            Or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> of redwings
grazing whatfalls--blossom and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX>, nutmeat and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX>--made light in the head
and cut by the light,swept from the ground, carried downwind, taken ...

            It's called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>-rowing,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>-burdened armsunbending, yielding, striking a balance,walking the white
invisible line drawnjust ahead in the air, first sign the slur,

            the liquid notes too
liquid, the heart in the mouth melodious, too close, which startsthe chanting,
the crooning, the long lyricsilences, the song of our undoing.

            It's called side-step,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>-forward, raised-crown, flap-and-glide-flight aggression, though courtship
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isthe</ENAMEX> object, affection the compulsion,love the overspill--the body
nodding,

            still standing, ready to
fly straight out ofitself--or it's bill-tilt, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>-flash, topple-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wing-droop</ENAMEX>, bowing, tail-flick and drift;back-ruffle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>-spread, quiver and
soar.

            Someone is troubled,
someone is trying,in earnest, to explain; to speak without swallowing the
tongue; to find the perfectword among so few or the too many--

            to sing like the thrush
from the deepest partof the understory, territorial,carnal,
thorn-at-the-throat, or flutelikein order to make one sobering sound.

            Sound of the breath blown
over the bottle,sound of the reveler <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX>, light of the sun a warbler
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yellow</ENAMEX>, the sun insong-flight, lopsided-pose. Be of good cheer,

            my father
says, lifting his glass to greet a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> in which he's awake to bewith the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>: or up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> in the sleepof the world, alive again, singing.

         
      
   
