
   
   
      
         
            My <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Panel Discussion With Andre</ENAMEX>

            Who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Shawn</ENAMEX>,
exactly? He's been around for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, yet it's still hard to know. In arty
circles, he's famous as the highbrow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exhibitionist</ENAMEX> who wrote and starred in
My Dinner With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre</ENAMEX> , but there's more to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shawn</ENAMEX> than grandiose nerd
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">angst</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Millions</NUMEX> of small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> could pick him out in a
lineup. They'd know him as the dotty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character actor</ENAMEX> from mass-appeal films
like The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Princess Bride and Clueless</ENAMEX> --a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who, unlike the
earnest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX>, appears to have stopped taking anything in life
seriously, least of all himself. On the contrary, he hams up his resemblance to
a clown and wheezes for laughs (and, presumably, a paycheck).

            Shawn
doesn't appear in this film based on his latest play, but his schizoid spirit
haunts it all the same. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Designated Mourner</ENAMEX> is one of those sobering
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allegories</ENAMEX> set in the not-so-distant future in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> not unlike our own.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> deliver lots of brooding speeches, and the plot is a downer. On the
other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX>, in his first-ever film appearance and
with a sneering comic timing that has somehow improved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 30-odd</TIMEX> years
since he stopped performing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine May</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>, a shrewd, middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pragmatist</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, in college, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> impulsively married smart but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prissy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miranda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>), unaware that by doing so, he was entering a stifling ivory <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tower</ENAMEX>.
At the time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David de Keyser</ENAMEX>), was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>. He was a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> but also a jerk; he surrounded
himself with suck-ups and expected his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to wait on him hand and foot.
For a while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack admired Howard</ENAMEX>'s strong convictions and his ability,
apparently rare in this bleak hypothetical future, to understand the poetry of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Donne</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> admitted to himself that he didn't give a damn
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> art or poetry, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> got on his nerves, and that anyway he'd fallen
out of love with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX>. Relieved, he left her and her clique behind.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hare</ENAMEX> has preserved the no-frills setup of the stage production he oversaw
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>. (It makes sense that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> production was more successful than
the American one, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> in the
film are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX>. Since when in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> have we really obsessed over the fate
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>?) The play unfolds in monologues, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> making a witty
case for his desertion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> speaking, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX>, then back to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>, and so on; the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them sit at a long table and talk into the
camera, occasionally pouring themselves glasses of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelists</ENAMEX> at a
conference do. The drama comes from the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Shawn</ENAMEX> craftily shifts your sympathy
back and forth among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. Just when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> has you convinced that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> is
a pretentious albatross (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX>'s very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> clucking-tongue routine
helps here), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX>'s stock rises as she stoically describes how the intolerant
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had begun to crack down on her and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. Then, slowly, it
becomes clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is going to do worse than harass the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX>. And you realize--or you're supposed to realize--that however
arrogant and annoying you find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX>, some bottom-line human decency
will be violated if they are harmed.

            
The writing is ostentatiously literary, and I
expect that although a hard-core <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> will praise The Designated
Mourner for condemning the vulgarian times we live in, a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> will
think it's just more intolerable hooey from that highbrow exhibitionist. It's
actually better than hooey, but it's also a hopelessly conflicted piece of
work. The whole conception of "the intellectual life" feels dated: The film is
set in the future, but its grasp of male-female relations harks back to the
1950s, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> starts off as a virgin, then becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servant</ENAMEX> to be
traded back and forth by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Later, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> casts off the brainy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifestyle</ENAMEX>, he becomes a porn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawnian</ENAMEX> scheme of things, being or
not being an intellectual would appear to be an issue only for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, as if the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> thing that kept them from humping everything like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">craven dogs</ENAMEX> was a
fondness for sonnets. Then there's the problem of what's killing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> off. They are themselves partly to blame, because they're such
insular snobs. But the big villain is a power-mad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> whose only agenda
seems to be hunting down and killing smart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawn</ENAMEX> has been vocal about
his belief that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> should be more political, but this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of
philistine meanies seems more like a cheap device designed to give his play
some tension. All he's really telling us is: Beware of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with bad
taste.

            Besides
being anachronisms, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> are underwritten and deliberately
unattractive. It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> who hogs all the energy, as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX> the highbrow
sketched out a play and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX> the clown took over the writing. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>, who
specializes in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>-proof irony, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clown</ENAMEX>'s ideal front <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. With his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flushed</ENAMEX> and blotchy skin, his narrow feminine nose, his gap-toothed grin, and
his eyebrows that rise to meet each other like sides of a triangle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>
looks like a scary blend of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Hefner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred E. Neumann</ENAMEX>. He's charismatic
and monstrous. In what must be one of the greatest nasal performances of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, he rasps and chuckles and seduces us into thinking that he's a detached
but basically trustworthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>--our friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>. Then out of the blue he
calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> a "stupid bitch," and we realize he's missing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>.

            And yet, before he turns completely sour, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> makes a
pretty unbeatable case for leaving the cloister. Once he gets away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> and their over-serious, isolated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, he discovers a kind of
peace. He realizes how noisy and restless his mind has always been, "an endless
tinkling of reportage and commentary." He sees how he's always trying to
squeeze everything into concepts--this is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beautiful</ENAMEX>, that isn't--instead of
taking in life as it is. He experiences silence for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, and finds
out that it's all right. Sounds a little like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddhism</ENAMEX>. But still, the segment
of the movie in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> begins testing what it would be like to live in the
present is funny and original. Up to this point, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> has been watching
with the spaced-out, slightly bored respect one feels when confronted by a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">medieval Flemish</ENAMEX> altar piece. But when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> starts making fun of all the
irrelevant thoughts that clog his brain--"I like poetry. I like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rembrandt</ENAMEX> ...
murmur, murmur, murmur, murmur"--we wake up, recognizing the sound of our own
inner babble.

            For a moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawn</ENAMEX> climbs
off his high <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, and the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">breathes</ENAMEX>. Then the moment passes, and it
becomes clear that all he wants to do is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wag</ENAMEX> his finger at the know-nothings.
The last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> die off, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> heads directly for the gutter. Toward
the end, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawn</ENAMEX> has him place a volume of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Donne</ENAMEX> in the bathtub and pee and
shit on it. We're supposed to mourn, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX>, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, and
even for poor, harmless <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Donne</ENAMEX>. But it's tempting to say "good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">riddance</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX>) on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">highbrow</ENAMEX> vs. lowbrow (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

            
               "One of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX>'s problems":
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miranda Richardson</ENAMEX>) (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">39 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

         
      
   
