
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moral Characters</ENAMEX>

            This is the premise of
Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> : <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have a way-cool vacation in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. They screw a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> babes in hammocks and smoke a lot of hash.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of them return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, leaving behind their idealistic
acquaintance, who plans to continue on to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Borneo</ENAMEX> and save orangutans from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poachers</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who went home are informed of what happened
after they boarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> discovered their leftover hashish
(purchased for a ridiculously low sum in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dollars and tossed into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">garbage</ENAMEX> as they were leaving) and imprisoned the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yank</ENAMEX>. The quantity
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> dictated that he be tried as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>; the punishment for dealing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> is death. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> didn't mention his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> until his legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">appeals</ENAMEX> were exhausted. Now, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> have a choice: Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Penang</ENAMEX> and serve
at least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> under barbaric conditions, or let a good and decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hanged</ENAMEX>. If only one of them returns, the sentence jumps to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>.

            Movies
that revolve around moral choices often have an aura of sanctimoniousness built
into them: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> is presented with the issue in the starkest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> and waits for the blinkered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> to "do the right thing." The
approach is certainly dramatic, but it can also be too comfy, allowing you to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pat</ENAMEX> yourself on the back for being nobler than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you're observing.
That's the downside of Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> , which hinges on whether a
noncommittal ne'er-do-well swain (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Vaughn</ENAMEX>) "has it in him" to
submit to an imprisonment that will be at best harrowing and at worst fatal. If
he doesn't have it in him, there's no drama. If he does, there's no drama,
either. So he sort of doesn't but maybe sort of does, and the picture hinges on
whether he'll come to his (moral) senses before his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> gets the chop.
Meanwhile, the condemned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anne Heche</ENAMEX>) pleads; the prisoner
himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Joaquin Phoenix</ENAMEX>), shivers half-naked in his filthy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarters</TIMEX>;
and you munch on your popcorn and say, "I'd be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>. I would."

            Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> doesn't boast many surprises. It's
straight-on, morally uncomplicated. Emotionally, though, it's dense and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">twisty</ENAMEX>--and smashingly potent. Its fleetness comes from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joseph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben</ENAMEX>, who once made crackerjack, BS-free thrillers such as Dreamscape
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Stepfather</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">True Believer</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>). He lost
his way in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX> with flagrantly commercial junk such as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sleeping With</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enemy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Money Train</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>); and so did his True
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Believer screenwriter</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley</ENAMEX>
Strick, who made his fortune and lost his good name with the abominable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape</ENAMEX>
Fear remake (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Saint</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>). With
Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> , both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have shed their commercial ornamentation
and gone back to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> roots, aiming for stripped-down emotional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trajectories</ENAMEX> and back-against-the-wall dilemmas. The upshot might be melodrama,
but it's melodrama with heart, bones, sinews, and tear ducts.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaughn</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swingers</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>]) is the flavor of the moment in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>--just saying
his name ("I got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Vaughn</ENAMEX>!") makes you feel like a hipster. At first,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaughn</ENAMEX> does the sort of noncommittal wise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> stud stuff you can see on any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prime</ENAMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX>, but the performance deepens and becomes extraordinary. He's
tall, and he uses his muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and good looks to show how his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff</ENAMEX>, keeps the world at bay; he's so handsome that he doesn't have to
communicate with anyone--even with us. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff</ENAMEX> has no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaughn</ENAMEX> gives
him a roving mind that seems to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> around its own hollow core with
increasing--and compelling--desperation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaughn</ENAMEX> is so good that by the end of
the film his every gesture and step seems weighted, as if he has put on a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> pounds. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy-on-the-spot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Conrad</ENAMEX>), is more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">superficially</ENAMEX> responsible and more inwardly aquiver. It's a thankless part, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>'s paralysis palpable, and you don't end up hating him. As his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fiancee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vera Farmiga</ENAMEX> is seen only briefly but makes a searing impression:
She's fierce and legalistic, and she fixates on the bottom-line questions in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> that frees her from looking at the moral ones.

            
It's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heche</ENAMEX> who does that--and who gives
Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> its soul. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth Eastern</ENAMEX>, is clearly more
than a hired gun: She seems to be pleading as much for her own life as for her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>'s. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waifish</ENAMEX> and vulnerable, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heche</ENAMEX> doesn't have an extra <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">ounce</NUMEX> of flab on
her, and you can read how high the stakes are in her taut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and hungrily
searching eyes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heche</ENAMEX> gives herself so directly to her material that I think
she could animate anything. She was astonishingly intense as the backwoods
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> of a suicidal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in the otherwise mediocre thriller <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">I Know What You</ENAMEX>
Did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>), and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carole Lombardish</ENAMEX> timing was a spark plug
for the tired <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Six Days, Seven Nights</ENAMEX> . She is the best thing to happen to
movies since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debra Winger</ENAMEX>; she might even be as good as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winger</ENAMEX>--which is as
good as movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actresses</ENAMEX> get.

            The movie
wastes no time in venting its outrage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysian</ENAMEX> system of justice that
forces these absurd choices on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strick</ENAMEX> (who rewrote
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> script by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Robinson</ENAMEX>, itself based on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">film</ENAMEX> called
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Force Majeure</ENAMEX> ) remind us of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> who was caned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> for
writing graffiti and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> who was hanged in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> for drug
dealing. The system is presented as a given and its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s intransigence
as something that no amount of diplomacy will soften. The real outrage is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> at a big-deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jada Pinkett Smith</ENAMEX>) who dogs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth</ENAMEX>, insisting
that the way to free <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> is to take her campaign to the media--a move <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
fears will fix the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Malaysians</ENAMEX>' resolve to keep from losing face. It's a sad
reflection on the times that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> of a lunatic system look like capricious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gods</ENAMEX>, whereas righteous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are parasites from hell.

            Let me apologize to fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooklynite Darren Aronofsky</ENAMEX> and
to 
                  Slate
                diarist of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Gullette</ENAMEX> for not seeing
Pi until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>. If you haven't seen it either, hie thee hence.
This is very much a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> feature, with all the hyperbolic, sometimes
indiscriminate cinematic energy of a student film. But it's also sensational, a
febrile meditation on the mathematics of existence. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gullette</ENAMEX>) is a
scurvy genius obsessed with finding a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">216</NUMEX> digit number that's somehow at the
root of all life. Tortured by headaches and nosebleeds, he lives a life of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fractions</ENAMEX> and spinning tangents, and the metaphors are right there in the
filmmaking, captured in the furious montage and in flurries of talismanic
signs--the swirls of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk dissolving</ENAMEX> in a coffee cup, the smoke spiraling off a
cigarette. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pi</ENAMEX> is in genuine black-and-white--all the grays have been
cooked out of the images. With its echoes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jorge Luis Borges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>
Kubrick, even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Henenlotter</ENAMEX>'s great splatter flick Brain Damage
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>), the whole movie is so hyperalert that it seems pitched on the verge of
a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>. I'm glad I'm not as smart as its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, because it looks really
painful.

         
      
   
