
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hush</ENAMEX>, Hush, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet City</ENAMEX>

            
               Stop 
               reading .
Put this review on hold until after you've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Confidential</ENAMEX> . No,
wait. Stick around until the end of this paragraph. It's not that I'm planning
to give away plot twists--as in, "She has a penis!" It's simply that I don't
want to orient you. I want you to see the film as I did, with no expectations
and no idea who's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, who's the villain, or even what's at stake. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Confidential is that rare mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> thriller that refuses to telegraph
its outcome in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 15 minutes</TIMEX> or, for much of its running time, to tell
you how to feel about its protagonists. So log off, see the movie, and come
back.

            Are you
back? My hunch is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curtis Hanson</ENAMEX>, once a craftily offbeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>-director
who found the beat in a big way and made those thumpingly predictable
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">blockbusters The Hand That Rocks the</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cradle</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>) and The
River <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wild</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), consciously set out to liberate himself from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hackery</ENAMEX>. He discovered the perfect project in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Ellroy</ENAMEX>'s punchy,
labyrinthine crime novel, one of the few from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last decade</TIMEX> that doesn't feel
as if it was written expressly to be filmed. The story isn't entirely fresh.
It's the old load of subterranean conspiracies and climactic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX>-a-tat--with a
new, post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX> acknowledgment that white cops who rough up minority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> are the rule, not the exception. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX>'s way of telling the story
catches you off-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>. He makes the familiar unfamiliar.

            In part, he does it with casting: Of the triptych of
leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, not one is traditional movie-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> material. The closest to a
"name" of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Spacey</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Vincennes</ENAMEX>, also known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vincennes</ENAMEX> works <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Narcotics</ENAMEX> and also serves as technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> for a
Dragnet -like TV show called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Badge of Honor</ENAMEX> . He isn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX>,
but he has almost no scruples; he's an unabashed fame whore.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
routinely pockets cash from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid Hudgens</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny DeVito</ENAMEX>), the film's occasional
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">narrator</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hush-Hush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and a fiendish imp out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gifford</ENAMEX>'s nightmares: Hudgens sets up public figures with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prostitutes</ENAMEX>, then calls in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vincennes</ENAMEX> to make the bust and pose for pictures.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spacey</ENAMEX> is disconcertingly breezy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> has been chewing the scenery for so
long--brilliantly--that I wasn't sure he had this kind of jaunty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> turn in
him. Better yet, he brings off the burgeoning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>'s conscience with
exceptional subtlety, beginning with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s embarrassment at shaking hands
at a party with a dupe he once collared and ending with his horror at a slaying
he has inadvertently abetted. Still, he's too opaque to serve as a moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">center</ENAMEX>, and besides, I haven't forgiven him yet for decapitating Gwyneth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paltrow</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX> .

            
The other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> leads, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Crowe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearce</ENAMEX>, are even tougher to get a handle on, although both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> (both
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX>, which you'd never guess) will be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Detective Bud</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowe</ENAMEX> is a beefy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thug</ENAMEX> with a compulsion to rough up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>-beaters. Oddly
tender, he nonetheless takes his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galahad</ENAMEX> act to the point of psychosis, dashing
off with gun cocked the instant he hears of a damsel in distress. He doesn't
think twice about blasting a crater in an ostensibly guilty suspect, planting a
weapon on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and claiming self-defense.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nemesis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Exley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearce</ENAMEX>), is everything we admire in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>--in theory. He
takes no bribes, vows never to plant evidence or to shoot hardened <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX>
instead of arresting them, and single-handedly dynamites the "blue wall of
silence" when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are caught beating the hell out of a group of Latino
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearce</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Exley</ENAMEX> a stuck-up, repressed little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prig</ENAMEX> who issues
orders wearing an all-purpose smirk on his rigidly chiseled face. Worse, his
snooty righteousness is tinged with opportunism: He's willing to make deals
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX> in return for promotions.

            The plot--which turns on the arrest of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> kingpin
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul Guilfoyle</ENAMEX>), a massacre at a diner, and a group of call girls surgically
altered to resemble movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>--is almost too diffuse to synopsize. Much of
the fun comes from finally learning which piece fits where.

            Lacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>, and
a moral compass, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the film leaves you adrift, which
means that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX> and his co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Helgeland</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Conspiracy Theory</ENAMEX> )
have to absorb you with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of their storytelling. The film opens with
DeVito delivering a sardonic ode to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> that captures both the gleaming
surface and the underlying rancidity. As filmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dante Spinotti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Confidential conjures up those racy old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Avon</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pocket Books</ENAMEX> pulp
covers--film noir but with colors that are lurid and deep--and comments on
them, too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX> pose for flashbulb pictures beside handcuffed
suspects or scenes of carnage, their hats rakishly tilted. In this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>, men
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> dreaming of fame arrive on the bus to be instantly victimized by the
ones who got there first.

            Perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>'s relationship
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Bracken</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Basinger</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> who's dyed and coifed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">resemble Veronica Lake</ENAMEX>, is a tad moist, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>' physical rapport is
sensational. You can believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX> would open himself up to this
bedraggled blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>, admitting, "I'm just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> they bring in to scare
the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>." And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Basinger</ENAMEX>, a cool <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>, has never looked more
comfortable with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, not even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Baldwin</ENAMEX>. As her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire pimp</ENAMEX>,
an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce Patchett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Strathairn</ENAMEX> does a classic
detective-movie turn: sleek, unruffled, every motion cagily deliberate. The man
has purged himself of all surface emotion.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanson</ENAMEX> co-wrote the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underrated</ENAMEX> White <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>) with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Fuller</ENAMEX>, and there's a touch of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fuller</ENAMEX> in this film's lugubrious trashiness. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-and-a-quarter hours</TIMEX>, the
picture is too long, and not exactly winged. But just when you start to get
impatient with the plodding, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-thing-after-another style of narration,
there's a shocker that blows you into the movie's last act, and then a scene in
which a couple of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">antagonists</ENAMEX> figure out what stinks and join forces in
an abandoned motel to stave off an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>. It's a virtuoso shootout,
a riot of angles--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX> depicted in whispers, scudding shadows, flashes
of body parts. Bullets explode in shards of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and light, bringing death in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chiaroscuro</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Confidential</ENAMEX> , with its divergent plot strands,
rockets to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>-movie heaven.

            
               Cop fight: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud White</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crowe</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Exley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearce</ENAMEX>) almost mix it up (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">59 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

         
      
   
