
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frankfort Laundromat</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
Halliday

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, July</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankfort Laundromat</ENAMEX>," click .

            Plastic chair, my eyes
closed, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> walked in,he had his bag of laundry. My laundry was in a
machine already, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty-eight years</TIMEX> prior to my death. Like memy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was
alive, he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. We were bothsunburned and tired, this was after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>
on the beach,after the picnic, after when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> got stuck in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX>,this was
after, then came the laundry; my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> said"Did you get burned much?" I said
"Not too bad" and he put his clothes in a machine. Small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tide</ENAMEX>.My eyes
closed over <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Burden of the Past</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. J. Bateand</ENAMEX> my eyes opened, hot
room smell of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX> and hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fabric</ENAMEX>,and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s shirt was dark pink, like a
heart.But my eyes closed, after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hours</TIMEX> in the sun andbuying the stuff for
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX> for everybody andmaking sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> didn't really hurt
the seagullsand after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asa</ENAMEX> felt sick at lunch and after the humid tennisso my
eyes closed. Then opened apparently for more living,I put my laundry in a dryer
and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was reading The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> --concentrating, with his
reading glasses,and caring about the truth, despite all the sun and all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX> and tennis and driving, and I lovedhim reading there in his dark
pink shirt. But my head wasgravitational to the floor, my chin to my neck, I
tried <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Burden of the Past</ENAMEX> and closed my eyes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> yearsbefore
my death unless it comes sooner, and a fly shiftedfrom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> magazine
to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s shirt to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Certs</ENAMEX> wrapperand the fly was the word "and." Then my
clothes were dryand awfully hot and I held my face to a hot dry towel.I wanted
to live--to live enough; but to live <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>--the sunburn and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gravitation</ENAMEX>--but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was stillreading. Therefore with the normal courage
ofany <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> or any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> I folded my laundry and carried itout to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX>
for more living, as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> went on reading for truth in his shirt dark pink
like a heart.

         
      
   
