
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>'s On

            Talk radio is uniquely
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>, it's democratic, it's interactive, it's ... OK, OK, it's mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush</ENAMEX>
talking to wack-jobs on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> about the budget and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard</ENAMEX> jawing with
lowlifes on weed about breasts. But not completely. Further up the yak food
chain, past the local politics and sports gabbers, you can find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garrison</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keillor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Car Talk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and, if you're lucky, the gentle wit of
Whad'Ya Know? and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Feldman</ENAMEX>.

            This is talk radio for the
rest of us--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who like information and words, have the conventional
concerns of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and work, and enjoy a little innuendo <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX>.

            "Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">listeners</ENAMEX> read," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldman</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">47-year-old</TIMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who looks and sounds fully
capable of being beaten up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>. "They play racquetball. They
disproportionately own foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>. They carry dental insurance."

            When asked if his marketing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are satisfied with this following (after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX> of national
broadcasts, the show, syndicated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Radio International</ENAMEX>, now reaches a
total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> via <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feldman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">responds</ENAMEX>, "What are marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?"

            Although
such comments reflect <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Whad'Ya Know?</ENAMEX> 's
let's-go-in-the-barn-and-put-on-a-show feel, the show is a full-time gig for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldman</ENAMEX>, who describes his salary as "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about .4</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keillor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX>."

            The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two-hour</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> show airs live, usually from
a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">175</NUMEX>-seat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wisconsin</ENAMEX> (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madison</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feldman</ENAMEX>
attended college and now lives with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>). But
sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldman</ENAMEX> takes it on the road to places like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Northfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minn.</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Springfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mo.</ENAMEX> The show always opens with a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five-minute</TIMEX> topical monologue
("One thing you gotta say about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>: They can't run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, but
they've made it a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> to fire your travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>.") and then segues
to an interview with a guest or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> included <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiley</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> who witnessed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kohl</ENAMEX>'s glutton-off at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> diner). Next comes the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Whad'Ya Know</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quiz</ENAMEX>, which pairs a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX>. Quiz
categories include "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Science,"</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Odds</ENAMEX> and Ends," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Things You Should</ENAMEX>
Have Learned in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Had You Been Paying Attention</ENAMEX>)." (Sample question: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Are</ENAMEX>
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> injured by clothing or by razors? Answer: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clothing</ENAMEX>.) Kitschy
prizes--like a book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Songs for Dogs and the People Who Love Them</ENAMEX>
or a pair of underwear with the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Contract With America</ENAMEX>" printed on them--go to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>.

            There's also the phone call
to an inhabitant of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Town of the Week</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is selected by a dart
thrown at a map, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldman</ENAMEX> dials the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> randomly until someone answers and
chats with him (the feature ran <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> before he lighted upon an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inhabitant</ENAMEX> who'd heard of the show). But most of the show is just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feldman</ENAMEX>
pacing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> and being funny. "It's sort of like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donahue</ENAMEX> without
the issues," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldman</ENAMEX> once told a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. "Or better yet, without
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donahue</ENAMEX>."

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLOCK QUOTE</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WOMAN AUDIENCE</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MEMBER</ENAMEX>: How can I wean myself from sleeping with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FELDMAN</ENAMEX>:
I say marry him. [END <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLOCK QUOTE</ENAMEX>]

            
In an age when even the most seemingly
spontaneous public events are in fact preceded by stacks of memos and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of
meetings, extemporaneous entertainment like this is no mean feat. And it's no
mean feat either. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Letterman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldman</ENAMEX> sees
to it that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foils</ENAMEX> have as much fun as he does.

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLOCK QUOTE</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FELDMAN</ENAMEX>:
What's your name?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">AUDIENCE MEMBER</ENAMEX>: Hankus
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netsky</ENAMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FELDMAN</ENAMEX>: Is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pig</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> version? I'm being serious with you, now give me a serious answer. What's
your name?
            

            HANKUS: That's really it.
...
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FELDMAN</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hankus</ENAMEX> is your
actual name?
            

            HANKUS: It's true. I was
actually named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hankus</ENAMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> ...
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FELDMAN</ENAMEX>: Why?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HANKUS</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GIRLFRIEND: Tell</ENAMEX>
him the truth.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FELDMAN</ENAMEX>: There can't be a
good reason for it.
            

            HANKUS: Well, let's see.
... There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> tradition of naming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> after ...
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FELDMAN</ENAMEX>: Of giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
lousy names ...
            

            HANKUS: Actually, my
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX> had to name me after a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> whose name started with an "H" and she
didn't like any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> names like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard or Harry</ENAMEX> or any of that sort
of stuff, so she got this name from a cartoon show, as a matter of fact.
...
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FELDMAN</ENAMEX>: What cartoon had
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Hankus</ENAMEX>"?
            

            HANKUS: There was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cartoon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hankus the Horse</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">END BLOCK QUOTE</ENAMEX>]

            At this point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldman</ENAMEX> dials
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hankus</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>.

            [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLOCK QUOTE</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FELDMAN</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX>, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netsky</ENAMEX>, this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Feldman</ENAMEX> calling from the radio show
Whad'Ya Know? with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Feldman</ENAMEX>. If you can answer a simple question, we
have a wonderful prize for you. Got a minute?
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HANKUS</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MOM: Just a</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX>, yes.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FELDMAN</ENAMEX>: OK--the question
is, "What famous cartoon <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> named after?"
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HANKUS</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MOM: Hankus the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Horse</ENAMEX> . ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> when I had to fill in the certificate
didn't like that. They said you've got to give him a proper name. ...
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FELDMAN</ENAMEX>:
They didn't think <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hankus the Horse</ENAMEX> was a proper name for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>?
[END <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BLOCK QUOTE</ENAMEX>]

            Playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>, agog at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earthling</ENAMEX> ways, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feldman</ENAMEX>
listens skeptically to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in the studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> who describes himself as a
"community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">planner</ENAMEX>" busy "coordinating a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s relationships with the
state and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." Bearing down, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldman</ENAMEX> gets him to admit that his
real duties are to "beg for money for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sewers</ENAMEX>."

            But the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Martian</ENAMEX> will
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gladly</ENAMEX> play the butt of a joke if it'll help him figure out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acclimating</ENAMEX> himself to the online world in one show, he required <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> to tap
their words into a keyboard as they spoke. Meanwhile, he did the same with his
manual typewriter.

            
"It's-very-nice-to-meet-you-over-the-Internet-What-do-you-look-like?"
spoke/typed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX>.
"Parentheses-smiling-broadly-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-foot-<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four-and-</NUMEX>a-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-blond-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran</ENAMEX>-type-you?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feldman</ENAMEX> spoke/typed back.

            "To communicate using only
your typing skills--to me, that's a special level in hell." Besides, he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confesses</ENAMEX>, "I don't like to be accessed."

            Which makes public radio the
perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> for him--and explains why the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> he made failed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX>.

            "The concept was for me to be
a white <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arsenio Hall</ENAMEX>," he says of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>. "I had the hardest time figuring
out what that would be--not hip, not black, not up that late. It came out as
Art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linkletter</ENAMEX>.

            "To tell you the truth," he
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sighs</ENAMEX>, summing up his of life on public radio, "I don't see any way out of
this."

            
               Illustration by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina</ENAMEX>
Frenkel
            

         
      
   
