
   
   
      
         
            My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picture Left</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>

            To hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Picture Left</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX>," click .

            In our contemporary
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">discourse</ENAMEX>, literacy and culture sometimes tend to be associated with the visual
act of reading: What comes in through the ear, that organ of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Walkman</ENAMEX>, may
be considered less reflective or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Jonson</ENAMEX>, writing this
brilliant poem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early in the 17 th century</TIMEX>, the opposite is true: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ear</ENAMEX> is the avenue of the spirit, while the eye is duped by mere seeming. What
he means about the ear he demonstrates in sentences that skim and dance across
the lines and rhymes, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">flamenco</TIMEX>-style, or like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> creating space
where there was none.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Pinsky
            

             

            I now think
love is rather deaf, than blind,

            For else it could not
be,

                      That she,

            Whom I
adore so much, should so slight me,

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> my love behind:

            I'm sure my
language to her was as sweet,

                  And every close did
meet

                In sentence of as subtle
feet

                      As hath the
youngest he,

            That sits in shadow of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apollo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>.

            Oh, but my
conscious fears,

                That
fly my thoughts between,

                Tell me that she hath
seen

            My <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of gray
hairs,

            Told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and forty
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>,

            Read so much waist, as she
cannot embrace

            My mountain belly and my
rocky face,

            And all
these, through her eyes, have stopt her ears.

         
      
   
