
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fetal Attraction</ENAMEX>

            Everyone knows that aliens
look like giant fetuses. Just think of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roswell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.M.</ENAMEX>, or the glowing eggheads
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Close Encounters of the Third Kind</ENAMEX> . But in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contact</ENAMEX> , the
closest thing to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX> is the adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who's tracking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> down.
She's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>), a brilliant, idealistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who, when things
go wrong, hugs her knees to her chest. She's been searching for signs of
extraterrestrial life ever since she was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. Why? Because her mother
died in childbirth, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> later her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> died of a heart attack.
Now, in her loneliness, she spends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">day and night</TIMEX> listening for signals from
little green <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. She knows that when she finds them, they'll be sweet and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">loving</ENAMEX> and helpful, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> she never had.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zemeckis</ENAMEX> ought to have been the ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for this film. After all, he's
the leading explorer of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. In the goofy Back
to 
               the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Future</ENAMEX> , he regressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J. Fox</ENAMEX> to a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1950s</NUMEX> high-school
student and had him strike up an incestuous flirtation with his then teen-age
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. In the whimsical-ponderous epic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest Gump</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zemeckis</ENAMEX> made a
saint out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">simpleton</ENAMEX> who was essentially a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5-year-old</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.
Contact opens in much the same vein, with a series of calm, loving,
emblematic scenes from childhood. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellie</ENAMEX>'s white clapboard house even looks
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspiciously</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, even though she's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and he
lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>.

            So fond of iconic childhood is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zemeckis</ENAMEX>, in fact, that he
takes a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> to inch toward anything that looks like a plot. Ellie
finally grows up to run a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> that listens for signals from
outer space, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, as she's sitting in the desert, her headphones pick
up a noise. Instantly, she knows it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> could be excused for
thinking it sounds like a garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> backing up). With remarkable speed, she
and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> figure out that the noise is actually a code, a blueprint for a
machine to carry a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> to the faraway solar system of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vega</ENAMEX>. The
government casually comes up with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">half a trillion dollars</NUMEX> to build it, and in
what seems like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX>, a launching pad as big as a mountain is ready to
go.

            But before
she can fly to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellie</ENAMEX> has to face down some earthly obstacles. There's a
selfish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Skerritt</ENAMEX>) trying to take credit for her discoveries, and
a national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Woods</ENAMEX>) scheming to be elected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
There's also a contest to see who'll get to fly the machine. Of course, by now
we know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellie</ENAMEX>'s lonely childhood has given her a unique gift for
listening, and that she's the only one who can go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vega</ENAMEX>, and that everything
that happens up until her trip is a mere distraction. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zemeckis</ENAMEX> seems
impatient to get to the magic; throughout the middle of this movie he simply
checks out, like the directorial equivalent of a deadbeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>. This is
unfortunate, because in his negligence he has allowed into his film dialogue
(by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James V. Hart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Goldenberg</ENAMEX>, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Sagan</ENAMEX>'s novel) that
falls far beneath the standards of your average corporate memo. Tearfully,
Ellie announces that her discovery represents "a profoundly impactful moment
for humanity." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew McConaughey</ENAMEX>--who plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie</ENAMEX>'s love interest, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ridiculously</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer Joss</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> who is now the respected author
of a best-selling book about "faith" and "meaning," and who, though still in
his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">20s</NUMEX>, is a trusted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>--thrusts out his lower jaw like
a calendar pinup while delivering such lines as "I'm not against technology,
I'm against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who deify it at the expense of human truth!" <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Charlton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> couldn't have said it better.

            
Occasionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zemeckis</ENAMEX> stops nodding off and
sprinkles in some flashy Gumpian touches. Refining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gump</ENAMEX> 's mix of real
and fictional footage, he makes truly shameless use of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> long clips from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> press conferences, and invites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hordes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> to stop by for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cameos</ENAMEX>. Talk about self-plagiarism. What we're waiting for is the trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vega</ENAMEX>,
and indeed, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this 10-minute</TIMEX> sequence turns out to be pure joy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellie</ENAMEX> gets
strapped into a metal ball and hurtles through a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> of space. Instead of
the massive, gray, meticulously detailed sci-fi city we've come to expect, she
floats through weird, puddly red and blue atmospheres. She speeds up and slows
down, and she has no idea why. She reaches out to touch the wall of the machine
and it ripples, the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> seems to flutter on a hot day. The scene is
grave, scary, and beautiful. It dawns on us that she's heading into something
completely unknown, something she can't even fully perceive. Also, that for the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX> is getting to act.

            Then she
lands on the alien planet, and the pat speechifying takes up where it left off.
I won't reveal the details of her encounter with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> except to say that
they are most un-fetuslike--in fact, they distinctly resemble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. Could
market research be to blame? Close <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Encounters of the Third Kind</ENAMEX> came out
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> largely consisted of trail-end <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX>
likely to groove to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dreyfuss</ENAMEX>' desire to throw off the shackles of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adulthood</ENAMEX> and play. Contact comes out at a time when we're obsessed with
role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, and nurturing, and making sure our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> grow up to be healthy,
responsible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alas</ENAMEX>, this is not the premise of a great movie. When
Contact finally comes alive, it leaves you frightened and thrilled and
emotionally overwrought, as only a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> can be. The rest is pandering.

            On a brighter note, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shall We Dance</ENAMEX>? is being hyped
as a throwaway feel-good movie, but it has moments of genuine depth. At first I
resisted the plot, which has a depressed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> secretly attending
dance lessons. Haven't we had enough of dance as therapy? Besides, it's stocked
with factory-made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eccentrics</ENAMEX>. There's your requisite bawdy spinster, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-worker</ENAMEX> who's a systems <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and a wig-wearing rumba <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX> by
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.

            What the
movie does have going for it is an amazingly moving performance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koji</ENAMEX>
Yakusho, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who plays the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX>. He's a handsome but humble
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everyman</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel McCrea</ENAMEX>. Another strength of the film is that its
surprises have little to do with the plot. They occur at random, whenever one
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">character</ENAMEX> discovers that another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> has feelings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> starts
dancing because he has a crush on his frail, beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, and for much of
the movie we watch her through his longing eyes. But quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late in the day</TIMEX>, she
reveals a cluster of emotions we couldn't have guessed at--she is, for example,
deeply absorbed in her failure to win a quick-step contest. And she, too, has
to correct a few unfair assumptions about him.

            
Abrupt shifts in sympathy like this result in
choppy filmmaking . Shall <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Dance</ENAMEX>? has neither the style of Strictly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballroom</ENAMEX> nor the cheap catharsis of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dirty</ENAMEX> 
               Dancing . But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clunkiness</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Masayuki Suo</ENAMEX>'s way of stopping to make sure that he's
emotionally accurate. Shall <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Dance</ENAMEX>? isn't quite art, and it doesn't
qualify as mass entertainment either. But it's alert to its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>'
constantly evolving desires in ways that high- and low-culture movies, with
their strict aesthetics or their mass-market formulas, tend not to be. Maybe
this movie will be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in a modest new genre--the inquiry into adult
happiness. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contact</ENAMEX> , and however doggedly, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shall We Dance</ENAMEX>?
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sincerely</ENAMEX> wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to grow up.

            
               "As long as I can
remember, I've been searching. ..." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arroway</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foster</ENAMEX>) explains herself to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joss</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McConaughey</ENAMEX>). (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">52 seconds</TIMEX>):
            

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> committee
debates the alien blueprints (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Skerritt</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woods</ENAMEX>). (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX>):
            

         
      
   
