
   
   
      
         
            Place Your Bets

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX> makes me wary--I
smell a hustler. But I can't catch him faking the way I can his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affleck</ENAMEX> or the prodigiously bogus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX>. No, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>'s a smartie, and
unquestionably a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. Already, he has staked out his own chunk of
dramatic territory: He's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual</ENAMEX> who's also a prole, who's arrested
between the worlds of privilege and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>, who thinks and gets high on
thinking but who also wrestles with earthier instincts. Are those instincts
base or noble? A sign of corruption or purity? The conflict is as old as
melodrama, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> makes the lines sound as if he's hammering them out on the
spot. It's seductive, the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> are always turning behind those small
eyes, the way he licks his lips to suppress his emotions and then cagily
examines his options. I can't recall another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who seems at once so earnest
and so cunning, so ingenuous yet with something so clearly up his sleeve.

            This
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">paradoxical</ENAMEX> persona serves him gorgeously in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rounders</ENAMEX> , a snappy and
ingratiating gambling picture in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> plays a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> who fleeces
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suckers</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker</ENAMEX> games yet has a fundamental rectitude. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McDermott</ENAMEX>
begins by explaining, in a current of voice-over narration that hums through
the movie, "If you can't spot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> in your <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">first half-hour</TIMEX> at the table
then you are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX>." Losing his life savings to a menacingly fey
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangster</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX>) in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first 10 minutes</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> has you
rooting for him not only to get payback from the weird <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russki</ENAMEX> but to take what
he can off anyone dumb enough to sit across a card table from him, accepting
the rightness of the line "It's immoral to let a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> keep his money."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arounder</ENAMEX> is defined--in a handy glossary included with my
press notes--as "[a] <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> who knows all the angles and earns his living at
the poker table. The absolute opposite of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'sucker</NUMEX>.' " But Rounders
makes distinctions among rounders. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> is supposed to be an honest connoisseur
of card playing nature, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> whose expertise derives from spotting "tells,"
from "watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, not the cards." On the other hand, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Worm</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward Norton</ENAMEX>), newly discharged from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, is a reckless and compulsive
cheat who gets off on perpetually putting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> impudent twinkle toe over the
line. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> attempts to go "straight" by enrolling in law school (!) and
moving in with a classy blond <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gretchen Mol</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Worm</ENAMEX> emerges from his
hole to play the snake and lure his old chum back into the game.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rounders</ENAMEX> is an unusually talky movie, but the talk is slick and fast and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Levien</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Koppelman</ENAMEX>, wear their research on their
sleeves. In fact, the script is a model of research and construction, a real
summa cum laude effort from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of screenplay pedant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McKee</ENAMEX>. The settings have a density of detail that makes them feel authentic,
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement dens</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> to the kitsch <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">palaces</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlantic City</ENAMEX> to the blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bingo halls</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Binghamton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>; and the
aforementioned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> page glossary is a bounty for urban anthropologists.
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alligator Blood</ENAMEX>: A compliment given to an outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> who proves
himself unflappable under great pressure. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snap Off: To beat someone</ENAMEX>, often
a bluffer, and usually with a not especially powerful hand.")

            
Despite its high-wire subject, though, this is
not a movie made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX>. It's a studied, deliberate, calculating piece of
work, a formula Go-For-It picture with a jolt of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mean Streets</ENAMEX> to give it
some edge. The morality is spoon-fed and self-serving. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> use <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Worm</ENAMEX> to
rack up debts with the vicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bully</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grama</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Rispoli</ENAMEX>), who's sponsored
by--guess whoski? So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> plays cards to save his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s life
and--climactically, against his old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adversary</ENAMEX>--his own. Although his blonde
says what all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blondes</ENAMEX> say in this sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>-movie setup--variations on "If
you play cards again, I won't be here when you come home"--his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly mentor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Petrovsky</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Landau</ENAMEX>), assures him he can't run from who he is,
that "our destiny chooses us." May the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Alligator Blood</ENAMEX> be with you, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luke</ENAMEX>.

            

               Rounders was one of those spec scripts that has become legend in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, selling for heaps of cash and attracting big-deal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> who boasted that they "didn't have to change a word." Actually, they
ought to have changed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>. They might have given the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Girl</ENAMEX> more to
say than her handful of wet blanket reproaches, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Worm</ENAMEX> deserved a bigger last
act. Only my abiding affection for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landau</ENAMEX> kept me from snickering out loud at
his rabbinical monologues, in which he explains why he defied his yeshiva more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century ago</TIMEX> and followed his dream by going to law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. (He says
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing he took from yeshiva was to be true to oneself. What tripe! In
yeshiva, being true to yourself is possible only if you recognize that your
true self longs to submit to the rule of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torah</ENAMEX>. It doesn't mean that God is in
those poker chips.)

            So why do I recommend Rounders ? Because I'm a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX>--I was entertained. It's fun to watch these jazzy young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>
scrutinize their cards and each other and throw around their poker lingo; and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Dahl</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Seduction</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>), gives the picture a
jaunty tempo and a deep-toned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rembrandt</ENAMEX> look without ever calling attention to
his hand. The script is good at making you think that it has better cards than
it really does. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> constitute a royal flush--OK, OK, enough with
the poker metaphors. The tall, skinny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX> bobs and slits his eyes and twists
his mouth into a yokel sneer and is wholly impossible to dislike, even when his
character keeps crazily upping the ante. In the schematic role of a sober,
family<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-man gambler</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Turturro</ENAMEX> proves that he doesn't always
need to chew the scenery: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mumbling</ENAMEX>, hovering, shuffling in the margins, he
makes you watch him closely to discern his real, complicated feelings.

            And then
there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX>, who does a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> mafioso the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olivier</ENAMEX> would have done
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Start with an accent unlike any heard anywhere on the planet, with
syllables drawn out so audaciously that you want to applaud every line. He
doesn't raise you, he rie-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">yee</NUMEX>-zes you, and then informs you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meester Son Ahv Ay</ENAMEX>
Beeeech, that you'll soon see your hups go dow-in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">drie-yeen</ENAMEX> (i.e., your
hopes go down the drain). He's steeped in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> melancholy, but he isn't
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pickled</ENAMEX>--those eyes are hard and mean. He opens an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oreo</ENAMEX>, holds it to his face,
and slides his teeth along the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> while raking his opponent with invisible
bullets. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malkovich</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">potboiler</ENAMEX> who dares .

            
He would have fit right into Touch of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> , which overflows with rococo, mannerist <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX> acting. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX> film has
been re-released in a new, expanded cut that conforms to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX> page list of
suggestions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orson Welles</ENAMEX>, its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, wrote after viewing
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> re-edit. Most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s so-called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s cuts" are marketing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gimmicks</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> behind this one--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Schmidlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Murch</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> among them--deserve some
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">kind of Academy Award</ENAMEX>. Sequences that once were run together by a studio bent
on linearity are now fractured and intercut in accordance with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX>'
intentions, and the still-astonishing <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> shot has been shorn of credits and
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Mancini</ENAMEX> theme that obscured its cacophonous sound mix. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX> years
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late</TIMEX>, Touch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> has arrived, and it's all of a piece.

            I <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> saw it when I was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
and thought it was one of the worst pictures ever--garish, oppressive, and
appallingly overacted. Grown up, I'd go with those same adjectives, except now
I think it's one of the best. But I'm not going to recant my first response.
Part of recognizing that Touch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> is a masterpiece means also
recognizing that it's often suffocatingly unpleasant, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX> is
working off his aggression for the vast, trash-movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> that he hoped to
attract. His <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">compositions</ENAMEX> are teeming, unbalanced, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> of gravity
that lurches left then right. The overlapping dialogue and squealing
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> music heard over tinny-sounding radios seems meant to induce a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migraine</ENAMEX> to accompany the seasickness.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX> isn't just plunging
his straight-laced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Leigh</ENAMEX>) into the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">squalor</ENAMEX> and chaos of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> border <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>. He's plunging us, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>,
into it, too. The wide-angle lenses spread the images out obscenely, so that
the whole movie takes on the sweaty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fatness</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Detective Hank Quinlan</ENAMEX>,
and our own sense of space is continually violated. The images in Touch of
E v il have been boiled down so that all its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingredients</ENAMEX> are mashed
together in the sludge. It's no wonder that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert McKee</ENAMEX>, the spiritual father
of something like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rounders</ENAMEX> , reserves a special place in hell for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen Kane</ENAMEX> , in which the exhibitionistic auteur incessantly
upstages his own narrative. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX> was at the peak of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> in Touch of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> , but let's never forget what an abrasive, high-wire, self-destructive
talent he was.

         
      
   
