
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unmitigated Gaul</ENAMEX>

            A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX> once attempted
to explain to me the plot of a convoluted kiddie <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sword</ENAMEX>-and-sorcery epic. I
didn't have a clue as to what he was talking about, but was charmed by his
fervor. The scrambled space opera The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Element</ENAMEX> has all the fervor
but none of the charm; it would probably improve in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10-year-old</TIMEX>'s retelling.
"When the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> planets are in eclipse, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">black hole</ENAMEX> opens and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> comes,"
intones an archaeologist in the opening scene, set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> in the early
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX>. He reads aloud from the wall of a cave: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water</ENAMEX>, fire,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">earth</ENAMEX>, air, gathering around ... a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> element ... a weapon against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>."
Suddenly, an enormous black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX> passes over the desert, and large rubber
tortoises with small bird heads emerge from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">spaceship</ENAMEX> shaped like a large
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rubber</ENAMEX> tortoise foot and kill the archaeologist. Then it appears that the large
rubber <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tortoises</ENAMEX> are good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>, and perhaps didn't mean to kill him. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of
them gets shot by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> 90210 and is shut in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cave</ENAMEX>, an event of great, if puzzling, significance. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three hundred years later</TIMEX>,
a big black ball spitting fire heads for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. Dispatched to do a thermal
analysis, a general reports, "The thermal analyzers have jammed." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holm</ENAMEX>) who happens to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> announces that the ball is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>
referred to in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the cave 300 years earlier</TIMEX>. "It is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eeevil</ENAMEX>," he confirms.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Absolute Eeevil</ENAMEX>." Another ship full of large rubber tortoises is shot down by
a ship full of large rubber hippos. Fortunately, someone has the sense to clone
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milla Jovovich</ENAMEX>, who scampers off in a loincloth to save <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>.

            It seems that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> are
behind all this. In fact, The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Element</ENAMEX> , at a reported cost of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">francs</NUMEX>), is the most expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>-financed film in
history. As directed and conceived by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luc Besson</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">La Femme Nikita</ENAMEX> ), it
may or may not be the worst movie ever made, but it is one of the most
unhinged. Much of its running time revolves around <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Retrieving the Stones</ENAMEX>. I had
no idea what the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stones</ENAMEX> were, but it eventually turned out that they represent
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Elements</ENAMEX>, and that the rubber tortoises, before being shot down, had
left them in the care of a blue-skinned opera diva with long hoses (bellows?)
dangling from her head.

            So
Jovovich, who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Element</ENAMEX>, and who, in combination with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stones</ENAMEX>,
has the power to save <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> up with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galahad</ENAMEX>, a fair-haired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX>, to Retrieve them. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fight off bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> to get seats aboard a
space <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shuttle</ENAMEX> bound for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">diva</ENAMEX>'s concert, which is being held on Phloston
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paradise</ENAMEX>, a sort of interstellar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oahu</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A good half hour</TIMEX> is spent getting the
couple past the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendants</ENAMEX>. It's as if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luke Skywalker</ENAMEX> had to wait around
for his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">billet</ENAMEX> to be stamped before he could fly off to destroy the
Death <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Star</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> would never have devoted so much time to what
is, after all, a matter of public transportation.

            Say this for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besson</ENAMEX>: He has never been hobbled by bourgeois
notions of logic, coherence, or consistency. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Element</ENAMEX>
alternates between high solemnity and low buffoonery, without for a second
finding the ideal middle ground. One moment, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creatures</ENAMEX> are blowing one another
away in gun battles that have all the suspense and emotional weight of
custard-pie fights, while a queenie talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Tucker</ENAMEX>) shrieks and
capers for the groundlings. The next, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> is viewing a series of
genuine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> wartime-atrocity photos, and weeping with doubt
over whether this vicious world is really worth preserving. At such times, that
big black space ball begins to look like a metaphor for the movie--a giant
Gallic turd.

            The other
thing to say for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Besson</ENAMEX> is that here, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nikita</ENAMEX> , he has a
communicable fetish for short-haired, feral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in scanty outfits. I imagine
that he was powerfully moved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daryl Hannah</ENAMEX>'s punky, kick-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> android in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blade Runner</ENAMEX> as well as her lissome, childlike mermaid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Splash</ENAMEX> ;
he has created a role for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ukrainian</ENAMEX>-born model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jovovich</ENAMEX>, who has an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urchin</ENAMEX>'s face atop a willowy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, that's a strange fusion of both. As a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Being</ENAMEX>, one of the most powerful forces in the universe, she spends much
of the film being slung around, semiconscious, by her male co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, on whom the
awesome responsibility falls to convince her that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> are capable of giving
love. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willis</ENAMEX> redeems the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> but not the movie. Still, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
persist in wanting to make this kind of American-style blockbuster, they should
study his performance, which is neither serious nor facetious but
something--intangibly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>--in between.

            
As it happens, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> film industry is the
target of an overpraised yet amusing satire called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irma Vep</ENAMEX> , which has
been enjoying a successful run at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Film Forum</ENAMEX> and will shortly open
in major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. In it, an aging, exhausted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Wave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, played by one-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truffaut</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alter ego</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Pierre Léaud</ENAMEX>, decides to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">remake Louis Feuillade</ENAMEX>'s static <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915-16</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> melodrama, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Vampires</ENAMEX> ,
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> starlet (and sometime <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Chan</ENAMEX> co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie Cheung</ENAMEX> as
the black-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">latex</NUMEX>-clad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> of jewel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX>. That he has no reason
to remake the film--apart from a very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> fixation on hommage , a need
to work, and a fancy for beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> girls in black latex--becomes apparent
to him a bit later than it does to his savvy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irma Vep</ENAMEX> has been
dubbed the anti- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day for Night</ENAMEX> , a cynical answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truffaut</ENAMEX>'s
romanticization of moviemaking for its own sweet sake. Yes, the shoot collapses
into chaos and despondency. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irma Vep</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olivier Assayas</ENAMEX>,
evinces a love of the process that's nearly as palpable as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truffaut</ENAMEX>'s. His
hand-held camera zigs and zags among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX>, embracing the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hubbub</ENAMEX> in the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> manner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>'s brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Larry Sanders</ENAMEX>
Show . He relishes the communal aspect of filmmaking: the near-familial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bickering</ENAMEX>, the post-shoot potluck suppers. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> occasions, the picture takes
off into cinematic flights that leave The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Element</ENAMEX> (which cost
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 50</NUMEX> times as much) sputtering on the launch pad. In the first sequence,
Cheung re-creates her character's nocturnal prowl in her own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>, the camera
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coiling</ENAMEX> around her like a boa and hovering breathlessly over her shoulder as
she snatches a necklace from another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guest</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, then regards it on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rooftop</ENAMEX> in a cool neon-lit drizzle. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> is a black-and-white montage
that's as mind-blowing, in context, as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'60s</NUMEX> shorts by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Snow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan</ENAMEX>
Brakhage that it so cheerfully apes.

            Cheung,
who speaks <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> with a surprising <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> accent, at once grounds the film
and gives it a touch of mystery--the mystery of simplicity. The movie uses her
open <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> face to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> faces seem neurotic and devious: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hers</ENAMEX> is
like a clear pool next to their rather pinched visages. The ingenue, the
straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, she is lithe and funny in her own right. She listens politely to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Léaud</ENAMEX>'s nearly incomprehensible <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> musings on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Feuillade</ENAMEX>, then goes ahead
and does her job with a minimum of fuss. You wouldn't spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> discussing
your motivation with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Chan</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irma Vep</ENAMEX> was written and shot on the fly, conceived as a
piece of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-part anthology and perhaps overextended. It's thin. It gains
much, however, from a subplot featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathalie Richard</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoe</ENAMEX>, a high-strung
lesbian costume <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> who's too shy to put the moves on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX>. (That
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> bears an uncanny resemblance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Heche</ENAMEX> adds to the frisson .)
Zoe doubles as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s aesthetics: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> films, she
complains, "have too much decoration, too much money"; <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> films are
increasingly impersonal and apolitical. It's not hard to imagine what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoe</ENAMEX> would
make of The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifth Element</ENAMEX> .

            In fact, watching Irma
Vep , my thoughts kept drifting to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luc Besson</ENAMEX>'s shambolic, would-be epic,
which represents the real dead end of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>. Imagine an Irma
Vep -like documentary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Fifth Element</ENAMEX> 's filming, on vast sets,
with hordes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technicians</ENAMEX> attending to hordes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX>-toting rubber hippos.
Imagine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Luc Besson</ENAMEX> sitting, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Pierre Léaud</ENAMEX>, amid the chaos, a hand on
his forehead, mumbling, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zere</ENAMEX> ees no flesh ... no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> ... I feel nossing
..."

            
               A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Being</ENAMEX> in the
big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leeloo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jovovich</ENAMEX>) goes out on a ledge (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zorg</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Oldman</ENAMEX>) demos
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">firepower</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45 seconds</TIMEX>) :
            

         
      
   
