
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Modem Marriage</ENAMEX>

            The first weddings happened
by capture. The groom, aided by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior friend</ENAMEX> (the "best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>"), kidnapped
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>, holding her in his left hand, and fought off other prospective
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mates</ENAMEX>, using his right hand. This is why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> stands on the left in modern
ceremonies. Or so I learned in my online research.

            The Internet is the final
civilizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> of this ancient ritual, transforming its anachronistic
intimacy into a fully automated <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cyberexperience.</ENAMEX> All things nuptial are at your
fingertips, from the history of marriage to methods for entertaining your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> at a shower and software that writes pithy wedding toasts. Once
you meet your fiancée or fiancé in an online chat <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, you need never leave
your laptop to plan, pay for, or execute the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Big Day</ENAMEX>.

            The chain
of hyperlinks to timeless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">matrimony</ENAMEX> begins with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cupid's Network</ENAMEX>, which
will direct you to the perfect match (please specify ethnicity and religion).
Or you could visit the virtual <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> Matchmaker, who commands, "Stop saying I can't and
get ready to say I do."

            Weddings are ideally suited to the Internet, since a Web
site can provide the unconditional love and attention that print media can't.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Roses Cyber Weddings</ENAMEX> will create a Web page for you, as well as locate "an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ordained minister</ENAMEX> to oversee every detail." Many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> include a customizable
"timeline,"reminding you when to buy what. Online <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX>, such
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ask Myrna</ENAMEX>, specialize in calming stressed-out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brides</ENAMEX>. Need to
come up with vows? The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Create-A-Vow Kit</ENAMEX> is yours for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24.95</NUMEX>. Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clergy</ENAMEX> are
easy: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Wayward Catholics</ENAMEX> are welcomed on the home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Robed Monks of St.</ENAMEX>
Benedict, who "recognize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> never really said No to
anyone."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> is
not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peddler</ENAMEX> but also town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">crier</ENAMEX>. There is no need to climb the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> with
a bottle of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> paint to announce your matrimony, or to petition the society
pages to include you. Web-site <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>, such as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wed</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>, promise to spare no
interactive technology in broadcasting your undying love to the world. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way Cool</ENAMEX>
Weddings site links to the best pages, which include heartwarming stories
and statistical details, along with music and video.

            
Like politics, the best wedding Web sites are
local. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Virtual Bride</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> ("Thank you for entering The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virtual Bride"</ENAMEX>), which gives hard-hitting hiring advice. On wedding
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>: "Beware of the use of the word 'I.' This means that she could
already be fantasizing that it is she who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>, not you." It also
recommends packing the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bride</ENAMEX>'s
Emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kit</ENAMEX>," whose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30-plus</NUMEX> items include smelling salts, a small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flashlight</ENAMEX>, directions to the reception, and masking tape.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wedding Resource</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Online of Houston</ENAMEX> is less dramatic but has better shower games, including
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toilet Paper Wedding Dress</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Metroweddings</ENAMEX> includes tips on trends from the
entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>'s most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tavern</ENAMEX> on the
Green. ("Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eighties</ENAMEX>, everyone is getting back down to the real meaning
of the occasion.") <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Viva Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, one of many online sites for the wedding capital,
offers theme packages such as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Intergalactic</ENAMEX>," which "includes the use of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Starship chapel</ENAMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intergalactic</ENAMEX> memorabilia, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Transporter</ENAMEX>,
illusion entrance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Captain Quirk/</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX>, theatrical lighting, and fog.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$650.00</NUMEX>." If your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> doesn't have a site, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bridal Gallery</ENAMEX>, an online
registry, will search for local resources.

            Identity politics can sometimes substitute for geography
when it comes to breaking down the Web wedding industry into usable chunks.
There are complete guides to ethnic--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Korean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Filipino</ENAMEX>--as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gay</ENAMEX> and Lesbian
ceremonies. Each urges you to shake free of the tired mainstream and embrace a
more spirited tradition. For those who wish to pursue this strategy to its
extreme, the Medieval and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance Wedding Information</ENAMEX> site, a favorite of
Dungeons & Dragons types, offers advice on everything from the
entertainment (jousting, minstrels, etc.) to how to get hesitant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> ("the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> discovered how much fun tights can be").

            For those
who tire of the entire process before the ceremony even takes place, wedding
sites contain their share of commentary on all things marital. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>'s
Wedding-related jokes and one-liners provides the usual dosage of in-law
bashing and sex-hurrahing, and there are several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funniest Home</ENAMEX>
Videos -type pages devoted to accounts of actual wedding mishaps
(the comatose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandpa</ENAMEX> and the topless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX>, and so on). Best of all is
And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bride Wore ...</ENAMEX>, which adds captions to pictures of hideous bridal
fashions. "This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX> has been hermetically sealed for your protection" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Run</ENAMEX>! Run! It
landed on your butt!" should conjure up some of the images.

            For arcane legal reasons, the actual ceremony must take
place offline. Still, when problems crop up after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the wedding</TIMEX>, you can go to
"The Marriage
Toolbox," which derides the outdated advice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yesteryear</ENAMEX>'s home-economics
textbooks in favor of an online "journaling" technique that helps you release
your inner kvetch. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX> I feel like a wretch. ... I am sticky and hot and
not very happy.") There remains the possibility that these methods will not
yield lifelong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bliss</ENAMEX>. Should such a fate befall you, there's always <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Divorce Online</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
