
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Employer</ENAMEX>:
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the biggest challenges you face may be to find qualified,
      educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to fill positions in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>.
      The number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> reporting a shortage of skilled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> almost
      doubled from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995 to 1998</TIMEX>; from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 47 percent</NUMEX>. Did
      you know that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> have low basic skills
      and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> have reading or writing
      difficulties?
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX> is working to change that!
      The literacy statistics change little from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year to year</TIMEX>.
      Did you know that the combined efforts of all literacy programs in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> reach <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only ten</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> with reading problems? The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> estimates business and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> foot a bill of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX>
      <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>; a bill caused by workplace accidents, lost productivity,
      unrealized tax revenues, welfare payments and crime.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX> is working to change these statistics, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> life at a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>.
      Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX> (formerly the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Indianapolis</ENAMEX> Literacy
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX>) has provided tutoring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County</ENAMEX> reading at the
      very lowest level of literacy. Today, in addition to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> tutoring,
      we offer small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a Second <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Language tutoring</ENAMEX> and
      video-based instruction for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> with learning disabilities.
      We bring together dedicated adult learners and committed, well-trained
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>.
      Because we believe everyone in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> should have an
      opportunity to learn to read and write, we are asking you to help by
      sending your contribution to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indy Reads</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indy Reads</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> make gains in reading, writing and language. They
      gain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and leadership skills and continually strive to change
      their lives by developing these skills.
      Will you help them change?
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX> is changing lives, changing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and changing the
      employment prospects for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. We
      need your support. Please consider a contribution to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX>.
      Corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX> will be acknowledged in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX>, annual
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Indy Reads</ENAMEX> webpage.
      We hope you will become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX> as we work to improve
      our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> through literacy.
      Thank you for your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> and support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lis Daily</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTHR</ENAMEX> channel <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">13 Honorary Chair Corporate Fund Drive</ENAMEX> Indy
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reads Annual</ENAMEX> Campaign
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Curts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairperson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indy Reads Annual</ENAMEX> Campaign
    
  
