
  
  
    
      YOU can be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to open the door... to a life long dream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
      who have never learned to read.
      Here's how YOU can make an important difference in someone's
      life...
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Friends of Literacy</ENAMEX>,
      We all share a special interest in reading. For some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, learning
      to read has been a lifelong dream. You can help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> reach their dreams
      of reading and learning by making a contribution to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX>. Although
      I'm a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> I have a beautiful outlook on life because of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX>. When I was working, I couldn't read well enough to accept a
      foreman job, so I turned it down. Now at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age of 67</TIMEX>, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>
      in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> with wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, I
      graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX> and I'm studying for my GED. Make your donation
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX> can continue teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to read and help them
      achieve their dreams.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James T. Moore</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Your donation will help us all!
    
  
