
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Donor</ENAMEX>,
      Your gift can plant the seed of learning in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indy Reads</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> like
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Johnson</ENAMEX>. You can hear how proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> is of his garden when you read
      his essay, can't you? Imagine how proud he must be of his writing skills,
      and his reading skills! When he was assigned his first tutor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> was
      reading below the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade level. Today, he and his new tutor are
      exploring the Internet and plotting routes to travel out west while they
      continue to strengthen his reading and writing.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s tremendous growth in these basic skills is the result of his own
      hard work, and the care and nurturing of his tutors. Your gifts have
      helped him grow, too, by providing the training and support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s tutors
      have needed, buying the books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> used, and giving him the opportunity
      to meet and learn with other adult learners from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> and around
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
      We hope the enclosed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bookmark</ENAMEX>, just the right size for a paperback,
      will remind you of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> working to
      improve their lives, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> through stronger
      basic skills. We also hope you'll take time out from your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> planting
      to make a gift in honor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garden</ENAMEX>. Your gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> will help
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> grow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      P.S. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> don't enjoy reading the way you and
      I do. Won't you help <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> the seed of learning in them through a gift to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indy Reads</ENAMEX>?
    
  
