
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 21, 1998</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIELD</ENAMEX>(contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIELD</ENAMEX>(contact title) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIELD</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIELD</ENAMEX>(address
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIELD</ENAMEX>(address <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIELD</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">city</ENAMEX>, state, zip)
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear FIELD</ENAMEX>(contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>),
      My name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Cooper</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> I was so proud to be named <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> of
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> that I thought my chest was going to burst when I was on stage.
      I learned first hand what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GILL</ENAMEX> is all about, giving to others
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unselfishly</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GILL Recognition Party</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18, 1998</TIMEX>
      there was a silent auction sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. We as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
      thank you for donating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIELD</ENAMEX> (we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX>) for the auction.
      I truly believe God had a purpose for me when I walked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Library</ENAMEX> and asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarian</ENAMEX> if she could teach me to read. It
      was like a guardian angel had come down to guide my feet into that door
      when she directed me to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GILL</ENAMEX>. I can not begin to tell you how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GILL</ENAMEX> has
      changed my life. All of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tutor</ENAMEX> have been so friendly and
      helpful they made me realize that I am a worthwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX>. I don't
      know why God chose me. I just know he did and I plan to make something of
      my life with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GILLâ</ENAMEX>€™s help. I volunteer for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> meetings,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leadership Council</ENAMEX> and speaking engagements.
      Your gift is appreciated by each and every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who will benefit
      from your generosity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GILL</ENAMEX> truly does make a difference in lives.
      
      Again, I thank you.
      
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Cooper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Leadership Council</ENAMEX>
      P.S. It took me <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1/2 hours</TIMEX> to type this on the computer because
      my writing skills need a lot of practice yet, but my tutor helped me with
      only a few words. She is a drill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> making me do all the work!
    
  
