
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 4</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> will attend the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YWCA</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>' "Everyone belongs" <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer Day Camp</ENAMEX>. And are we
      going to have fun! Our camp <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> worked all winter long planning some
      great activities to keep everyone safe and active <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. We'll be
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">swimming</ENAMEX>, planning sports, going on exciting field trips, helping others
      through community service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>, planning our own camp carnival, and
      joining great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> like jewelry making, juggling, snack cooking, and
      nature crafts. As you can imagine, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> like this is expensive to
      provide. And <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 30%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we serve cannot afford the camp
      fee. Won't you help the WYCA provide a great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>?
      Please contribute to our campership fund <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Provide an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> full of fun! <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> of campership contributions
      directly support camp scholarships. Giving levels:<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> club sponsor
      provides supplies needed for one club <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> camper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> provides one
      child a whole week of fun at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> pays for a visit
      from a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magician</ENAMEX>, or zookeeper.$<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000 summer</TIMEX> sponsor
      provides <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> a whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> of camp <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2500</NUMEX> field trip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> sends
      the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> on an educational field trip.
      A response card is enclosed for your convenience. Your contribution
      may be tax deductible.
      
    
  
