
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 3, 1997</TIMEX>
      Dear Name,
      Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are growing up in an ever-changing society. As a
      contributor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> in past appeals I know that you are aware of
      our mission---to prepare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> with ethical values, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, a desire
      to succeed and a commitment to their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
      This letter is our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> request to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3~</NUMEX> for a gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual</ENAMEX>
      Campaign for support of our operating budget.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual</ENAMEX> Campaign goal is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX>. We invite you to consider
      a contribution.
      Your gift, along with the many others we receive, will provide vital
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> to become <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and
      business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Your investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> is one that will pay
      dividends for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come, not only in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, but in your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>. A recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Harris</ENAMEX> poll indicates that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 66%</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
      female business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> backgrounds.
      Take a step toward making a difference in the lives of our young woman
      and recommit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> vision. Your investment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual</ENAMEX>
      Campaign is sure to yield high returns.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheron Seward President</ENAMEX>
    
  
