
  
  
    
      Dear Name:
      Please join me as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shareholder</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts of Hoosier Capital</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council, Inc.</ENAMEX> You can be assured that a donation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> is a
      sound investment opportunity. Contributions will be used to cover program
      and membership costs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in financial need; subsidize the cost of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> camp; and provide training and resources to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, parents
      and adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>. Additionally, it will help provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX>
      experience to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> "at risk" or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in "hard to serve" areas like the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Girls School</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juvenile Justice Center</ENAMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year's Annual</TIMEX> Appeal goal is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX>. Please consider a corporate
      donation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 Million</NUMEX> or more to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> programs and
      activities throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Central Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Appeal</ENAMEX> is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> initiatives you will hear
      <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. In addition to this appeal for operating funds, you will
      be contacted to consider making a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year</TIMEX> commitment to give to our <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX>
      million capital campaign. The campaign funds will help provide a resource
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">library</ENAMEX>, training materials and equipment; development of progressive
      math and science programs; and the construction of new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
      of our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp properties</ENAMEX>.
      Take the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step toward making a difference in the lives of our
      young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shareholder</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> vision. Your
      investment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Appeal</ENAMEX> is sure to yield high returns.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte G Fisher Honorary Chair</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996 Annual</TIMEX> Appeal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Harris Stores</ENAMEX>, Inc.
      
    
  
