
  
  
    
      The answers are endless... The dreams in process.
      Dear Name,
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> we need your continued
      support to help these dreams become a reality.
      I am sure you are aware that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> provides programs which
      help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> to develop values, contribute to their society, and develop to
      their own potential. With so many conflicting pressures in our society
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>-the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> program is a proven solution and supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
      like you help to make it happen.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s challenge is to keep pace with our growing membership
      through increased levels of support from every facet of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>, and
      other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. A strong participation is essential to successfully reach
      out to more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20,349</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. Your gift to the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1997 Girl Scout Annual Campaign</ENAMEX> can ensure that even more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> will
      receive the benefits that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> has to offer.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>---and they're counting on
      YOU!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheron Seward President</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Thank you for your past gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scout Capital Campaign</ENAMEX>.
      Please consider a gift to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Campaign</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
