
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 24, 1997</TIMEX>
      Dear:
      Now more than ever girls need your support to help their dreams become
      a reality.
      Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> faces new challenges: new technology, new
      moral issues, new opportunities. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> experience a wide range of
      real life skills--first aid, resume writing, and managing money. They
      also reap benefits that are difficult to measure, including enhanced
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-esteem</ENAMEX>, greater confidence in their abilities, and the strength and
      conviction to take the lead and excel in their endeavors.
      We start early. As a preventive, informal education program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>
      Scouting helps girls relate to others, develop values, contribute to
      their society, and develop their own potential. Resulting in reduced risk
      of teen pregnancy, suicide, truancy, substance abuse and so many other
      crises.
      A gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1997 Girl Scout Annual</ENAMEX> Campaign helps to ensure that
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">girls</ENAMEX> will continue to receive the benefits that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> offers.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>--and they're counting on
      YOU!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheron Seward President</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Ensure the future of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. Please send your check
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      
    
  
