
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 16, 1998</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear ,</ENAMEX>
      Look at the benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> participating in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> receive. Girl
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scouts of the U.S.A.</ENAMEX> commissioned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEC Associates</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Program</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evaluators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consultants, Inc</ENAMEX>) to conduct a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Outcomes Study of</ENAMEX>
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> program The results were overwhelmingly positive. Its
      findings include:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> helps girls build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> personal assets which research
      has shown to be essential for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s healthy development and well
      being. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> assets are known to enhance school success, educational
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">aspirations</ENAMEX>, and the development of positive behaviors.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> unites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. When asked to
      compare opportunities received in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> activities versus
      those in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> at all age levels responded that
      troop activities offered them significantly more chances to achieve
      positive, pro-social outcomes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX> cited feelings of belonging,
      helpfulness, teamwork, and leadership, while gaining respect for others
      and values and decision making skills. Older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>
      Scouting provided even more positive outcomes during the crucial
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">adolescent</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> relationships. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> reported
      significant benefits from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and
      themselves. The benefits included sharing more quality time and improved
      relationships with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parents</ENAMEX> also gained friendships with
      other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and a feeling of giving back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> by developing their leadership
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skills</ENAMEX> and self-confidence. The study concludes, "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>, Juliette
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Low</ENAMEX> had a vision. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> that vision is connecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>,
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> for opportunities to tap their skiffs, to succeed in their
      lives, an to enrich their relationships with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>."
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girls</ENAMEX> are important to us. They have the potential to shape our world
      and make important decisions that will affect us all. Yet they face many
      challenges in their lives. Through outdoor activities, learning projects,
      and community service, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> provides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> with the tools to
      face those challenges and make sound decisions. Please join me in making
      a generous contribution to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Campaign</ENAMEX>. Invest in the
      future of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> - the future of us all.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Starla A. Tigg Development Committee Chair</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
