
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 4</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
      Dear :
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts Opportunity of Hoosier 'Capital Council</ENAMEX>' would like to
      invite you to join us in an investment in our future business and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community leaders</ENAMEX>. Because of your past support, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> has been
      able to reach out to more of our future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>-our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts of Hoosier Capital Council</ENAMEX> has a strong and growing
      membership. We are requesting your continued support, of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual</ENAMEX>
      Campaign to meet the needs of our growing membership.
      Your last gift was ~~~. Please consider an increase in your
      contribution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scout Annual Campaign</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> program offers an array of benefits to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and
      adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scouts of the U.S.A.</ENAMEX> commissioned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEC Associates</ENAMEX>
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Program Evaluators</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Consultants, Inc.</ENAMEX>) to conduct a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outcomes Study</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> program. The results were Overwhelmingly
      positive. Its findings include:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> helps girls build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> personal assets which research
      has shown to be essential for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s healthy development and well
      being. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> unites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>. Girl
      Scouting benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parent</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> relationships. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> benefits
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> by developing their leadership skills and self-confidence.
      Our ability to provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> program to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> and
      reach out to more girls depends on the generosity of a caring community
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like . Your investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> is sure to help
      build <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> today
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie A Pickens</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
