
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Girl Scout Memorial</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gift Fund</ENAMEX>
      In Honor of ... ... those special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have enriched our lives
      and will be remembered by you with us through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Girl Scout Memorial</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gift Fund</ENAMEX>.
      In Honor of... ...<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and loved ones, who may be honored through
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Memorial</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gift Fund</ENAMEX> on many special occasions --- birthdays,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anniversaries</ENAMEX>, graduations, engagements, marriages, and promotions.
      Contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Memorial</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gift Fund</ENAMEX> are used not only to
      perpetuate he memories of those no longer with us, but also to recognize
      good deeds and achievements.
      In Honor of... ....<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX>'s many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have been the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> of good wishes, we have enhanced our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and programs
      to increase the joy that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouting</ENAMEX> brings to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>.
      When a contribution is received, an acknowledgement is sent to both
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX> and the individual being honored. In the instance of a
      memorial gift, the card is sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of the deceased.
      Small contributions as well as large are encouraged, and all are tax
      deductible.
      Please use the attached contribution form and send a check today
      to:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial and Gift Fund GIRL SCOUTS OF HOOSIER CAPITAL COUNCIL</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1800</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Meridian Street Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46202</NUMEX>
      Share you gift with us.
      Send a contribution today
      In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Honor of... ...Girl Scouting</ENAMEX>.
      THE <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GIRL SCOUT MISSION</ENAMEX> "To inspire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> with the highest ideals of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, conduct, patriotism, and service so that they may become happy
      and resourceful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>."
      THE <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GIRL SCOUT PROMISE</ENAMEX> On my honor, I will try To serve god and my
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, To help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at all times, And to live by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX>
      Law.
      THE <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">GIRL SCOUT</ENAMEX> LAW I will do my best to be Honest, and fair, Friendly
      and helpful, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Considerate</ENAMEX> and caring, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courageous</ENAMEX> and strong, and
      Responsible for what I say and do, and to Respect myself and others
      Respect authority Use resources wisely, Make the world a better place,
      and Be a sister to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
