
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gentlemen:</ENAMEX>
      The goal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society, __</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX>, is to reach the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> of every business in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> with important
      <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> information. An informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and financially supported research
      program are the keys to the conquest of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      We are therefore requesting your cooperation. Our free educational
      programs can save lives. Encouraging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to practice breast
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-examination</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> to quit smoking are just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas of cancer
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>. The __ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> can help your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> save money by promoting good
      health practices.
      Our fight also needs financial support. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City/County</ENAMEX>)
      will have the opportunity for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to contribute
      to the fight against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. The donations will enable the __ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Unit</ENAMEX> to
      continue supporting the research, educational and service programs.
      Will you kindly use and return the enclosed envelope, and assure us of
      your enthusiastic participation in the continuation of the excellent work
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
    
  
