
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Mr. & Mrs. Two-Shoes:</ENAMEX>
      Why should you give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX>?
      If you have had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, you already know why. If you had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> or
      close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, you will appreciate our request for money.
      If you have been fortunate thus far, let me explain our need for your
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> donation.
      Over __ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> in __ <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> are diagnosed as having <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will be diagnosed with
      having <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point and time in their life. However, preventive
      measures can reduce the chances of one's contracting <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      Knowledge is a result of research which requires money, and your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">donation</ENAMEX> (or more, if you can) will assure continuation of this research.
      It's your are concerned about. Please use the enclosed envelope so we can
      help you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.K. Corral</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> My <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unit</ENAMEX>
      P.S. --- Enclosed please find a booklet containing lifesaving
      information.
    
  
