
  
  
    
      Dear Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>:
      <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Three a.m.</TIMEX> is a rough time to be needing a ride to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>...
      Some jobs nobody wants:
      (Name) has <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, and driving him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> in ___ for
      treatment is one of those jobs nobody wanted. Nobody except <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Cancer</ENAMEX> Society <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX> is a nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that helps
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">___ County</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX>
      also has programs of research as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> thru adult education
      programs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX> helps the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> through its
      educational programs, and it helps those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> who
      have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and have nowhere to turn.
      Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX> could use some community support. In
      order to continue our fine programs at the present level and, hopefully,
      to expand them in the future, we need your help. If you would like to
      help us keep going, please send a contribution in the enclosed
      envelope.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Neal Banister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B Unit</ENAMEX>
    
  
