
  
  
    
      I am sure you will understand my writing to you once more about the
      important work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX>.
      I know that as an important business and community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, you are
      frequently deluged with requests for funds from worthwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX> is, of course, such an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, but it
      is much more than just that. It is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> private, volunteer
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> that exists to end the menace of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, to ease the pain of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, to rehabilitate those who survive, and
      to enlighten and inform both the professional world and lay public about
      the latest developments in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      Support is needed both to maintain and expand these comprehensive
      programs. Please help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX> continue its vital
      work. I would most appreciate receiving your generous check made payable
      to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX> and sent to me in the enclosed envelope,
      if you have not already done so.
      Thank you very much.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
    
  
