
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 10, 1998</TIMEX>
      Mr. & Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Smith</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">123</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main Street Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46200</NUMEX>
      Dear Mr. & Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>:
      Holidays are a time for sharing. The sharing of love, of gifts, of
      goodwill towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. But for many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> that
      Visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nurse Service</ENAMEX> cares for, it can also be a troubling time. Nearly
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VNS</ENAMEX> receives a call about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in need of home
      care who has limited financial resources. Calls for help from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
      that need the crisis services <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">VNS</ENAMEX> provides for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> ring
      throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>. This is not the ringing that you and I
      traditionally picture during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday season</TIMEX>.
      But there is something you can do to help. With your gift of sharing,
      we can: provide needed home care services to the most, give emergency
      respite to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at risk for neglect or abuse, help
      establish a "Seniors to Seniors" program to provide companionship and
      homemaker services to homebound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
      Visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nurse Service</ENAMEX> has been a part of this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 85</NUMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Serving the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy</ENAMEX> has been an important part of our mission. Over
      the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VNS</ENAMEX> has delivered over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> worth of free
      services to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Central Indiana</ENAMEX>. But we can not do it alone.
      We need your help.
      A gift of sharing can bring comfort and hope to those most in need
      during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this holiday season</TIMEX>. I hope that you will join with us to help
      ease the suffering and indeed ring in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most joyous holiday season</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John L. Pipas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
    
  
