
  
  
    
      May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 1997</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST, Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Name</ENAMEX>:
      I want to thank you for your past support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visiting Nurse</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Foundation, Inc.</ENAMEX> It is through support from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> like
      yourself, that we are able to care for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> each year
      who may not otherwise have been able to afford proper home health care or
      even basic services.
      I wanted to briefly share with you some of the specific uses of the
      funds that are donated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. Our nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> has used funds for:
      buying prescriptions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who need them, but can not afford them;
      providing transportation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physician</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> for shut in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>;
      paying utility bills when there is an immediate jeopardy of shut off;
      medical supplies not covered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> or other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> and
      heaters for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>; and even basic needs like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> your memorial gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for hospice care in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> gave
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VNSF, Inc.</ENAMEX> the ability to address the needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> I described
      above. I am asking that you consider supporting our efforts once again
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> with a similar gift.
      Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX>, we have remained true to our mission of providing quality
      home health care to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> regardless of their ability to pay. By
      contributing again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, you will help insure we can continue our
      efforts to needy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Central Indiana</ENAMEX>. I have enclosed a return
      envelope for your convenience, as well as an overview of the services we
      provide. Thank you in advance for your consideration. I look forward to
      hearing from you soon.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John L. Pipas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
      Enclosures
    
  
