
  
  
    
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army 3100 N. Meridian Street Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">46208-4718</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1, 1999</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>,
      If The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red Shield</ENAMEX> could talk, it might tell you how
      we recently helped a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> get the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insulin</ENAMEX> he needed... a
      single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> purchase eyeglasses for her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>... or an
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly widow</ENAMEX> find the strength to face life on her own...
      I enjoy sharing these small victories with you through my letters.
      After all, your generosity makes them possible.
      I know that from my desk at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Salvation Army</ENAMEX>, I have a unique
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>, and I want you to know without a doubt that we are meeting
      needs -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> at a time, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> ... <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> round. And the
      scope of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Salvation Army</ENAMEX>'s services extends far beyond this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
      It blankets the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. It covers the globe.
      That's why I believe it's important for you to hear what people
      outside of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> are saying about The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX>. Over the
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, a number of well-respected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> have spoken out on behalf
      of our mission ... our service ... and our stewardship.
      By endorsing The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX> as a whole, they're supporting our
      efforts here at home, as well. I've enclosed a few of the excerpts I keep
      close at hand. After you read them, I hope you'll feel even more
      confident about the role you play in helping us help others.
      I hope your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, too, will continue its endorsement of The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX>. Your gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX> or more will help
      keep our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Red Shield</ENAMEX> a strong, reputable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> of hope -- for those we
      assist, as well as for those who are watching!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Blessings,</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack C. Getz Major DIVISIONAL COMMANDER</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Your gift to The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX> will be used right here in
      Central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
