
  
  
    
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army 3100 N. Meridian Street Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">46208-4718</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 1999</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST, Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Name</ENAMEX>,
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX> received a note not long ago from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who makes
      contributions to our programs from time to time. She'd been thinking
      about our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camping</ENAMEX> program for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      Her note explained that while driving through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> recently --
      in a rare moment when she didn't have a lot on her mind -- she found
      herself truly aware of her surroundings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lush</ENAMEX>, green fields that
      stretched for <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX>... wisps of white clouds scattered across a clear,
      blue sky... tranquil silence broken only by cheerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX> songs... the
      fresh, sweet scent of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> air. And she felt a sense of peace, for the
      <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>.
      What a contrast from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> she'd left <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> back. Filthy
      sidewalks where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> play. Boarded-up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live.
      Blaring sirens and horrendous crime. She recalled a report on TV the
      <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenager</ENAMEX> who shot an even younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> to death as
      part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> initiation.
      She has a hard time understanding why things like this happen -- why
      some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have no respect for life, not even their own.
      She wondered what would happen if she could take <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> from the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and place that youngster where she was now -- in the midst of this
      beauty and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">serenity</ENAMEX>. What would change for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>?
      That's when she thought about The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX>'s camping program.
      She remembered reading how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> spend a week
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every summer</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hidden Falls Camp</ENAMEX>. They spend most of their time
      outdoors, playing games with new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, discovering <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> they've
      never seen, and creating treasures from sticks, rocks and leaves. Here,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get their fill of good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, love and attention -- things many of
      them get too little of at home.
      With her note, she enclosed a check for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$230</NUMEX> to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to camp
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. She'd never given that much money before. But she was
      convinced it would make a difference.
      
      It's hard to explain exactly how <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> can change a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s heart. But
      I know it does.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> probably wonder what God looks like. If I could speak to them, I
      would tell them they can see a great deal of God in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and stars
      and streams that He created. When they're running with the wind in their
      faces and the sun on their backs... or stepping barefoot onto cool, green
      grass... they would begin to understand what I mean.
      I'm telling you all this because perhaps you, too, are asking
      questions -- why <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> takes the life of another... why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> feel
      so empty inside that they turn to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to fill the void... why they have
      so little self-worth that they value the friendship of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thieves</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>.
      And perhaps you're also asking, "What can I do?"
      I don't have all the answers. But I am certain of this: You can make a
      difference in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s life by sending a gift to The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX>'s
      camping program.
      It costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $230</NUMEX> to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>. That may sound like a lot. However, when you
      consider transportation, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, lodging, crafts, sports, counseling and
      much more, you realize it covers a lot (and equals what you might pay for
      <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a night</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of lodging at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>).
      If you can't sponsor a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> for a whole week, perhaps you can send
      enough for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> -- or even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just one day</TIMEX>. Your contribution may
      also be used to support our year-round programs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      You see, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> is only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step. Through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, we also offer
      a number of different programs -- including scouting, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and
      after-school activities -- to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> develop talents, character
      and self-esteem.
      Please <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prayerfully</ENAMEX> consider how much you can give... and give just a
      little more.
      I guarantee you'll feel good knowing you've helped us touch a heart.
      Perhaps you'll even save a life. At the very least, you'll give one child
      the chance to see God's face, and feel His love. Often, that's all it
      takes to change a life.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Blessings,</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack C Getz Major DIVISIONAL COMMANDER</ENAMEX>
      P.S. The list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who want to attend camp <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> grows
      longer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, and it's important that we send every one of them. With
      your help, no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> will be disappointed. Please send your most generous
      gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
    
  
