
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21, 1999</TIMEX>
      Dear Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Name</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX> is a single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 10</TIMEX>. He's never been
      on welfare and he's always had a job doing manual labor. Life isn't easy
      for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>, but he's determined to raise his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> himself and be a good
      role model for them. It wasn't always like that. There was a time when he
      felt like he had no choice but to tolerate his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s constant abuse and
      neglect of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX> decided the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> deserved a
      chance to start over in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, no matter how difficult it might
      prove to be.
      What happens when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are living on the edge -- barely able to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">survive –</ENAMEX>- and an unexpected emergency arises? What happens if they
      can't pay their heating or electric bill because of extreme temperatures?
      What happens if their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> get sick? What happens if they get
      sick?
      Starting over can be very hard -- especially for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't have
      family or financial resources to draw from in an emergency.
      That's why I'm writing to you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Through your financial support,
      you've already demonstrated that you want to help genuinely needy people
      begin anew. So, I'd like to give you one more way to make a difference:
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army Care Card</ENAMEX>.
      Although it can't be used to make purchases or withdraw money from an
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATM</ENAMEX>, the value of this Card could be immeasurable -- for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> whose
      life it might change.
      Here's how it works: Simply detach the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Care Card</ENAMEX> from the top of this
      letter and keep it handy. Then, if you know of or come across someone who
      needs our help, please give the card to him or her. It shows our address
      and phone number in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, but through our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Extension</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Office</ENAMEX>, we can put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in contact with the volunteer
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton County</ENAMEX>. We'll welcome their call and do our
      best to help them through the difficult time, so they can get on with
      their lives.
      And just as important, I invite you to renew your partnership with The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX> by sending a contribution, once again, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Your
      donation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX> or more will help us remain a steady
      source of assistance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>.
      Thank you for your continued financial support, and for remaining
      alert for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> who need a helping hand. God bless you for your
      compassion and kindness.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Blessings,</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack C. Getz Major DIVISIONAL COMMANDER</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Your gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> will help us care for struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, hungry
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX> and needy senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> right here in this
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
    
  
