
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 16, 2000</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST, Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Names,
      "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amazing grace</ENAMEX>! How sweet the sound..."
      The words of this familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hymn</ENAMEX> have echoed through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> all
      across the globe for over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace</ENAMEX> is sometimes defined as
      undeserved favor. Have you ever stopped to consider how grace is given to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>?
      I like to think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Salvation Army</ENAMEX> as a place of grace --where
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> find love and help in their time of need,
      regardless of the situations that bring them to us!
      ...<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> struggling with addictions find healing, forgiveness
      and the chance to make a new start in life... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> living from
      paycheck to paycheck find comfort, food and emergency assistance... and
      underprivileged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have the opportunity to eat well-balanced meals
      and participate in special activities.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">God</ENAMEX>'s grace is found in His forgiveness and unconditional love. In
      turn, we have the opportunity to extend that grace to others by meeting
      their physical and spiritual needs with kindness and compassion.
      Here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Salvation Army</ENAMEX>, this is our continuous goal.
      Maybe you can remember a time in your own life when you were shown
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grace</ENAMEX>... when someone reached out to you with answers you couldn't find
      yourself. Or perhaps a specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> comes to mind --such as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>,
      a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> --whose life is characterized by grace.
      When I think of grace, I am reminded of the many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who selflessly dedicate their lives to the poor
      and brokenhearted. In my years of working with The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX>, I've
      seen grace transform the lives of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Often, those who come to
      us for help have exhausted all other resources. But the love, assistance
      and guidance that we offer them hope for a better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.
      I can think of no better time to continue extending grace to others
      than at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>. This special season reminds us that God's mercy is
      available to each of us --regardless of who we are or what we we've
      done.
      In the same way, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Salvation Army</ENAMEX> offers grace and compassion to
      those in need in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> --regardless of the difficulties they may
      be facing. You've been so generous with your giving in the past, and we
      are grateful. Your additional gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> will enable us to provide food
      and clothing for physical needs... emergency assistance during times of
      crisis... spiritual guidance and encouragement... and much more.
      "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amazing Grace</ENAMEX>, how sweet the sound..." These words ring true in the
      hearts and lives of changed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Salvation Army</ENAMEX>. And just
      as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> of this beautiful hymn celebrates God's grace, so do
      we.
      On behalf of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Central Indiana</ENAMEX> who
      will benefit from your kindness, thank you. May you experience God's
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grace</ENAMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Blessings,</ENAMEX>
      Lt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Colonel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DIVISIONAL COMMANDER</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Please send your gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. So many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need our assistance.
      In appreciation of your generosity, I've enclosed a special bookmark
      printed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Newton</ENAMEX>'s familiar hymn, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amazing Grace</ENAMEX>."
    
  
