
  
  
    
      Name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> (if applicable) Address <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Salutation</ENAMEX>:
      Who helps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX> way help <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy</ENAMEX> learn responsibility and
      self-esteem at an overnight camp?
      Or who helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX> break a cycle of violence and become a better
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>?
      Or who helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> learn important job skills that will enable him to
      become self-sufficient?
      Or who helps <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>, who has spina bifida, learn to talk, dress
      himself, and get around independently?
      Without you. no one.
      And we need your help <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to make sure these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> are there
      for you, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hancock</ENAMEX>,
      Hendricks, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morgan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>.
      I am writing you in the hope of getting your support for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> campaign. The funds raised by the campaign support a family of
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">83</TIMEX> health and human service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that provide services like family
      counseling, care for abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, scouting and youth programs, job
      training, disaster relief and much, much more.
      Your generous support is very important. Here are just some of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> your gift can touch lives right here in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>:
      A gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> could mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> friendly visits to a homebound elderly
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. A gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> could mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of
      domestic violence and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. A gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> could mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> of
      overnight camping for an underprivileged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. A gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> could mean
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX> of shelter and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> for a homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> touches the lives of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 3,100</NUMEX> central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> people
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">365 days a year</TIMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you are generous. Here
      are some quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose lives were touched by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>:
      "After losing my job due to downsizing, I lost my home, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and
      nearly everything I owned. You arranged for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to see a doctor
      and to have her <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medications</ENAMEX> renewed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX> provided bus
      tickets for me to go to interviews. You treated me with dignity and made
      me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> feel there was hope for the future." -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
      "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Big Brother</ENAMEX> acts like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, but since he's an adult I get to
      make use of all his experience. We do fun stuff that we both like. No
      matter what we do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX>, I always seem to learn an important lesson."
      -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew</ENAMEX>
      "If it were not for the services they provide us, the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>
      would not be able to get around to do our business, such as visits to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">grocery</ENAMEX> and drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>." -<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel</ENAMEX>
      Who helps these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>? Without you. no one.
      When you give to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>, you can rest assured that your gift will
      be used efficiently and effectively to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in need here at home.
      Knowledgeable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community volunteers</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just like you -- ensure that
      your gift is spent wisely and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX> PERCENT OF FUNDS RAISED GO TO HELP
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PEOPLE IN NEED RIGHT HERE IN CENTRAL INDIANA</ENAMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, you gave us a contribution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$xx</NUMEX>, for which we, and the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you helped, are grateful. Please find it in your heart to renew
      your pledge or, if possible, increase it. Just check the appropriate box
      on the enclosed pledge card and return it in the reply envelope.
      Thank you in advance for touching a life and helping to make our
      community a better place to live, work and prosper.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen A. Stitle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of Central Indiana</ENAMEX> Campaign
      Chair
      P.S. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>'s ultimate success comes down to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> like you
      and me and how we respond to human need. We must all do our share! Please
      support our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> campaign.
    
  
