
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 20, 1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John E Prospect</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Main St. Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46200</NUMEX>
      Dear Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prospect</ENAMEX>:
      You can help <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> gift.
      And your gift is needed now more than ever.
      Your one gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of Central Indiana</ENAMEX> supports <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">82</NUMEX> human
      service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> right here in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. Only if
      you contribute <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> can these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> continue to provide programs
      and services that:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strengthen Families</ENAMEX> -- Help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse & neglect,
      answer crisis hotlines, prevent family violence & <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> the
      mentally ill;
      Invest <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Our Children</ENAMEX> -- Provide child care, scouting & youth
      programs, foster care & adoption as well as mentoring &
      counseling for teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>;
      Serve <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Elderly And Disabled</ENAMEX> -- Provide meals & visits to the
      homebound, as well as speech, hearing & physical therapy for people
      with disabilities;
      Help <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">People Become Self-Sufficient</ENAMEX> -- offer shelter for homeless
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, disaster relief, employment & training, neighborhood
      support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> & specialized transportation;
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promote Health And Well-Being</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Administer</ENAMEX> immunization programs
      provide <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug & alcohol</ENAMEX> treatment, screening for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, heart disease
      & other conditions and provide health education & <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> nursing
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>.
      Odds are that you, a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> may already be
      benefiting from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>
      listed at the left.(see hard copy). EACH YEAR, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITED WAY OF CENTRAL</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INDIANA AGENCIES</ENAMEX> HELP MORE THAN <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">PEOPLE</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hendricks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Morgan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>.
      Your gift matters to all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, who lived as a homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White River</ENAMEX> until he was helped by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horizon House</ENAMEX>. Gifts to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>
      helped provide <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelter</ENAMEX>, medical care, counseling and job placement to end
      his homelessness.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levi</ENAMEX>, who was born with spina bifida and
      unable to walk or talk until he received therapy at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crossroads</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rehabilitation Center</ENAMEX>. Now he gets around, talks, and even attends a
      public preschool.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">74-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX>, who keeps active by playing bridge
      and taking classes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>, aerobics and sewing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage</ENAMEX> Place.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX>, who was able to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX> thanks to the
      mammography early detection program at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Red Door Cancer</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophronia</ENAMEX>, who was abused by her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> before she
      and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> received shelter and counseling from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Julian</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ALL OF THESE PEOPLE RECEIVED MUCH-NEEDED HELP, BECAUSE PEOPLE LIKE YOU</ENAMEX>
      GAVE TO <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNITED WAY OF CENTRAL INDIANA</ENAMEX>.
      Your gift, no matter what the size, can benefit the lives of people
      here in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. Here are just some of the services your gift can
      buy:
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.81</NUMEX> provides a hot, nutritious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> aged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>+.
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23.32</NUMEX> provides <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> visits by a trained home health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to an elderly
      homebound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$69.70</NUMEX> provides <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 hours</TIMEX> of vocational evaluation & training for
      an unemployed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16</TIMEX> or over.
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90.58</NUMEX> provides the cost for one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to participate in
      scouting activities for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$146.50</NUMEX> provides <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 hours</TIMEX> of services to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> aged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> to help her
      or him overcome a learning disability.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">YOU CAN HELP SUPPORT THESE AND OTHER NEEDED SERVICES HERE IN CENTRAL</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INDIANA</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX> needs are increasing and your help is needed more than ever.
      Please consider giving a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$__</NUMEX> to help your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>
      here in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> who benefit from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
      Just fill out the enclosed pledge card and send it with your check in the
      return envelope right away.
      Any gift you can send is appreciated and will be put to good use
      helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who really need help right here in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      Thank you in advance for your generous support.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sallie W. Rowland 1994 United Way of Central Indiana</ENAMEX> Campaign
      Chair
      P.S. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">YOUR TAX-DEDUCTIBLE CONTRIBUTION WILL BE USED EFFICIENTLY</ENAMEX>. 90
      cents of every dollar you donate go directly to programs and services
      that help your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> here in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
