
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picture</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Indiana 3901 N. Meridian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">St. P.O. Box</ENAMEX>
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88409</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46208-0409</TIMEX>
      Cecilia desperately searched for medical care for her unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
      She would have a better chance of getting help and delivering a healthy
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX> if she lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecilia</ENAMEX> lives in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cecilia</ENAMEX> might even be your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>.
      Dear:
      When I found out that the infant mortality rate in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">86</NUMEX>
      percent greater than for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>, I was shocked.
      Later, my distress hit home in a personal way when I discovered than
      an expectant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> who lived just a few blocks from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">County</ENAMEX> - a young, unmarried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> just like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cecilia</ENAMEX> -- had difficulty
      obtaining prenatal care.
      Realizing the seriousness of the problem helped motivate me to join
      with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> like you who have helped to prevent needless suffering
      in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> by contributing to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of Central Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      When a young, unmarried <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecilia</ENAMEX> becomes pregnant, the risks
      to her unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> are very serious. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cecilia</ENAMEX>'s case she had to face
      the situation with a limited education, no skills and no source of
      income. Would it surprise you to learn that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than two years</TIMEX> away from
      the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">millennium</TIMEX>, the problem of supplying prenatal care to young, single
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> is one of growing concern in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>?
      Of those beginning prenatal care in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> trimester, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> rank in the lower <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> receiving such care
      nationwide. And that's just one significant example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> need.
      There are many other important areas where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX> need our help.
      Having exhausted all of her options, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecilia</ENAMEX> turned to her family
      priest where she found support and guidance. Cecilia was brought to a
      residential outreach maternity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of Central</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. When I investigated all the different ways I could get involved
      to help local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, I discovered the answer that made the most sense
      was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of Central Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>, and ONLY <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>, regularly conducts research in our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> to find out where the most important needs are. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>
      didn't do this it wouldn't be done at all. At <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Elizabeth</ENAMEX>'s home,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cecilia</ENAMEX> received a place to live until her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> was born. She received
      prenatal care, child care training, friendship and peer group
      support.
      Your past contribution provided a direct line of support for local
      programs that promote health and wellness, strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, invest in
      our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> become self-sufficient, and serve the elderly
      and disabled.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cecilia</ENAMEX> gave birth to a healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boy</ENAMEX>. Whenever she looks at her
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> she feels grateful to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> for the good start she was able to
      give him.
      And that's why I'm writing to you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. I urge you to continue to
      make a difference in the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecilia</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>.
      You can literally help save a life. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">89 percent</NUMEX> of the at-risk pregnant
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> served by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Elizabeth Home</ENAMEX> have given birth to healthy
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>.
      Following the birth of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cecilia</ENAMEX> received job training at
      another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. This story ended happily... perhaps
      because of your past contribution. Remember, just <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.16</NUMEX> per month
      can provide a homeless. expectant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> visits to an
      obstetrician for Prenatal care.
      Thanks to the support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of Central Indiana</ENAMEX> receives from
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> stories like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cecilia's</ENAMEX>. But
      unfortunately there are also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of</NUMEX> examples where vital services
      were not available because of lack of funds.
      Please continue with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> to see to it that no expectant
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> goes without medical care... no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> goes without nourishment ...
      no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> goes without shelter.
      Will you help? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>?
      If you would consider increasing your past pledge by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $25</NUMEX> this
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> it would be wonderful. If you could possibly increase your pledge by
      even more, I would be overjoyed. But please join us again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> so
      that stories such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cecilia's</ENAMEX> can continue.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of Central Indiana Campaign Chair</ENAMEX>
      P.S. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today Cecilia</ENAMEX> is self-supporting. She lives with her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-month</TIMEX> old
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in a clean, cheerful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Without the support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of</ENAMEX>
      Central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cecilia</ENAMEX>'s story might not have had such a happy ending.
      Please join with us to see that happy endings do continue.
    
  
