
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 18, 1997</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Marion Co.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'93-95 Donor</ENAMEX>:
      I'm writing to tell you about an investment opportunity. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> that will
      allow you to change pain into relief, anger into love, despair into
      opportunity -- and assure you that you'll be making central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> a
      better place to live, work and prosper.
      It's not just any investment. It's an investment in our community
      through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of Central Indiana</ENAMEX>. An investment with many returns of
      relief, love and opportunity. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, your investment is more
      important than ever.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> can touch the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> in need AND
      demonstrate an impact on our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s urgent needs. That's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>'s impact begins with research that helps answer important
      questions:
      What are the most important human needs here in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>? What
      programs can be funded to effectively reduce those needs?
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that asks, and answers these
      questions. And by doing this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> makes your investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">count</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human</ENAMEX> needs are on the rise in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and we have to meet the
      challenge. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> we've set an ambitious goal -- <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$31.75 million</NUMEX> --
      which is over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> more than our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> total.
      Why is your investment so important? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, your investment
      helped:
      Strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">96</NUMEX>) of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">106</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in parenting
      classes at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Service Association</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse, reported
      increased use of positive discipline and decreased use of abusive
      discipline.
      Teach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">96%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">173</ENAMEX>) of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">177</NUMEX> at-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> enrolled in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s early childhood program demonstrated an increase in their social,
      emotional, physical, cognitive, speech and language development.
      Make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> self-sufficient. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87%</NUMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">325</ENAMEX>) of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">344</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless families</ENAMEX>
      (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,353</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>) assisted and sheltered at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Social Services</ENAMEX>' Holy
      Family Shelter found independent housing.
      These good things happened in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> because people
      like you cared enough to make an investment in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
      And it's not just about programs. You're investing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, as well.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> who otherwise wouldn't have anywhere to turn. Here are some quotes
      from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have been helped by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of Central Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agencies</ENAMEX>:
      'If it were not for the services they provide us, we older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX>
      would not be able to get around to do our business, such as visits to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">grocery</ENAMEX> and drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>.' -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 72</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Thanks</ENAMEX> to the job training I received, I've learned the skills to get
      and keep a job, and take care of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> on my own. ' -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle</ENAMEX>, age
      34
      'I was able to get pre-natal care and have a healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. Not only
      that, I learned how to care for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> after she was born. ' -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>,
      age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17</TIMEX>
      These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are living proof that your investment pays off.
      Your investment is used efficiently -- <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">88%</NUMEX> OF FUNDS RAISED ARE
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INVESTED DIRECTLY IN SERVICES</ENAMEX> THAT <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">HELP MEET CRITICAL COMMUNITY NEEDS</ENAMEX>.
      This is much more efficient than most other non-profits and
      government-run programs. Your money counts when you invest through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Way</ENAMEX>.
      Your investment is critical to making our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> a better place.
      According to our records, you invested <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX> in the past, but we haven't
      heard from you recently. Please find it in your heart to renew your gift
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> if at all possible. We need everyone's help to make our goal
      and meet our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s increased needs.
      Just fill out the enclosed pledge card and send it in the return
      envelope <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. And be assured that you've made a good investment -- an
      investment that benefits all of us.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J. Alley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way of Central Indiana Campaign Chair</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Your investment helps serve the elderly and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX>, too. Last
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">64</NUMEX> physically <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled adults</ENAMEX> who received occupational therapy
      at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Crossroads Rehabilitation Center</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">58</NUMEX>) improved their independent
      living skills. Your tax-deductible contribution can make a measurable
      difference!
    
  
