
  
  
    
      Some of the strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of our welfare system are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
      have become dependent on it.
      Their complaint: the system discourages working because unemployment
      provides benefits that many entry-level jobs don't include.
      That's where you --and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> --come in. We help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> train for
      and find jobs that make it possible for them to get off of welfare. Last
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> placed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">511</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in jobs, more than double the number we
      placed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.
      While the debate on welfare reform is gathering like a storm at sea,
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who need jobs are floundering. We need your support to
      continue getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off of public assistance.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Welfare</ENAMEX> is not the answer. And welfare reform is an uncertain solution
      with an unknown starting date. Goodwill works. Right now.
      Please give the largest gift you can to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Dustman Chairman</ENAMEX>
    
  
