
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1998</TIMEX>
      ...totally off of welfare. I really like my job." -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry</ENAMEX>
      wanted to be there ...I had my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> chance to change my life." --
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX>
      Because teaching a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to fish will keep him fed for his entire
      life.
      "Before I got to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX>, I was on a mission. I just wanted a job. It
      didn't matter what the job was, I just wanted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Now, I'm on a journey.
      I've got more than a job; I've got a career. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> played a role
      like no other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> I've ever had I appreciate everything that
      Goodwill has done for me." -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornell</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX>, we help <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who face tremendous obstacles.
      Their <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> common goal: they all want to work. A robust economy helps by
      providing job opportunities, but to be honest, most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
      aren't working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are quite simply the ones who face the greatest
      obstacles.
      The kinds of services we provide help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX> like
      health care, transportation and child care -problems that are big enough
      on their own without being compounded by factors like physical and mental
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disabilities</ENAMEX>, illiteracy and lack of job skills.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> helped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find jobs that increased their
      self-sufficiency. Your gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> will be used directly to support
      services that will help even more find jobs.
      Right now, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do not know what it feels
      like to support themselves. You can help them to know that feeling.
      Please help <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> and help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> find jobs. Use the enclosed card
      and give a generous gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James M. McClelland President</ENAMEX>
    
  
