
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 10, 1996</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Mailhouse</ENAMEX> donor reminder:
      You and I have done some important work together.
      We've helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> break free of the welfare cycle. We've found ways
      for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with disabilities to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>. We've expanded
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwill</ENAMEX>'s proven methods to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and neighborhoods where they are
      needed most.
      Of course, we've played different roles. You have helped make
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwill</ENAMEX>'s work possible with your previous support. Goodwill has devised
      the programs that turned your investment into results.
      Who has benefited from our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>? Everyone has. When you and I
      help somebody find a job, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> joins the ranks of tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX>,
      fewer tax dollars are spent on public assistance and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> gain
      another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX>.
      There are a lot of barriers that keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from working: physical
      and mental disabilities, history of welfare dependency and lack of
      education or self-esteem. And there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who face these
      challenges <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> of their lives. So our work must continue.
      Everyone benefits from the work we do together. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need our
      help.
      Please continue our important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>. Support <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> with a
      generous donation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James M. McClelland President</ENAMEX>
    
  
