
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 17, 2000</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST, Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> was released from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, he knew it would take hard work
      and determination to straighten out his life. He knew he had made a bad
      mistake, but despite his commitment to rebuilding his life, he just
      didn't count on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">obstacles</ENAMEX> that would be thrown up in his path.
      Reality hit when he was unable to reconcile with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and ended up
      on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>. He went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Center Township Trustee</ENAMEX> for food stamps
      until he could find a job and a place to live. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trustee</ENAMEX> referred him
      to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Triangle</ENAMEX> where he consulted <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX>'s Career <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX> staff
      for job search assistance.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill caseworker</ENAMEX> found him a job immediately. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>'s
      troubles didn't end there. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> construction job he obtained soon
      ended, and he returned to Career <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX> for help once more. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unemployed</ENAMEX>,
      homeless and with a prison record, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry now</ENAMEX> faced going back to prison
      for failure to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support.
      It took some time and hard work, but with the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill, Jerry</ENAMEX>
      was able to work out a payment plan with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, find
      housing and conduct a more thorough job search.
      With unemployment at its lowest point in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>,
      many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still have a hard time finding meaningful employment. Of the
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 42,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> Goodwill served in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 5,000</NUMEX> of them have
      multiple barriers to finding and keeping a job. Some, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>, are
      ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX>. Some are blind, deaf or have other physical disabilities.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 100</NUMEX> were homeless.
      But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwill</ENAMEX> offers hope even to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with numerous obstacles to
      overcome, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>. With a promising new job at a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> injection
      molding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, his legal troubles in check and a safe place to
      live, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> can get on with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of building a life for himself
      and contributing to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. For as long as he needs it, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX>
      will continue to help.
      Your support of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> will provide job training and placement
      services to help the hardest to serve in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> find meaningful
      employment. And, with your assistance, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> can help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>
      develop resources to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> on the job.
      Please make an investment in the stability of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> by sending
      a gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX>. Your generosity will help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> help themselves.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James M. McClelland President</ENAMEX>
    
  
