
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear ,</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few months ago</TIMEX> you received a letter from me telling the success
      stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who got jobs with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX>'s help.
      Here's another story of success from what might seem like an unlikely
      source: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Juli</ENAMEX>. She tells me that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3,666</NUMEX> people
      we helped find jobs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> earned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $49 million dollars</NUMEX>. In
      addition to that, by helping them find jobs, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> reduced the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
      Public Support tab by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an estimated $4 million</NUMEX>. Your gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> will
      help us do even more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> because your gift will be used to directly
      support our work.
      What kind of work does <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> do?
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodwill</ENAMEX> finds jobs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with mental and physical disabilities.
      After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen</ENAMEX>'s job <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> taught her how to do her job in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>,
      we helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen</ENAMEX> step out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shadow</ENAMEX> sometimes cast <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
      physical and mental disabilities and find a fulfilling job smack dab in
      the middle of society. Remember what she said in my last letter? "If I
      wasn't working here...I would be sad..."
      Goodwill helps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get off of public assistance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry</ENAMEX> learned
      through our Future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Works</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> that she could rise out of the mire of the
      welfare system and support her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> she gained in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-confidence</ENAMEX>, in her vision of her future and in the job skills she
      needed to find and keep a good job. "Coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> was the first
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">welfare</ENAMEX>."
      Goodwill prepares <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for life-long employment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell</ENAMEX> found a
      number of employment options that he never dreamed existed after a
      work-site injury forced him out of his job at a foundry. He trained in
      desktop publishing and combined his enthusiastic work ethic with
      new-found skills in a burgeoning industry. "I've got more than a job;
      I've got a career."
      Goodwill provides jobs at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX>. After a lifetime of trials, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX>
      not only earned her GED at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX>, she earned a job here. "I rode a
      bike to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and snow. I wanted to be there...I had my
      <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> chance to change my life."
      Your gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> will help the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who want to tell their
      own stories of success. Your support will help them go to work.
      Please use the enclosed envelope to give a generous gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William A Carter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodwill Industries Foundation</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Your gift is a wise investment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. For every dollar
      donated to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Goodwill</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, we helped our "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>" earn an estimated
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$102</NUMEX>. That money was then spent in a variety of ways, adding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> to our
      thriving economy.
      
    
  
