
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21, 1999</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear ,</ENAMEX>
      Do you remember the combination of elation and apprehension you felt
      when you first left home? The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> who leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasant Run</ENAMEX> have
      those same feelings. Very few have family support to get them started.
      Many need furniture, linens and other basic necessities to begin lives on
      their own.
      To help them establish themselves in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasant Run</ENAMEX>
      Emancipation fund was begun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> by private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> who wanted to
      provide a measure of financial support for those leaving our
      programs.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> who are being emancipated are eligible to receive up to
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fund</ENAMEX> if they formally apply and meet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> requirements: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>.
      Release by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> 2. Successful completion of all life skills tests
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Positive termination of his or her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasant Run</ENAMEX> program <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>. Possession
      of a high school diploma or GED
      Proof of meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> staff reference letters and an essay
      stating why they should receive a grant and how it will be used are all
      reviewed by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasant Run</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>, which determines if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX>
      merits the funds.
      Such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> are often used for college tuition, vocational training or a
      deposit on an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>.
      Because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasant Run</ENAMEX> is the only "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>" for so many, our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emancipation Fund</ENAMEX> is one way we can help a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> take the first
      steps into his or her new life as an independent and productive
      adult.
      Without private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> support, this Fund doesn't exist. Please take a
      few <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to send a donation to help one or more of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
      successfully cross that threshold into the future.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Roth</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
    
  
