
  
  
    
      It's hard to believe that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday season</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two months</TIMEX> away.
      At <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pleasant Run</ENAMEX>, Inc. we are making plans and arrangements for our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in our
      community-based programs. These programs focus on keeping the family
      together by providing counseling and other services to the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      After our caseworkers meet with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they
      often find they lack even the basic necessities such as cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">utensils</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beds</ENAMEX>, cleaning supplies, etc. We meet these needs immediately. But, the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> season is a particularly difficult time for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. They
      do not have the resources necessary to purchase gifts or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> meal.
      We are asking you to consider sponsoring one of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> for this
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">holiday</ENAMEX> season. If you are interested and would like more information,
      please contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Lusk</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Whited</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">693-9222</ENAMEX>. We would like to
      have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> matched with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> non later than xxxx. Thank you for
      considering this opportunity to make this a memorable <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday season</TIMEX> for
      a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in need.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
    
  
