
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 1998</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BOYS & Girls Club OF INDIANAPOLIS</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>,
      It's summertime, so it must be time for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">CAMP</ENAMEX>! Yes, it's that time of
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> -- the start of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys & Girls</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>'
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camp</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six weeks</TIMEX> of learning and exploring, sports, arts, and fellowship.
      A time for a youngster to enjoy the fun and benefits of residential camp
      living, dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and instruction, and a chance to make special
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
      
      I know you're committed to ensuring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have safe,
      healthy, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">positive summer</TIMEX> experiences. That's why I want you to learn
      more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Summer Safari Camp</ENAMEX>.
      At <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Summer Safari Camp</ENAMEX>, there are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> sports, nature, and arts
      activities. In addition to the fun stuff, important life-skills such as
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-esteem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, and interpersonal cooperation are being
      developed. Please read the enclosed brochure for more information on the
      wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Summer Safari Camp</ENAMEX>!
      It costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$225</NUMEX> to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Girls Clubs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> can't afford to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> without
      financial assistance, and that's why we need you!
      Please make camp possible for all deserving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
      send in a tax deductible contribution <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the enclosed envelope.
      Consider sponsoring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1, 2</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. No matter the size of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">donation</ENAMEX>, please know that your gift will be appreciated and make a
      difference.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Dickinson</ENAMEX>
      P.S. You can make a difference in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s life. Sponsor a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> at
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys & Girls Clubs of Indianapolis</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>!
      
    
  
