
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> 25,1997
      Dear Name,
      What a Summer!
      And we're just getting started!
      I hope you'll consider continuing your support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jameson</ENAMEX>'s special
      campers by renewing your last gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ xxx</NUMEX>. I can tell you we need your
      help now as much as ever before.
      All of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six summer</TIMEX> camping sessions are booked to capacity (and,
      truth be told, with maybe one our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> extra returning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> squeezed
      in) and we have a waiting list of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who are hoping to come if a
      spot should open. Many more camper referrals are coming from new
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> such as school social-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and family counseling
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>. It seems summer options aren't readily available for troubled
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have limited incomes, so we're doing all we can to
      make <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Jameson</ENAMEX> available.
      That "we" includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Youth Leadership teens</ENAMEX>. These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60 or so</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campers</ENAMEX>
      have takenon a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund raiser</ENAMEX> with a goal of raising <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,000</NUMEX> for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camperships</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> of them told me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that as a group they decided
      they had to earn the right to ask others for help by accomplishing
      something real to help themselves. And that's from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> see
      as a problem.
      Even after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> sessions come to a close, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jameson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> will
      take part in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-round</TIMEX> programs designed to keep that positive contact
      with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> and role <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> alive and important. We've scheduled more than
      15 follow-up camper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> and going around till
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summers camping season</TIMEX>.
      Please, consider renewing your support of these great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Marsh</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
      P.S. We know our follow-up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> are going to be better attended
      than ever <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX>. If you can give a little more to help
      meet this increased expense we would appreciate your support.
      
    
  
