
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10, 1997</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Name</ENAMEX>,
      Confidence. An understanding that, above anything else, success
      requires genuine effort, a willingness to set challenging goals. Caring
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> others.
      These are the attributes we want all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to have. You help
      Jameson <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> reach for them. If these special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are to become
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> we all need them to be, we have to lead them in the right
      direction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Jameson</NUMEX> points the way for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who need that extra hand and I
      hope you'll continue your support <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. You're last gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50.00</NUMEX>
      helped make it possible for us to provide guidance, encouragement and fun
      to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 400</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> area <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. And not just during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>,
      but throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.
      What has your support of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> meant to them and what have they
      been able to accomplish because you care?
      The best indicator I can give you of the positive effect our
      year-round contact has is the growth in and deeds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youth Leadership</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just the past few years</TIMEX> this program has grown from a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
      and a few extra activities to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 60</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> taking on
      real projects. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> will make <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juniors</ENAMEX> happen again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> for
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 and 8 year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">campers</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five day</TIMEX> camp, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juniors</ENAMEX> introduces
      at-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jameson</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years earlier</TIMEX> than we could previously
      reach them. That means we now have the opportunity to be a stable,
      positive and important part of each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s life for an entire
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> have also decided to raise money to provide camperships for
      other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> because they know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jameson</ENAMEX> has meant to them. And their
      activities aren't isolated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jameson</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> have undertaken a
      volunteer project to regularly visit with sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at a local
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX>.
      Please consider renewing your gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> need your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> now more than ever. If you can increase your last donation, we
      would appreciate that show of support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> and their efforts
      to overcome obstacles and create successful lives.
      Thank you again for helping point the way.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Marsh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Director</ENAMEX>
      P.S. You make it possible for us to help special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with learning
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disabilities</ENAMEX>, behavior problems and economic disadvantages to gain the
      confidence required to put genuine effort into achieving real goals. I
      hope you'll continue -- and if possible increase - your support for these
      great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
    
  
