
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11, 1997</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Mr./Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Name</ENAMEX>:
      We need your help in continuing the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jameson Camp</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jameson</ENAMEX> is a not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> established in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX> to serve the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> of central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> who have special needs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> offers <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer</TIMEX>
      residential programs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 7-17</TIMEX>, and continues contact
      with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">campers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with special <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> and weekend
      follow-up events during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the school year</TIMEX>.
      All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> are referred by social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselors</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>. Many of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> have learning disabilities, behavioral problems, or come from
      economically distressed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. The goal of our organized camping
      experience is to improve the total health of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> socially,
      emotionally, and physically.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jameson Camp</ENAMEX> is planning an <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inaugural</ENAMEX> fund-raising event:
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jameson Grill</ENAMEX>! This event is designed to be fun for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">campers</ENAMEX>, their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and anyone interested in
      finding out more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jameson</ENAMEX>. In short, Fun for Everyone!
      The family-friendly event, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 20, 1997</TIMEX>, will include a hog
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">roast</ENAMEX>, activities for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, prizes for activities, and a small
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">raffle</ENAMEX>. Lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> can go home with a great <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX>. This is where we
      need your help.
      Can you help support this wonderful event by furnishing any type of
      products or services that can be used as prizes for our activities or as
      a raffle <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prize</ENAMEX>? Your contribution will help with funding so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jameson Camp</ENAMEX>
      can continue providing the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-round</TIMEX> camping experience that gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
      a chance to create dreams.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is a form you can complete and return to us in the
      postage-paid envelope. Or, you can fax us at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">241-2760</ENAMEX>, or e-mail,
      icfundrzr@aol.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>. Your quick response will help us begin organizing our
      prizes. After we receive your commitment, we will contact you about
      picking up your contribution. If you have any questions, please call me
      at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">241-2661</ENAMEX>.
      We appreciate your support of our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> event of this type.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Bray</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX>
      Help <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Blaze The Trail</ENAMEX> -- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jameson Camp</ENAMEX> Thank you for your last
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> Fund Gift!
    
  
