
  
  
    
      July30,1999
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ratcliff</ENAMEX>:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCI</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">federation</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> neighborhood-based multi-service centers
      whose mission is to identify and meet the human service needs of
      residents throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County</ENAMEX> in the most effective, efficient and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> way possible. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, we served a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31,484</NUMEX>
      low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> through job training and placement assistance,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and senior programming, family counseling, emergency assistance,
      and much more.
      As you can see from the enclosed map, your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> is located in
      the heart of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of our service areas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> that serve these
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary Rigg Neighborhood Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawthorne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Multi-Service Center</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christamore House</ENAMEX>, have teamed up to
      run an exciting job readiness program for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 and 15 year old</TIMEX> area
      residents called the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer Enrichment</ENAMEX> Program. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Between June 21</TIMEX> and
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 31, 45</TIMEX> youth will spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 hours</TIMEX> a week developing life management
      and work ethic skills, learning the computer, visiting area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>, and
      interacting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest speakers</ENAMEX>. The end result will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who have a
      better understanding of and vision for their own future, be it college or
      a career.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer Enrichment</ENAMEX> Program will conclude with a celebration that
      includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. We would like to offer our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> a small
      reward for their participation by presenting them with gift certificates
      from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX>. Therefore, we are asking you to donate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">45</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> gift
      certificates that can be used toward the purchase of school supplies or
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clothing</ENAMEX>, in the total amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450</NUMEX>. In return, we will recognize
      Target as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our</TIMEX> event and in the event program.
      Target is well known for it's support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and we believe
      that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer Enrichment</ENAMEX> Program represents your interests and concerns
      quite well. I will be happy to supply any additional information you may
      need and thank you for your consideration of our request. We look forward
      to hearing from you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valery De Long</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX>
    
  
