
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 30, 1999</TIMEX>
      Dear Name:
      Question What do you get in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">987,165 hours</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">291people</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15</TIMEX>
      locations?
      Answer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34,700</NUMEX> opportunities to change a life!
      This is exactly what happened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Centers</ENAMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> provided its comprehensive, neighborhood-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> all over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County</ENAMEX>. And we can do even more
      in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> with your financial support! Just look at the range of services
      we offer:
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70,0001</NUMEX> career assistance for youth Preschool for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
      School <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age Child Care for</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and youth Access services such as
      emergency and holiday assistance for all ages <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adult Day Care</ENAMEX> for seniors
      Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Case Management Aids Education</ENAMEX> for youth and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Involvement Computer Training</ENAMEX> for youth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> Senior
      Nutrition meal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">program Day Care</ENAMEX> for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Development</ENAMEX> and
      Recreation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HIPPY</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Instructional</ENAMEX>
      Program for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preschool Youngsters</ENAMEX>) for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. Stopover crises
      counseling for youth. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Services</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation</ENAMEX> for youth and seniors
      
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCI</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">federation</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> neighborhood-based multi-service centers
      (plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliate</ENAMEX>) whose mission is to identify and meet the human
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">service</ENAMEX> needs of the greater <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in the most
      effective, efficient and comprehensive way possible. Better yet, most of
      these services occur in cooperation with private and public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> from
      all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> - CICOA The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Access Network</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodwill Industries</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Housing Agency</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> Private
      Industry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family and Social Services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, OTC, Indy
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX>, and numerous community development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, neighborhood
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, to name <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just a few</NUMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 34,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> benefited from our services in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, and the
      final count for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> could be even higher. We're asking for a
      contribution in the amount of because you can't got a better bang for
      your buck than to support an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that impacts so many lives in
      so many ways. Your gift will enable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCI</ENAMEX> to provide these and other
      necessary services at a neighborhood level, face-to-face, where it
      counts.
      Please, make a tax deductible gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Centers</ENAMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, and know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">COMPANY</ENAMEX> is playing an important part
      in meeting the needs of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. If you have any questions, please
      feel free to give us a call at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">638-3360</ENAMEX>. We thank you for your
      consideration, and look forward to hearing from you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earline S. Moore President</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valery De Long</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
