
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MMM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F_NAME L</ENAMEX>_NAME <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">TITLE COMPANY ADDRESS CITY,ST ZIP</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4, 1999</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear LTR_NAME:</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCI</ENAMEX> has come a long way in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last five years</TIMEX>. We've worked hard to
      structrue the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> so that we've ready to move boldly into the
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next century</TIMEX>, and I believe that we have an exciting and successful
      future ahead of us.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the areas we've decided to focus on is development. It's clear
      that if we don't increase our base of private funding, we won't have the
      kind of control we need to ensure the continued success of our centers
      and the very important services they offer. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCI</ENAMEX> served <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">31,484</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> right in their own backyards. Where else would that many
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> turn if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCI</ENAMEX> weren't there to help?
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> initiatives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> is working with our development
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to put together a long-range fundraising plan that will ultimately
      bring more money into our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. This in turn will help us to increase
      and even improve the services we offer.
      With this in mind, I am asking each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of you to make a personal
      contribution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 or even $1,000</NUMEX> to show that you believe in the
      work that we do and are willing to support it with both your time and
      your finances. This way when we go out to ask for community support and
      are asked about our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> giving level, we can show our in-house
      commitment through <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> board participation. I also encourage you to seek
      additional support through your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, or service
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>.
      I know that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> will be happy to go with
      you to talk to these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> if you need their help. We're at an exciting
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">juncture</ENAMEX> and it won't be long until we start seeing solid results from
      our efforts. Your financial support of the development process is just
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step in making CCI a stronger, more efficient and ultimately more
      effective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">federation</ENAMEX> of service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>. Please, make your contribution
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.Chris Graffeo Chair</ENAMEX>
      P.S. If you have any questions, feel free to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valery De Long</ENAMEX> at
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCI</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">638-3360 x23.</ENAMEX>
    
  
