
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 4, 1999</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      The goal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCCOY, Inc.</ENAMEX> has been to make a difference. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MCCOY</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> led <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> efforts that, we believe, will help our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> continue
      to take the steps necessary to help all young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> grow up and develop
      well.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Participants</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Youth Outcomes Educational Initiative</ENAMEX> identified
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> goals for all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> to obtain: economic self-sufficiency,
      healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, social relationships, and involvement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. A
      short time later, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Youth Mapping Project</ENAMEX> sent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> young
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to identify the resources they need to grow
      up well: caring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, safe places to go, and positive things to do.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of youth, through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> very different
      processes, have arrived at the same conclusion; our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> still has
      much to do if we are to help ALL of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> successfully develop into
      the responsible, productive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> who will our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in the
      future.
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> of youth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCCOY, Inc.</ENAMEX> is here to support your
      valuable efforts to develop young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Recently, through a lot of hard
      work and alliances with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> like yours, some steps have been
      taken in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that will help young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> continue to be
      involved in positive activities. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IndyGo</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> adopted a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">much-needed</ENAMEX> policy that all young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under the age of 19</TIMEX> may ride on
      their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> at half the normal fare <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year long</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>, funding was made
      available <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> for youth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> to conduct
      positive youth programming on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> evenings. Through the youth
      mapping process, it was confirmed that the positive opportunities for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> evenings were lacking. That need is being met.
      As it has been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an exciting year</TIMEX> for all of us, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCCOY, Inc.</ENAMEX> cannot do
      its part without the support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> like yours. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annually</ENAMEX>, we
      ask several of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> serving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> to join us in our effort
      to help young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> grow up well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is a donation
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> that will enable you to make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> a great place for ALL of
      not hesitate to call me at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">921-1288</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Brandon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MCCOY</ENAMEX>, Inc.
    
  
