
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 7, 1996</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1993</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County Commission on Youth</ENAMEX> began
      what can best be described as a "new era" in its history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MCCOY</ENAMEX> was
      reorganized as an independent, not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, separate from local
      government. It retained, however, the same mission with which it had been
      charged from its inception: to serve as a catalyst for effective,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">coordinated</ENAMEX>, and collaborative service delivery to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> in our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
      For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MCCOY</ENAMEX> has been actively engaged in
      accomplishing this declared mission in cooperation with many others:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, funding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>, and interested citizens
      to name a few.
      We have met with a number of successes along the way, most notably the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summer Fun Line</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Metro Summer Bus Pass</ENAMEX>, and the development of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
      neighborhood youth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">councils</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Providers Council</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youth Coalition</ENAMEX>
      are building relationships that will hopefully bear great <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> in the
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come. The formation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Community Academy</ENAMEX>, a pilot project
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">directed</ENAMEX> at expelled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX>, has come about
      as a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCCOY</ENAMEX>'s efforts to mobilize community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> in response
      to a pressing issue.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCoy</ENAMEX> is actively represented and working with numerous community
      collaborations where we regularly raise our voice to speak out for the
      inclusion of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in both decision-making and program planning
      processes. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> concrete example is a joint project undertaken in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Northwest Area</ENAMEX> in partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Junior League of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> and Community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Partnerships</ENAMEX> with Youth from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Wayne</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are working with
      neighborhood youth and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> to build a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Caring Neighborhood with Youth</ENAMEX>"
      , mobilizing the assets of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> to build a
      better neighborhood for all.
      Since its re-organization, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MCCOY</ENAMEX> has established its unique niche
      within the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> by refraining from direct service programming and
      focusing on what it does best: helping to identify <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> needs, convening
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> which can address those needs,
      and moving toward collaborative solutions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCoy</ENAMEX> has only one interest:
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> being of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County</ENAMEX>'s young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCoy</ENAMEX> invites the support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The __ Company Foundation</ENAMEX> in the amount
      of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000.00</NUMEX> to support such activities as:
      ---- the co-ordination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth leadership</ENAMEX> training and youth
      empowerment efforts at the neighborhood level by means of
      neighborhood-based youth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">councils</ENAMEX>; ---- the promotion of youth employment
      opportunities; ---- the facilitation of ongoing discussions regarding
      effective and efficient youth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> delivery;
      ---- the provision of technical assistance and guidance to
      neighborhoods which seek positive youth-adult relationships;
      ---- the development of community-wide supports for the positive
      growth of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County</ENAMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several years</TIMEX>, the business and corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> has
      recognized that the positive development of youth is directly related to
      the development of a competent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Youth</ENAMEX> who are supported and
      encouraged by both a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and a society that values
      
      Them have a much greater likelihood of becoming productive and
      contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of adult society. While we have made significant
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inroads</ENAMEX>, there remains much to be done and it is clear that we cannot do
      it alone. We seek the financial support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> to help us be
      successful in creating the atmosphere in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> where young people
      can grow and develop well. Your contribution will enable us to both
      continue and expand the good work we have begun in making <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> famous for its commitment to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
      In our fund raising efforts to date, we have received the support of
      local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> as well as the personal
      financial commitments of individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCCOY Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. We believe there
      is no more appropriate time to have a coordinated and collaborative
      effort to financially support the services MCCOY offers to the community
      as a whole.
      Thanking you in advance for your support, we remain,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John T. Neighbours Philip B. Roby</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Treasurer</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Brandon</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
    
  
