
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 5, 1997</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Bill</ENAMEX>:
      This is the time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> when our thoughts turn to ways to do things
      differently, things that will make our lives better and improve the
      quality of our life. As you begin that process <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, I would like to
      ask you to consider helping young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County</ENAMEX> toward more
      positive youth development by becoming a supporter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County</ENAMEX>
      Commission on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youth, Inc.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCCOY Inc.</ENAMEX>, originally founded as a government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> but re-organized
      in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> as an independent not-for-profit, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX>-wide youth services
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coordinating</ENAMEX>, planning, and convening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. Its purpose is to encourage
      collaboration and cooperation between the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, programs, and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> that serve our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>. In addition to that
      behind-the-scenes role, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MCCOY</ENAMEX> has taken an out-front role in developing a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Summer Bus Pass</ENAMEX>, neighborhood youth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">councils</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">We Value Youth</ENAMEX>
      information line. It is our goal that every young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County</ENAMEX>
      have access to the programs and services that can best assist them in
      their growth toward a positive adulthood.
      I am hopeful that you as an individual and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meridian Insurance</ENAMEX> as a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corporation</ENAMEX> might consider becoming sustaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCCOY</ENAMEX>. I
      have enclosed a packet of information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MCCOY</ENAMEX> and its work as well as
      an application with various options for supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> of our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
      I obviously can't tell the whole story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCCOY</ENAMEX> in a single letter but
      I hope this provides an overview of the scope of our work. I will call
      you in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX> to discuss your level of interest. Please consider
      joining together with your fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> in support of the work of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County Commission on Youth</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Brandon</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
    
  
