
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 27, 1998</TIMEX>
      Dear Name:
      Join us for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sale</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JCC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Auction '99</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>,
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 13, 1999</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">9th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> JCC Auction will benefit the numerous
      scholarship programs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish Community Center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. Because you are an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that cares, you are
      invited once again to be an integral part of this fabulous event as a
      corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> for JCC Auction '99.
      We are so grateful for your generous contribution to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s
      auction. Your continued participation is very important to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JCC</ENAMEX>, as we
      work to build <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and our not-for-profit
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX>, you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> will have a special <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>,
      knowing that your tax deductible contribution will help support
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">preschool</ENAMEX>, childcare, senior and resettlement services, as well as
      quality cultural events in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is a corporate sponsorship package that includes a sample of
      your ad from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s auction book, current JCC market statistics and
      an overview of the many JCC programs that will be preserved and
      strengthened through your generous support.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of us will call you to discuss how your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> can continue to be
      an important, highly visible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JCC</ENAMEX> in support of our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrna Weinberger</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">251-9467</ENAMEX>, ext. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">256</NUMEX>. Thank you in advance for your
      consideration.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Laikin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chair Auction '99 Sponsor Committee</ENAMEX>
    
  
