
  
  
    
      
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, Zip
      Dear Name,
      It's tough growing up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. We know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do better when they
      have a network of caring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> to nurture and motivate them. When young
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have that support, they need other resources for
      encouragement to guide them along the way. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX> helps <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> that
      gap by providing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with the resources they need -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who empower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> to more fully
      reach their potential, experience life's opportunities and perhaps begin
      to dream. The relationships that are formed provide strong foundations
      from which healthy values and strong self-confidence can grow, helping
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> become strong, independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> we will serve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> through our mentoring
      programs. This is an impressive number; but for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> served, more
      are left unserved. Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are currently waiting for a Big
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>.
      You can make an impact by supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters Annual Campaign</ENAMEX> and
      our <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> goal. If you are a regular contributor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual</ENAMEX>
      Campaign, I encourage you to consider increasing your gift by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>. If you
      have not supported <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX> in the past, please join me in doing so by
      completing and returning the enclosed pledge form.
      Early adolescence is the most vulnerable age for youth. But caring
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> like you can reach out and help. It's the perfect time to make a
      world of difference.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      
      
    
  
