
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 6, 1998</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Adolescence</ENAMEX>. It is a pivotal time in the life of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>-when
      small changes in her behavior, or the choices she makes, can affect her
      future. It's hard enough for her to make good decisions when she's
      surrounded by support. It's even harder when she isn't.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX> helps fill that void by matching caring, responsible adult
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> with at-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages 8-14</TIMEX>. A Big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>, a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> and a role model, helping a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> to develop the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">self-confidence</ENAMEX> and life skills necessary to become a responsible,
      productive and successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX>. Your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> contribution can put a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mentor</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s life-and hope in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s future.
      The results of an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-month</TIMEX> study completed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public/Private Ventures</ENAMEX>
      showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> participating in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother</ENAMEX> matches for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just one year</TIMEX>, reduced <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX>;
      lowered school absenteeism by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52%</NUMEX>; cut aggressive behavior by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX>;
      enhanced school performance; and improved relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
      This is positive proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> mentoring program
      helps change lives. Today, we are offering you the opportunity to help
      change a life. By contributing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> you can support one match for one
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. This money maintains the infrastructure that fosters and supports
      the development of effective relationships. This includes a volunteer
      screening process, orientation, training and ongoing supervision and
      support by a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.
      As a Matchmaker you will receive a description of "your match" and be
      identified as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matchmaker</ENAMEX> on a plaque in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big Sisters office</ENAMEX>, in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">agency</ENAMEX> newsletter and annual report.
      Today <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX> serves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. But for
      each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> served, more are left unserved. Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">235</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are currently
      waiting for a Big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>. Imagine the difference the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> could make
      if each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregation</ENAMEX> pledged its support of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX> match!
      I encourage you to Join me in presenting this matchmaker challenge to
      your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congregation</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda McCoy Pastor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">THE GARDEN A Blossom</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Luke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist Church</ENAMEX>
    
  
