
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 10, 1999</TIMEX>
      Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Caring Philanthropy 01234 Giving Way Contribution</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> 56789
      Dear Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philanthropy</ENAMEX>,
      "The urgency you feel to make changes is just the extent that change
      will be made. Do not sit this one out. Do not play it safe. Understand
      the world and change it where it needs to be changed... Make our society
      better. Make a world worthy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> will
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bear</ENAMEX>." -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Sagan</ENAMEX>
      You can help make positive changes in the lives of at-risk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> in
      central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. We often hear about economic poverty, but what some of
      these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are growing up with is emotional poverty-they have
      often given up on hope and the possibility of a successful future. With
      your help, we can change that.
      Many <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Little Sisters</ENAMEX> are preparing to go back to school this fall full
      of hope and with a positive outlook. Thanks to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volunteers</ENAMEX>, these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are self-confident, believe in themselves
      and are beginning to realize their full potential. A recent study by
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public/Private Ventures</ENAMEX> (PPV) showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who had a Big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> for
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just one year</TIMEX>:
      reduced first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46%</NUMEX> lowered school absenteeism by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52%</NUMEX>
      cut violent behavior by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33%</NUMEX> enhanced school performance showed improved
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">peer</ENAMEX> and family relationships
      Former Little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX>, now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18-years old</TIMEX>, is a testament to the Big
      Sisters program.
      "I was matched with my Big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June of 1992</TIMEX>. Since then, she and
      I have grown very close and I have been able to experience lots of new
      things. We go to movies, dinner, concerts, and other stuff like that, but
      I have also been able to participate in charity events and fundraiser
      type things.
      Not only did I have a lot of fun with my Big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sister</ENAMEX>, but I learned a
      lot from her too. I have become more open-minded, more responsible, and,
      most importantly, I have gained a lot more self-confidence. I am very
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thankful</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX> program for allowing me this very special
      opportunity.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX> served <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">972</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> through its many
      programs. But the need is still great. Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are still
      waiting for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor</ENAMEX>.
      You are an important part in making sure these young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
      matched with caring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult mentors</ENAMEX>. Will you make a financial gift to Big
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sisters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> that will ensure that more young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> receive the
      guidance they need, that more young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, stay off drugs
      and make good choices?
      Your contribution will be used to recruit and retain quality
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>. It will also be used to help maintain the infrastructure that
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fosters</ENAMEX> and supports the development of effective relationships,
      including volunteer orientation and training and ongoing supervision and
      support by a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> your gift can go farther!
      Gifts of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> or more will be matched thanks to a special 25th
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anniversary $100,000 Challenge Grant</ENAMEX> and will be placed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Growth For</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls Fund</ENAMEX>. This fund will support the goal of having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">550</NUMEX> mentoring
      relationships by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1999</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,200</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2004</TIMEX>.
      If you would like to find out more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX> program,
      please call us, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">317</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">634-6102</TIMEX> and ask for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Robinson</ENAMEX>. Thank you very
      much for your time, attention and consideration.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew T. Burns Patron Relations</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairperson</ENAMEX>
      P.S. When you give to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Sisters</ENAMEX>, you can get <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> back! For a minimum
      contribution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX>, you become eligible for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> state tax
      credit through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Department of Commerce Neighborhood Assistance</ENAMEX>
      Program (NAP). A limited number of credits are available. To receive an
      application form, check the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> on the enclosed pledge card or call
      us, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">317</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">634-6102</TIMEX>, ext. 20.
    
  
