
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 29, 1999</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invest</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youth Campaign</ENAMEX> is in full swing. As a former board
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> is still important to me. We must be able
      to reach all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> interested in values-based programs. The
      Invest in Youth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> helps insure this.
      New initiatives in the inner-city are taking hold. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Mission</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX> is reaching out to middle school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> with programs based on
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">caring</ENAMEX>, honesty, respect and responsibility for themselves and others.
      For some, these are very different messages from the ones heard in the
      street. They are learning to make positive choices concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tobacco</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and to support each other when those choices are
      challenged.
      You have shared in the vision and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Indianapolis</ENAMEX>. I now invite you to continue to support the mission
      and the message that is so important to building strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, strong
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and strong communities. Please consider joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>'s
      Roundtable with a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>. I have enclosed a pledge card for your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convenience</ENAMEX>. We would like to announce the success of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s
      campaign at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Annual Meeting</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27</TIMEX>, so please return you pledge
      or gift within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 30 days</TIMEX>.
      Thank you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard H. Gilbert, Jr.</ENAMEX> Past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
