
  
  
    
      
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 25, 1999</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX>:
      It's hard to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is beginning and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Autumn</ENAMEX> will be here
      in just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few short weeks</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> are back in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> enjoying
      the fun of renewing friendships and activities interrupted by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">summer</TIMEX>
      vacation.
      However, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> are wrestling with the problem
      of providing a safe and caring environment for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> during,
      before and after school <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. You can help.
      It is not widely recognized that in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> there are families
      in need. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamilton County YMCA</ENAMEX> awards over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> in
      scholarships to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who are at or near poverty. Many of these
      scholarships are for before and after school care for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of working
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.
      The funds for these scholarships come from concerned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> like
      you who contribute in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Invest</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youth Program</ENAMEX>. Please consider
      a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> or more to help insure that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> will be
      in safe, age appropriate activities before and after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Give a youth
      a chance to receive help with homework, healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX>, and value-based
      programs that are fun. Every dollar you give goes directly to
      scholarships for youth in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
      Together we can build strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, strong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and a strong
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
      Thank you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam McConey</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamilton County YMCA</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
