
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 16, 1998</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greetings</ENAMEX>):
      It is with great pleasure that I take this opportunity to share with
      our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> family some of the wonderful activities and accomplishments of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Committee</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. We continue to stay active in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>, in the rebuilding of life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX>, and with our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sioux</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian YMCA</ENAMEX>, sharing the strengths that each of us possess, so as to
      strengthen both of us in the process. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">life-changing</ENAMEX> experiences that
      are made possible because of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA International</ENAMEX> work will remain with the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> who participate for a lifetime! Thank you in advance for
      helping to keep our outreach and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX> alive!
      Please take a moment to look over the highlights of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>!
      Partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX> - In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, we continued our efforts
      to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX> re-establish after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 years</TIMEX> of civil war.
      Thanks to a generous contribution from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Retired YMCA</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executives</ENAMEX>, partial funding was made available for us to host an
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Camp Counselor</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugenia Langford</ENAMEX>, a
      staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX>, spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire summer</TIMEX> working at the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly YMCA Outdoor Center</ENAMEX>. While there, she was provided with
      program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, and management training and experiences and a wide
      variety of opportunities to work in various roles at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.
      Partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latvia YMCA</ENAMEX> - A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Indianapolis</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latvia</ENAMEX> in
      late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> to provide additional training to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>
      in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> skills and camp management. A highlight of their trip was
      visiting a new, remote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> location and helping them get started with
      their programs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruth Lilly YMCA Outdoor Center</ENAMEX> hosted an
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Camp Counselor</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latvia</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> young
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Latvia</ENAMEX> were our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> to
      participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA World Camp</ENAMEX> program.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Alliance</ENAMEX> of YMCAs - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Wells</ENAMEX>, long time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Indianapolis International Committee</ENAMEX>, was nominated to represent
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> as a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult delegate</ENAMEX> to the 14th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Council</ENAMEX>
      in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>. As a result of his participation, he was
      nominated to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Committee</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Camp</ENAMEX> 1998 - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Indianapolis</ENAMEX> hosted 9
      International young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> - 3 from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Latvia</ENAMEX>,
      and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Camp</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. During their
      visit with us, they worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> and day <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, enjoyed homestays,
      toured the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> area, and visited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX>. The highlight of
      their experience in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 16-22</TIMEX>, when the
      International <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> attended a regional
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Camp</ENAMEX> program at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA Camp Potawotami</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Wayne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IN.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sioux Indiana</ENAMEX> Cultural Immersion Program -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susie Davis</ENAMEX>
      and staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Hill</ENAMEX> led a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX> who spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> at
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sioux Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">S. Dakota</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second year</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Susie</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> received an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Outstanding International Leader Award</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> for creating this program in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX> also named
      it an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outstanding International Program</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA International Conference</ENAMEX> -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegates</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>
      staff attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA International Conference</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toronto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> in
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Representatives</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">43</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> were in attendance.
      Workshops focused in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> initiatives around the globe such as: community
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, refugee relief, teen programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> sports, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX>, and
      much more. While there, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> spent extended periods of time
      with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Kamei</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">General Secretary</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>) of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Service Fund</ENAMEX> Raising -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">All YMCA International Programs</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Service Projects</ENAMEX> are funded through special fund raising efforts of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Committee</ENAMEX>. The primary funding source
      is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA International Open</ENAMEX>, which will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 1999</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pebble Brook Golf Club</ENAMEX>. Please call <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">266-9622</ENAMEX> and
      ask for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> to register your foursome early.
      I hope that you agree that these activities are essential to being a
      part of a world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. The most important way to express that
      approval is through a financial contribution to support the work of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Committee</ENAMEX>. Your support is vital and your generosity will
      make a real difference.
      "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Therefore</ENAMEX>, since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>,
      let us lay aside every weight and the sin that clings so closely, and let
      us run with perseverance the race that is set before us..." Hebrews
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-2</ENAMEX> With best wishes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holidays</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie Kile Love Michele Goodrich International Committee</ENAMEX> Chair Vice
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
