
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 29, 1999</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST, Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      Thank you for visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruth Lilly YMCA Outdoor Center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camp</ENAMEX> is now
      in full swing and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are having a great time.
      We would like to give middle school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> who are part of our Urban
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission Branch</ENAMEX> a chance to participate in an outdoors experience. The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opportunities</ENAMEX> presented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruth Lilly Outdoor Center</ENAMEX> offer these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
      learning experiences not available in the inner-city environment. Please
      consider a grant of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> in support of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> weekend
      adventures for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> will include team course,
      environmental education, and self-esteem <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> for youth ages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
      through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>.
      A critical transition takes place between <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">3rd</NUMEX> grade and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">8th</NUMEX> grade
      - elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. A survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 36,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Prevention Resource Center</ENAMEX> found that
      <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of substance abuse begins with this age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
      Therefore, this age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> continues to need more adult supervision and
      positive programs during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">after school hours</TIMEX>. Many skills and life
      patterns, which are key components for self-sufficiency, are formed
      during this period.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Mission Branch</ENAMEX> was established to address this underserved
      age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX>'s goals focus on increasing the percentage of youth
      who: Grow into mentally and physically healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>; Know how to
      structure their lives in ways that produce meaning and enjoyment; Plan
      their high school program to allow them to qualify for future higher
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, even if the current goals are vocational; Use non-violent
      conflict resolution skills when needed; Reach adulthood without being
      involved in alcohol, tobacco and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use; Are able to develop and
      achieve their goals and aspirations.
      The initial programs have been very successful and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> has been
      invited into more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Center Township</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> program, which
      has experienced immediate results, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sista Friends</ENAMEX> program. Designed
      to resemble a sorority, this project emphasizes active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> involvement
      in character education to reinforce the enduring values of caring,
      honesty, respect and responsibility. In this way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> seeks to
      fulfill its mission: To put <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> principles into practice through
      programs that encourage personal growth and build health of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>, mind
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> for all.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greater Indianapolis</ENAMEX> RLYOC-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Mission</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 29, 1999</TIMEX> Page
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
      Educational outreach, tutoring services, family planning and mentoring
      are provided in an ongoing and systematic approach to these inner-city
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> who participate are selected with the help of school
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">counselors</ENAMEX> and other community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> that serve as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX>
      staff trained in conflict resolution and adolescent programs guide the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> through a process of skill and esteem <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sista Friends</ENAMEX> is
      based on a similar model that has experienced great success in other
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">urban</ENAMEX> areas. The young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> targeted for this program are from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School #</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stonybrook Middle School</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethel Teen</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers</ENAMEX>.
      The program will be evaluated using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>'s Youth
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development Survey</ENAMEX> based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Search Institute</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youth Asset</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model</ENAMEX>. The
      survey will be conducted at the fall and again at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring weekend</TIMEX>.
      Anticipated outcomes from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> survey include: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> of youth will
      report increased supervised time in safe environments. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> will report increased conflict resolution skills. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> will have established short and long-term goals for self
      sufficiency in adulthood as measured by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> checklists. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> will report a minimum of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 hours</TIMEX> per week doing homework
      outside of school. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> will report doing community
      service work on survey. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> will indicate that being in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> has helped them stay out of trouble. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX>
      will indicate that since they have been coming to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX>, caring about
      other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> has become more important to them.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>, there will be significant new initiatives to
      organize community resources and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX> for youth development. The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> has the experience, resources and track record to be in the
      forefront. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YMCA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> can influence these constructive efforts in
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to expand youth development programs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoover Family</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> can help us begin with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX>, inner-city young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.
      Thank you for your continued support of community-based projects which
      have an impact.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberta L. Donahue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>
      Enclosures
    
  
