
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer 1997</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>:
      The good news is that the teen-age birth rate has fallen <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 9%</NUMEX>
      since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. The bad news is we have a long way to go. Less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> nationally have anything approaching a comprehensive sexuality
      education program. Yet, study after study has shown that unresolved
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">curiosity</ENAMEX>, not knowledge, is more apt to lead to early sexual
      involvement. The mission of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Health Association of Central</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> is "to promote healthy behavior and responsible relationships
      through sexuality education and life skills training. our education
      programs are abstinence-based, factual and encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to make
      responsible choices."
      The degreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educators</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Health Association</ENAMEX> provide
      in-school presentations in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> areas:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Growth & Development</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sexually Transmitted Infections</ENAMEX> (including <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>)
      Life <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Skills</ENAMEX> (conflict resolution, assertiveness, peer pressure and
      decision-making)
      These programs are provided at a price far below actual cost. Each
      <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour</TIMEX> of instruction costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $100</NUMEX>, of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way Of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Indiana</ENAMEX> pays <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX>. The balance comes from fees, special events,
      grants and individual gifts. Thus, your gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Health</ENAMEX> is vitally
      important to our success and can accomplish the following:
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> will pay for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> of programming.
      *<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$160</NUMEX> will pay for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> program for an entire grade.
      *<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$240</NUMEX> will pay for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> programs in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> grade.
      *<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> will pay for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> program for an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      A list of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> served during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996-97 school year</TIMEX> is
      enclosed. You may designate your contribution to a specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> if you
      choose. Your support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Health Association</ENAMEX> can help us make a
      real difference in the lives of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      Thank you so much for your help.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy K. Haskell</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
