
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Each day</TIMEX> you participate directly and indirectly in a search for a
      cure for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> through your work with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walther Cancer Institute</ENAMEX>. By
      sharing your expertise, you join a network of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> committed to
      finding ways to eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> as a cause of suffering and death.
      Once a year, we ask you to consider supporting the mission of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> in another way -- through a charitable contribution.
      Just as a disease as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> will not be cured by just one
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> university, finding better ways to prevent, treat
      and eventually cure <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> will require support from all of us.
      Please use the enclosed form and envelope to send a contribution
      through a check or credit card. Or, you may use payroll deduction to make
      your gift.
      Your gift may be restricted to the research area of your choice.
      Please indicate the specific research area on the enclosed form. In
      addition, please provide your phone number in case we have any questions.
      Gifts designated for a specific area of research are matched on a
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-to-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> basis by a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> established by our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX>.
      As with all gifts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> of your contribution will be
      used directly for research. Our endowment allows us to use your money
      exclusively for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> research, not administrative overhead.
      Please call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharyl Hamblen</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">921-2049</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Gattle</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">921-2056</ENAMEX> if
      you have any questions. Thank you again for sharing our hope for a future
      without <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happy Holidays</ENAMEX>,
    
  
