
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2000</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>:
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, we sent letters sharing with you a story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boys</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& Girls Club</ENAMEX>, a wonderful, positive place for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> in
      our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. We hope you had an opportunity to read about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX> and
      his time at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> before the letter became lost in the numerous pieces
      of mail <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> receives over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX>. The new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> is here, and it
      offers us an occasion to share with you another way your gift can touch
      the life of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>; many ride the vans
      and run into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with backpacks and books. One little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> runs
      in and gives a special hug to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Becky</ENAMEX>,
      is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years old</TIMEX> and lives with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. She often has a drawing or
      craft project which she made in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becky</ENAMEX> gives the "artwork" to our
      staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> who hangs the budding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s work on the office door. The
      staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> has mentioned several times to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becky</ENAMEX> that she should take
      the art <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky</ENAMEX> doesn't want to; she wants the staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to
      have it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becky</ENAMEX> is a friendly, bright little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who often gets confused
      and will refer to a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff person</ENAMEX> as "mommy". The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> can never
      replace a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>, but the caring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> can help fill the
      void in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Becky</ENAMEX>'s life during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the few hours</TIMEX> she is there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>.
      Touching the lives of youth on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> basis, helping develop new
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skills</ENAMEX>, and preparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to face the challenges of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>
      are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>'s strengths. And we need Your help to meet the
      challenge!
      Please help more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hamilton County</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky</ENAMEX>, know about a
      safe positive place for them in their non-school <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>. Won't you take a
      few minutes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and invest in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>. A contribution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$395</NUMEX> provides
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> participation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>; however,
      your gift in any amount can make a difference in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s life.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Crow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chair Sustaining Membership</ENAMEX> Campaign
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don McMahon Board President</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
