
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sudden Infant Death Syndrome</ENAMEX>, commonly known as "crib death," is our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s major cause of death for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year of age</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annually SIDS</ENAMEX> claims the lives of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">approximately 3,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. It is one of the more significant factors that places the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20th</NUMEX> among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> of the world in
      infant mortality rates. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX> is a public health issue of utmost concern
      to every new and expectant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>--and grandparent--in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      Although research is beginning to provide answers regarding factors
      that may increase the risk for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX> and suggest actions <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> can take
      to reduce the risks, these measures will not save all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>.
      We still do not know what causes <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SIDS</ENAMEX>, we cannot predict which babies
      are vulnerable, nor can we prevent all <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">SIDS</ENAMEX> deaths. Further research is
      needed and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> still need help.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS Alliance</ENAMEX> is a non-profit, tax exempt national voluntary
      health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, established <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a decade ago</TIMEX> to combat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">SIDS</ENAMEX>. The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS Alliance</ENAMEX> and its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affiliates</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are
      dedicated to eliminating SIDS through research, serving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>,
      and educating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX>. The SIDS
      Alliance meets all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Charities Information Bureau</ENAMEX> (NCIB)
      standards, and is listed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCIB Wisegiving Guide</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS Alliance</ENAMEX> has also received a high rating (A-) from the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Institute of Philanthropy</ENAMEX>, and has been named <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the top
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parenting</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parents</ENAMEX>
      magazines.
      Until our future is free from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS Alliance</ENAMEX> will continue to
      serve as a source of strength for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who
      have experienced the loss of a beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> for
      compassion and public understanding, and a catalyst for finding solutions
      through research. Our battle is far from over and we are grateful for
      your support of our efforts.
      We count on your continuing interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sudden Infant Death Syndrome</ENAMEX>,
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIDS Alliance</ENAMEX> and our programs. We need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> to help provide
      essential services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> whose lives are tragically changed by the
      loss of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>; and financial support to expand our public education and
      research efforts that will some day solve this mysterious threat to our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s lives. Please consider making a contribution to help us SAVE
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">OUR BABIES</ENAMEX>. The dream of a future free of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sudden Infant Death Syndrome</ENAMEX> is
      a gift we can give our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Thank you for helping make that dream
      come true.
      Do not hesitate to telephone us on our toll-free hotline
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-800-221-7437</ENAMEX>) if you have further questions.
    
  
