
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>:
      Thank you for requesting material from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Association of</ENAMEX>
      Kidney <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patients</ENAMEX>. We hope you find the enclosed material beneficial.
      I'd like to take this opportunity to invite you to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AAKP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> receive a membership package that includes all of our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">educational</ENAMEX> material, a subscription to aakp <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RENALlFE</ENAMEX>, membership in a
      local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> if applicable and assurance that your voice is heard in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>. I have enclosed a membership application for your use or
      you can call us at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">749-2257</TIMEX> to join <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      I hope you join our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, loved ones and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>.
      Your membership will keep you up to date on the newest advances in
      end-stage <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">renal disease</ENAMEX>. I look forward to seeing your name on our
      membership list.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris Robinson</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
    
  
