
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear ,</ENAMEX>
      Thank you for your interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Harbor</ENAMEX>.
      I'm enclosing some information on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Harbor</ENAMEX> which I hope
      you'll find interesting. We were founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> and Luanne
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX> who wanted to do something special for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> here on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>. Our mission is to strengthen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>, and we are
      now focusing our resources on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who have long-term, serious
      illnesses and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. We provide free counseling and support
      services to them through our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Birmingham</ENAMEX>, and we have camping
      and adventure services for them here on our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Martin Campus</ENAMEX>.
      Unfortunately, There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> each year who have a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> diagnosed with a serious illness at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Hospital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX>.
      The names of these illnesses are some of the most feared in our society:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, cystic fibrosis, renal failure - just to name a few. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX>'s
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harbor</ENAMEX> is working with many of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> to help
      them cope with the changes brought on by a chronic illness and to help
      them lead productive lives both now and in the future
      We are privately funded by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>, foundations -and others. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founders</ENAMEX> underwrite
      administrative and fundraising costs so that other contributions go to
      provide services to the, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
      me.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn J. Ray</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Relations and Financial</ENAMEX>
      Development
    
  
