
  
  
    
      May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25, 2000</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear ,</ENAMEX>
      I am writing to thank you for contacting Prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Child Abuse New York</ENAMEX>
      and to invite you to continue sharing our mission by becoming a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 48,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were abused and
      neglected -injured, molested, emotionally abused, denied adequate care
      and supervision. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each week</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> die from child
      abuse or neglect. Most are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and toddlers, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are
      overwhelmed. You can help.
      Join Prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child Abuse New York</ENAMEX> in protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. We are the
      only statewide not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> whose primary mission is child
      abuse prevention. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> , your voice will be added to those of
      others across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, with the message that we can and must create
      caring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> that support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and shelter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      You can help us help overburdened new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. Healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Families New</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> is an effective voluntary home visiting program We train <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> at
      sites across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> to develop the service for
      their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
      We provide help by phone <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24 hours a day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7 days a week</TIMEX> through the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prevention Information Resource Center</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Parent</ENAMEX> Help line. We promote
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compassionate</ENAMEX>, effective policies to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and prevent their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">maltreatment</ENAMEX> through our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Legislative Advocacy</ENAMEX>. We educate through Child
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abuse Prevention Month</ENAMEX> and other public awareness and media
      campaigns.
      All of this is possible because we are a statewide member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>.
      Please join us, by sending in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX>-application -<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>!
      When we receive your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX>, we'll send you a thank you gift, one
      of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Ribbon</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prevent Child Abuse</ENAMEX>" lapel pins. Please help us
      protect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      Thank you for your serious consideration of joining Prevent Child
      Abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. I'd be glad to respond to any questions you might have
      about our work. You may call me at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CHILDREN</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">518-445-1273</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine S. Deyss</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
