
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4, 1992</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIELD</ENAMEX>(contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIELD</ENAMEX>(address <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FIELD</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">city</ENAMEX>, state, zip)
      Dear Mr. & Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Name</ENAMEX>:
      It is wonderful to be able to write this letter to you as a special
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leukemia Society of America</ENAMEX>. As you know, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> Layton
      and I have been active in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leukemia Society</ENAMEX> since our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> was
      diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>. And now as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trustee</ENAMEX> for our local <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX>, I'm
      seeing first hand how our volunteer efforts are paying off for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>'s are expected to be a "break through" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> in the
      search for the causes and cures for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Hodgkin's disease</ENAMEX>, and
      related blood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX>. I can also tell you that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>'s will be a
      "break through " <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX> for us here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter</ENAMEX>. But we need
      your help! I'm writing to you as one of our strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> asking
      for a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100.00</NUMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX> so that we can fulfill our part in
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leukemia Society</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Research Program</ENAMEX>. If you, and just
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> others provide this very special gift, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Chapter</ENAMEX>
      will be able to honor our share of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leukemia Society</ENAMEX>'s national
      research commitment to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Taparowsky</ENAMEX> at
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue University</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yu-Chung Yang</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University Medical</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>. Mr. & Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Platter</ENAMEX>, you've always been there to help when
      we've counted on you. As we come to a close of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our fiscal year</TIMEX>, would you
      please help us again?
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Elliott Special Gifts</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.S. Nick</ENAMEX> is in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">remission</ENAMEX> and we're saying he's been cured. But not every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> is as lucky
      as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>. Your gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> really will make a difference in their
      lives!
    
  
