
  
  
    
      Keep <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Beautiful</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Thornburg</ENAMEX>
      Cordially invite you to our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Donor Recognition</ENAMEX>
      Luncheon
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keynote</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G/ Raymond Empson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, Keep America
      Beautiful
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, November 10, 1999 11</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">30am-1pm</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes & Thornburg</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Meridian Street</ENAMEX>, Downtown 9th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Floor Conference Room</ENAMEX>
      Thanks to all of you our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is a better, more beautiful
      place.
      We look forward to seeing you at our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> recognition event <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX> is
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">limited</ENAMEX>. Please <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSVP</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Jackson</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, November 2, 1999</TIMEX> at
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">264-7555</ENAMEX>, ext. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">102</NUMEX>.
    
  
