
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 8, 1999</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Jo Ellen</ENAMEX>,
      Though we at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Keep Indianapolis Beautiful</ENAMEX> enjoy sharing our story, we
      thought it might be a nice change for you to hear from some of the people
      who have worked with us to create positive changes in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. "Our
      corporate volunteer shirts read 'Making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community a Better</ENAMEX> Place to
      Live.' Keep <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Indianapolis Beautiful</ENAMEX> helps us do this by providing us
      opportunities to work with outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gould</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Federal Savings Bank</ENAMEX>) "We're a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that wants to
      create a presence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, and help it thrive. Keep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      Beautiful is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that helps us do that." (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Sullivan</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heartland Golf Cars and Equipment</ENAMEX>) "We are long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of Keep
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Indianapolis Beautiful</ENAMEX>. We're in it because we believe that as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>,
      we need to give back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that supports us." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dennis</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Kroger Company</ENAMEX>) We are proud to say that we have a long
      list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, many of whom have been long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>! "Why would I
      want to get involved," you ask? While we have accomplished a lot with our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>, fulfilling our mission of helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and beautifying the
      environment is a constant effort! Through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX>, Keep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      Beautiful and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 15,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> have planted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">502</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>,
      beautified <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">102</NUMEX> properties, painted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> homes, created <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>/gardens, and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">cleared 233</ENAMEX> neighborhoods of unsightly litter and debris. As we strive to
      continue and improve upon our efforts for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, it is our hope
      that you will join us by providing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keep Indianapolis Beautiful</ENAMEX> with a
      generous gift. Your contribution will help <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of people create a
      beautiful city <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, and for future generations. We have enclosed an
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">invoice</ENAMEX> to help facilitate your check. Thank you in advance for your
      generous donation.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Forsell Tammy Jackson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Contributions Manager</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Please remember to include <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Keep Indianapolis Beautiful</ENAMEX> in your
      budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>!
      
    
  
