
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3, 1999</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST, Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name,
      Would you find it rewarding to help fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>, who
      despite tremendous challenges, are striving to turn their neighborhoods
      around <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">180 degrees</NUMEX>? What if your contribution to Keep <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      Beautiful would only cost you <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10-25%</NUMEX> of its full value? It can be done!
      Keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Beautiful</ENAMEX> has been awarded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Assistance</ENAMEX>
      Program (NAP) state tax credits from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Department of Commerce</ENAMEX>.
      Please read on to learn more...
      Availability of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Assistance Program</ENAMEX> (NAP) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Tax</ENAMEX>
      Credits
      Keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Beautiful</ENAMEX> has been awarded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> of tax credits by
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Department of Commerce</ENAMEX>. We are able to offer these on a first
      come, first serve basis, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30, 1999</TIMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAP</ENAMEX> state tax credit
      chart is included to illustrate how the credits work. Your contribution
      is more than a simple tax-deductible donation. These credits help reduce
      an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>' overall state tax liability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Donors</ENAMEX> receive
      tax credits equaling <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of their contributions. So, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> donors
      receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> worth of NAP credits, reducing their state tax liability by
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>. In addition, the full donation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> can be itemized as a
      federal income tax deduction. An example: if you are in the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> tax
      bracket and choose to give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>, the federal deduction is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350</NUMEX>.
      Coupled with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> state tax credit, your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> donation costs just
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150.00</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 15%</NUMEX> of the value of the contribution! To many of our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">donors</ENAMEX>, the benefits seem almost too good to be true- but they are firm
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX> now!
    
  
