
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Audubon Society</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">700 BROADWAY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">NEW YORK</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">NY 10003</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>:
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Audubon Society</ENAMEX> make up only a small
      fraction- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than one</NUMEX> percent of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>.
      My hope is that you will want to join them. And for this reason I have
      enclosed an interim membership card already inscribed in your name.
      You are invited to accept this free trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX>, including a free
      issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDUBON</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> without obligation. Simply move
      the token on your invitation from the top to the bottom, detach along the
      perforation, and return it as soon as possible in the postage-paid
      envelope. Later, if you wish to continue as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, you may do so
      simply by paying our bill for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $20</NUMEX>. You may also take advantage of
      our special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-year</TIMEX> membership offer for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>, a savings of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">almost 60%</NUMEX> off
      our regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2 year</TIMEX> rate. Or you may cancel your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> and owe us
      nothing.
      As an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audubon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, you will experience the wonders of our planet in
      a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> widely considered to be the most beautiful published
      anywhere.
      At the same time, you will be helping to preserve those wonders
      through your support of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most effective conservation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
      There are other benefits as well, which I will outline in a moment.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">AUDUBON</ENAMEX> ...the beauty of a fine art book, the excitement of an
      adventure story.
      In a world of throwaway <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDUBON</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> is truly worth
      reading and worth keeping. Reading it makes you feel the same way you do
      after a walk in the deep woods, or a swim in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal</ENAMEX>-clear lake. You
      feel rewarded. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enriched</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uplifted</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDUBON</ENAMEX> radiates with magnificent color photographs. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 20</NUMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> it has been the premier showcase for the world's finest nature
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX>...the world's most thoughtful and motivating nature
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDUBON</ENAMEX> has won the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Magazine Award</ENAMEX> not
      once, but...<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDUBON</ENAMEX> will expand your world. It will bring the magnificence of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nature</ENAMEX>'s most breathtaking creations into your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. And, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDUBON</ENAMEX> will
      alert you to conservation progress and emerging environmental issues.
      In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adirondacks</ENAMEX> you canoe on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Raquette River</ENAMEX>, and quickly the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trip</ENAMEX> takes a radical swerve toward bliss. In the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early-morning</TIMEX> sun,
      silver lines <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> typically draw to represent a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">loon</ENAMEX>'s wake come
      alive. As we look into the sun, all is a silvery glitter, a captivating
      light show with this one color. Rounding a bend, with the sun now behind
      us, the show suddenly transforms to green moss, yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX>, blue-green
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conifers</ENAMEX>. Next bend, back to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX>. And at every upwelling of currents,
      interruptive <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree trunk</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>'s paw of wind, those silver lines
      intensify.
      It's the quintessential <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Adirondack</ENAMEX> scene -a favorite of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winslow Homer</ENAMEX>.
      But to be on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raquette</ENAMEX> in springtime pleases more than the eye. You
      are also drenched in birdsong.
      And as you share this bliss, this sense of place with the AUDUBON
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who actually experienced it, you begin to understand why we must
      preserve this beauty that is our heritage.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lonq live Spring Creek Prairie</ENAMEX>! Just outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>,
      there's a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">610-acre</NUMEX> tract anyone would love to call home. It's called
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring Creek Prairie</ENAMEX> and it's absolutely beautiful. Problem is, its acres
      of rare tallgrass prairie, wetlands, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">springs</TIMEX>, ponds and pristine creek
      and woods are already home to an abundance of wildlife and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s migratory <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>. Plus, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> artifacts are plentiful.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">..</ENAMEX>and ruts created by covered wagon traffic on the<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">- Oregon Trail</ENAMEX> are
      still clearly visible.
      To save this precious, historical land from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audubon</ENAMEX> worked
      with a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and purchased this land for preservation. In turn,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audubon</ENAMEX> will apply for a grant, so <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife</ENAMEX> will continue to
      flourish and so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> can come and enjoy this rare
      tract in all its natural splendor.
      In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wind River Forest</ENAMEX>, you float above ancient firs and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hemlocks</ENAMEX> in a construction crane gondola <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> stories high. You're cruising
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the least-explored realms on earth -the intricate web of life in
      the forest canopy.
      On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>. off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Cod</ENAMEX>, you scan the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pre-dawn</ENAMEX> pine forest
      with a high-tech microphone to solve a bioacoustic mystery: Why this
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">island</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chickadees</ENAMEX> sing a different song from all other chickadees in
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> !
      You share adventures like these in every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDUBON</ENAMEX> issue, exploring
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nature</ENAMEX>'s frontiers with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intrepid researchers</ENAMEX>. Finding his
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woods</ENAMEX> "infested" with an endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, the red-cockaded woodpecker,
      a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowner</ENAMEX> launched a preemptive strike. He simply
      clear-cut <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">600 acres</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">longleaf</ENAMEX> pine.
      There would be no more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX>, therefore no woodpeckers, therefore no
      annoying government regulations limiting his property rights just to
      protect a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>.
      Yet even this angry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">landowner</ENAMEX> wound up living happily ever after with
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Endangered Species</ENAMEX> Act. That's because the in- genius <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe Harbor</ENAMEX>
      Plan made the conservation worth his while.
      This plan is one more reason to preserve the perennially endangered
      <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Endangered Species</ENAMEX> Act -the most effective wildlife law ever passed.
      Will the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> live up to its environmental promises? Can we
      save the last of our ancient forests from the chainsaw? Is an economy
      based on non-fossil energy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> an achievable dream? What can be done
      to prevent more catastrophic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> spills?
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUDUBON</ENAMEX> keeps you in touch with vital environmental issues. You cannot
      touch, see, or hear the most important benefit of your Audubon
      membership.
      The most important benefit of membership in the National Audubon
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> gives you nothing immediately tangible in return. Nothing, that
      is, except peace of mind. Nothing except knowing that you are helping to
      protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s precious natural resources.
      Your dues directly support active and vital programs to protect
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wildlife</ENAMEX> and habitat, and help ensure a healthier environment.
      Quite simply, very few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> do more (or more important) work
      to save the balance and beauty of nature plus the acquisition and
      maintenance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife</ENAMEX> sanctuaries all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.
      Free admission to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audubon Nature Centers</ENAMEX> is another advantage of
      membership. You and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> will be awestruck by the sights and
      sounds along <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Audubon</ENAMEX>'s nature <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX> and wildlife exist
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">undisturbed</ENAMEX>. And where natural environments are protected from the
      depredation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audubon Nature Centers</ENAMEX> are among the most serene and pristine
      places on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. You can visit them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>.
      Local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapter</ENAMEX> membership, exciting adventure tours, special purchase
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opportunities</ENAMEX>, and more.
      Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Audubon Society</ENAMEX> membership also gives you the
      opportunity to be part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audubon Network</ENAMEX>. You can participate in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enjoyable</ENAMEX>, worthwhile activities with some very interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
      over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> chapters. One is almost certain to be in your
      area.
      You can make a difference by joining one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audubon</ENAMEX>'s conservation
      campaigns or programs.
      You can also travel with fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to fascinating places like
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chilean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patagonia</ENAMEX> at reasonable costs. And take
      advantage of offers on select <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audubon</ENAMEX> products. Here's all you have to do
      to begin receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AUDUBON</ENAMEX> at once, your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FREE CLOCK</ENAMEX> and enjoy all the
      other benefits of membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Audubon Society</ENAMEX>.
      Just lift the token on your enclosed membership invitation from the
      top right of the page. Press it firmly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">circle</ENAMEX> on the bottom left.
      Then detach the lower portion and return to us as soon as possible in the
      postage-paid envelope.
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, you'll get <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s worth of insightful AUDUBON issues.
      Plus, all other membership benefits. Plus, the satisfaction of knowing
      you are doing your part to preserve the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s precious natural
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX>. Later, after reviewing your free issue, you wish to become a
      permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>, you may do so, simply by paying our bill. As soon as we
      receive your dues, we'll ship out your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FREE CLOCK</ENAMEX>. Or you may cancel your
      membership and owe nothing.
      If you decide to continue, as I hope you will, you will be joining
      over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> of the most concerned, interesting, and informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on
      the face of this struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. I look forward to welcoming you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Flicker President</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Act <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to reserve your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FREE CLOCK</ENAMEX> and become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Audubon Society</ENAMEX>. You'll be joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> doing so much to
      help save our threatened planet <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. And at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $30</NUMEX>
      for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>, that's more value for less money than I've heard of in a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX>, long time! So please become an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audubon Society</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> now!
      P.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">S.S.</ENAMEX> We hope you enjoy using the enclosed postcards to show the
      world how much you care about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">wildlife</ENAMEX>.
    
  
