
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Springtime, 2000</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Friends</ENAMEX> of the pelicans,
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twelve</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby pelicans</ENAMEX> were hatched and raised <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> just outside
      our pens by the wild pelicans that hang around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seabird Station</ENAMEX>. (The
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38</NUMEX> permanently injured pelicans inside our pens are still waiting for the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U. S. Fish</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildlife Service</ENAMEX> approval before they can breed). One
      little pelican was abandoned by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in their haste to start a
      <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> mating and nesting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same season</TIMEX>. He was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two weeks</TIMEX>
      short of being old enough to fly, but still afraid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and very
      difficult to catch so that we could continue feeding until he was
      self-sufficient. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> of self-imposed starvation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX>
      cornered him behind an aviary and fed him, and he immediately jerked
      away, running and flapping to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>'s edge where he sat with a pouch
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">The next morning</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two weeks</TIMEX>, he was in the
      corner behind-the aviary waiting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>. Now he comes running out from
      there whenever he sees <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>. How quickly they learn bad habits! Our
      problem now is how to teach him to go out and catch his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> instead
      of waiting to catch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> behind the aviary.
      The smallest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby duck</ENAMEX> we have ever seen was brought to our door about
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks ago</TIMEX>. We think it is a wild <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mallard duck</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rescuer</ENAMEX> said the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX> abandoned this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. We put the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> in an indoor cage
      and fed it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a day</TIMEX> until we noticed that it was getting entirely
      too attuned to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, peeping a little greeting whenever someone passed
      his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX>. This can lead to a condition called imprinting, where the baby
      grows up thinking it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> instead of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX>. Although this results
      in a "cute" pet, it is a disaster to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> because it looks to people
      for its normal social interaction, even the most intimate kind.
      In an effort to avoid imprinting, we enlisted the aid of a regular
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">barnyard muscovy duck</ENAMEX> that was hanging around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seabird Station</ENAMEX>. We put
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby mallard</ENAMEX> in a small aviary with the half-grown muscovy, and it
      worked. We were delighted to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">muscovy</ENAMEX> sitting down and just the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby mallard</ENAMEX> peeking out from under its <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX>. The next day
      when we went out to the aviary we were concerned that we didn't see the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX>, even when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">muscovy</ENAMEX> stood up and walked to the other corner of
      the aviary until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> fell out from under its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> mallard
      will probably think it's a muscovy when it grows up, but that's better
      than imprinting as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
      <begin R12>=We've had=about 10=cases of=botulism among=the 105</txt>=<txt>      sick or injured pelicans that we've received in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two months</TIMEX>,
      which is about as many botulism cases as we normally get in an entire
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. We've only been able to save <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 5</NUMEX> of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>, by
      supporting them with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">I/V</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX> given through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> bones (the
      preferred method in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Botulism</ENAMEX> is caused by the toxins excreted
      from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> that sometimes occurs naturally when vegetable matter
      decays anaerobically (without <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oxygen</ENAMEX>) under the mud. It then bubbles to
      the surface of the water and a small amount is ingested by the pelican
      when he eats. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Botulism Research Laboratory</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> gave us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> doses of experimental botulism anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX> about
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>. The trick is to catch the botulism in the very early
      stages before the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX> attacks the nerves and causes progressive
      paralysis The problem here is that some paralysis is usually the first
      visible symptom. We'll let you know if this anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toxin</ENAMEX> turns out to be
      the silver bullet that solves the botulism problem.
      Our sincere thanks to all of you and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate & Jon Sage</ENAMEX> for
      another successful fish drive.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darlene & Harry Kelton</ENAMEX> and all the other pelicans
      
    
  
