
  
  
    
      May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23, 2000</TIMEX>
      Thank you for your recent inquiry about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental League of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. Enclosed please find background materials for your review.
      Founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898</TIMEX>, we are proud to be one of the oldest conservation groups
      in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
      Your support for our work would be greatly appreciated. It is only
      with the help of concerned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> that we are able to continue to carry
      out our mission effectively. With the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> like you, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELM</ENAMEX> will
      be here to preserve and protect the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> environment for many
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> receive our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> Bulletin, the best source of
      information on environmental issues in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> can also
      receive periodic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action Alerts</ENAMEX> on current issues by either regular mail
      or e-mail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> receive invitations to special events at various times
      throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>.
      If you would like to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">ELM</ENAMEX>, please fill out the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enclosed</ENAMEX> membership form and send it back at your earliest convenience.
      You may pay membership dues by check or with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX>, and all
      contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental League</ENAMEX> are tax deductible.
      staff at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">617-742-2553</ENAMEX>. Again, thanks for your interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">ELM</ENAMEX> and our
      environment.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christa M. Vidaver Outreach Coordinator</ENAMEX>
      P.S. You can find out more about our work and environmental
      developments on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Beacon Hill</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ELM</ENAMEX>' s website,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EnvironmentalLeague</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>.
    
  
