
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2000</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>,
      If your pet were lost would you spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18.39</NUMEX> to get him back?
      Did you know:
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> is lost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>;
      <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> we take in come from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashua</ENAMEX>;
      Of that number, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> are stray, lost <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>;
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> we aided <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,418</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stray animals</ENAMEX> but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,191</NUMEX> of them were never
      claimed by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>;
      Incoming strays increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19%</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three years</TIMEX> and is
      expected to continue to climb;
      Almost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$390,000</NUMEX>) of our operating budget is consumed by programs
      to serve stray and unwanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Charities Information</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau</ENAMEX>'s standard is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX>);
      All these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> need some form of costly care including boarding,
      food, medical care, testing, surgery, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, training, or physical
      therapy;
      We are faced with the real possibility of turning away <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> if
      donations do not increase.
      Our goal for the remainder of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100.000.00</NUMEX> to
      meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2000</TIMEX> operating budget. If each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> receiving this letter
      gives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $18.39</NUMEX> we will make the goal. Please donate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      Your humane society provides not only effective community social
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but also serves as the "pound" for
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashua</ENAMEX>. Pound services ensure that lost <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> have a clean and
      safe place to stay and be cared for until their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> can be
      located.
      In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> that are not recovered by-their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> uses a wide variety of - services to aid those <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and
      give them a chance at a happy life. While every <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> that makes it to
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> receives the care it needs and deserves, the ones that
      go unrecovered claim the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lion</ENAMEX>'s share of resources.
      For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years</TIMEX> we have been under contract with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashua</ENAMEX> to
      provide these services, as mandated by state law. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> has lobbied the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for ever-increasing levels
      of funding to help us meet expenses. In the past our relationship with
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> has been quite good, but we have never been able to achieve <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX>
      funding for the services the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> expects and that which the community
      requires. Instead the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX> provided only <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$57,000</NUMEX>) of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>
      revenues.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of providing care for an increasing number of animals
      has eroded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX>'s reserve funds to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX>; one minor
      emergency and we could be wiped out.
      The most recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> pound contract with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX> expired on
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30, 2000</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six months</TIMEX> prior to that we began working with Mayor
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streeter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to negotiate a new agreement that would provide the
      funds we need to continue full service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> without suffering
      the ongoing operating deficits we have endured for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 21 years</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Streeter</ENAMEX> was sensitive to our needs but cited the spending cap
      as the roadblock to providing us with sufficient funding. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> sponsored a resolution seeking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70,000</NUMEX> per year to fund our
      contract for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> with a provision to seek <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $10,000</NUMEX> from
      the contingency budget in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2001</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance Committee</ENAMEX>
      approved that contract on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3rd</TIMEX>. But if the additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> is not
      approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Aldermen</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Trustees</ENAMEX> will
      be forced to cut services.
      Over the course of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Philbrook</ENAMEX>,
      along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Trustees</ENAMEX>, will continue to work closely with
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashua</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldermen</ENAMEX> to negotiate an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> contract that will come closer
      to providing the needs of the stray and abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nashua</ENAMEX>.
      WE NEED YOUR HELP. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WE ARE FACED WITH THE REAL POSSIBILITY OF TURNING</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">AWAY ANIMALS</ENAMEX> IF DONATIONS DO NOT INCREASE.
      You can help in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways:
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Please donate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Our goal for the remainder of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is to
      raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000.00</NUMEX>. If each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> receiving this letter gives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just $18.39</NUMEX>
      we will make the goal. However, the average response rate to our appeals
      is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX>, which means that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 544</NUMEX> of you send in checks -- if history
      repeats itself with this appeal then each of you will have to give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$182</NUMEX>
      to make the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> goal. We are most grateful for your support in
      whatever amount you can spare! We love <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and we know you do, too.
      Thank you for your support --we can only do this because of you!
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Contact your ward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alderman</ENAMEX> and lobby for his/her support of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX>'s needs. If you don't know who your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alderman</ENAMEX> is, contact
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">594-3341</ENAMEX>.
      If you would like more information please call me at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">880-1490,</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ext</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">235</NUMEX>, or email me at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">john</ENAMEX>@jghenry.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contact</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Philbrook</ENAMEX> at
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">889-2275</TIMEX>, ext. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>, or email him at philbrook@hsfn.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>.
      Thank you for your continued support.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely Yours</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Henry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Trustees</ENAMEX>
    
  
