
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear ,</ENAMEX>
      Have you noticed your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> mentioning <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fountain Square</ENAMEX> lately? It
      seems that everywhere I go <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are making positive observations about
      how our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is on the upswing! This shift in our neighborhood image
      is very satisfying after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen years</TIMEX> of concerted efforts by South-East
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Development</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEND</ENAMEX>) to reverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> decline.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> banded together to form
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> which is now called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SEND</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEND</ENAMEX>'s redevelopment efforts
      have played a major role in rebirth of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fountain Square</ENAMEX>, directly
      investing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $12 Million</NUMEX> into affordable housing, commercial
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>, and beautification project since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. This investment has
      resulted in the renovation and sale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homebuyers</ENAMEX> of modest
      means, and in the rehab of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than 100 affordable</NUMEX>, high quality
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 500</NUMEX> low income <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>, often senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>,
      have been able to remain in their homes thanks to home repairs supported
      by SEND. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> have been able to expand and employ more
      residents. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two hundred at-risk</TIMEX> neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> have gained work and
      life skills to overcome the appeal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and school drop out
      which constantly threaten their future These direct investments by SEND
      have been a catalyst encouraging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> more in investments by
      residents and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> who now hold hope for the neighborhood's
      future.
      While the trends of decline are reversing, our work is far from
      complete. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> still live in sub-standard conditions,
      our teen pregnancy rate is the highest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of
      residents have high school diplomas, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> have
      little hope of participating in community improvements because they do
      not own their home.
      We need your help to continue our work, particularly as we enable area
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with low incomes to become <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>. The cost of creating
      these homes far exceeds what our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> cm pay, so we rely on grants and
      individual donations to keep them affordable. I hope you will take this
      opportunity to make a contribution to support SEND's homeownership work.
      As a bonus, we are now able to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> or more a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Neighborhood Assistance Program</ENAMEX> (NAP) <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> tax credit. This means
      that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of your contribution will be returned to you through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> tax
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">savings</ENAMEX>, while the entire donation amount will remain deductible on your
      Federal taxes. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> will actually be contributing less
      than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> while SEND benefits from the entire gift. However, these tax
      credits are only available for a limited time, so we ask that you act
      soon if you would like to use them.
      Please join us as we continue to rebuild this historic neighborhood
      into a place of pride and community strength. Feel free to call me if you
      would like, more information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAP</ENAMEX> tax credit program or any of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEND</ENAMEX>'s programs.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yours</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William G. Taft</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
