
  
  
    
      
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>,
      I am pleased to present the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southeast Neighborhood Development</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEND</ENAMEX>)
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> report. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past several years</TIMEX> we have been making a
      significant investment in the southeast side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> and the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that live in our neighborhood. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEND</ENAMEX> is taking the lead with new
      and innovative initiatives for urban <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>.
      Thanks to our many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnerships</ENAMEX>, SEND accomplishes its mission through
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> areas of activities: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building</ENAMEX> and maintaining quality affordable
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>, emphasizing home ownership. Helping, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> to gain the skills
      needed for independent living. Creating and expanding opportunities for
      neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. Advocating for neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX>.
      Our annual report highlights a few of our successes during the past
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> who helped make them happen. If you're not already
      a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and want to be a part of our future, we'd like to talk to you.
      I am a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of SEND and would like to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few moments</TIMEX> of your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in the near future to tell you, personally, about our programs and
      how you can help. I will call you soon to arrange a time when I can
      introduce myself and, more importantly, introduce the many programs SEND
      is accomplishing in our neighborhood.
      By combining our assets, we can make a difference.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      
    
  
