
  
  
    
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      I care about the plight of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are forced to
      raise their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in poverty housing, and I am grateful - as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s
      Day approaches -that I am in position to help make the essential
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> of a decent home possible for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. To ensure <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Habitat</ENAMEX>'s worldwide building efforts, I enclose my
      tax-deductible contribution of:
      * <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 $30 $40</NUMEX> Other $
      * <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PLEASE TRY TO CONTRIBUTE THIS AMOUNT OR MORE</ENAMEX> IF YOU CAN. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MILLIONS OF</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">MOTHERS ARE STILL WAITING FOR THE DECENT HOMES THEY AND THEIR FAMILIES SO</ENAMEX>
      DESPERATELY NEED! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">GOD BLESS YOU</ENAMEX>.
      MILLARD
    
  
