
  
  
    
      
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15, 2000</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Habitat Partner</ENAMEX>,
      As you know, just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few short weeks from now</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> everywhere will
      be celebrating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX>, honoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> in ways that have become so
      familiar to all of us over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>.
      There'll be greeting cards filled with loving sentiments, and brightly
      wrapped gifts, too. There'll also be long-distance phone calls from the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Or maybe even dinner for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> at a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX>. And for
      those whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are now deceased, there'll be moments of remembrance
      and prayer expressing gratitude to God for a lifetime's worth of love and
      protection - as a newfound appreciation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s Day gestures-that
      come from their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Just about everyone I know has experienced
      these kinds of things over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> to mark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX>.
      But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, I am asking you to be even more aware of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s Day this
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, and what it means to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in need. Because I doubt
      that you have ever encountered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> I want to tell you about. Nor have you experienced a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX>
      ending that is so glorious as this one.
      And when I'm finished telling you her incredible story, I'm hoping you
      will see your way clear to send <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Habitat for Humanity</ENAMEX> a generous
      tax-deductible contribution to help make the same kind of joyous ending
      possible for so many other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who have the same
      urgent need for a simple, decent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and the sense of hope that goes
      along with it.
      Before I tell you more about that remarkable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX>,
      however - a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda Rudolph</ENAMEX> whose love, compassion and sense of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">generosity</ENAMEX> ought to be an example to everyone -I want to tell you just a
      little bit about what every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> trying to go it alone with her
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> on a marginal (or worse) income is facing.
      Put plainly, there is no way to overstate the alarm everyone in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> ought to feel over the fact that childhood poverty, despite our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s skyrocketing wealth, is still on the increase!
      Nor can I overstate the fear that every low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> throughout
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and around the world must carry with her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>:
      that the consequences of poverty will ultimately catch up with her
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, too. Consequences of poverty include inadequate nutrition and
      its effects, such as the real possibility of slow mental development. Or
      the childhood maladies left untreated because there is no money for a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>. Or the terrible cycle of poor self-esteem, bad study habits,
      unfulfilled potential, and a life ultimately lived without hope. In the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>, we have a rate of childhood poverty that is higher
      -sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times higher -than other major western
      industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than one-fifth</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in this rich
      nation live in poverty. Indeed, while many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> grew wealthier
      during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s and 1990s</TIMEX>, the rate of childhood poverty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> was
      actually rising by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>!
      This tragic background brings me to the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda Rudolph of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, who made a courageous decision on behalf of her
      family <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26-year-old</TIMEX> single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX> was already up
      against the hard economic realities presented by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      More than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> of working at a local fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> had allowed
      her to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> on the table and pay the rent for the small <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-bedroom
      apartment they shared, but not much more.
      Things were certainly not easy, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX> was determined to give her
      kids the very best life she could, just like her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had for her,
      a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanda</ENAMEX> describes as a wonderful role model. "We may not have had
      everything that we wanted or we'd seen other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have, but she made
      sure we had the necessary things that we needed. And she was always there
      for us;" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX> says of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.
      In fact, long after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX> was on her own, her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was still being a
      role model, and still being there for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. For she had taken in
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>'s deeply troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, rather than see them
      separated and shuffled off to foster care.
      There were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> - but they were family, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>,
      even though she was getting on in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, was determined to keep them
      together, no matter how difficult it would be financially.
      And then, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago this past December</TIMEX>, disaster happened in a family
      that didn't need any more trouble. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> passed away, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>
      had a decision to make. It was a decision made with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s heart.
      Rather than giving her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Services</ENAMEX> - to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strangers - Wanda</ENAMEX> chose to take on the responsibility of raising them
      herself, knowing full well that the likelihood of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> coming back
      into the picture as a fulltime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was not a strong one, at all.
      It was a decision made not only with love, but with courage. And the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">situation Wanda</ENAMEX> then found herself in bore that out.
      Can you imagine trying to raise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-bedroom
      apartment?
      Can you imagine what it must be like - never mind the financial
      pressures - of just trying to live? Can you see the bunkbeds and
      mattresses on the floor that put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>(as young as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and as
      old as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>) in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>? Or the mealtimes that have the entire
      family trying to find a place to sit and balance their plates while
      eating wherever they can find a place?
      Or the demands placed on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> by a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>? Or the
      virtual impossibility of finding a quiet place to study or even think, so
      that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> can cope in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> have a chance of
      achieving something better? Or the seemingly impossible task of trying to
      keep such a crowded home neat and clean?
      Well, if you can imagine these things, I know you can imagine that
      even in the atmosphere of love that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX> created, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> began to
      have trouble. Problems at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and at home began to surface as the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> reacted to the pressures of their crowded living situation, and
      their emotions such as pain and anger at having been abandoned by their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homework</ENAMEX> went undone. Fights began to occur at home. The phone
      repeatedly began to ring at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>'s new job with calls from school
      because another of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> was having problems. Worst of all, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>
      had to deal with this worsening problem as she was trying to succeed at
      her new job. Her anxiety level rose every time the telephone rang.
      But because of the compassion and generosity shown by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Habitat partners</ENAMEX>
      like you, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>'s prayers were suddenly answered - she was approved for a
      Habitat house -the kind of miracle that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who grow up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>'s
      world never seriously hope for, let alone expect.
      And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>'s miracle isn't just the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, which will make it possible
      for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to achieve some privacy and basic space from one
      another. That will only be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step toward healing the pain of
      having been abandoned several times, neglected, and denied the happy
      childhood that should be every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s birthright. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX> explains:
      "They've been shipped from places, from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> to home...and I think
      they missed out on things they shouldn't have, like having their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">birthdays</ENAMEX> celebrated. They didn't get to do all that, and they
      should.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mom</ENAMEX> was too old to try to do it, so I give them that chance. This past
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, even though it was kind of hard, we always made sure they had a
      birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time they ever got to go to
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> fair."
      I'm trying now with counseling to get them to get along with each
      other, and to let them go out and be with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and do the stuff
      that I did as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. But I'm also trying to teach them that they have
      to earn what they get, and to be part of making sure their lives are
      better."
      That's all I want, for them to be better. So I can feel like they're
      going to accomplish something, and be fine on their own."
      And the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> step toward accomplishing something, of course, is
      learning that it's possible - growing up experiencing home ownership as a
      fact of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life ...knowing there's a quiet place to study ...having
      your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> over to play without being embarrassed about where you
      live.
      But this new awareness of life's possibilities isn't confined to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, by any means. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> feel it, too - especially the single
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> who have accomplished something of extreme difficulty, changing
      their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s economic prospects on their own, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that still
      makes that harder for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> than for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, while still filling all the
      roles that go with the blessed title of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>."
      And as I talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women homeowners</ENAMEX> all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, I am always
      mindful of how very much they see the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Habitat</ENAMEX> experience from exactly
      this perspective -as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> they see the lives of their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> constantly enriched by living in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
      helped build their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, as others had helped them.
      Is it any wonder they go to bed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> with prayers of thanks for
      what is now possible for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>? And you can be sure that there
      are also prayers of thanks in their hearts for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you who
      made it possible. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX> is as aware as any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> can be about the new
      possibilities you create, which she calls a "wonderful" thing to know. "I
      told all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habitat</ENAMEX> and how it works. When I hear them talk
      about how they'll never own their own home, I tell them there's hope for
      us, that I'm living proof and everything I've prayed on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> has
      been answered."
      You're a part of those answered prayers. That's why I hope you will
      take special delight in knowing that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX>'s new Habitat house
      is dedicated, your loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> will be felt on that joyous
      occasion.
      I hope you'll think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wanda</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>' prayers and dreams
      this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX>. And more than that, I hope you'll also think about
      what it will mean for them to have a simple decent home for their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>.
      Your continued generosity can help change a desperate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s
      life.
      And in tribute to all of the precious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> in your own life, I hope
      you will share your love with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> in need the world over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Bless
      you!
      In joyous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Millard Fuller Founder</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
      P.S. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> you be blessed, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and always, as you so generously share
      your blessings with others. For your timely reply, you have my deepest
      thanks.
    
  
