
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 3, 2000</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear DONOR:</ENAMEX>
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> was so pleased to receive
      your contribution of --- toward the support of our programs. As we step
      into the new millenium, we are excited about the many challenges facing
      us in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> as our international population continues to grow.
      Your gift encourages us to continue to meet the varied international
      needs of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with challenging and interesting programs and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX>.
      We look forward to seeing you in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming year</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Citizen</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> dinner, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 26</TIMEX> and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Festival</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 19</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21,2000</NUMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, you are welcome
      to contact us at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any time</TIMEX> if we can assist you with your international
      needs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">501</NUMEX>(C)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX> supported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caterina Cregor Blitzer</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
