
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 6, 1999</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Supporter</ENAMEX>:
      In central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> we hear unfamiliar languages and see the
      faces of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> who are making our city their home. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> is committed to making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> from other
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> feel welcome in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and to helping all of us to
      discover the multicultural aspects of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and prepare for
      global challenges.
      Our mission is to be the BEST community resource for those with
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">international</ENAMEX> needs and the best international resource for those with
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> needs. Here are just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of the ways we have accomplished our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in revitalizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
      Festival of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. Collaborating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nationalities Council of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, we celebrated multi-cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> at this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-day</TIMEX> event in
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> with entertainment, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> cultural and food <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booths</ENAMEX> and the presence
      of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 8,000</NUMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> from around
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>,
      worked in the planning phase and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> could not
      have put on the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX> without them.
      Many school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX> received advance
      preparation with the help of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ameritech</ENAMEX> study guide, published and
      distributed to every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who requested this valuable tool.
      The culmination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX> was a breathtaking performance by the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shangri-la Acrobats</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taiwan</ENAMEX> on the final <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fairgrounds</ENAMEX>.
      For <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> they captivated their large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
      with stunning acrobatics and death defying spins from the rafters-
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> is assessing the ways in which youth programs in central
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> introduce and explore diverse cultural experiences. This
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assessment</ENAMEX> will lead to new approaches in training <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth workers</ENAMEX> so that
      they can build stronger programs which make all young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> feel
      welcome and accepted.
      On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 12, 1999</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Smulyan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmis Communications</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Citizen</ENAMEX> of the Year. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 400</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gathered to applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emmis</ENAMEX>'s accomplishment
      as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of the most listened to radio station in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> to
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX> His <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excellency Geza Jeszenszky</ENAMEX> was present
      to add <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">his accolades that evening</TIMEX>.
      As the local host <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Council of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Visitors</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South Africa Internship Program</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
      Medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internships</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> welcomed over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> to
      central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Visitors</ENAMEX> coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, northern and west
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Britain</ENAMEX> spent from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> to
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. Local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> welcomed these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> into their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an evening</TIMEX> of dinner and conversation or acted as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host families</ENAMEX>
      for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as long as two months</TIMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> has entered into partnership with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> local
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> with a multi - national presence. Through Destination
      Services the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> works hand in hand with human resource <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> we helped over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">100</NUMEX> international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> settle into central
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> assists with the housing search, school decisions,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>' licenses, leisure time activities, and daycare. A valuable
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-week</TIMEX> course called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">COPES</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Community Orientation</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expatriate</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Spouses</ENAMEX>] introduces the non-employed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> life and
      opportunities in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of many voices and many faces. The attendance
      of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 16,000</NUMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">International Festival</ENAMEX> confirmed our belief in
      our own festival publicity "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Many Faces, One World</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International</ENAMEX>
      Center we are proud to welcome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newcomers</ENAMEX> to our city whether they come to
      live with us or to learn from us.
      We value your contributions to our programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly Endowment</ENAMEX>, a key
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporter</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, has challenged us by offering a
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> grant, which we must match in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Your gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ICI</ENAMEX> will help
      us meet this challenge. With your help, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Center of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> will continue to serve our multicultural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in
      central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Tanner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caterina Blitzer Board of Directors Executive</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
    
  
