
  
  
    
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DISABLED BUSINESSPERSONS ASSOCIATION</ENAMEX> (DBA) is a national 501(C)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonprofit</ENAMEX>, public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> and educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> to
      help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> maximize their potential in
      the business world, and to encourage the participation and enhance the
      performance of the disabled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>.
      Services Provided by the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DBA" Challenged America Our</ENAMEX> sailing team
      sets an example of success through teamwork "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Giving Disabled Veterans the</ENAMEX>
      Business" An article from the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disabled American Veterans"</ENAMEX> (DAV) Magazine
      "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Challenge too Great for These Vets</ENAMEX>" An article from the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans of</ENAMEX>
      Foreign Wars" (VFW) Magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">How YOU CAN Help Support the "DBA</ENAMEX>"
      Services Provided Include: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Personal Business Advisor Business Plan</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Assistance Packaging Market</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Product Research Marketing</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advertising and Public Relations Presentation</ENAMEX> and Proposal Documentation
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Consultant, Vendor and Business Network Information Newsletter</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Seminars, Workshops and Conferences Technology and Equipment</ENAMEX>
      Research and Evaluation "Serving the needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s enterprising
      disabled"
      Giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disabled Veterans the Business Urban Miyares</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAV</ENAMEX>'s
      Outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Disabled Veteran of the Year</ENAMEX>, gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled veterans</ENAMEX> the
      business - literally. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and guiding spirit behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disabled</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Businesspersons Association of San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX> helps
      disabled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> nationwide start their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAV</ENAMEX> will recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outstanding Disabled Veteran of</ENAMEX>
      the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 73rd</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National Convention of the DAV and Auxiliary</ENAMEX> in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 20-25, 1994</TIMEX>.
      On his way to becoming an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>
      veteran suffered a number of setbacks and gained experience as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skier</ENAMEX>, and "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spiderman</ENAMEX>". They named him "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spiderman</ENAMEX>"
      because of the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX> clung to the walls and blindly felt his way
      along the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Blind Rehabilitation Center</ENAMEX> (WBRC) at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palo Alto</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>.
      Miyares, a life member of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">DAV Chapter 2</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>,
      became blind in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> due to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. He also suffers a hearing loss,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney disease</ENAMEX>, and neuropathy (loss of feeling) in his legs. The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neuropathy</ENAMEX> and blindness caused him to cling to the center walls for
      balance and orientation.
      Being at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WBRC</ENAMEX> learning to cope with the disability was a major feat
      for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> took his sight he suffered severe depression,
      became withdrawn, and all but refused to leave his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> until he went for
      rehabilitation training at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WBRC</ENAMEX>.
      While attending computer training at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WBRC</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX> heard about
      the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National Disabled Winter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Clinic</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Junction</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>. Now an annual event, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> is sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DAV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>,
      with financial assistance from business and private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.
      Originally, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WBRC</ENAMEX> asked if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX> wanted to go skiing at some
      kind of "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> thing" that was starting up. "Listen, I
      told him. I'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. I moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>. I don't like snow.
      I've never been on a pair of skis. I'm a concrete <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>; I'm not crazy;
      and besides that I'm blind", <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX> said.
      But the "concrete baby", <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AKA</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spiderman</ENAMEX>", changed his mind and went
      skiing. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn</ENAMEX>, the decision changed his
      life.
      "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Winter Sports Clinic</ENAMEX> helped Urban a lot", <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn</ENAMEX> said. "The first
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> he attended we tough. He wanted to come home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> he got
      off the slopes, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Trombetta</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX> and recreation
      therapist at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Junction VA Medical Center</ENAMEX>, convinced Urban to try
      again. The rest is history.
      With self-determination, pursuit of excellence and a love affair with
      skiing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX> went from a bumbling beginner on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bunny</ENAMEX> (low and slow
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beginner</ENAMEX>) slope to exceeding <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">63 miles per hour</NUMEX> to rank as the number one
      B-1 (totally blind) downhill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skier</ENAMEX> in the world. His skiing awards
      include the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Disabled Veterans Winter Sports Clinic 1988</ENAMEX> Linne
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Spirit Award</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego Hall of Champions Museum 1990 Disabled</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Athlete of the Year Award</ENAMEX>, and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 and '91</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. National Disabled</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpine Ski Championships</ENAMEX>.
      No decision since his decision to return to the field during the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> had as much impact on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX>. However, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, returning to
      the field wasn't entirely voluntary.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sgt. Miyares</ENAMEX>' repeated trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sick</ENAMEX> call
      basically boiled down to, "get your act together and get back in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>, or we'll make you a private again <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX>."
      The message we clear. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> suspected him of malingering, and that
      didn't sit well with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">9th Infantry Division</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon sergeant</ENAMEX>. Miyares
      geared up and moved to the field with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. The blurred vision,
      sever stomach cramps, headaches, constant fatigue, and vomiting would
      have to take a back seat to the war.
      His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">platoon</ENAMEX> came under attack in the field. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX> heard explosions,
      thought they were mortars and collapsed.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX>, he emerged from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">diabetic coma</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saigon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next four months</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
      before being medically discharged from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> with as service-connected
      disability for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> had been right. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> became a private, a private
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> fighting a new war against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX> wasn't alone. He
      had an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn</ENAMEX>, was by his side the moment he returned home.
      "When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urban</ENAMEX> left for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, we'd only been married a short time,"
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn</ENAMEX> said. "When he came home, it was harder controlling <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>. We
      didn't know as much about it as we do today, and were learning and
      adjusting to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> at the same time we were building our marriage. We
      had our ups and downs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> is very self-determined
      and motivated, and we got through it.
      "When our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urban Paul</ENAMEX>, was born, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> was a really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.
      He liked to do little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> with him, and we did all the
      things <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> do.
      "But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> wasn't feeling good, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> knew it was because daddy
      was a diabetic. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are younger, they don't always understand
      what that means, but as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> grew he understood more and more. When
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> became blind our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was very understanding of it, and at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>, he's
      adjusted very well to all that's happened. Whenever we need him, he's
      there".
      Landing meaningful and productive employment was hard for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX>. He
      became so frustrated with available jobs that he went into business for
      himself.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>, he opened is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> business, a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> construction
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. It didn't last very long, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX> discovered he loved being a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>. He had an appetite and aptitude for business. He moved on to
      open his own retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>, sales <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, a
      manufacturing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and a public relations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>. Business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ventures</ENAMEX> led
      him from coast to coast, gaining experience along the way.
      After his blindness, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX> couldn't find resources for a blind
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>.
      "They tried tremendously to help me at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Blind Rehabilitation</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>, but the only resources for a businessperson were for the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">non-disabled</ENAMEX> and non-blind", <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX> said. The more I searched for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> and assistance to benefit a blind businessperson, the more I
      couldn't find any.
      "I took business <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, but again, they were slanted toward the
      non-disabled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>. At that point, I knew that if people
      who are disabled are to compete in this world and be productive, we have
      to compete on a non-disabled basis. I also knew we couldn't do it without
      information and assistance. When I tried to get answers to my questions,
      I got nothing - not even encouragement or advice. What I got a lot of was
      "sorry" and "blind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can't do that". I became so frustrated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>,
      I made a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled veterans</ENAMEX>. I chose disabled veterans
      because that's what I am. I knew a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled veterans</ENAMEX>. Some were in
      business and some were talking about starting a business. I started
      offering free consulting advice and helped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10-20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the first
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>."
      Business to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Assistance</ENAMEX>
      The business grew and eventually, he was helping <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> nationwide.
      Miyares expanded the business to include all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled persons</ENAMEX>, and in
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> formed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disabled Businesspersons Association</ENAMEX> (DBA), a non-profit
      public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> and educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>. Today, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBA</ENAMEX> continues to
      assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> maximize their potential
      in the business world, and encourages participation and enhances
      performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled persons</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workforce</ENAMEX>, all free of charge. The
      only payment asked of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled clients</ENAMEX> is that they, in turn, volunteer
      their time and expertise to assist other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled persons</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX> has received many awards for his business accomplishments.
      They include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blinded Veterans Association</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Irving Deaner Award</ENAMEX>;
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Small Business Administration</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Veteran Small Business</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocate</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">California Certification</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recognition</ENAMEX> for
      Small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Advocacy; San Diego Center for the Disabled 1992</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Independence Award; a 1992 Presidential Point of Light Award</ENAMEX>, presented
      to him at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> ceremony by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>; and in
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Entrepreneur of the Year Supporter of Entrepreneurship</ENAMEX>
      Award. He is also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">finalist</ENAMEX> for the upcoming Inc. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magazine Entrepreneur</ENAMEX>
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year Award</ENAMEX>.
      According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBA</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> to target the
      role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled persons</ENAMEX> in business. Current DBA data shows <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX>
      of all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> assisted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBA</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 per cent</NUMEX> are service
      connected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled veterans</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 per cent</NUMEX> are non- service connected
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">veterans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX> isn't satisfied with the figures.
      "I'd like to help more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled veterans</ENAMEX> or, at least, see more
      investigating self-employment," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX> said. "Many will find out, as I
      have, that just being active and productive will improve your health,
      relationships, and quality of life.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX> is a quick to share credit for his success with his business
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> and long time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay Chong</ENAMEX> (they own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NUVENCO Group</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX> based product and business management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chong</ENAMEX> is president
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chong</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan</ENAMEX>, administrative supervisor
      for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn</ENAMEX>.
      "I wouldn't have been able to do what I've done without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn</ENAMEX>,"
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX> said.
      "My disability has never been a barrier to our marriage. Understanding
      is the key. Our marriage has grown through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>. We're more than
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>; we're best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. She's a valuable part of the DBA
      and also consults with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled persons</ENAMEX>. She has experience with
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with a variety of disabilities and has lots of valuable
      information to share with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> under stress or having problems; she's a
      good sounding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> from the heart."
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn</ENAMEX> says working with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is fun. She calls herself
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receptionist</ENAMEX>, but, in truth, admits it would be very hard to train
      someone to do what she does for her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.
      "I make sure he gets his lunch on time, take his blood tests
      throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, and make sure there's a snack around," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn</ENAMEX> said.
      "He has to eat on time and properly to maintain his energy and blood
      sugar level. I also car pool him around and help with his schedule.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maintaining Miyares</ENAMEX>' schedule would be a busy job for nearly anyone.
      In addition to running <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miyares</ENAMEX> finds time to be liaison for blinded
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego VA Medical Center</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lecturer</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mira Mesa/Scripps Ranch Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego Union-Tribune</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-host</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego Inventors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Inventions</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFMB-TV</ENAMEX>, and many
      other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, military, civic, and athletic organization
      activities.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX> is also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> and regular crew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of "Challenged
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>" a racing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX> and able-bodied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailors</ENAMEX> who compete in
      major ocean-racing events. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>'s goal is to enter and complete the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biennial Transpac</ENAMEX> race from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> in
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miyares</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> Sheppard seeing-eye-<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>, probably won't make
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transpac</ENAMEX>. It's one of the few times you won't find the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> together.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> can find his way out of a crowded reception faster than a waiter
      with an empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hord</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d'oeuvre tray</ENAMEX>, and can locate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miyares</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> is a
      crowded parking lot with a simple command. "I don't know what we'd do
      without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn</ENAMEX> said. "The independence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> gives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> is
      phenomenal. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> did excellent with his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane</ENAMEX>, but with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX>
      gets from point A to point B in a snap- quicker than I can take him."
      Asked what is most special about her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn</ENAMEX>, with quiet
      conviction, says, "I think it's helping other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban</ENAMEX> is
      genuinely concerned that the disabled community is not getting a fair
      share, and he goes out of his way to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled people</ENAMEX>.
      No <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Challenge too Great for These Vets</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenged America</ENAMEX>
      We Need Your Help Are you seeking a worthwhile cause that really
      changes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives for the better... where every dollar goes directly
      to provide services in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>...one you would be proud to be part
      of and support? We are seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">benefactors</ENAMEX> in the community
      to assist with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBA</ENAMEX>'s growth and services in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways</ENAMEX> you can help The following is a list of ways your can participate
      in the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DBA</ENAMEX>. If you would like information, please enter
      your response in the appropriate area and your name, address and /or
      phone number in the space provided at the end. When you have completed
      your entry, click on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Submit Query</ENAMEX>" button at the bottom. If you choose
      to change or delete your entry, click on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reset"</ENAMEX>.
    
  
