
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DISABLED BUSINESSPERSONS ASSOCIATION</ENAMEX> TM
      Thank you for contacting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disabled Businesspersons Association</ENAMEX>
      (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dba</NUMEX>) and requesting information.
      Founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> by successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> with
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">disabilities</ENAMEX>, and restructured in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> as a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">501</NUMEX>(c)(<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) charitable,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonprofit</ENAMEX> membership <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, the dba provides business information
      and assistance to enterprising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> with disabilities,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worldwide</ENAMEX>.
      Having served <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>, the .<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dba</ENAMEX> is recognized as one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s
      largest and leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> on the self-employment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with
      disabilities.
      To better help us assist you, write, fax or E-mail and tell us more
      about yourself...background, employment/business experience, likes,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dislikes</ENAMEX>, hobbies, interests, disability, etc., and your current or
      planned business activity, if known.
      How can we assist you?
      We look forward to your written response, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> support, and
      having the opportunity to work with you.
      Best regards,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
    
  
