
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 30, 1992</TIMEX>
      Dear :
      Recently, the world watched as the newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">space shuttle</ENAMEX> made its
      maiden voyage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endeavor</ENAMEX> held our attention and focused our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">imaginations</ENAMEX> once more upon the stars, and renewed our commitment to the
      knowledge and curiosity that made such a mission possible. The IUPUI
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger Scholars Program</ENAMEX> encourages bright and dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who
      want to teach to continue in that career path. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars</ENAMEX> were named in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-93</TIMEX> academic year. These
      newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars</ENAMEX> bring the number to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> who, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christa McAuliffe</ENAMEX>,
      will touch the future.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner</ENAMEX>, the second <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger Scholar</ENAMEX>, wrote recently that she
      teaches <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Elementary</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Franklin Township</ENAMEX>. "Life
      is hectic, yet very rewarding." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanne</ENAMEX> is making a difference in the
      lives of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Challenger Scholars</ENAMEX> are chosen from among outstanding
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the humanities, sciences, technologies and education who have
      chosen to pursue careers in teaching, at any level. You can see from the
      enclosed newspaper article the quality and diversity of those who receive
      this honor. Your past support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX> program has been critical
      to its success. Each award involves a tuition/fee remission and a $<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stipend</ENAMEX>. These have been accomplished through the generosity of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> like yourself in combination with some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> and school
      allocations. Please renew your commitment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Cohen Professor</ENAMEX>
      P.S. When your gift helps an outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> become an outstanding
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, you will know that you, too, have touched the future.
    
  
