
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3, 1991</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 28, 1991</TIMEX>, I attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> ceremony which remembered
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronauts</ENAMEX> and presented awards to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Challenger</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars</ENAMEX> and a new award, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald McNair Challenger Scholar</ENAMEX>. Our sense
      of joy was tempered by the undeniable intrusion of the war in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>. Intrusion because one of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars</ENAMEX> couldn't be here to
      receive her award. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Morehead</ENAMEX>, a biology major, was serving on a
      hospital ship in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Operation Desert Storm</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger Scholar Program</ENAMEX>
      honors the memory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX>
      disaster <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholars</ENAMEX> are chosen from outstanding
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the sciences, technologies and education who have chosen to
      pursue careers in teaching, at any level. The national crisis in science
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> is clear to all of us. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger Scholars Program</ENAMEX> attempts
      in a small way to address this crisis by encouraging bright and dedicated
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with a desire to extend their knowledge into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> as
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to continue in that career path. That one of those chosen to
      receive this honor was herself facing a new and unimaginable danger was
      sobering. But the promise she and her fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny Wright</ENAMEX>
      (elementary education), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Browning</ENAMEX> (physics) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Van Vlymen</ENAMEX>
      (elementary education), all hold for the future is impressive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric</ENAMEX>
      Hiatt, the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger Scholar</ENAMEX> is currently working on his doctorate
      "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Receiving the Challenger Scholarship</ENAMEX> was a great honor and continues to
      be a source of inspiration to me as I work toward my doctorate degree.
      ...<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> I have been... teaching introductory geology <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX>.
      Teaching again has reminded me that this is what I am here for..."
      Your past support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX> program has been critical to its
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these last four years</TIMEX>. Each award involves a tuition/fee
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">remission</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1000</NUMEX> stipend. These have been accomplished through the
      generosity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> like yourself in combination with some campus
      and school allocations. In order to grant these awards a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, your
      continued support is critical. Please renew your commitment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. When
      your gift helps an outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> become an outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, you
      will know that you, too, have touched the future.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Cohen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Education</ENAMEX>
      P.S. By the way, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teresa</ENAMEX> is back and safe. Won't you be a part of
      extending the promise with your gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? I have supported this
      scholarship for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> and feel it not only recognizes our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' abilities but indicates <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>'s commitment to excellence in
      teaching. If you are interested in making a payroll deduction gift,
      contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Foundation</ENAMEX> office at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">274-3711</ENAMEX>.
    
  
