
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear 1990 Graduate:</ENAMEX>
      Congratulations on the completion of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree from
      As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of your graduating class, we appreciate the hard work that
      has made your degree possible. Not only have many of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> juggled
      family and job responsibilities with studies, but they also have made
      time to participate in student activities which have become traditions in
      our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. For example, those in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MET</ENAMEX> who worked on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team Indy</ENAMEX> were among
      the first <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> campus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue Grand</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prix</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Lafayette</ENAMEX>. Others who worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACM</ENAMEX>'s high school
      programming competition, with engineering's super mileage <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>, with
      RHllv1's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baker's Club</ENAMEX>, or with any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>'s other activities
      helped to maintain traditions in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> that future classes
      will be encouraged to continue. These activities have helped develop a
      sense of community that enabled everyone to endure and succeed, even in
      difficult times.
      Even if we have not engaged in formal extracurricular activities,
      however, many more of us have helped each other-by reviewing homework
      problems in one of the student <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounges</ENAMEX>, by participating in group
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> in classes--meeting sometimes after class <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, by taking time
      to listen to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX>'s personal problems, or just by socializing
      between classes.
      As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> of the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, we would like to leave behind
      something tangible, in appreciation for the support and encouragement we
      have received from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Engineering</ENAMEX> and
      Technology. To do this, we are initiating another tradition: Senior
      Challenge.
      Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenge</ENAMEX> is an opportunity for us to contribute to the school
      that has given us the tools to enrich our lives and make our dreams come
      true. The goal for <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Senior Challenge 1990</ENAMEX> is to raise funds to purchase
      furnishings for the student <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounges</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and in the new
      building that will house <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Computer Technology and Engineering</ENAMEX> programs. At
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time or another we have all met <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounges</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ET</TIMEX>
      Building or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Building</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">38th Street</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>. We all
      realize how the availability or lack of comfortable seating and
      conference <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> made it possible for us to socialize or to get help in a
      course giving us difficulty. Lounges newly furnished through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior</ENAMEX>
      Challenge will promote teamwork in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> by allowing future classes
      to benefit from each others' friendship and assistance. With this goal,
      the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> gift will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who follow
      us.
      As our senior year draws to a close, we challenge you to participate
      in this worthy project. By making a contribution or a pledge, using the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> enclosed, you can put a positive "finishing touch" on your
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">graduating year</TIMEX>. With the participation of everyone, we will all be proud
      when the presentation of the class gift is made to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Renda</ENAMEX> at
      Commencement on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 13, 1990</TIMEX>.
      Please complete the enclosed card and mail it in the envelope
      provided. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX> you will be contacted by a fellow senior
      either by phone or in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> to answer any questions you have about
      Senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenge</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyrone Artis Larry Gutsch Carol Hutton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BS/EET</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'90</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">BS/MET '90</ENAMEX>)
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BS/SPV</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'90</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Lashbrook Melissa Warriner</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BS/CPT</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'90</NUMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BS/SPV</ENAMEX>
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'90</NUMEX>)
    
  
