
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 9, 1994</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name,
      You may remember bumping into me somewhere along your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">path</ENAMEX> through
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX>. I have been with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Manufacturing Technology</ENAMEX> for
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about thirty years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-five years</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> and have recently
      retired. As I recall, I've never asked you for a contribution...until
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. At the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honors Convocation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> established a
      scholarship award in my name to honor an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outstanding Student</ENAMEX> from our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. I was moved, excited, and very surprised by this gesture from
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> , who funded this award from their pockets.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Badger</ENAMEX>, the recipient of the award was equally surprised,
      not to mention a little better off financially. I am concerned, however,
      about the plans that exist for continuing this award in the future. The
      intent is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> will contribute to the award <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.
      Unfortunately, times and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the faculty change, but the need
      for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to receive scholarship awards will continue at an
      unprecedented rate. As I see it, this can only be done through the
      establishment of a scholarship fund which will generate sufficient income
      to support this award. I hope you will join me in supporting this
      scholarship opportunity by sending your check <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> made payable to the
      "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peale Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX>."
      I hope this letter finds you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in good health. I am
      always happy to hear from you about your accomplishments, career, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
      etc.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert E. Peale</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emeritus</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> will match your gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engineering and Technology</ENAMEX> so I've enclosed a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Double Your Dollars</ENAMEX>
      brochure for your convenience.
    
  
