
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Alumnus</ENAMEX>:
      When was the last time you stopped at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> since you graduated? Was
      it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as last year</TIMEX> that you could find your way around, or has
      it been so long that if you were to visit the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> you could not
      recognize it? Whether you are a recent or not-so-recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX>, I
      invite you to watch us grow as a maturing urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> on the go! In
      addition to expanded physical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> since the completion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engineering and Technology Building</ENAMEX> Phase <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX>, several of the programs in
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> have expanded in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> size; the
      research and development contracts with federal and state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and
      private industry exceeded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">one million dollars</NUMEX> in value for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>; interaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> on
      campus increased drastically in terms of joint research projects on
      medical imaging, computational neuroscience and biomechanics and the
      partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Avionics Warfare Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Weapons Center</ENAMEX>
      flourished with the moving of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electronic Manufacturing Productivity</ENAMEX>
      Facility from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one mile</NUMEX> of the main
      campus.
      Since the beginning of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> have been
      important <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in the development of our programs. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> we
      will begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our annual</TIMEX> telefund. Gifts received will be used in various
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is continually challenged to provide state-of-the-art
      training for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. In order to do this, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> must be
      developed and maintained with equipment that will provide first-rate,
      "hands-on" experience for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Also, there is the area of
      student support. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and programs within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engineering and Technology</ENAMEX> provide <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousands of dollars</NUMEX> of scholarship
      support <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Still there is great need, especially in
      the way of endowed scholarships. These funds would insure that
      scholarships are available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> as long as there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to
      support. I am confident that as a proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX> you will
      participate in supporting our telefund and extend the promise of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>
      programs at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> to many new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>.
    
  
