
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 27, 1990</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      This is absolutely the last time that I will ask you to please donate
      a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Geology Alumni Fund</ENAMEX>. That is, this is the
      last such request that will be penned from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavanaugh Hall</ENAMEX> address.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next year</TIMEX> at this time, my letter of solicitation will have a new
      address, the address of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> building on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Michigan Street</ENAMEX>. We
      expect to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavanaugh Hall</ENAMEX> and move into the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in mid-
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer 1991</TIMEX>. So this solicitation marks that special occasion, the end of
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> era and the beginning of a new era. I feel sure that you will want to
      be one of that special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> who responded to this last
      solicitation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavanaugh Hall</ENAMEX>.
      Again, let me assure you that we would appreciate receiving one
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> from you and each of our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">161</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>. But let me also
      assure you that we would appreciate equally well any contribution you are
      able to make. Whatever you can contribute, you will be helping to support
      Geology at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> contributions were used to
      provide awards to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Geology students</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honors Day</ENAMEX>, to pay partial support
      for an undergraduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to attend a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geomorphology Conference</ENAMEX>
      in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, to augment the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Geology Alumni Undergraduate</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scholarship</ENAMEX>, and to award partial tuition support to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> awarded
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alumni Scholarship</ENAMEX>.
      We really do appreciate your efforts, whatever amount you can
      contribute. Your tax-deductible contribution may be sent in the enclosed
      postage-paid envelope with the attached return card.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Mirsky Chairman</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
