
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 14, 1993</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, St Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      I am pleased to have survived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly five months</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geology</ENAMEX>'s new
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. It has been a busy time, for we have an ambitious agenda for
      growth and development. Among our objectives for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-94 year</TIMEX> are
      increasing enrollments, re-evaluating both our undergraduate program and
      our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> program, better coordinating our curricula at all levels,
      developing and promoting new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, increasing communication with
      current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>, and establishing beneficial "outside"
      contacts. Much of our effort is focusing upon the strengthening of our
      environmental programs.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mirsky</ENAMEX> is retiring as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty member</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May, 1994</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stocum</ENAMEX> has authorized the hiring of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant professors</ENAMEX>. Both
      new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> will have credentials in the environmental field. To have
      achieved this commitment from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> means our new efforts have already
      impressed him, and we intend to keep his attention.
      The whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will know about us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>! The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> will
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> a symposium on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DING FEST</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24-26, 1994</TIMEX>. Virtually
      every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX> in the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.A.</ENAMEX> will be here. However, our
      major emphasis is on involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of all ages. The event will be
      big! Contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenberg</ENAMEX> for details.
      So, we are a dynamic place. This is where it is happening in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-94</TIMEX>!
      You will be even more proud of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> than you already are.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geology</ENAMEX>, however, continues to need your financial assistance. Our
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-94</TIMEX> budget has been cut nearly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> versus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, operating costs
      are mounting, and it costs money to grow. We have many needs, both for
      the overall operation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>, and for special programs like
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DING FEST</ENAMEX>. Contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DING FEST</ENAMEX> are especially important because we
      believe that our initial investment will result in substantial earnings
      for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>. Also, contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DING FEST</ENAMEX> will make its
      activities more affordable to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. As in the past, you can also
      contribute directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGGS Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX>.
      I urge you to be a contributor to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geology</ENAMEX>'s dynamic growth. This
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s contribution form includes a place to indicate how your donation
      should be used, or just make your check out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGGS Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Holidays</ENAMEX>!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert D. Hall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
      P.S. As an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX>, your Federal tax-deductible contribution
      also qualifies for a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana State Income Tax</ENAMEX> credit of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> (up
      to a maximum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> for an individual or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> for a joint return). For
      your convenience, a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Form CC-40</ENAMEX> (which should be filed with your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana State Income Tax</ENAMEX>) is enclosed.
    
  
