
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1, 1991</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX>,
      Great things are underway at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX>! Not only have we had the highest
      enrollment ever for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery</ENAMEX> is exhibiting
      some of the most exciting work in its history. On top of all this, we're
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> to celebrate our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">90th</NUMEX> birthday as one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s most
      prestigious professional art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>'s showcase for
      the latest art trends. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is a schedule of upcoming
      exhibitions.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> there are close to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">450</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX> studying for their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX> degree in fine arts, art education, art history, or visual
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> are continuing to enjoy a
      number of special programs, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Visiting Artist Program</ENAMEX>, which
      draws <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 10</NUMEX> nationally known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> who present free public slide
      lectures about their work, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday School</ENAMEX>, now in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 70th year</TIMEX> of
      providing art classes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX> and senior high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> every
      spring and fall, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pre-College Program</ENAMEX>, offering art classes for
      recently graduated high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who are interested in careers in
      the arts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery</ENAMEX> will enhance the course work and programming with
      its exciting array of exhibitions and related events planned for the
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991-1992 season</TIMEX>.
      As you can imagine, it is costly to maintain the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>, provide
      compensation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and to provide financial aid, supplies,
      programming and equipment to make all this happen. We do receive some
      funding from the state and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, but we must rely on private
      gifts for any costs above the basic necessities.
      Won't you consider making a gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX>'s operating fund? You will
      be helping us to continue to serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> through our public
      programs, to provide scholarships to deserving young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, to attract
      the best arts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and to continue to train many of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s public
      school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art teachers</ENAMEX> and visual communicators.
      Please complete the enclosed form and return it with your check made
      payable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron School of Art</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery / IUF</ENAMEX>. We're counting on
      our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> to help us maintain our excellence.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean of the Herron School of Art</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery</ENAMEX>
      P.S. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few months</TIMEX> you'll receive more information about even
      more exciting events at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX>!
    
  
