
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1993</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Herron Friends</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> excel again! Not only are they winning awards around
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> but many will be presented with scholarships or gift certificates on
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 30th</TIMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Awards & Honors Ceremony</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Faculty members</ENAMEX> select outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in each area to receive
      funds that come from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> donations and the interest from endowed
      scholarships. The funds go directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' tuition. The gift
      certificates are most typically from art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> and art supply
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>.
      Winning an award is a tremendous honor for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Herron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>. It
      exemplifies the support and encouragement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and community
      provides. For many it's the extra boost they need to continue their
      studies toward a productive career in the visual arts.
      Please consider making a donation to this rewarding program. Come that
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evening</ENAMEX> and see your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> shine as he or she goes to the stage to
      accept the award. Your involvement will be greatly appreciated.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William J. Voos Dean</ENAMEX>
      
      
    
  
