
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1, 1991</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Friends of Herron Gallery</ENAMEX>,
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early September</TIMEX> you received an annual appeal from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herron</ENAMEX>. Don't
      forget that you need to respond to renew your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends membership</ENAMEX> and keep
      your name on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery</ENAMEX>'s mailing list. Otherwise, you'll miss receiving
      the new quarterly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chronicle</ENAMEX> newsletter, the special exhibition opening
      invitation, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Janus Ball</ENAMEX> invitation and advance notice of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visiting</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist lectures</ENAMEX> and the exciting activities planned to celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX>'s
      90th birthday.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is another renewal card. Return the completed card with your
      check by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 15</TIMEX> to receive an invitation to a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> dinner
      on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 8</TIMEX>.
      I hope you'll renew your donation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron Gallery</ENAMEX> and join us
      for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> of terrific contemporary happenings.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dorit Paul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends of Herron Gallery</ENAMEX>
    
  
