
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10, 1993</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Herron Student Family</ENAMEX>,
      Perhaps you have heard your student talk about the visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>
      who present slide lectures at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX> about their work, sit in on classes,
      and mingle with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herron</ENAMEX> each year
      from allover the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. These are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> who are either emerging as
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in their fields or who have already become well known.
      The visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artists Program</ENAMEX> is a critical component of the Herron
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">curriculum</ENAMEX>, as it exposes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> who are successfully
      supporting themselves with their art and to the most current art trends
      outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX> funding is sought through grants and gifts
      from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>.
      Grants are becoming harder to secure and we must look to the
      generosity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to sustain the program. The funding covers
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX>, lodging and lecture fees for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and publicity.
      In total, the program costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $10,000per</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
      I am asking for the support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to help
      maintain this vital program. We feel that it is of great importance to
      the curriculum and helps to broaden your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Herron</ENAMEX> experience.
      Simply fill out the enclosed form and return it with your donation to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX>. All checks should be made payable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron- IUF</ENAMEX>. Any gift will
      be greatly appreciated.
      Feel free to join us for any of the lectures which are held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> in our auditorium. Contact my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in the fall for the schedule
      and listing of this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William J. Voos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
