
  
  
    
      As an arts patron, you know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron School of Art</ENAMEX> has a rich
      tradition in art education, shaping the talents and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> of some of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s most noted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>. In fact, an impressive number
      of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> with national reputations are products of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX> program,
      succeeding despite old-often inadequate- <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>. Please consider
      making an important investment in the future of professional art
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> by being part of an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> renaissance of the arts.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Areas</ENAMEX> where support is needed are identified below:
      -<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GENERAL FUND</ENAMEX>. These funds allow the school some flexibility by
      putting your gift to work in an area that most needs it as circumstances
      arise.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">-SCHOLARSHIP/AWARDS.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> need to be recognized and rewarded for
      their abilities and efforts. Your gift in this area has a direct impact
      on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s continuing education. Please identify whether you wish to
      support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX>- or a particular scholarship
      (indicate name of this scholarship here):
      -<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">VISITING ARTIST SERIES</ENAMEX>. Assistance is needed to continue this program
      which brings in some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s most noted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> to speak with
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> as well as the public.
      -<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HERRON GALLERY</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INDIANAPOLIS CENTER FOR CONTEMPORARY ART</ENAMEX>. Assistance
      is needed to underwrite the costs of these special and exciting
      exhibitions.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-SATURDAY SCHOOL</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saturday School</ENAMEX> offers various art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> in
      different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> for young and old alike who wish to improve their
      artistic expertise but are not full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Herron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Your assistance
      will allow the continuance of offering these programs at reasonable
      rates.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-FACULTY ENRICHMENT</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> needs support in preparing
      exhibitions of their work for shows, for continuing education to maintain
      the knowledge base necessary for teaching and to meet with faculty
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to exchange ideas and information at national
      meetings.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-DEVELOPMENT</ENAMEX>. Funds are needed here for use as seed money as we work
      toward establishing projects that should become self-supporting for the
      school. These monies also help defray the cost of putting on activities
      for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Herron Awards Night</ENAMEX>.
      Thank you for your gift! Please make checks payable to: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron School</ENAMEX>
      of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art/IUF</ENAMEX>, check the area from the above-listed categories where you'd
      like your gift to support and return both items in the envelope.
      
    
  
