
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Friends of Art Education</ENAMEX>,
      It's birthday time! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX> is celebrating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 90th birthday</TIMEX> with
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> art exhibitions all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, parties, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s art programs,
      an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>'s symposium, lectures, tours -you name it! The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is going to
      explode with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX>'s artistic contributions! As we prepare for all the
      events <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>, we are also looking into the future with the
      preparations for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> for the professional art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>,
      administrative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, faculty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>, a library and a contemporary
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX>. Having been only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> set of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> erected in the
      country expressly for art instruction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron</ENAMEX> has had a long history of
      granting degrees through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX> for many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and visual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>. It's time to
      celebrate that achievement and to prepare for an even more productive
      future.
      Your donation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron School of Art</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery</ENAMEX> is crucial to
      this goal. Even though we receive operating funds from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, there
      are a myriad of additional expenses to be met, such as welding equipment
      for sculpture, pottery wheels for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX>, and computers for graphics.
      There's our art programs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX> and senior high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> which
      are so critical now with less and less allocated in school budgets for
      the arts. And, there is always a need for scholarship funds to help make
      college degrees possible for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, most of whom come from central
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      Your contribution means so much to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> who enjoy
      our outreach programs and gallery exhibitions. Please complete the
      enclosed card and return it with your check made payable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron School</ENAMEX>
      of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art-IUF</ENAMEX>. Don't forget to indicate to which area you would like your
      donation to be directed.
      Thank you for your interest and support in this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our 90th year</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William J. Voos Dean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron School of Art</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery</ENAMEX>
      P.S. I have enclosed a schedule of our upcoming exhibitions. Take the
      time to stop by and visit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis' Center</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary Art</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron School of Art</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gallery</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> is contemporary art!
    
  
