
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 30, 1993</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Name</ENAMEX>:
      Response ability: As the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of a thriving urban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>, the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> faces many responsibilities. In many ways, the
      ability to respond is crucial to the mission and well-being of the
      campus. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> provides <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald L.</ENAMEX>
      Bepko with an important source of unrestricted funds to help him to
      respond to the challenges of a rapidly changing environment.
      Contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Circle</ENAMEX> have already been
      extraordinarily valuable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>: by helping to recruit a
      national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in institutional planning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudy Banta</ENAMEX>, by bringing the
      advice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> on such topics as race relations and freshman
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retention</ENAMEX>, and by helping us to strengthen our ties with the community
      through participation in programs like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WordStruck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-day</TIMEX>
      festival of books and reading. You are invited to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s
      Circle at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> which provides unrestricted funds for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>'s use. Those
      who contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Circle</ENAMEX> believe that our urban
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">university</ENAMEX> is an important community resource for the educational,
      cultural, and economic quality of life of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
      Your support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> will contribute to the success
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> continue to grow and to change.
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Circle</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associates</ENAMEX>,
      you will receive reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Bepko</ENAMEX> on how he puts your gifts to
      work. You also will be invited to special events and receive selected
      mailings about progress on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>.
      As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, you can participate by making an annual unrestricted
      gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> or more for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX>, or of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> or more for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associates</ENAMEX>. Corporate participation involves an annual
      unrestricted gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> or more for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Circle</ENAMEX> or of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>
      or more for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associates</ENAMEX>.
      I have enclosed a brochure which tells you more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> and which includes a reply card. I have also enclosed a reply
      envelope for your convenience.
      I hope you will join me in support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> at
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>. Thank you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John R. Hodowal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> Enclosures
      
    
  
