
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31, 1993</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name and Name:
      I would like to thank you for your support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX>
      at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> in its initial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. You joined many others who contributed to
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Circle</ENAMEX> and demonstrated their belief that our urban
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">university</ENAMEX> is an important community resource for the educational,
      cultural, and economic quality of life of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellor s Circle</ENAMEX> have
      already been extraordinarily valuable to IUPUI: by helping to recruit a
      national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in institutional planning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trudy Banta</ENAMEX>, by bringing the
      advice of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX> on such topics as race relations and freshman
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retention</ENAMEX>, and by helping us to strengthen our ties with the community
      through participation in programs like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WordStruck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-day</TIMEX>
      festival of books and reading.
      You are invited to renew your support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> at
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> which provides unrestricted funds for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Bepko</ENAMEX>'s use.
      Your support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> will continue to contribute to
      the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> grow and change. As
      you know, you can participate as an individual by making an annual
      unrestricted gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> or more for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">of $500</ENAMEX>
      or more for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellors Associates</ENAMEX>. Corporate participation involves an
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> unrestricted gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> or more for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Circle</ENAMEX> or of
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> or more for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellors Associates</ENAMEX>. I have enclosed a brochure
      which tells you more about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellor s Circle</ENAMEX> and which includes a
      reply card. I have also enclosed a reply envelope for your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convenience</ENAMEX>.
      I hope you will continue your support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellor s Circle</ENAMEX> at
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>. Thank you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John R. Hodowal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellor s Circle</ENAMEX>
    
  
