
  
  
    
      You are invited to participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University-Purdue University</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> (IUPUI).
      This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> will directly help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> meet immediate
      needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. These needs require unrestricted
      gifts that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> can use for special purposes that the usual
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> of support can't cover.
      With your personal commitment, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> will be able to
      act sooner and more effectively when special opportunities arise.
      As is true at other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>, almost all of our operating funds are
      restricted. We must use income from fees and appropriations for defined
      purposes, and most gifts are designated. Even at ivy-covered,
      well-endowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, discretionary funds are limited. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>,
      they are scarce. Through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> unrestricted gifts from individual and
      corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> will make it possible to
      respond more fully and flexibly to current needs. You are invited to
      become a part of this important new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> to strengthen this growing
      partnership of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> great state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mission</ENAMEX> and Plans
      Every great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> needs a first-rate system of higher education-both
      public and private-anchored by a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>- rate public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>. For
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, that public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> must be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>.
      From its start in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue University at</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> with its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> in their shared
      growth and development. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>'s contributions of teaching, research, and
      public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> have helped to lift the quality of life in its
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>'s goals for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, in the context of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>'s
      statewide plans, call for improving undergraduate education, enhancing
      relationships with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> , and strengthening research that will
      stimulate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s economic growth.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> envisions a complete and unified university <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>, one that
      will become a model for public higher education for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.
      Private gifts will play a vital role in reaching these goals. The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> offers distinctive ways to add momentum to further
      growth of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faculty Recruitment and Development Discretionary</ENAMEX> funds are especially
      needed to attract and retain faculty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, there
      will be much stiffer national competition for new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>. The numbers of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ph.D.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX> will be down, many current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> will retire, and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">enrollments</ENAMEX> will increase. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>, where we continue to face critical
      shortages of full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>, we will have to make special efforts.
      Gifts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> will help pay travel costs to our city
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> for prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>, along with some
      relocation costs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> also will help current faculty
      keep up with their scholarly and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX>. They need individual
      support to attend conferences, present papers, publish their works, and
      keep in touch with others in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Awards Annual</ENAMEX> presentations of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s awards
      encourage outstanding work among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. These
      awards provide chances to recognize unusual achievements and sometimes
      offer honoraria as incentives. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> will help to
      defray costs of these special awards.
      Special Opportunities No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> can anticipate every opportunity
      that may become available during its next budget cycle. These can include
      unforeseen chances to enhance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> learning by inviting
      special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> when they happen to be in the
      state. sometimes local events can generate chances for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and staff
      to assist the community because of their unique forms of expertise.
      Or sudden changes in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> can create openings for faculty
      research. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> also can serve as a community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX>, sponsoring
      public lectures by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> on issues in the news. Support from the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> can help us take advantage of such emerging
      options.
      Joining The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Circle</ENAMEX> As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX>, you
      will receive reports from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald L. Bepko</ENAMEX> on how he puts your
      gifts to work. You also will be invited to special events and receive
      mailings about campus activities. Other benefits of participation are
      being planned. Initially, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> can take part by making an annual
      unrestricted gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> or more for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">of $500</ENAMEX>
      or more for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellors Associates</ENAMEX>. Corporate participation involves an
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> unrestricted gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> or more for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chancellors Circle</ENAMEX> or of
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> or more for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chancellors Associates</ENAMEX>.
      Checks should be made payable to: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Foundation/IUPUI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle University Conference Center</ENAMEX> 850 West <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Michigan Street</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Suite</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">241</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46202-5198</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">317</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">274-3711</ENAMEX> For information on gifts
      of stocks, bonds, or mutual funds, or how to make a gift through the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue Foundation</ENAMEX>, please contact the above <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue University at Indianapolis Board of Advisors</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honorable Sarah Evans Barker Percy Clark, Jr. Mitchell Daniels, Jr.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Deppert Joseph P. Pogliano David R. Prick Harry L. Gonso John T.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hackett Honorable William H. Hudnut, III Sam H. Jones Thomas A. King</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter B. Kirkwood, Jr. J. Timothy McGinley E. Kirk McKinney Ted R.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meredith Thomas Miller James T. Morris John Myrland Dr. C.W. Pettinga</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George P. Rapp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.D.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William T. Ray Dr. Beurt Servaas Eric A. Todd Eunice</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trotter Patricia Tumer-Smith Phil Votaw P. Blake Wallace Emeritus Mrs.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edna B. Lacy</ENAMEX>
    
  
