
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31, 1994</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name,
      Thank you again for sending me the information on your "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> reasonable
      request" direct mail appeal as well as your detailed analysis of results.
      I shamelessly and freely borrowed the concept, making adaptations to fit
      our needs and used it as a direct mail appeal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>...samples
      enclosed.
      Here's the results so far: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#</NUMEX> mailed: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,615</NUMEX> targeted to our non-donor
      alumni <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">#</NUMEX> responses: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81 1.4%</NUMEX> # raised: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,840</NUMEX> smallest gift: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.00</NUMEX> largest
      gift: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250.00</NUMEX>
      Summary: While we didn't generate as much gift income as you did, we
      were extremely pleased with the results, the overall favorable response
      to the nature of this ask, and the additional notes and comments received
      from these non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> sent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> because "you asked me for a
      reasonable amount". Several filled out the questionnaire and returned it
      with an apology why they couldn't give...at least they were honest!
      Thanks again for your kind assistance.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Fehlman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX>
      I asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> to submit a few reasons why they
      felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> would contribute <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $25</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX> College
      in support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Malone College Fund</ENAMEX>. They came back with lots of
      reasons ! We hope you find your reasons on the list. If not, be sure to
      add yours next to the blanks provided. On the reverse side of this card,
      you will find an explanation of how funds contributed to The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malone</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College Fund</ENAMEX> are utilized. Please let us hear from you soon!
    
  
