
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1, 1992</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geography Department</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> has graduated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">67</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geographers</ENAMEX>. There have been so many changes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> campus and your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> that you and your fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> might not recognize
      them.
      A major development of national significance has provided much
      prestige to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Geography Department</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      decided to develop a massive geographic information system (GIS) called
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Mapping and Geographic Infrastructure System</ENAMEX> (IMAGIS) in
      which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geography Department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> were invited to
      participate. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> banded
      together with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> to develop an accurate multipurpose computer
      map of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> manages the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> in exchange
      for the privilege of being able to carry out geographic teaching and
      research on the system. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratory</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Spatial Information</ENAMEX>
      Research (LASIR) was established as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>'s interface with
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMAGIs</ENAMEX>. Faculty research and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GIS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> are conducted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LASIR</ENAMEX>. You
      might be interested in checking out the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>.
      Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> has been recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The National Geographic Society</ENAMEX>
      which has granted over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350,000</NUMEX> to be matched by state funds to develop
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">geographic</ENAMEX> education in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Geographic Education</ENAMEX>
      Network of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana, Inc.</ENAMEX> (GENI) manages the statewide project from the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Geography Department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GENI</ENAMEX> organizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> workshops for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and assists them in developing geography teaching materials for
      classroom use. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GENI</ENAMEX> also promotes the expansion of geography in teacher
      training curriculums and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> curriculums.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, there are over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40</TIMEX> geography <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>. They must
      compete with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> for limited financial aid. For
      the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> has received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1000</NUMEX> gift to
      begin a scholarship fund to benefit geography <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> only. $<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1000</TIMEX> is
      very generous, but in order to preserve a scholarship, it must be
      invested. An endowment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> would allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to award
      needy geography majors small, but very important scholarships--every
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>.
      You can help in several ways. Most obviously, you can make a personal
      gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IUPUI Geography Alumni Scholarship</ENAMEX>. If <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1000</NUMEX> seems like a
      lot, please consider a gift in an amount you can afford. Perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> is
      more to your liking or, perhaps, you would be interested in making
      several smaller gifts during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. Any contributions are tax
      deductible from both federal and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> state taxes. Please send your
      contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Foundation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Geography Department</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX>, with the enclosed card in the self-addressed envelope.
      Please contact me if you have any questions.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Bein Chair</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Especially appealing, for you and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, is the fact
      that a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that will match their
      gifts--sometimes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as much as three</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. If you do, and you make a gift
      of perhaps <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s match could raise the value of your gift to
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX>! That makes a big difference in the amount available
      to establish a scholarship to benefit geography <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>.
      Enclosure
      
    
  
