
  
  
    
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Apri1 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16, 1990</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Christopher</ENAMEX>:
      The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Senior Challenge</ENAMEX> is about to begin. We invite your
      participation!
      WHAT IS THE <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">SENIOR CHALLENGE</ENAMEX>?
      The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Senior Challenge</ENAMEX> is a giving program for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> to help the
      School of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Arts</ENAMEX>.
      WHERE DOES THE MONEY GO?
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> areas have been targeted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>: (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the general fund of the
      School of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Arts</ENAMEX> to provide assistance where needed, (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan B. Wolf</ENAMEX> Loan Fund for enrolled liberal arts
      majors who are in need of temporary financial assistance.
      WHY GIVE?
      We have been the direct <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> of private as well as state
      support of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>. Gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> are essential to bridge the
      gap between what our tuition dollars and state funding provide, and the
      actual cost of an undergraduate education. A better <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Liberal</ENAMEX>
      Arts helps increase the value of our own degrees.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Liberal Arts</ENAMEX> Senior
      Challenge. Over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> was raised. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, our goal is to double that
      amount. Those of us on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Council of the School of Liberal Arts</ENAMEX>,
      representing you to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX> and funding your departmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>, trips
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, believe that you can help us convey to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX> and our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> how much we appreciate them. The way is simple.
      Join us in helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Liberal Arts</ENAMEX> be all that it can be.
      Complete and mail the enclosed form in the self-addressed postage-paid
      envelope with your check made to the ill <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation/Liberal Arts</ENAMEX> Senior
      Challenge.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle A. Hoffmann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'91</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Council</ENAMEX> of the
      School of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Arts</ENAMEX>
    
  
