
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 26, 1990</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Name</ENAMEX>:
      As a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> with a liberal arts education, you are well
      aware of the importance of education in our society--and of the challenge
      we have in making it available to a wide range of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
      With the cost of providing quality and diversity always on the rise,
      the financial generosity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> continues to allow
      important, nationally recognized, projects to move forward. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Projects</ENAMEX>
      which enliven and enrich the student experience and draw some of our
      finest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>--and to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
      Whether you attended classes full time, were an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> returning
      student, or worked full time in a career while taking classes, I believe
      you know first hand how important it was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Arts</ENAMEX> was open and
      available to you--and you also know how important it still is.
      You may not have realized it at the time, but you and your fellow
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were part of something very big in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>. Today, the
      School of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Arts</ENAMEX> experiences national prominence as a focal point
      for innovation in our humanities and social sciences.
      Let me mention some of the interdisciplinary publishing projects the
      School has developed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> of the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles S. Peirce</ENAMEX>,
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the most important scholarly editions in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> letters, has
      been featured in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Times Literary Supplement</ENAMEX>, the most widely
      read international book review in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Religion</ENAMEX>
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Culture</ENAMEX> will begin publication <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. The Encyclopedia
      of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> is progressing well. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Studies Project</ENAMEX> is
      planning a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX>.
      Funds from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> were essential aspects of initiating all these
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>. As they continue to receive national attention, annual funding
      is necessary for them to grow and excel further.
      We (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> and you) have come a long way--not only under our own
      steam, but with the combined help of many others. Please join in this
      help with your gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      Best regards,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Barlow Dean</ENAMEX>
    
  
