
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 4, 1992</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      Here we are, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Communication</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Theatre</ENAMEX>, and there
      you are, an alum of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>. Yet, in the midst of all our activity
      over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX>, many of us have NOT COMMUNICATED--at least not with one
      another.
      Under separate cover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Wagener</ENAMEX> recently sent a mailing to you
      in order to confirm your current educational and occupational status,
      your ongoing involvements and interests, and future plans you might
      have.
      Our records in that regard are fragmentary at best. Most recently, we
      received results of an employment survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1990</NUMEX>- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">91</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>, conducted
      by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Career and Employment Services</ENAMEX>--it was pleasing to learn that
      we had nearly twice as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> as any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> in the
      School of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Arts</ENAMEX>. A proportionately large number of you responded
      to that survey.
      But, it is high time that we establish direct contact with all alumni
      from all the graduation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, from all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> activities and areas.
      That is why, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagener</ENAMEX> indicated, departmental newsletters soon will
      be forthcoming, sharing information on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> as well as happenings in
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>.
      Recently a project' arose that should be interesting to you as a
      former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> who struggled to clear the financial hurdle of education.
      We were generously offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> toward the establishment of our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>'s first scholarship program. It was given as a start toward a
      goal of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> alumni scholarship fund. That fund would allow us to
      grant a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> scholarship <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> to meritorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX> with
      financial need.
      Here is where you can help. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> is a highly commendable goal
      which can be realized through contributions in whatever amount you can
      give. As you probably well know, the resources provided by such
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholarships</ENAMEX> might well determine whether or not promising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> can
      continue their education. Please use the enclosed postage-paid envelope
      to make your gift. I might add that a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> qualifies you for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">recognition</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Liberal Arts Dean's Council</ENAMEX>, a critical
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> whose generosity does a lot to advance the calibre of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>.
      Whether the tax deductible gift you can give is for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> or
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>, I urge you to join us as we build better ways to help our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NOW OUR FIRST INVITATION</ENAMEX> TO YOU: We invite each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX> and
      her/his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest</ENAMEX> to attend our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department Reception</ENAMEX> for Graduating
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Seniors</ENAMEX> and Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guests</ENAMEX>. In this way, you can be recognized and thanked
      in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, while visiting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The reception is
      held on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same day</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Liberal Arts Honors Convocation</ENAMEX>.
      The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> reception was by far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our biggest</TIMEX> and best--it was held on campus
      during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hours</TIMEX> immediately preceding School activities. Our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
      reception will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 16</TIMEX>. Please note that on your calendar. Specifics
      will be sent to you once the menu and plans have been finalized and
      invitations printed.
      We look forward to hearing from you and interacting more frequently in
      the future.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert C. Dick</ENAMEX>, Ph.D. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairperson</ENAMEX>
    
  
