
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1993</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dr. Name</ENAMEX>:
      Everyone at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> is excited about the upcoming
      Fall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental Alumni Conference</ENAMEX> to be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16-18</NUMEX>. By now, you should have received registration materials for the
      conference, and we are hopeful that you can attend. If you have not
      received the mailing, please call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Alumni Association</ENAMEX>
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">317-274-8828</ENAMEX>) as soon as possible.
      At this time of your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">45th</NUMEX> reunion of graduation from dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, I
      would like to tell you about an opportunity to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX>. Funds are needed to upgrade the student
      lounge so that it can be a more comfortable place for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to break
      the tension of their heavy academic load. The upgraded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> is a
      priority program for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> other reunion classes will be participating in this effort.
      Together, we believe that our reunion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> can make a contribution
      which will be very meaningful for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. To make it
      interesting, a little competition has been proposed --the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with the
      highest participation rate and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with the highest dollar total
      will be honored.
      I do look forward to seeing you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. I am
      hopeful that the Class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> will be well represented both in
      attendance and in participation in the class gift program. Best
      regards!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry F. Smith Director</ENAMEX>
      P.S. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is a pledge card and return envelope to assist you in
      making your tax deductible contribution. Make your check payable to IU
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>. Thanks!
    
  
