
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20, 1992</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear IDDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX>:
      Very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentists</ENAMEX> will deny that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> is lacking in qualified,
      well-trained dental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University School of Dentistry</ENAMEX>'s
      program for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental Assisting</ENAMEX> is one of the most outstanding in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
      Yet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>, it almost closed its doors due to a lack of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicants</ENAMEX>. In the same period, programs like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aristotle</ENAMEX> have had
      no problems filling their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX>.
      A recent survey of dental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> showed many of them would have
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chosen I.U.</ENAMEX>'s program if they had known it existed! Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U.</ENAMEX>'s
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental Assisting</ENAMEX> program is not listed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow Pages</ENAMEX> due to a lack
      of funds. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U.</ENAMEX>'s program is also less expensive than competing programs.
      Who knows how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dropped their interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental Assisting</ENAMEX> when
      they heard the tuition costs at other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>? Hopefully, all of us can
      do more "internal marketing" with our young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to encourage them to
      consider the field of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental Assisting</ENAMEX>.
      We can also offer scholarships to young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> interested in attending
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U.</ENAMEX>'s program. Don't overlook your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> as potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
      Lastly, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Dean</ENAMEX> can be contacted about establishing a special
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endowment</ENAMEX> fund to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental Assisting Program</ENAMEX> conduct more public
      relations and advertising and hopefully even list its phone number in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellow Pages</ENAMEX>. Checks should be made out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University Foundation</ENAMEX>
      and sent directly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development Office</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUSD</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1121</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Michigan</ENAMEX>
      Street, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indiana 46202</ENAMEX>, Attention: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Dean</ENAMEX>. A pledge card
      and return envelope are enclosed.
      Each of us needs to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassadors</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dentistry</ENAMEX> within our own
      practices, and at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>, athletic and social events. Let's do our best
      to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U.</ENAMEX> 's programs fully enrolled and funded. Let's head off an
      auxiliary crisis before it happens! Remember all donations are tax
      deductible.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia W. Crose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.D.S. Consultant</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U.S.D. Dental Assisting</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advisory Committee</ENAMEX>
    
  
