
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4, 1991</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dr. Name</ENAMEX>:
      We have something common in addition to being orthodontists who
      graduated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U.</ENAMEX> orthodontic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>. If you recall, when we
      were in the grad program and making much less money than we now pay in
      taxes, we were awarded a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prentice Scholarship</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Fifteen</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, when I
      received a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prentice</ENAMEX> check for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1000.00</NUMEX>, it was like winning the lottery.
      Of course, at that time my rent was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50.00</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson Prentice</ENAMEX> received his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.D.S.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX> and lives in
      Jeffersonville, IN. His generous contribution to dentistry in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> has
      helped <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> orthodontic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> so far to meet educational
      expenses; and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> will receive scholarships <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
      I hope you will join me in thanking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prentice</ENAMEX> for his generosity
      and to help build the fund that once assisted us. Maybe you have already
      done so, but if not, please give it some consideration.
      An envelope and pledge card is enclosed to assist you in supporting
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prentice Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX> and our future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth R. Hyde</ENAMEX>, D.D.S.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">KRH/jes</ENAMEX>
      P.S. If you would like to write Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prentice</ENAMEX>, I'm sure he would be
      happy to hear from you. His address is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1535</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nole Drive</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jeffersonville</ENAMEX>,
      IN <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">47130</NUMEX>.
    
  
