
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 12, 1994</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few months ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Newton</ENAMEX> and I wrote a letter asking you to
      consider a financial contribution to graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Endodontics</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>. I am pleased to tell you that we have had a positive response
      to the letter.
      It is great to know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, like you, who have graduated from our
      program are willing to support us in such a significant way. We are using
      the funds to support graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endodontic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>. without
      the financial backing of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>, their educational experience would
      be somewhat diminished.
      I'm sending this follow-up letter to let you know that your support is
      greatly needed and appreciated by everyone involved with graduate
      Endodontics at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU</ENAMEX>. With <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> tax decisions on the horizon, I hope
      that you'll include our program in your charitable contributions.
      Your gift, made through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University Foundation</ENAMEX>, is
      tax-deductible.
      Let me assure you that all contributions directed to graduate
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endodontics</ENAMEX> will be used only within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our</TIMEX> program. You can be certain that
      your support is very meaningful to us. I've enclosed a gift card and
      envelope for your convenience. Thanks for your consideration!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecil Brown Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate Professor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graduate</ENAMEX>
      Endodontics
    
  
