
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 4, 1993</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Classmates</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>:
      The time of our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">50th</NUMEX> reunion is rapidly approaching - we'll be
      celebrating that event in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 16 - 18</TIMEX>. By now, you
      should have received registration materials for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fall Alumni Dental</ENAMEX>
      Conference. If you have not, please call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Alumni Association</ENAMEX>
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">317-274-8828</ENAMEX>) right away.
      Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX> other reunion classes, has been challenged to
      support a program which will directly benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUSD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Remember the
      student lounge which we enjoyed so much - where we played euchre with
      some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Healy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humphries</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boesinger</ENAMEX> and others
      - where some ate their lunches and ... some even studied?
      Well, the student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> today is much larger and in a different
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">location</ENAMEX>, and it badly needs upgrading so that it can be a more
      comfortable place for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to break the tension of their heavy
      academic load (much heavier than what we experienced).
      Together, I think we can make a contribution to that upgrading of the
      lounge which will be very meaningful for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. I have sent a
      check for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> and hope that you will consider a like gift or more.
      By the way, it must have been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX> or more when I was a member
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> told me they were going to refurnish our old
      student <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> and asked if I would like to have one of the old octagon
      shaped oak tables. They were pretty beat up and the tops well covered
      with carvings of teeth, initials, etc. He said that I might "midnite
      requisition" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. Well, I did and sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> removed it to my cottage
      in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and used decopor (a thick, clear glazed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">resin</ENAMEX>) on the top. I
      think it is preserved forever. Anyway, I treasure that table. Someone
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">carved</ENAMEX> (expertly) "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">43</ENAMEX>" on it. A well carved "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. F. Pope</ENAMEX>" appears on it as
      does "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bob Bergman '43"</ENAMEX>. Also carved on the top are the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> letters of
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fraternities</ENAMEX>. It's obvious from the beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carvings</ENAMEX> of teeth
      on the surface that we had a good instruction in dental anatomy.
      Someone made it possible for us to have the benefit of that lounge
      which I'm sure you can all still picture in your minds. By contributing
      to the upgrading of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s student <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX>, we have the opportunity to,
      in a small way, provide a part of the memories of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU</ENAMEX> that will last a
      lifetime. You may recall from my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> letter regarding our 50th
      reunion that a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Union Building</ENAMEX> has been reserved for our use
      following the banquet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. A bartender will be available and we
      will have a chance to enjoy reminiscing the equivalent of our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
      academic years together and the happenings during the time that has
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transpired</ENAMEX> since our graduation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years ago</TIMEX>.
      Hope you will be present.
    
  
