
  
  
    
      May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9, 1991</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dr. Name</ENAMEX>:
      As of this date, we have received commitments for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately forty</NUMEX>
      percent of our goal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy J. O'Leary Periodontal Endowment</ENAMEX> Fund.
      We greatly appreciate those who have been able to contribute or pledge a
      gift for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX>.
      I know we are all grateful for the benefits received from our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endowment Fund</ENAMEX> is a way we can show our appreciation and
      support; and at the same time, make sure future <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> receive the
      same benefits. I do hope this is a convenient time for you to make a gift
      or commit to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year</TIMEX> pledge. If we obtain our goal soon, the fund can
      begin to be used for excellence in teaching and research.
      I will continue to keep you informed of the progress on this project;
      and if there are any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> you would like me to contact, I
      will be happy to do so.
      Once again, should you have any questions in regard to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy J.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Leary Periodontal Endowment</ENAMEX> Fund, please feel free to contact me.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Nishimine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.D.S., M.S.D.</ENAMEX>
      P.S. I have enclosed a pledge card and envelope to assist you in
      making your gift. Please make checks payable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Foundation</ENAMEX> for the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy J. O'Leary Periodontal Endowment</ENAMEX> Fund. Thank you.
    
  
