
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCHOOL OF DENTISTRY</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 18, 1990</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Colleague</ENAMEX>:
      Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> have recently
      asked how they can become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Club</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> is made
      up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> with
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> gifts of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> or more. I believe many of the questions are being
      asked because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU</ENAMEX>'s major fundraising effort
      that started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>) is ending and many who supported <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUSD</ENAMEX> through the
      campaign are wondering how they can continue their support.
      Payroll deduction is perhaps the easiest way to make a contribution.
      For example, with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 biweekly</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> contributon, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can
      be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Club</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">member</ENAMEX>. And if a person decides to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX>,
      the best time to begin is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> prior to salary increases. This
      allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> to adjust their budget without losing any money they are
      already receiving. I guess I encourage this method because I've always
      made my contributions this way, it's a "painless" method and at tax time
      I enjoy the deduction.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">726</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century I</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>; we would like to
      have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1990</TIMEX>. If you would like to help us reach
      our goal, we have enclosed a pledge card for your convenience. Please
      return it to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Stafford</ENAMEX> or me (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Room 202</ENAMEX>) so that
      we can personally thank you for your support. You will also receive a
      letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Gilmore</ENAMEX> expressing his appreciation.
      Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> we've been able to make many improvements that
      would not have been possible without the generosity and backing of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Club</ENAMEX>. Support from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Club</ENAMEX> helps us continue to provide
      a progressive learning and working environment for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, faculty
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>. I thank all of you who are already supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUSD</ENAMEX>, and I look
      forward to welcoming many of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">new century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
      If you have any questions, please feel free to stop by and see me.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny R. Dean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX>
    
  
