
  
  
    
      May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">28, 1991</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Classmate</ENAMEX>:
      I know most of you will find it hard to believe, but we are about to
      celebrate our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35th Anniversary</TIMEX>. I am just amazed when I see one of you at
      a dental meeting; you just don't look like you have been in practice that
      long!
      But time is marching on and I know all of you will want to make plans
      to attend the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">IU Fall Dental Conference</ENAMEX>. We had a great time <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX>; but due to the remodeling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Building</ENAMEX>
      on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bloomington Campus</ENAMEX>, the conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is being held in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>. You will soon receive information from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alumni</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> with the details.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> is being challenged by the other reunion classes
      to raise funds. The goal is to equip <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> new operatories at the dental
      school. The deadline for donations from each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31</TIMEX>. There
      will be winners in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> categories (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) the Class that contributes the most
      money, and (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the Class that has the greatest percent of class member
      participation. A <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> plate will be placed in each operatory to honor the
      reunion classes.
      Contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> will receive an added
      bonus, of a tuition waived registration to a nonrestricted <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">CE Course</ENAMEX>, at
      the dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1991-92</TIMEX> academic year. This is a great
      opportunity for the Class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> to show who is really number one!
      Best regards,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>, D.D.S.
      P.S. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is a pledge card and return envelope to assist in making
      your tax deductible contribution for the Class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX>.
    
  
