
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1993</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Doctor</ENAMEX>:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Health Center</ENAMEX> are
      pleased to announce a program that will positively affect the oral health
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> needs of the underserved while providing a significant educational
      opportunity for future dental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX>. This collaborative effort,
      which is scheduled to begin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1993</TIMEX>, will place well- trained
      dental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, under the supervision of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty members</ENAMEX>, in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clinic</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Health Center</ENAMEX> to provide care to the homeless. (The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center's Homeless Initiative Program</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">section 340</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care for</ENAMEX>
      Homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grantee</ENAMEX> and provides comprehensive primary health care to
      homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marion County</ENAMEX>. The primary service
      area is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Center Township</ENAMEX>.)
      The oral health care needs of homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are overwhelming. Dental
      distress is widespread in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> whose inability to seek care is
      compounded by fear and a lack of resources, transportation, and providers
      from which to receive care. Poor oral conditions greatly impact the
      overall health of homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> as well as their ability to survive
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>. Dental problems can even interfere with opportunities for
      employment.
      Public health dentistry is an essential component of a well-rounded
      dental education. Early introduction to this topic in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>'s career
      helps produce an informed and caring practitioner who has a strong sense
      of community service and the needs of underserved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. This
      educational experience brings to light what an integral role the dental
      component plays in an individual's overall health.
      In addition to the dental instruction provided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> will be
      introduced to the objectives of community health <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, with particular
      emphasis on the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Health Center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> will provide
      dental health education for homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> as well.
      Significant costs of this exciting collaboration will be absorbed by
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Health Center</ENAMEX>. However, over
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> in dental instruments, equipment, and supplies is needed to make
      the program successful. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Funding</ENAMEX> is being requested from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, and others interested in serving health care needs of
      homeless and other underserved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX>. We are pleased to note that
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hu-Friedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L.D. Caulk</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Dental</ENAMEX> have each agreed to contribute to
      this worthy cause. We are hopeful that you will agree to help, also. This
      program will see many positive outcomes with your investment.
      Thank you for your consideration of this request. You can help make
      this valuable program available to many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who are not currently
      benefiting from dental care.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. William Gilmore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">DDS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer R. Kugar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDS Dean of Dentistry</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's Health Center</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Please use the enclosed reply card and the postage-paid envelope
      to make your contribution. Make checks payable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>. All contributions are tax-deductible.
    
  
