
  
  
    
      May<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">,1994</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Alumnus</ENAMEX>:
      When I last wrote to you about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph E. McDonald</ENAMEX>/Pedodontic Fund,
      it was with the news that expenditures were greater than contributions
      for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Many of you responded in a positive manner by increasing your
      contribution or contributing to the fund for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time. Thanks to
      your efforts, the account was again in the black for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>!
      The account description written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph E.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald/Pedodontic Fund</ENAMEX> states "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Expenditures</ENAMEX> of the fund shall be
      approved by the fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>. All expenditures should be
      restricted to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pedodontic</ENAMEX> area." This fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> is still in place
      and I have served as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> since I was elected to that
      position by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970</TIMEX>'s.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pediatric Dentistry Clinic</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> is scheduled to be
      relocated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> will be in the old grad pedo
      area across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orthodontic Clinic</ENAMEX> in the south <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the
      School. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> are looking forward to using a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> that
      will be equipped with the newest dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> and systems available. The
      money to pay for the renovation and major equipment will be taken from
      non-departmental funds and hopefully recovered with increased clinic
      revenues over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX>. However, I am sure there will be other
      items that will be needed in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> to enhance the educational
      experience of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, including graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
      I want to encourage you to continue to support your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX> with
      contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald Fund</ENAMEX> and to increase your contribution, if
      possible. Please use the enclosed, coded card and envelope, which will
      insure that your contribution is deposited directly to our account. This
      Fund provides <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s pedo program with enrichment opportunities that
      are equaled by few, if any, other programs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. We are most
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sincerely</ENAMEX> grateful for your generosity.
      
    
  
