
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6, 1990</TIMEX>
      Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>:
      In writing our invitations for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this years century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Club</ENAMEX> reception we
      noticed that you did not renew your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. We hope that you
      will reconsider and join us for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Club</ENAMEX> reception on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
      May 3 (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6-7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>) at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyatt Regency</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Dental</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> meeting. Our attendance has grown over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and,
      frankly, we just feel it wouldn't be a successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> without you! If
      for some reason you are unable to renew your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX>, we still would
      like to thank you for your past support and hope that you will again
      join.
      Again, thanks for your support. Your contribution helped make it
      possible for us to provide our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> a quality education. If there is
      any way I can be of assistance, just let me know.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny R. Dean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">DRD/jes</ENAMEX>
      P.S. There's still time to be listed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ALUMNI BULLETIN</ENAMEX> and for us
      to send you an invitation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Club</ENAMEX> reception on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3rd</TIMEX>. I
      hope to see you there!
    
  
