
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 13, 1993</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Classmates</ENAMEX>:
      I am happy to report that we have reached our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> minimum and
      the Class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'58</NUMEX> will be celebrating, as planned, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Inn</ENAMEX> on
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, September 18</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30</TIMEX>. I am still accepting reservations 'till
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 3rd</TIMEX>. If you have not received the registration materials for
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fall Dental Alumni Conference</ENAMEX>, please call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Alumni Association</ENAMEX>
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">317-274-8828</ENAMEX>} as soon as possible.
      Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> has been challenged to support a program which will directly
      benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX>. Funds are needed to
      upgrade the student <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> so that it can be a more comfortable place for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to break the tension of their heavy academic load. According to
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourth-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Schmidt</ENAMEX>, who serves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> Affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX>, the upgraded <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> is a priority for the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> other classes will be participating in this effort, as well.
      Together, I believe that we can make a contribution which will be very
      meaningful for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. To make it interesting, a
      little competition has been proposed --the class which contributes the
      most money and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> with the highest participation will be
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">honored</ENAMEX>.
      Contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> will receive an added bonus
      of a tuition-waived registration to a non-restricted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C.E.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> at the
      dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1993-94</TIMEX> academic year. (The average tuition for
      a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">C.E.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $125</NUMEX>.)
      I do look forward to seeing you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. I am
      hopeful that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> will be well represented both in attendance and in
      participation in the class gift program. Best regards!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDS</ENAMEX> Enclosure
      P.S. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is a pledge card and return envelope to assist you in
      making your tax deductible contribution. Make your check payable to IU
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>. Thanks!
    
  
