
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 8, 1990</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dr. Name</ENAMEX>:
      We are pleased to report that another successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> meeting was
      held in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in attendance were on
      their best behavior (although we did have the name of a good bail
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bondsman</ENAMEX> just in case).
      At the dinner on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> a special project was announced to
      our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that, if you were unable to attend, I believe you will find
      exciting.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> periodontics program at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> are establishing an endowment fund. The
      fund will be named The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy J. O</ENAMEX>'Leary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Periodontal Endowment Fund</ENAMEX> in
      honor of the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Leary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> have benefited all of us and this is a way
      we can show our appreciation in a tangible way. The purpose of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fund</ENAMEX>
      will be to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX> to continue to excel in teaching and
      research in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">periodontics</ENAMEX>.
      As of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> meeting, we now have over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000.00</NUMEX> pledged toward
      our goal of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000.00</NUMEX> The goal will be obtained before the fund can
      begin to make disbursements. Interest from early donations will be used
      to build the principal.
      If a major contribution is not possible at this time, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year</TIMEX>
      pledge is acceptable. We are asking all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> for a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1000.00</NUMEX>
      per year for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. Of course, any gift will be appreciated. Based
      on each individual tax situation, your gift may be tax deductible. Let's
      get <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> participation from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>.
      We hope that you will consider supporting this special project and
      help us honor a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that has given us all so much.
      When we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> we talked about the good and, of course bad
      times we had at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUSD</ENAMEX>. But we all agreed on how lucky we were to have
      received the education that has provided us with the successful life we
      enjoy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Nishimine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.D.S., M.S.D.</ENAMEX>
      P.S. We are also organizing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Periodontal Alumni Association</ENAMEX> that
      we discussed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>. A report of the discussion will be sent to all
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> who were unable to attend.
    
  
