
  
  
    
      May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 1994</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dr. Name</ENAMEX>:
      An another academic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> comes to an end, I am pleased to report that
      your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> is continuing its leadership role in
      advancing dental education. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> are reviewing
      all aspects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> -curriculum, competencies, financial
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, just to name a few - to make sure that we remain at the
      forefront of dental education. Indeed, our entire <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> is being
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">renovated</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> so that our physical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> can accommodate the
      changing needs of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      Private donations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> play an essential role
      enabling us to continue as one of the top dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
      There are several critical areas which cannot be funded by the citizens
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State of Indiana</ENAMEX>, and without these programs our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> cannot
      completely fulfill its mission. Student scholarships, special faculty
      research, and advancements in technology need to be funded with
      contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      Your contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in the past have been very important
      to us, and I sincerely hope that you will make a financial investment in
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. I have enclosed a brochure which
      explains more about our needs. These are challenging times for dental
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and I firmly believe our ability to remain in
      a leadership position will be enhanced with your support. Please consider
      this request carefully --it is very important to us, the future of dental
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and your private practice.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. William Gilmore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDS Dean</ENAMEX>
    
  
