
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 17, 1993</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Services</ENAMEX>, I would like to
      introduce a new scholarship program designed to help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Afro-American</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> pursue studies in dentistry at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU</ENAMEX>.
      I have talked with, and attempted to recruit, many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afro</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for
      the doctoral program at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Dentistry</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>
      competes with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> other dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for the very
      brightest and most highly qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> candidates
      have declined our invitation to enroll at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU</ENAMEX> because other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have
      been able to offer scholarships, stipends, or other means of financial
      assistance. Recently we lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> to universities
      which offered <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> scholarships to cover their supplies and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX>.
      To boost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU</ENAMEX>'s enrollment of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afro</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, I have made
      a commitment to donate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> toward the establishment of a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minority Student Scholarship</ENAMEX> program. Our goal is to award scholarships
      in the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first-year</TIMEX> minority dental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to pay for
      supplies and equipment required in the first academic year.
      I am excited about this new program and invite you to join me in
      building a strong foundation for the project. Your gift will help us
      reach our immediate goal of awarding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> scholarship to a
      student for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall semester of 1993</TIMEX>, and our long-term goal of awarding
      several <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> scholarships <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>.
      Thank you for considering our request for your contribution to the
      this program--please call me at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">317/274</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5625</NUMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaForrest D. Garner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDS</ENAMEX>, MSD
      P.S. Checks should be made payable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Foundation</ENAMEX>. An envelope and
      giving card are enclosed for your convenience.
    
  
