
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 12, 1994</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Dental Hygiene Colleague</ENAMEX>:
      Turn back the hands of time and remember when you made the decision to
      become a dental hygienist. For some that decision was made in the recent
      past and for others, the distant past. Whatever the case, that decision
      was a defining moment in your life and the beginning of a productive and
      rewarding future.
      Each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> that enters our dental hygiene program is embarking on
      the same journey that you traveled before them. However, the excitement
      and motivation of that goal is often diminished by the difficult
      financial constraints that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> experience. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student population</ENAMEX> is
      changing and greater demands are placed on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
      Financial assistance through the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Rebekah Fisk Memorial Scholarship</ENAMEX>
      Fund has helped many dental hygiene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> achieve their career
      goal.
      If you have supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Rebekah Fisk Memorial Scholarship</ENAMEX> in the
      past, I would like to thank you for your commitment to dental hygiene
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> and ask for your continued support. If this is your first
      donation I would like to thank you in advance for your interest and
      support of this important scholarship fund. An envelope and giving card
      are enclosed for your convenience. Please make checks payable to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Foundation</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail F. Williamson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDH</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MS Dental Hygiene</ENAMEX> Alumna
    
  
