
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 24, 1993</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Name</ENAMEX>:
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> greatly values the support of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">friends of the School</ENAMEX>. Your membership in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Club</ENAMEX> has been very
      important for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>. I noticed that we did not receive your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> contribution in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, and hope that you will renew your gift.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> is committed to remaining the recognized
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in scholarly research, teaching and service. Your investment
      enables us to maintain our margin of excellence.
      Thank you for your support. Your contribution helped make it possible
      for us to provide our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with a quality education.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry F. Smith</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX>
      P.S. We will host a reception for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Club</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">members</ENAMEX> during the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Dental Association</ENAMEX> meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>. The reception is
      scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 29</TIMEX>, (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:00-7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>) at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hyatt Regency</ENAMEX>.
      We hope that you will renew your gift and join us for the reception.
    
  
