
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 10, 1993</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name,
      You are probably aware of the periodontal scholarship fund at the
      dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> under my name. This is administered through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Foundation</ENAMEX>.
      An award of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500.00</NUMEX> is given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yearly</TIMEX> to a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in each
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> who excels in scholarship. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> program has now been
      extended to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> which entails another cash award. In addition to
      this award the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> pays for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliate</ENAMEX> membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX> as well
      as providing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal of Periodontology</ENAMEX> for each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>. With the
      additional year of training our financial obligation has increased by a
      <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>.
      Payment of these awards is made from interest and dividends generated
      by the principal. As you are aware interest income and dividends have
      dropped considerably prompting this letter.
      You will find a contribution form from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Foundation</ENAMEX>. If you have
      or have not yet contributed to the foundation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> I am asking you
      to consider doing so. Please fill out the enclosed form indicating that
      this contribution is to be awarded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry M. Swenson Periodontic</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX>. As with all contributions made through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I U Foundation</ENAMEX>,
      your gift is tax-deductible according to federal and state laws. It will
      most certainly be appreciated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> as well as the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours ,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry M. Swenson</ENAMEX>
    
  
