
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 23, 1994</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Colleague</ENAMEX>:
      Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last fifteen years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Dental Association</ENAMEX>
      have built the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pursuit of Excellence Endowment</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dentistry</ENAMEX> with contributions in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX>. We have funded
      significant research endeavors and rewarded outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> for work
      that is at the leading edge of oral health care. In addition to funding
      these projects, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> has invested the money well, and the market
      value of the endowment has grown to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $750,000</NUMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trustees</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Dental Association</ENAMEX> approved a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> to raise funds to build the endowment to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>, to fund a
      distinguished chair at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUSD</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Dental Association Distinguished</ENAMEX>
      Chair will represent the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> state dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to
      complete such a commitment to its dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. In the rapidly changing
      health care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX>, this chair will serve as an important symbol of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> commitment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and profession in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      An endowed chair will greatly benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX>. From
      its inception, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDA Pursuit of Excellence Fund</ENAMEX> has supported and
      rewarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> for unique and outstanding effort on behalf of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dentistry</ENAMEX>. Income from the endowment will enable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUSD</ENAMEX> to attract and
      retain an eminently qualified faculty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. We will be
      able to fund the position with important incentives for excellence which
      would not be available from any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>.
      Our entire profession will benefit greatly from this endowment. It is
      important and we hope that you will make a significant contribution to
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pursuit of Excellence</ENAMEX> fund <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Five-year pledges are
      essential, and will be recognized at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDA Annual Session</ENAMEX> and in school
      and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>. Your contribution, made through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Foundation</ENAMEX>, is tax-deductible to the fullest extent of the
      law.
      Thank you for your consideration of this important request.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. William Gilmore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDS Dean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd J. Phillips</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DDS Chair, IDA Endowment Committee</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
