
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1990</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dr. Name</ENAMEX>:
      I hope that the plans you made as a dental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> for a career in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dentistry</ENAMEX> are developing to your satisfaction and that you are well on
      your way to achieving your professional goals. If any of us at the dental
      school can be of assistance, please write or call. I already miss my
      informal discussions with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the Class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'90</NUMEX>. Along with the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faculty</ENAMEX>, I always found your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to be one of the most personable that
      has graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUSD</ENAMEX>. Your opinions were valued and many improvements
      were made by having information about our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX>.
      As you know, major changes in dental education are under way
      throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Like all other dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>
      School of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dentistry</ENAMEX> is carefully re-evaluating its programs and planning
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ways</ENAMEX> to better serve the dental community. Your comments and suggestions
      as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> are valuable.
      Perhaps while you were in school you heard of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CENTURY CLUB</ENAMEX> which
      honors those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> who give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $100</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a calendar year</TIMEX> to any
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>'s programs. Support at this level could assist the dental
      school in a variety of ways. Now that you are of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> status, I would
      like to extend an invitation to you to join our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CENTURY CLUB</ENAMEX>.
      Alumni gifts have always played a major role in the dental school
      programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> from classes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX> received
      an education that was rounded out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> contributions. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumnus</ENAMEX> who
      gives today is helping to assure a quality education for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.
      We would be delighted to welcome you as a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CENTURY</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLUB</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. William Gilmore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.D.S. Dean</ENAMEX>
      P.S. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CENTURY CLUB</ENAMEX> member reception is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2</TIMEX> during the annual
      meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Dental Association</ENAMEX>. We look forward to seeing you
      there as a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CENTURY CLUB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>!
    
  
