
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear IUSD Colleague</ENAMEX>:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX> and the health profession suffered a significant
      loss with the passing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven L. Bricker</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21, 1994</TIMEX>. A
      nationally recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">innovator</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oral Diagnosis and Oral Medicine</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> is remembered as a gentleman whose care and concern for his
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> was warm and genuine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bricker</ENAMEX>
      pursued excellence for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and profession with
      unending determination. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chair of Diagnostic Sciences</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University School of Dentistry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Bricker</ENAMEX> set a standard for
      excellence to which we all aspire.
      We have created a scholarship endowment which will permanently
      recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Bricker</ENAMEX>'s contributions to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and
      profession. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bricker Scholarship</ENAMEX> will provide support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
      engaged in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> and post-graduate work in the diagnostic sciences at
      our dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. This endowment is a fitting tribute to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who made
      a difference, and will realize one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>'s passions - supporting
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
      The outcry from across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> over the loss of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Bricker</ENAMEX> has
      been significant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> have asked for the
      opportunity to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and recognize his good work by
      participating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven L. Bricker Scholarship Endowment</ENAMEX>. You may use
      the attached form if you wish to make a gift. Your contribution, made
      through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University Foundation</ENAMEX>, is tax-deductible.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">STEVEN L. BRICKER</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCHOLARSHIP ENDOWMENT</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
