
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 15, 1990</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dr. Name</ENAMEX>:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dentistry</ENAMEX> has been a part of my life for as long as I can remember. My
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is a practicing hygienist, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> a certified dental
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">technician</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> has been both a general practitioner and dental
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">educator</ENAMEX>. It was all of those positive influences that I have to thank
      for opening my eyes to dentistry as a profession.
      Being a third-year <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>--and having just escaped crown and bridge
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lab</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the second year</TIMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (exhausted) piece--I have just
      now begun to put <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> of learning into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> clinical practice. It
      has become obvious to me already how crucial the latest techniques and
      materials are to all fields of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dentistry</ENAMEX>.
      Not only are the latest and best techniques important to delivering
      quality dental care, they also help to preserve the traditional quality
      of dental education offered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately these improvements are
      costly, so additional funds are necessary.
      I'm sure that stepping into private practice for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time will
      be intimidating enough; but doing so without the best training possible
      would be twice as stressful. That is why it is essential to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
      at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUSD</ENAMEX> that you continue your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> or more as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II Fellow</ENAMEX>. Support at this level is assisting the dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in a
      variety of ways. We look forward to your renewal as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX> II
      Fellow.
      On behalf of all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUSD</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, I would like to personally thank you
      for your past support of dental education. As I have learned from the
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> who have already earned degrees from the
      School of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dentistry</ENAMEX>, the quality of my education will have a direct
      bearing on my professional life for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to come. Thank you for helping
      make my education in dentistry an excellent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Schimmele</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>, Class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>
      P.S. Please send any survival tips for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third and fourth year</TIMEX> dental
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to me, in care of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">IUSD</ENAMEX>!
    
  
