
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 22, 1994</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      Most of you remember sitting in a lecture <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> and learning about
      dental <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph W. Phillips</ENAMEX>. Perhaps you were one of the
      many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who were able to spend some time on a research project with
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> or one of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Dental</ENAMEX>
      Materials.
      Undoubtedly you have attended some of his postgraduate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, many
      of which were presented in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto Rico</ENAMEX>, and have used <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>' text,
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Science of Dental Materials</ENAMEX>. You now have the opportunity to help
      your school honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> by contributing to an endowed
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">professorship</ENAMEX> in his honor which will help assure continuation of his
      work.
      We are hoping to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUSD</ENAMEX> to create the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph W.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips Professorship</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dental Materials</ENAMEX>" and are asking for your help
      in this endeavor.
      A pledge card and envelope are enclosed for your convenience. Please
      make check payable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University Foundation</ENAMEX>. Your tax
      deductible contribution will help honor a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who devoted a lifetime of
      service to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX> and to dentistry. Thank you for your
      consideration and for your donation.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie L. Swartz</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emeritus Dental Materials</ENAMEX>
    
  
