
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 22, 1993</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dr. Name</ENAMEX>:
      These are challenging times for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> of higher
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, with legislative appropriations unable to fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to the
      level they have in the past. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> is limited in
      these times because it is impractical to raise tuition and fees
      sufficiently to offset lost state appropriations. I hope you have read,
      in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alumni Bulletin</ENAMEX>, how our dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> has taken
      aggressive steps to streamline operations and enhance academic
      opportunities while becoming more financially efficient.
      To continue to excel in its educational mission, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dentistry</ENAMEX> turns to us, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, to provide financial support
      for priority programs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean H.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Gilmore</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> has identified student support and
      technological infrastructure as the greatest needs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s annual
      fund appeal.
      Dental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are incurring more and more debt as they progress
      through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> has limited ability to provide
      scholarship money to deserving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who otherwise might choose
      another career option because of educational expense. Private support is
      needed to offset this problem.
      Additionally, there is a tremendous need to upgrade the technological
      infrastructure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> need support to be
      able to keep up with rapid advancements in oral health care and the use
      of technology for many procedures. We can help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> achieve this
      goal with donations to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX>.
      Your support as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Club</ENAMEX> has been very meaningful.
      I hope that you will take this opportunity to renew your gift or even
      consider joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">II Fellows</ENAMEX>, which recognizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>
      annually to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX>. Information is enclosed
      highlighting the various giving levels. Thank you for your ongoing
      support of our great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
    
  
