
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 22, 1993</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Colleague</ENAMEX>:
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, marks the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten-year</TIMEX> anniversary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Rebekah Fisk</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Scholarship</ENAMEX>. During this time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> have been selected by
      the dental hygiene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> to receive scholarship awards. I would like to
      personally thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the dental hygiene program who
      have made past contributions and hope you will continue with your
      support. In addition, I would encourage other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to
      consider providing their support for this scholarship fund.
      Dental hygiene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX> are incurring more and
      more debt as they progress through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> has
      limited ability to provide scholarship money to deserving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who
      otherwise might choose another career option because of educational
      expense.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Rebekah Fisk Memorial Scholarship</ENAMEX> enables the dental hygiene
      program to provide financial assistance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> so that they can
      concentrate on their education while in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, we were able
      to award <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six $500</NUMEX> scholarships to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in our dental hygiene program.
      These scholarships were made possible through contributions from alumni
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the program.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Rebekah Fisk Memorial Scholarship</ENAMEX> fund is a priority for the
      dental hygiene program. I hope that you will help us to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> by
      making a tax deductible gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. All contributions are very
      important, and with your support, we can really make a difference.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Please make your check payable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Foundation</ENAMEX> and use the
      enclosed postage-paid envelope to make your contribution. Thank you!
    
  
