
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCHOOL OF DENTISTRY</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10, 1992</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Dental Hygiene Colleague</ENAMEX>:
      While awaiting my licensure to practice dental hygiene, I have had the
      opportunity to look back upon my education at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University School</ENAMEX>
      of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dentistry</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1990</TIMEX>, I was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A. Rebekah Fisk Memorial</ENAMEX>
      Scholarship <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX>. This financial assistance enabled me to
      concentrate on my education and achieve many goals while in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> like you who support the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fisk Memorial Scholarship</ENAMEX>
      many other dental hygiene <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> will benefit from your generosity and
      reach their goal.
      Dental hygiene is proving to be an exciting and rewarding career, both
      in private practice and community settings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student American Dental</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hygienist's Association</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hearty Smiles</ENAMEX>" project at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riley Hospital</ENAMEX> has
      been successful and rewarding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as well as the hygiene
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Projects</ENAMEX> such as this touch the lives of others and enhance the
      education of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Your support enables the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to apply
      their knowledge and participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
      Thank you in advance for your contribution and interest in dental
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hygiene</ENAMEX> education. An envelope and giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> are enclosed (with checks
      payable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University Foundation</ENAMEX>).
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommi L. Davis Dental Hygiene Alumna</ENAMEX>
    
  
