
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 19, 1993</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear IDA Colleague:</ENAMEX>
      Since its inception in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDA Pursuit of Excellence Fund</ENAMEX> has
      enabled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> to support and reward <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> members
      for outstanding achievement. This fund has given us, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Dental Association</ENAMEX>, the opportunity to make a direct investment
      in the quality of dental education in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. We are pleased to tell
      you of a very exciting development with the fund, which has reached a
      market value of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750,000</NUMEX>.
      At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDA Endowment Committee</ENAMEX>, a goal was set to
      raise funds to increase the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">IDA Pursuit of Excellence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> to a minimum
      of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>. Our intent is to establish a fully endowed chair at the
      dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDA</ENAMEX> would comprise the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">FIRST</NUMEX> state
      dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">association</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to complete such a commitment to its
      state dental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      An endowed chair will greatly benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX> in
      recruiting and retaining outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>. Income from the chair will
      provide funds for research and publishing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate assistants</ENAMEX>, library
      and laboratory acquisitions. In the hands of an already successful
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholar</ENAMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX>" that endowments provide ensure continued success -
      for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      Fulfillment of this goal requires full participation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Dental Association</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Dentistry</ENAMEX>, and our
      entire profession, will benefit greatly from this endowment. Please join
      your fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and make this dream come true for your association
      by making a significant pledge to this program. Your full consideration
      of this investment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IDA Pursuit of Excellence Fund</ENAMEX> is greatly
      appreciated.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
    
  
