
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1, 1992</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> SPEA celebrates its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2Oth anniversary</TIMEX>. As the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> program
      to encompass public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and policy as well as environmental
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> and policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> is now established as one of the leading schools
      From our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1972</TIMEX> through those who
      graduated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May, 1992</TIMEX>, we now have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 9,800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>. To a great extent
      this extraordinary growth was made possible by the generosity of our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and their commitment to making SPEA the successful
      program it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. You are one of those who has made the difference and
      we thank you for your past support.
      Let me share with you some recent exciting achievements at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX>:
      -The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Urban Policy and the Environment</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      supported by a major grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly Endowment</ENAMEX>;
      -Significant enrollment increases on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      campuses as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> interest rises in several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> programs
      --environment, health service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and policy, and criminal
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">justice</ENAMEX>;
      -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty members</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>;
      -<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> new academic programs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> campus: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX> in
      Planning degree and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonprofit Management Concentration</ENAMEX> in the MPA
      program.
      We look toward a bright and even more distinguished future. Stay a
      part of it by renewing your gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> and sending the enclosed
      contribution reply card. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni undesignated</ENAMEX> gifts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> are
      used to help support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most important forms of support
      is student research assistantships, an area not adequately provided for
      under current levels of state funding.
      And remember, gifts made before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 31, 1992</TIMEX>, will still provide
      you with maximum tax deduction benefits.
      With grateful appreciation of your support,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. James Barnes</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
