
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 16, 1992</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear SPEA Alum</ENAMEX>:
      was formed, it has been guided by a vision of developing a world-class
      public affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that encompasses public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and policy as
      well as environmental science and policy.
      At the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master of Public Affairs</ENAMEX> program has held a
      successful reputation compared to other programs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. An
      integral part of that reputation has been the professional success of our
      alumni. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> of the MPA program at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>, you are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassadors</ENAMEX> for
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and represent the program to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and associates
      wherever you may work and live - outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> or here in the center
      of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> politics in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of Indianapolis</ENAMEX> have a unique <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>. We share
      many of the same resources. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> are involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>,
      working with city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, conducting research, and providing the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> with expertise and service.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> also shares the expertise of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> and
      other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. The professional success you have
      achieved reflects well on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and keeps the MPA program at the top
      of public affairs programs across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
      Let me share with you some recent exciting achievements at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX>:
      -A <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25%</NUMEX> increase in credit <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall, 1992</TIMEX>;
      -The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nonprofit Management Concentration</ENAMEX> in the MPA program, a
      joint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Philanthropy</ENAMEX>;
      -The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Masters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning</ENAMEX> degree;
      -The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Urban Policy and the Environment</ENAMEX> funded by a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.6</NUMEX>
      million grant from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly Endowment Inc.</ENAMEX>
      We look toward a bright and distinguished future. Stay a part of it by
      making a gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> and sending the enclosed contribution reply card.
      Alumni gifts are used for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> programs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX>. The most important
      program is student research assistantships, an area not provided for
      under current levels of state funding.
      With grateful appreciation of your support,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark s. Rosentraub Associate Dean</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
    
  
