
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 6, 1991</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      much as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX> --bring a rich diversity of backgrounds and
      interests to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Interacting with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and their fellow,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, they develop skills and perspectives that will help them meet
      the complex challenges that face our society in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the coming years</TIMEX>.
      Despite our efforts at innovation and efficiency, however, the cost of
      providing a quality educational experience continues to rise. Because of
      the financial generosity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> is able to enliven
      and enrich the student experience by allowing us to provide extra support
      that is not available from state and university funds. This support helps
      in a number of areas on all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX>:
      -Student support through scholarships and assistantships; <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-Classroom</ENAMEX>
      activities such as field trips; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">-Colloquiums</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guest speakers</ENAMEX> from
      around the world.
      Your generosity over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past four years</TIMEX> has provided an extra bonus
      to the SPEA program. Your renewed gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> will enable us to
      sustain our reputation of excellence, to prepare our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> for
      successful, satisfying careers, and at the same time, to enhance the
      value to you of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX> degree.
      We very much appreciate your assistance.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. James Barnes Dean</ENAMEX>
    
  
