
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 17, 1992</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear MHA Alumnus</ENAMEX>:
      My purpose in writing to you is twofold. First, to inform you of some
      recent activities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA MHA Alumni Association</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, to ask
      for your commitment, both financial and participatory. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last spring</TIMEX>, we
      surveyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> to find out what types of programs we would value
      and thus, would like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alumni Association</ENAMEX> to be involved in. You will
      find attached this survey plus our directional statement (goals) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
      that is a direct result of the survey.
      To help accomplish these goals we need your support. As you are aware,
      This has proven to be very beneficial over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> because of the
      faculty support and attention that our program has received.
      Consequently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHA Alumni Association</ENAMEX> has become the strongest alumni
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      We need your participation in our activities and your financial
      support to help make our goals happen. Alumni gifts will be used for
      student programs and to help support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHA Alumni Program</ENAMEX> goals. Please
      consider making a gift by returning the enclosed contribution card.
      With grateful appreciation of your support,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark E. Moore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHA Alumni Association Administrator</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital North</ENAMEX>
    
  
