
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Tom</ENAMEX>:
      From its inception in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Public and Environmental</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs</ENAMEX>(SPEA) has been guided by a broad vision of developing a
      world-class multidisciplinary public affairs <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, one that encompasses
      public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and public policy as well as environmental science and
      policy.
      That vision has become a reality. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> recent evaluator ranked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> as
      the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> best public affairs program in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> has an
      impressive and dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> that includes inspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and
      distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> who are contributing to the solutions of some of
      our most difficult public policy and public management problems,
      including those concerning health, the environment, and criminal justice;
      it is attracting a diverse, capable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>; and its graduates
      are making contributions in a wide range of challenging positions in the
      public, private, and non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sectors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX>'s enviable reputation
      benefits everyone connected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>, and most
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">importantly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>.
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the SPEA alumni <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> and a supporter of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX>'s
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> fund, your gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> will help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPEA</ENAMEX> continue to provide the very
      best education possible for its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and to help recruit new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
      who will be able to widen their horizons just as you did during your
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> here. Your gift in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> made possible: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> support and
      fellowships, seminars and colloquiums, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> research
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fellowships</ENAMEX>.
      You believed enough to invest in yourself then; now you can renew your
      investment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that made so many of those beliefs possible.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. James Barnes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>
    
  
