
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 26, 1990</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name,
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> I will complete my <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> anniversary with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>
      of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physical Education</ENAMEX>. I have enjoyed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these years</TIMEX> of service to all the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, who like you, have studied here. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of my proudest
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">achievements</ENAMEX> has been the creation and sustained achievement of the IUPUI
      Moving Company. Performing before <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 6,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K-12</ENAMEX>, for
      state professional conferences, for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pan-Am Media Event</ENAMEX> and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic Academy XI</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Moving Company</ENAMEX> has delighted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> with
      its energy and joy in moving. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will celebrate its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>
      season with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual spring</TIMEX> concert. Our theme <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance:</ENAMEX>
      Design in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motion</ENAMEX>" featuring compositions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ballet</ENAMEX>, modern, jazz and tap.
      I write to ask you to become a supporter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Moving Company</ENAMEX>. Your gift
      will help make <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s concert more special by providing funds for
      costumes, programs and lighting. You may use the enclosed card to
      respond. I look forward to hearing from you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Maitland Kimball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Dance MMK</ENAMEX>/rf
      P.S. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dates for the Moving Company</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> concert are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27th</TIMEX> and
      28th at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Performances</ENAMEX> will be held in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary Cable Theatre</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">525</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Blackford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Street</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> campus.
    
  
