
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1994</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donor</ENAMEX>:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX> is fortunate to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, like you,
      who have made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993 one of the best years</TIMEX> ever in private support for the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 70,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> have demonstrated in a very real way
      their understanding of the need for private funding so necessary if the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> is to maintain and enhance its service to society.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s reputation as one of the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> in the nation
      continues to grow. Along with these accolades comes the challenge to
      sustain that level of excellence. Private gifts are the only way we can
      meet the expectations of such an environment. This is where your caring
      concern for the welfare of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> means so much.
      University <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman B Wells</ENAMEX> once remarked that the longer he
      spent studying university finance the more he was convinced that "the
      peaks of excellence are provided typically by private money." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>'s "peaks of excellence" are becoming more numerous and, at the
      same time, more vulnerable.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is a reply card and envelope with the hope that you will
      consider beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> with a gift to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU</ENAMEX>. It truly is a wise investment
      in the bright future ahead. As an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU</ENAMEX>, you are
      entitled to a credit against your State taxes for your gift. The form you
      will need to claim your credit, and attach to your return, is
      enclosed.
      Thank you for your continuing support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>. We are
      very grateful.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curtis R. Simic President</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
