
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TO: Our Campus Colleagues FROM: The IUPUI Campus Campaign Steering</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <Names> DATE: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 5, 1994</TIMEX> SUBJECT: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partners</ENAMEX> in
      Progress: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Assuring the Future</ENAMEX>
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> came together as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> -- supporting programs and issues we believe in.
      Scholarships were enhanced or established. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> received a
      significant vote of pride and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>, with contributions coming from
      all areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> were able to create special staff
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> funds and other enhancements as a result of the campaign.
      Through the efforts of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX>, nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$89,000</NUMEX> was raised
      through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Campus Campaign</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Almost 900</NUMEX> of us made new gifts in
      support of the things we care about. Together with those who were already
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">donors</ENAMEX>, there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 1,350</NUMEX> staff and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> supporting the work of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> with their gifts.
      Your efforts on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> are resulting in changes--some
      dramatic, others more subtle. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> IUPUI is celebrating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partnership</ENAMEX>. Yet our roots go much deeper. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Physical</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education</ENAMEX> is oldest at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Law</ENAMEX> celebrates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>, and
      Medicine is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> and program that make up this community
      called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> has a treasured and valued history .The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Campus</ENAMEX>
      Campaign celebrates our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> and helps us, as individual members
      of that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>, to assure the future.
      With this letter, we are asking you to take the opportunity of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campus Campaign</ENAMEX> to consider how you can help IUPUI be what you want it to
      be. A group of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> recently volunteered to help set the
      priorities for this campaign. They surveyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and
      faculty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">councils</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> and others and learned that we at IUPUI
      have a number of vital concerns.
      One is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> development. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resources</ENAMEX> for this purpose are
      limited or non-existent. And yet we all recognize the need to invest in
      professional growth and development.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> are another area of interest (what would we do without
      them--and some of us are them). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Staff Council</ENAMEX> scholarship,
      awarded for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time last summer</TIMEX>, is the direct result of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campus Campaign</ENAMEX>. And scholarship funds are in limited supply here at
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>, especially for the part time returning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>. Additionally, the
      need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to have a gathering place, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Center</ENAMEX>, is
      perceived by most to be critical.
      The new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX> remains on the list--it is at the heart of the
      academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and will require increased and ongoing support for
      acquisitions and other needs.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shape the Future</ENAMEX> Fund is designed to address unexpected
      opportunities. It will provide the flexibility <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> needs that state
      appropriations cannot. In many ways, the name describes what this campus
      campaign is all about. We have the chance to shape the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> by
      what we choose to do here.
      And finally, though perhaps of most importance to you, through the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campus</ENAMEX> Campaign you can continue to make your gift to any IUPUI program
      that matters to you. Your commitment will count.
      When you are contacted by your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campus Campaign</ENAMEX> volunteer, we hope
      you'll choose to become one of the many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
