
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1992</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>:
      Why am I writing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to ask you to support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue University</ENAMEX>? You
      and I didn't graduate from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>. Even though our educational goals and
      career paths led us elsewhere, we each have a special place in our hearts
      for this outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">University</ENAMEX> located on the western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> of the Wabash
      River. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> has been a part of my life for as long as I can remember...
      I was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Lafayette</ENAMEX>. As I grew older, I realized more and more
      that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> isn't just a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>; it is a public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>.
      Moreover, it is a world-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> belongs to all of us
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hoosier</ENAMEX> and non-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hoosier</ENAMEX> alike), and it will be no better than those of
      us who love and support it. Your gift through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> will help
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> continue its leadership role in higher education. Your gift will
      also count toward the largest campaign for private contributions in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>'s history.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vision 21</ENAMEX> seeks to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 million</NUMEX> in private support to
      ensure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of the future will receive an education unsurpassed.
      The campaign will support scholarships and distinguished
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">professorships</ENAMEX>...new and creative research...special assistance to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX>...new and renovated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX>...increased library
      acquisitions...state-of-the-art telecommunications...and more.
      I urge you to think about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> and the commitment you can make to
      help us reach these goals. Your contribution--large or small-- through
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> will carry us <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more step toward realizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX>
      dream for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James C. Shook</ENAMEX>
      P.S. A reply card and return envelope are enclosed for your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convenience</ENAMEX>. Make your check payable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue Foundation</ENAMEX>.
    
  
