
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>,
      Thank you for your interest in futures for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Children</ENAMEX>, whose mission is
      "to improve the well-being of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> help
      themselves." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the ways we achieve this mission is through our
      Friendship Program for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is information that describes this program, as well as our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> education initiatives in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Indian Nation</ENAMEX>. We
      invite you to participate in Futures for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children</ENAMEX> by sponsoring an
      <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> or by joining a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Membership Circle</ENAMEX> to support our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> education projects.
      Futures for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children</ENAMEX> was founded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over 30 years ago</TIMEX> to provide unique
      solutions for positive and sustainable social change by placing children
      at the center of community decision-making and action. For example:
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Batavia</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hopi Reservation</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> were
      motivated by their desire to rekindle traditional cultural values among
      younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> when, with the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Futures for Children</ENAMEX>, they
      decided to restore traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace gardens</ENAMEX> at the edge of their
      village -gardens that had been abandoned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. During the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reconstruction</ENAMEX> project, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elders</ENAMEX> took advantage of the opportunity not only
      to teach <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Hopi</ENAMEX> language and culture to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, but also to restore
      a sense of balance and spiritual integrity to their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. Now, as
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> tend their gardens, they have a new appreciation of their
      relationship to the land, their cultural heritage, and their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80</TIMEX> reservation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> in the .<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> participate in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Futures</ENAMEX>' Friendship Program, building
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross-cultural</ENAMEX> ties with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult mentors 'from</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. By means of supportive relationships developed through letters,
      phone calls and visits, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are, encouraged by their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> to
      stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, to be, involved in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, and to learn about
      the world beyond their reservations. the relationship formed between a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> often lasts a lifetime.
      Futures for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children</ENAMEX> relies on the generosity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> like you;
      by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> policy, we do not accept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> funds.
      Furthermore, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 75%</NUMEX> of our total income is expended directly
      on program activities. Because of this and other factors, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Futures</ENAMEX> has
      earned an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>" rating from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Institute of Philanthropy</ENAMEX>, as well
      as the highest rating of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Charities Information Bureau</ENAMEX>
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCIB</ENAMEX>).
      We appreciate your taking time to read about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Futures for Children</ENAMEX>, I
      hope you are inspired to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sponsor</ENAMEX> and/or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>. Our staff
      would enjoy sharing additional information about our work and answering
      any questions you may have. Please call us any time at
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-800-545-6843</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim West</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Executive Officer</ENAMEX>
    
  
