
  
  
    
      May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22, 2000</TIMEX>
      Thank you for your interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Education Program</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Education Program</ENAMEX>, in conjunction with a network of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
      in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and neighborhoods, works firsthand with young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who,
      we feel, are the hope for the future. We provide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> with options to
      stand up for themselves and resolve conflicts nonviolently. We teach
      conflict resolution, peer mediation and the principles of prejudice
      reduction not just in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>'s neighborhoods and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, but also
      throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>.
      With over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX> experience, we have found that many conflicts
      between young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are rooted in attitudes and prejudices that exclude
      and target <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. By shifting attitudes and teaching
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> to understand each other, we halt the violence that plagues our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and neighborhoods.
      Our commitment to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and neighborhoods has a long tested record
      of accomplishment. We have worked hard to create a strong
      school-neighborhood linkage or safety net. School suspensions are down in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jefferson County</ENAMEX> and we are part of the answer (see attached
      <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>).
      Enclosed are additional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> to illustrate the commitment of
      Peace Education Program to "giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> more than a fighting
      chance."
      Peace,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaDonna R. Murphy Office Manager</ENAMEX>
    
  
