
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 5, 1990</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor xxx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> of xxx Campus
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear</ENAMEX> (use <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name),
      As the tax year draws to a close I would like to urge you to make a
      tax deductible contribution for the support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women's Studies</ENAMEX>. We now
      have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> accounts with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Foundation</ENAMEX>:
      Account <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"># 32</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">141</NUMEX>-93 which we use to supplement our regular (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">meager</NUMEX>)
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX> in order to pay visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> honoraria, give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> awards
      and finance special receptions.
      Account <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"># 32</NUMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-142-08</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends of Women's Studies</ENAMEX> account, which is
      to be used for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> scholarships, to supplement <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> activities
      when all other sources of income have been exhausted and, eventually, to
      encourage WOST scholarship through research grants to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WOST</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>.
      Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> have already contributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> account
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> but many have not. Support from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> is important, not
      only for the income it provides, but also to demonstrate to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX>
      in the community our own commitment to the goals and purposes of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX>.
      Please consider making a contribution to either or both of these
      accounts. Due to the generosity of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> tax law, a contribution to the
      University of any amount <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $200</NUMEX> will only cost you half that
      amount--less the deduction you claim on your federal tax return. I
      enclose a copy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> tax form you will need to file with your
      return plus an envelope to use for sending your contribution to the IU
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>. Please write one of the above account numbers on the face of
      your check to be very sure that your $$ stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WOST</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.
      Have a happy, healthy holiday.
      Best regards.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Donchin Director</ENAMEX>
    
  
