
  
  
    
      Dear Name,
      Outstanding, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fantastic, Rewarding, Fulfilling All</ENAMEX> of these words
      describe the results which were achieved by the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> during the
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998-1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Annual Fund Drive</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> won the coveted "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spirit Award</ENAMEX>"
      along with our good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> from the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>. The award was
      presented at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All-Class Reunion</ENAMEX>" in front of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dear Old Cathedral"</ENAMEX>. The award is given annually
      to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> that increases their "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund Giving</ENAMEX>" participation by
      the highest percentage. We were very proud that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> stepped up and
      made a difference for young deserving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> -just like we were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">THANK YOU, THANK YOU</ENAMEX>, THANK YOU to all that
      participated.
      Once again, we are writing to ask for your support. Even after last
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s success, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than 113</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> is registered as a donor. As
      your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class representatives</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999- 2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Annual Fund Drive</ENAMEX>, we are
      certain that we can significantly improve upon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last years</TIMEX>' results.
      Any dollar amount you wish to contribute is fine. However, a donation
      of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> or more entitles you to official membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alumni</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> with the privileges thereof, including: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The right to vote
      in the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alumni Association Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX> elections (currently two
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the Class of' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">84</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Althert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Elson</ENAMEX> serve on the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) An official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alumni Association</ENAMEX> decal and membership card; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) A
      discount on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alumni Association</ENAMEX> apparel; and, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Eligibility for the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charity Raffle</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> to be given to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> of your choice.
      As you know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> is an integral part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX>'s
      financial infra-structure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. Among the many important roles it
      plays, the most significant is that this fund allows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX> of the student
      body the opportunity to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX> through the help of financial
      aid. Imagine the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Alumni</ENAMEX> who might not be alumni if the
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> Fund did not exist.
      Please help us and participate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> so that the Class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'84</NUMEX> can
      defend the title at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All-Class Reunion</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 11th</TIMEX>. We will
      try to contact each of you who have not participated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fiscal year</TIMEX> in
      the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 45 days</TIMEX> so that our goal can be reached by the deadline of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
      30th. We look forward to your support, and thank you in advance for
      helping make "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX>" the best private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">catholic high school</ENAMEX> in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>.
      Best Regards,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Elson</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'84</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Welch</ENAMEX> ' 84 3750 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Priority Way S. Drive 135 N.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennsylvania Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46240</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">46244-0992</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">317</ENAMEX>) -
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">317</ENAMEX>) - brian elson@.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> rwelch@.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>
    
  
