
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 20, 2000</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear,</ENAMEX>
      I hope this correspondence finds you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> doing well. I am
      writing in regards to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral High School</ENAMEX> and her
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> Fund <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drive</ENAMEX>. It is a privilege and honor to be asked to serve as
      your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class representative</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral High School</ENAMEX> is indeed a special and exciting place. Your
      loyal support and generosity clearly make a difference. As many of you
      may be aware, this academic year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Helmich</ENAMEX> began his tenure as
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifth president</ENAMEX>. Mr .<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Helmich</ENAMEX> brings many unique gifts to the
      position. His outstanding leadership skills will serve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX>
      exceptionally well. The future of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral High School</ENAMEX>, under the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Helmich</ENAMEX>, is indeed bright.
      The "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral Report</ENAMEX>" is a good one. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is enjoying full
      enrollment with many accomplishments being achieved by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>. We continue to place many of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> into top schools
      across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Our dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> works extremely hard to give
      all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> every opportunity to reach their potential. The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Department</ENAMEX> is in the process of renovating the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> and other
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> in order to provide our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with science instruction that
      is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to none. A local software <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has generously donated a
      complete analysis of our computer hardware and software needs so that the
      school can offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> the most up-to-date information
      technology. Needless to say, this is a must if we are going to continue
      to offer a top-notch education to our young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. We are doing
      everything we can to adjust to the "new economy."
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral High School</ENAMEX> makes a general solicitation of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our Annual</TIMEX> Fund Drive raised a
      record <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$365,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> plays a significant role in providing
      financial assistance to those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who cannot meet the ever
      increasing cost of a quality education. Tuition for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999-2000</TIMEX> school
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,250</NUMEX> and is expected to go up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately 25%</NUMEX> of
      the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX> student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> receives some amount of financial
      assistance. So you see the purpose of this fund is about need and helping
      worthy, but less fortunate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, who without your help would not be
      able to attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of their choice.
      Please think about a donation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fiscal year</TIMEX> which ends
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30, 2000</TIMEX>. Your help is needed more than ever. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX> has made
      great progress but is continually challenged to do more. Small, private
      high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> face a constant pressure to raise funds in order to keep up
      with the public funded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> with their unlimited access to taxpayer
      dollars. The battle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">never ends</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathedral</ENAMEX> provided us with a good education and a great foundation for
      our futures. Please help make that same opportunity available to some
      deserving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> today.
      Thanks in advance for your support!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael P. Alerding</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'67</NUMEX>
    
  
