
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INDIANA UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF LAW-INDIANAPOLIS</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">STUDENTS</ENAMEX>
      Total Enrollment. Fall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">823</ENAMEX>
      Full-time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">day</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">525</ENAMEX>
      Part-time. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evening</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">298</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1993 Entering Class Profile:</ENAMEX>
      Number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applications</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.293</NUMEX>
      Number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Offers Extended</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">430</ENAMEX>
      Number of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Students Enrolled: 263</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">182</NUMEX> full-time. 81 part-time)
      Number of undergraduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> represented: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mean LSAT Score</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">80th</NUMEX> percentile
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mean Undergraduate GPA</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.3</NUMEX>
      Average <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Women</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minorities</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16%</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALUMNI</ENAMEX>
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eighty</NUMEX> percent of our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6.000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      Alumni reside in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> foreign countries
      COSTS, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FINANCIAL AID, AND SCHOLARSHIPS</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-94</TIMEX> in-state tuition: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 143.65</NUMEX> per credit hour
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-94</TIMEX> out-of-state tuition: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$373.80</NUMEX> per credit hour
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-94</TIMEX> tuition supplies <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s total operating
      budget
      <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Forty-four percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> receive loans and/or grants
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Thirty-one</ENAMEX> privately-funded scholarships totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$82.000</NUMEX> awarded to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> annually
      Additional monetary awards provided through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Law Alumni</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>. local law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>, book awards, and discretionary funds
      derived from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> giving
      LAW LIBRARY
      Features one of the largest and most highly automated legal research
      collections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      Provides electronic bibliographic and data-base services such as
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WESTLAW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEXIS</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">On-line Computer library Center</ENAMEX>
      Serves law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>. and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CENTER FOR</ENAMEX> LAW & HEALTH
      Serves as information resource on health law issues
      Conducts research on law reform issues currently facing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and
      the nation
      Supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> grants, private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">law firms</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">STUDENT PROGRAMS AND ORGANIZATIONS</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> acquire experience through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>-supervised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>, trial
      practice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, moot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> counseling, and pro bono
      programs
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> law reviews provide opportunities for research and writing, as
      well as a forum for articles of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, national, and international
      interest
      Student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> include: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Bar Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Black</ENAMEX>
      Law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Association</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Law Society</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health</ENAMEX> law
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IV Association for Public Interest</ENAMEX> law, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX>'s
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caucus</ENAMEX>--just to name a few
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">HOW ALUMNI CONTRIBUTIONS HELP TO SUPPORT THE LAW SCHOOL</ENAMEX>
      All of the foregoing areas are supported by contributions from alumni
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the school
      In addition, gifts provide essential support in a number of other
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>, including recruitment of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty members</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>,
      maintaining our Career <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, securing guest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX>,
      supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s commencement and publications
      Make your contribution payable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University Foundation</ENAMEX>
      with the designation for <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law- Indpls</ENAMEX>.
    
  
