
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 14, 1993</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      During the current period of declining state funding for our law
      school, there is one outstanding development. In increasing numbers,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are providing the private resources necessary for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholarships</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> support and other items which enrich the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s
      curriculum related programs.
      Significant examples are the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> trust agreement executed by
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Rosen</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> in honor of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, and our former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>,
      "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill" Foust</ENAMEX>. More recently alumni have responded generously to the
      special <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Townsend Endowed Professorship</ENAMEX> campaign, as more than
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> has now been given or pledged.
      Have these events put our law school on easy street? By no means. They
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will</ENAMEX>, however, together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> contributions and other gifts,
      assure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> continue to receive an excellent legal
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>. So, as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 1993</TIMEX> approaches, we ask that you remember
      what your law school education has meant to you and to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law</ENAMEX>
      School <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX>.
      Consider the current enrollment picture at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and the costs
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> bear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      Demand for a legal education remains high. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Law</ENAMEX> in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 1,300</NUMEX> applications to enroll its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
      first-year class of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">260</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX> full- and part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> provide, in fees and
      tuition, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> operating budget. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-94</TIMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$143.65</NUMEX> per credit hour and non-residents pay
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$373.80</NUMEX>. The average annual course load for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the
      day program (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">31</NUMEX> credit <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>) costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,453</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,588</NUMEX> for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">non-residents</ENAMEX>. To meet tuition payments and other expenses, total loans
      of the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> now exceed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000,000</NUMEX>. Consequently, we
      have approached the limit on student tuition increases.
      You are all too familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s budget pinch and the pressures
      on state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to cut expenditures. Consequently, significant
      increases in state financial support for higher education is extremely
      unlikely during the remainder of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>.
      Gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, therefore, are more critical than ever.
      They provide scholarship dollars which aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and enable the school
      to compete with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> for outstanding
      young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Gifts also support student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> such as moot
      court, supply library materials, pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>, and
      make available other necessary resources.
      Your contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> level
      have provided significant assistance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Please continue that
      tradition by completing and returning the enclosed pledge card. Payment
      of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> (or more) may be made now or at anytime before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 31</TIMEX>,
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.
      Thank you for your past help and your continued support.
      Sincere best wishes,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John M. Holt Donald K. Densborn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean's Council</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
