
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1992</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Graduate</ENAMEX>:
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Law</ENAMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, you are one of
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 5,900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately 80%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s
      alumni reside in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,200</NUMEX> living and working in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion County</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">contiguous counties</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> are leaders
      in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, business, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and community affairs. We can be proud
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> of our law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      Unfortunately, these are difficult times for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> of
      higher education. Legislative appropriations are either flat or in the
      decline, and tuition increases cannot make up the difference. I therefore
      cannot overemphasize the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> support. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, only
      <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20%</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> contributed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. If the
      school is to maintain and improve upon its programs, it needs our
      help.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Law</ENAMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> has initiated a Law Firm
      Campaign. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campaign</ENAMEX> is directed at law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>
      or more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>. The goal is to get each alum to commit to financially
      support the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. A precedent has been established by our sister
      school, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Law</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, their "law firm
      solicitation program" succeeded in obtaining a range of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57% to 100%</NUMEX>
      contributing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> -employed by participating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. For the same time
      period, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> participation in similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31% to 67%</NUMEX>. We can
      do better!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is a pledge card and reply envelope which you may complete
      and return to me by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, October 30</TIMEX>. Please show your support and make
      a gift. Remember that as an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">resident</ENAMEX> you may receive tax benefits
      through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Tax Credit</ENAMEX>, which is applied directly against the
      "bottom line" of the state tax return. More importantly, your gift to the
      law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> will be an investment in the future quality of legal education
      at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
    
  
