
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 6, 1991</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>:
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty years</TIMEX> is a long time to be part of the law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. I
      have witnessed many changes --physical location of the law school, new
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> coming on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> retiring, tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> surviving my
      classes, and a periodic changing of the deans.
      Legal education nationwide also has been changing, and your law school
      has been keeping pace with the times. For example, we now provide
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> both traditional classroom education, which emphasizes legal
      reasoning and analysis, and extensive training in fundamental lawyering
      skills. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> must now fulfill the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s legal writing
      requirements, and they encouraged to participate in a wide array of
      courses and programs that teach professional skills, such as trial
      practice, the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s civil practice and criminal defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>,
      moot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> counseling.
      The law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> also continues to develop its curriculum in a number of
      specialized fields, including environmental, health, and international
      law areas.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this year</TIMEX>, the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> published the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue of its
      <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> law review -the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indiana International</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comparative Law</ENAMEX>
      Review.
      At a recent gathering of the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent Dickson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">'68</ENAMEX>) of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Supreme Court</ENAMEX> commented about the
      impact which our law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> have had on the governance of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and,
      indeed, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. For example, he noted that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> of the law school, that our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">360</NUMEX> trial court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>, and that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30%</NUMEX>
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> graduated from the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. And, of course,
      former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Whitcomb</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">'50</ENAMEX>), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Coats</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">'74</ENAMEX>), are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> of your law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      The law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 5,700</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 80%</NUMEX> of whom
      reside in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. The balance practice law throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and
      live in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. I think you can be proud, just as I am, of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> of your law school and of their accomplishments.
      I also believe that you can be proud of your law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. We have
      provided throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> quality legal education, and we are
      continuing to improve. However, these are difficult times for public
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> of higher education, because legislative appropriations are
      either flat or in the decline.
      State funds for your law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> are not now - nor have they ever been
      --sufficient to fund all of our costs. To continue to excel in our
      educational mission, we must have both public and private support. For
      this reason, I ask that you think of your law school, in financial terms,
      in the same way that you would view private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>.
      The law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s needs range from purchasing additional computer
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminals</ENAMEX> to paying travel costs of our moot court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and from
      refurbishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gray Lounge</ENAMEX> to purchasing necessary reference materials
      for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>. These are just some of our needs; others are discussed
      in the brochure which is enclosed with this letter.
      As a tenured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and staunch supporter of your law school, my
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">task</ENAMEX> is to beat the drums for financial contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. I cannot overemphasize the importance of your support. If we are
      to maintain our programs and thus continue to enhance the value of the
      diploma that you earned from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Law</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, we need the
      help of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>.
      You can see "by reading the code, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>" that there are still many
      federal and state tax advantages for making charitable contributions. In
      addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> may receive tax benefits through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      tax credit which is applied directly against the "bottom line" of the
      state tax return.
      Please give. Your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> gift to the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is an investment in
      the future quality of the legal profession and a significant way for you
      to remember your past, and I thank you, in advance, for your gift.
      Best wishes,
    
  
