
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 19, 1990</TIMEX>
      Dear Name:
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University School of Law</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>,
      its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> lost a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent Frandsen</ENAMEX> selflessly gave <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX> of service offering
      advice and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and growth of the law school and its
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. He played a significant role in our education and our
      lives.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Bepko</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>, paid tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kent</ENAMEX> through these
      remarks.
      "His sense of good fortune helped him to be the most beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> ever
      to serve at our law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. His work as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean for Student Affairs</ENAMEX> is
      legendary. He loaned them money, out of his own pocket, something he
      never wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marilee</ENAMEX> to know about. He helped them with housing, career
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">planning</ENAMEX>, and personal problems. He was for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mentor</ENAMEX>, chaplain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, and true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> understood how
      much he cared about them and how wise, decent, and honest he was."
      You were one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who responded
      generously to an appeal to endow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Kent Frandsen Memorial</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX>. Overall, contributions produced <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$258,000</NUMEX> to invest in
      an endowment account, and this prestigious scholarship already has been
      awarded to several deserving law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. They are the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of many
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who will benefit from the generosity of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>.
      Your continued support of the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is vital, not only in
      providing scholarships, but also in meeting a variety of needs ranging
      from purchasing additional computer terminals to travel for our moot
      court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>.
      We are proud of our law school and its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,539</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>. Our achievements
      reflect the excellence of the legal education we received. We can
      continue to strengthen the education of good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
      I urge you to make a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> gift to the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Your gift may be
      designated for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frandsen Memorial Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX>, for any of the
      programs described in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> brochure, or for use where you
      believe there is the greatest need.
      It takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> of private support and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> funding for
      our law school to continue to grow in stature and influence. I look
      forward to hearing from you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lante K Earnest</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frandsen Campaign Steering Committee</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Please take a moment to review the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> brochure. Then use
      the enclosed donor reply card to let us know how you can help.
      Thank you!
    
  
