
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November, 1990</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Name</ENAMEX>:
      There is an ever-increasing interest in the study of law. But there is
      also intense competition among law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to attract the best and
      brightest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. At our law school, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> applications for admission
      increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35%</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> applications for
      admission increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">an additional 20%</NUMEX>! For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s entering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>, we
      had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than five</NUMEX> times the number of applications for every freshman
      seat. While the numbers are impressive, scholarships often are critical
      in recruiting the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with financial need.
      Having good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> is only part of the picture. An outstanding legal
      education requires more than just classes in case analysis and legal
      reasoning. Fundamental lawyering skills --advocacy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> counseling,
      negotiation, legal research and writing --are vital.
      Several professional skills programs are offered each year to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Practice Clinic</ENAMEX> has operated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX>, and
      we recently added a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criminal Defense Clinic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moot Court Program</ENAMEX> and
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Law Review</ENAMEX> are consistently popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. These
      programs are essential to a quality legal education, but they require
      financial support over and above that provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>.
      Private giving does have a significant impact at the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,300</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> responded to an appeal to
      fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Kent Frandsen Memorial Scholarships</ENAMEX>. Their generosity produced
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$258,000</NUMEX> to invest in an endowment account.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, we were able to award this prestigious scholarship to
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> deserving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. They are among the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who
      will benefit from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni generosity</ENAMEX> demonstrated during the Frandsen
      Scholarship fund drive. There are numerous other challenges still to be
      met.
      I cannot emphasize enough how vital your support is, not only in
      providing scholarships, but also in meeting a wide variety of needs
      ranging from purchasing additional computer terminals to travel for our
      moot court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. It takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> of private support and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
      funding for the law school to continue to grow in stature and influence.
      As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> draws to a close, I know you may be reflecting on many giving
      opportunities.
      Your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> gift to the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is an investment in its continued
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excellence</ENAMEX>. I look forward to hearing from you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Please take a moment to review our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> brochure. Then use
      the enclosed donor reply card to let us know how you can help. Thank
      you!
    
  
