
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 3, 1992</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      It only takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> quick, easy steps to obtain a matching gift from
      your (or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>'s) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> to enhance your donation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University School of Law</ENAMEX> -<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Determine if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> works for has a
      matching gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> (through the personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>).
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Obtain a matching gift form (again through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>).
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Complete the form and send it, along with your gift, to the law
      school.
      Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> match at a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>:<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> ratio, but some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> match <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX> or
      even <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:1</TIMEX>! Take advantage of the benefit your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> provides by having
      your gift matched for your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX>. Don't forget, too, that in many
      cases <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX> of larger parent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are also eligible and that
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will sometimes match a gift retroactively. Check out these
      possibilities with your personnel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.
      I cannot underestimate the importance of matching gifts to the law
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">school's Annual Fund</ENAMEX> program. In a time of legislative budget cuts, every
      dollar helps to fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> programs and scholarships. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, the law
      school received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38,912</NUMEX> in matching gifts from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, the
      law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $18,114</NUMEX> in matching gifts from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Our
      alumni records show that we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">184</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> directly employed by
      matching gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. We can only guess the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> who work
      for a matching gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or one of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiaries</ENAMEX>.
      When you make your contribution to the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, please take
      a moment to follow the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> easy steps listed above. Then watch your
      gift multiply.
      Thank you!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joni Thompson</ENAMEX> Assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean for Development</ENAMEX>
    
  
