
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30, 1992</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      The law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> are a distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. We are
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>, business, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and community affairs. We
      reside in all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> excepting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> (don't ask me
      why!). I am proud to say that our law school and fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> play a
      significant role both in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
      Legal education nationwide has been changing, and our law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> has
      been keeping pace with the times. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are provided both
      traditional classroom education, which emphasizes legal reasoning and
      analysis, and extensive training in fundamental lawyering skills.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Students</ENAMEX> must now fulfill the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s legal writing requirements,
      and they are encouraged to participate in a wide array of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and
      programs that teach professional skills, such as trial practice, the law
      school's civil practice and criminal defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>, moot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, and
      client counseling.
      The law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> also continues to develop its curriculum in a number of
      specialized fields, including environmental, health, and international
      law areas. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> published the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> issue of its
      <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">review</ENAMEX> --the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indiana International</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Comparative Law Review</ENAMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last fall</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Law Review</ENAMEX> celebrated publication of its 25th
      volume.
      We can be proud of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX>. Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> the law school
      has continued to provide quality legal education. However, these are
      difficult times for public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> of higher education, because
      legislative appropriations are either flat or in the decline. The law
      school is limited in these recessionary times because it's impractical to
      raise tuition significantly to gain the difference from lost state
      appropriations. (The law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> had to raise tuition by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991-1992</TIMEX>]
      and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-1993</TIMEX>]). It's not a new story but it is an important <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to
      consider. To continue to excel in its educational mission, the law school
      must have both public and private support.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> of the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">staunchest</ENAMEX> and most important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. We are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who annually
      donate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> or more to the law school and, by our actions, demonstrate
      that we care deeply about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and that private contributions make
      a difference.
      There are still many federal and state tax advantages for making
      charitable contributions. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> may receive tax
      benefits through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> tax credit which is applied directly against
      the "bottom line" of the state tax return. Matching contributions from
      your (or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX>'s) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> can also double or triple the value of
      your gift.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> brings together <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who share a desire to
      provide enduring and generous support for the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. During the next
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week or so</TIMEX>, I will be calling you to discuss your willingness to support
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      Your gift may be made when the pledge is submitted or anytime prior to
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 31, 1992</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> brochure and a pledge card are
      enclosed for your review.
      Your gift to the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> will be an investment in its continued
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excellence</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
