
  
  
    
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      It is my privilege to extend an opportunity for membership in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society of the Indiana University School of Law</ENAMEX>
      -<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>. As you know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> includes those
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> who contribute <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000 or more</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> to the law
      school.
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Alumni Board</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Visitors</ENAMEX>) you are quite
      well acquainted with the programs, progress and problems of the law
      school. Without engaging in too much repetition I might note a few items
      of interest.
      The student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> has at long last (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>) been completely
      refurbished due to a gift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth M. Daily</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.D.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>. It is now
      an inviting place for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to study and visit.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Rosen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.D.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>)
      established a charitable remainder annuity <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in honor of his longtime
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleon H. Foust</ENAMEX>. His <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> gift, designated for
      faculty support, is the largest single private gift ever received by the
      school.
      Applications for enrollment remain high and the quality of entering
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> is excellent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,437</NUMEX> applications to seat 260
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> entering class.
      In contrast to this rosy picture there are still significant
      opportunities for improvement in the physical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> and programs at
      the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Several are noted below:
      Scholarships are essential for attracting the best and brightest
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to study law at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1991-1992</TIMEX> academic year,
      only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$135,00</NUMEX> was available for scholarship assistance. This figure
      represents <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5%</NUMEX> of the total cost that law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> paid for their
      legal education. It is far less than is available at most law schools
      including <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$279,000</NUMEX> for scholarships during the same
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> period! <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Approximately</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">100</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, which is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1/7</NUMEX> of our
      student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, received scholarships funded through private gifts last
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. Statistics for the current academic year are the same.
      A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>'s report on the law school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> indicates the need for
      improvement in that area. The report concluded:
      "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Library</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> is inadequate--in both quality and quantity -
      to provide satisfactory, let alone excellent, services to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX>, shelving
      for the collection, and staff <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>."
      "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Library</ENAMEX>'s funding is insufficient to allow for appropriate
      collection development and maintenance, to hire a sufficient number of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, especially professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarians</ENAMEX>."
      After evaluating the law school building the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U. Architect's Office</ENAMEX>
      advised:
      "The space presently occupied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Law and Law Library</ENAMEX> is
      deficient both in quality and quantity."
      "Quality improvements needed chiefly involve spatial relationships
      among functional areas, personal security needs, electronic access to
      information, effective access to modern instructional technology, and
      aesthetics of public areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>."
      "Quantitative deficiencies chiefly derive from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> growth but also
      from growing program diversity (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>, research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutes</ENAMEX>, new
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journals</ENAMEX>), from changing pedagogical techniques (e.g., smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX>,
      use of technology), and from a longstanding shortage of student support
      space (lockers, food service, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> for student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>)."
      Information regarding inadequate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX>, moot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">court facilities</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and support service areas follow the above
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paragraphs</ENAMEX>. Other needs might also be recited.
      The current recession and political concerns regarding taxation make
      increased legislative appropriations unlikely. Student tuition has been
      raised <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-92</TIMEX>, a significant increase. Although tuition at the
      School of Law -<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> still remains among the lowest of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Big</ENAMEX>
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX>" law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, further increases could have an adverse effect on
      securing quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>.
      These factors increase the need for financial support from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. I urge your consideration of joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> by
      making a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> per year. If this is not possible, please
      consider membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean's Council</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500- $999</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>). Your
      gift or pledge may be made now with the pledge to be paid before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31, 1992</TIMEX>.
      Thanks for your courtesy in reviewing this request. It is our hope
      that all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> will affirmatively respond and that each will
      provide some level of financial support for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John M. Holt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> enclosure
    
  
