
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 21, 1994</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      As one who generously supports the law school, you understand the
      importance of alumni contributions in providing an excellent legal
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The demand for a legal education remains
      high, as we received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,243</NUMEX> applications for our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994 first-year</TIMEX> class.
      From this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">applicant</ENAMEX> pool, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> were selected to enroll for
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> a small number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> each contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $2,500</NUMEX> and
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,999</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. To recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> who have achieved this level,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Lefstein</ENAMEX> has now established the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Cane Society</ENAMEX>. If the law
      school is to increase its endowment (currently <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.1 million</NUMEX>) and cover
      all of its expenses, a strong financial response from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> is
      essential. State financial support is unlikely to increase significantly
      during the remainder of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>.
      You have been a loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> by contributing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> to the
      law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>, and we are grateful for your past support. All <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> are
      being asked to increase their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> level of support. If the law school
      is to provide necessary scholarships and services needed to compete with
      other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and private law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we cannot simply maintain
      the status quo.
      During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, you will be asked by a volunteer to consider making a
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> commitment to the law school during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. Your gift may be
      designated for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s general endowment, a particular scholarship
      or program, or a combination of needs. I hope we can include your name
      among the list of inaugural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Cane Society</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry B.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">'56</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy N.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">'56</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blackwell Black Cane Society</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cc</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Norman Lefstein</ENAMEX> enclosure
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Cane Society</ENAMEX> is named after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Cane</ENAMEX> award which is
      given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> by the law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> who is voted to be
      the most outstanding classroom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
