
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12, 1994</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX> the graduating class traditionally contributes a class gift
      to the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Sometimes this constitutes an item of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">remembrance</ENAMEX>,
      establishment of a scholarship, or individual tax deductible
      donations.
      Due to the current nature of the economy, and the effect that it has
      wrought on the legal employment situation, we decided that the latter
      course would be most advantageous to the graduating student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.
      Each of you may contribute the amount that you feel able to
      contribute, and then you may deduct for it on your taxes. Moreover, the
      total amount contributed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> may be put to use by the law school
      where it is most needed, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library fund</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX> programs,
      or monies for professional research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>.
      We believe that this is the best format in which to contribute our
      class gift since it benefits all concerned. Please review the enclosed
      information, and decide which contribution format would best suit your
      needs: an outright gift, a pledge to be paid by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 31, 1994</TIMEX>, or a
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX> graduated pledge. The better our law school becomes directly
      increases the valuation of our degrees.
      THANK YOU!!
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commencement Committee</ENAMEX>
    
  
