
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 10, 1993</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Graduate</ENAMEX>:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosed</ENAMEX> is a specially prepared and entertaining crossword puzzle
      that challenges your knowledge about the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Also, you will find
      with this letter a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> fact card" about the law school, information
      about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Tax Credit</ENAMEX> (if you reside in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>), and a gift card
      and envelope to use in returning your contribution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      These are exceedingly difficult times for public higher education. For
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fiscal year</TIMEX> and next, the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is required to absorb
      reductions in its state appropriation and increased health costs totaling
      more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX>. Moreover, significant increases in state financial
      support for public higher education are extremely unlikely during the
      remainder of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>. As a result of the current economic climate,
      alumni support is more critical than ever before.
      We are no longer a state supported law school, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> no longer
      provides the great bulk of our funding. Instead, I believe we can best be
      described as a law school that is state assisted. Student tuition covers
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of our operating revenues, and gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
      provide the true margin of excellence for our programs. Contributions to
      the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Fund</ENAMEX> enable us to increase our support for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">scholarships</ENAMEX>, student programs and activities (e.g., moot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and
      client counseling), student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, and stipends for faculty
      research projects, to mention <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just a few</NUMEX> examples.
      I believe we do our job well and are continually strengthening our
      reputation as a first-rate law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. We have excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and a
      talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> who are highly regarded as classroom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>. We cannot entirely succeed, however, without the financial help
      of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>. I urge you to support your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX> so that we can
      continue to make you proud of the degree that you hold from this
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">institution</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Lefstein Dean Enclosures</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
