
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 20, 1992</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law Alumni Telephone</ENAMEX> Campaign for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Law</ENAMEX>
      -<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> was conducted during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second week of October</TIMEX>. For the
      <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> year, the campaign was managed by the law school and current law
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> volunteered their time to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>.
      You were called and requested additional information prior to making a
      pledge or gift to the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. We appreciate your interest in wanting
      to learn more about our funding needs!
      As the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> for development, I am especially
      sensitive about our efforts to create new or increased sources of income.
      We are more concerned about money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, but not because we want to
      be - we simply have to be. The law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s operating budget for this
      current academic year is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.4 million</NUMEX>. That is what it takes to pay our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, provide programs such as the civil and criminal
      practice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> travel for the moot court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>, cover expenses
      for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> law reviews, provide scholarships for deserving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, and
      meet the rising costs of maintaining our law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>. There is no fat in
      our budget.
      You can be proud of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX>. Throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> the law
      school has continued to provide quality legal education. However, we too
      have felt the effects of a prolonged recession; and I don't need to tell
      you that costs continue to rise. Legislative appropriations are either
      flat or in the decline. We maintain a kind of juggling act as we try to
      keep tuition costs in line. While the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> had to raise tuition by
      <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991-1992</TIMEX>] and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12%</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the current year</TIMEX>, our tuition is still among
      the lowest of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big 10</ENAMEX>" law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.
      Please make an annual contribution to your law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifts of $40.00</ENAMEX>
      add up to provide valuable funding.
      Gifts of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100.00</NUMEX> are more are recognized through various ways by the
      school. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,400</NUMEX> of our <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,980</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>) may also take
      advantage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Tax Credit</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Form CC-40</ENAMEX>).
      We do need you, and so do our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. What we are able to accomplish
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> is a direct result of your generosity and your understanding of
      what it takes to provide the best legal education we possibly can. Thank
      you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joni Thompson</ENAMEX> Assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean for Development</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
