
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 19, 1990</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      The law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,539</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> form a distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. They are
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in business, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and community affairs. During the past
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>, I have had witnessed significant growth in alumni commitment
      to the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. The generosity of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> is lead by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
      our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, who contribute <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1000</NUMEX> or more through
      their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> contributions, continue to demonstrate that support can make
      an impact at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. State appropriations alone are not sufficient to
      fund all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> research, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> acquisitions and services,
      professional skills programs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moot Court</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Practice</ENAMEX>
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Criminal Defense Clinics</ENAMEX>, or lecture programs such as the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Distinguished Jurist in Residence</ENAMEX>. Alumni contributions help provide the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">services</ENAMEX> and programs that distinguish a great law school from just a
      good one.
      We continue to attract top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and consistently our graduates
      have the highest success rate of any law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      Bar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exam</ENAMEX>. On the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> exams, for example, our pass rates
      were <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">96.5% and 91.4%</NUMEX>! Having good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> is only part of the picture.
      The law school prospers due to the commitment of a dedicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>. As
      our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> are aware, the faculty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">excels</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>, which is
      where quality in law teaching can be seen, felt, and heard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>.
      The need for private giving will continue to increase as we strive for
      a higher level of excellence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Graduates</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I. U</ENAMEX> .School of
      Law-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> leave with fundamental lawyering skills and a sound
      legal education.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> brings together <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who share a desire
      to provide enduring and generous support for the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. I urge you
      to consider a significant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $1,000</NUMEX>.
      Your gift can be made in one payment, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two semi-annual</TIMEX> payments, or
      on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> basis.
      Your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> gift to the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is an investment in its continued
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excellence</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Lefstein Dean</ENAMEX>
      P.S. We hope not only to revive the historical memory of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Building</ENAMEX>, which housed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, but also to continue to build for the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s future
      through the philanthropic support of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. Thank
      you!
      
    
  
