
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1, 1991</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This fall</TIMEX> alumni and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University School of Law</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> will initiate several programs to encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> support
      for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      As outlined during recent meetings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Visitors and Alumni</ENAMEX>
      Association <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Directors</ENAMEX>, these will include an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> law
      student/alumni telephone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> and increased emphasis on giving at the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> level.
      Prior to launching these programs, we are requesting each of our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni leaders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> to review their support of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> and, if no pledge or contribution has been made, to
      consider joining their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX>.
      As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumnus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of that activity, my function is to beat
      the drums for financial contributions of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> (or more) per year from
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. Accordingly, a brief recital of unmet
      needs is given below with a request for contributions. Also, I want to
      express my gratitude to those of you who have already pledged or
      contributed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>.
      These comments, for better or worse, are not accompanied by
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heartrending</ENAMEX> pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty members</ENAMEX> standing in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> lines nor with
      snap shots of undernourished law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> appears
      quite professional and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> reasonably fed. However, the school
      does have specific needs, some quite visible and others somewhat subtle,
      which are not being adequately met by legislative appropriations, student
      tuition and fees. Any of these include:
      
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Lounge</ENAMEX>: This area is usually the first seen by prospective
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> of wear have left furniture and
      other decor in a shabby state inconsistent with an impressive law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      Rehabilitation costs are estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85,000</NUMEX>. No state dollars are
      available for this project.
      Scholarships: For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-1991</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our school</TIMEX> of law received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$57,000</NUMEX> in
      state funds and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$78,000</NUMEX> from private endowment and gifts for a total of
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$135,000</NUMEX> for scholarship assistance. This is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 6%</NUMEX> of the total
      cost that law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> paid for their legal education at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> last
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. It is far less scholarship aid than is available at most law
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, for example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of Law</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bloomington</ENAMEX> spent
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$279,000</NUMEX> for scholarships from private and public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, although their
      student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is somewhat smaller than ours.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faculty Salaries and Research Support</ENAMEX>: Our law school ranks last in
      median base salaries for full <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> when compared with salaries paid
      to full <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> other "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Ten</ENAMEX>" law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. The school
      also lacks sufficient funds to award adequate summer stipends to support
      faculty scholarship and to cover the costs of student research
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>.
      Library expenditures: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Again</ENAMEX>, our law school ranks last in this
      category when compared with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> other "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Ten</ENAMEX>" law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Expenditures</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Highest</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,686,398</NUMEX> Average <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,700,395</NUMEX>
      Law-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,219,785</NUMEX>
      Your patience will not be tested by commentary on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assembly</ENAMEX>'s problems in providing more support for higher education.
      Rather, these humble efforts will be directed to increasing private
      sector contributions.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the selling points in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>'s development campaign is the
      level of support given by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s alumni <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> on the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alumni Association Board</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Visitors</ENAMEX>. Obviously, if all
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Boards</ENAMEX> were to pledge <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> per year, we would be
      most grateful and we would have a great story to tell. However, we
      recognize that contributions at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> level are not
      possible for all. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> may have had their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX>
      move in, another mouth to feed and a loss in domestic tranquility. Junior
      may have wrecked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> may have attained the age for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">orthodontia</ENAMEX>. If circumstances do not permit your participation in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX>, please do contribute at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the levels recognized
      annually by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean's Council</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 500</NUMEX> -999
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrister's Club</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$ 250 -499</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Law School Associates</ENAMEX> $ <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">100 -249</ENAMEX>
      Contributions may be made when the pledge is submitted or anytime
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">prior to the end of 1991</TIMEX>. A pledge card and return envelope are enclosed.
      For the reasons noted below, please return your card before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 30</TIMEX>,
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>.
      If you have pledged or contributed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, you have my thanks and
      the appreciation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> of the law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      Also, you have the satisfaction of knowing that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> are being
      urged to emulate your good judgment.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early September</TIMEX> it will be my privilege to personally contact any
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Visitors or Alumni Board</ENAMEX> who through
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">misadventure</ENAMEX>, oversight, procrastination or the pendency of personal
      bankruptcy proceedings have not made some pledge or contribution, however
      large or small, to our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>.
      As I consider the talented, loyal and resourceful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> on these
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boards</ENAMEX>, I assume few, if any, calls will be necessary.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> last matter: we will be contacting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> for membership in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. If you are willing to make a
      few (<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six or less</NUMEX>) telephone calls to assist the law school, please so
      indicate on your pledge card. Those participating will be provided
      prospects' names, addresses and telephone numbers, as well as background
      information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s needs.
      Thanks for your courtesy in reviewing this epistle and for your
      response.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John M. Holt</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'56</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maennerchor Society Committee Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University School of Law</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
