
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July, 1994</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Board of Visitors cordially</ENAMEX> invites you to become a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Center</ENAMEX> on Philanthropy
      Dear Name:
      I need your immediate help <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to save a tradition... a uniquely
      <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tradition that has flourished in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>...
      ...a living tradition of voluntary action for the public good known as
      "philanthropy."
      I look to you because you are among the few who have an outstanding
      commitment to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropy</ENAMEX> --a commitment based on your personal
      conviction that the "<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX>" is essential to our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way of
      life. And indeed it is.
      Unfortunately, our view of the importance of philanthropy is not
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shared</ENAMEX> by all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Many see philanthropy as no more than the grand
      gestures of the rich.
      They do not understand, as we do, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>
      and community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropy</ENAMEX> are the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cornerstones</ENAMEX> of our very quality of life. They do not realize that right
      now voluntary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> are helping to address some of the most
      troubling social issues of our time, including homelessness, crime, and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> and alcohol abuse.
      Perhaps most important, few comprehend that the perpetuation
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> of our diverse tradition of giving, caring and
      serving, carried out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> from all walks of life, is
      key to the present and future vitality of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
      Evidence strongly suggests that this lack of understanding is
      undermining young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s commitment to philanthropy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> ... which
      will devastate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> and
      causes.
      We cannot let our rich philanthropic heritage --a vast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> that now
      includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred million</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> --be placed in jeopardy!
      It is critical that we educate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> about the importance of
      Philanthropy that we develop a new generation of informed and committed
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. To do all this we need a place where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropy</ENAMEX> can be
      explored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> as a serious academic
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>.
      This is why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philanthropy</ENAMEX> was founded
      and why I am writing to seek you support of our mission <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      We want you as a true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> because we know you share our deep
      conviction that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropy</ENAMEX> is essential to our democratic society.
      I am therefore delighted to extend this invitation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> giving you
      the opportunity to join us as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Charter Associate of the Center</ENAMEX> on
      Philanthropy.
      JOIN WITH <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KINDRED SPIRITS</ENAMEX>
      As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate</ENAMEX>, you will join many kindred spirits - <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like
      you who believe that professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">practice</ENAMEX> can be improved by closely
      linking nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and fund raising to education, study and
      research.
      Specifically, you will be joining a group of distinguished foundation
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>, business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, development <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> in the nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sector</ENAMEX> ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles A. Johnson</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> for Development of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly Endowment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Rosso</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founding Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Fund Raising School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Society of Fund Raising Executives</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milt Murray</ENAMEX>, an
      extraordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund raiser</ENAMEX> upon whom both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSFRE</ENAMEX> have
      bestowed their highest awards. These are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who share your dedication
      who never close the door on their commitment to philanthropy at the end
      of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each working day</TIMEX>.
      But before you decide to join us, let me tell you more about our work
      and our achievements.
      THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LILLY ENDOWMENT CHALLENGE</ENAMEX>
      We were founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> with a major grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly Endowment</ENAMEX>,
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest and most prestigious private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX>. Our
      earliest goal was to "permeate the intellectual consciousness" of the
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> campuses of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX> and establish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropy</ENAMEX> as a
      serious field of study.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> we have accomplished all this and much more. Currently, the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">university</ENAMEX> lists <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> in philanthropic studies that touch
      on a wide range of disciplines including the law, sociology, and the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humanities</ENAMEX>.
      We also have a groundbreaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master of Arts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philanthropic Studies</ENAMEX>
      program and are developing a doctoral degree in the field. What's more,
      over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX>, lecturers, and other distinguished <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> from
      around the world participate in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>-sponsored <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX>, conferences,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">symposia</ENAMEX> and research programs designed to enrich our understanding of
      the vitality of our philanthropic tradition.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> participate
      annually in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> and workshops offered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center's Fund</ENAMEX> Raising
      School, the only national university-based fund raising training program
      with an international reputation for helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> become leaders
      in ethical fund raising.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">REACHING OUT TO AMERICA</ENAMEX>
      Developing a new generation of informed and committed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philanthropy</ENAMEX> is, in fact, one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>'s highest priorities. That is
      why we have just introduced an exciting new program called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leadership</ENAMEX>
      Works. Co-sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association for Community Leadership</ENAMEX>,
      the program is designed to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteer leaders</ENAMEX> learn fund raising
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">skills</ENAMEX> and better appreciate their work as part of our philanthropic
      tradition.
      We are well aware that the ultimate importance of the study of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">philanthropy</ENAMEX> is found outside the walls of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX>. That is why this
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> initiative is now being launched in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Midwestern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>. It is
      part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>'s effort to serve the needs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> directly by
      training those 'who are responsible for sustaining philanthropy at the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grassroots</ENAMEX>.
      This is but one of many projects we envision as we work to develop the
      next generation of philanthropic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>'s core
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> out into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> across our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
      Because if you and I truly want to preserve philanthropy as a way of
      life, we must make certain that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> everywhere take philanthropy
      seriously, that they talk about it, debate it, challenge it, and
      ultimately keep it alive as a cherished tradition.
      But we cannot achieve this ambitious task alone. We need your support
      to help us make it all happen!
      This is why I am counting on your commitment as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate</ENAMEX> of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Center</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Philanthropy</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">WE ARE UNIQUE AMONG OUR PEERS</ENAMEX>
      I realize that, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>, you are frequently asked to
      support worthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, including other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> associated
      with philanthropy. I must therefore tell you why the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Center</ENAMEX> on
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philanthropy</ENAMEX> also deserves your support.
      We are the only educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> actively dedicated to changing
      the way <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> think and fell about the importance of philanthropy to
      our way of life.
      We are the leading academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> promoting the study of
      philanthropy as a vital <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> tradition. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> depend on us to provide materials and direction as they
      incorporate philanthropic studies into their curriculum.
      YOU CAN MAKE A DIFFERENCE
      Your help <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> will enable us to strengthen further <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s
      philanthropic heritage by expanding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>'s crucial educational,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and outreach programs.
      When you join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate</ENAMEX> with a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> or
      more, you are entitled to many privileges, including a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charter</ENAMEX>
      Associate Certificate you'll be proud to hang in your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and a copy
      of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Board of Visitors</ENAMEX>' prestigious publication <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Report</ENAMEX>
      on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of Philanthropy</ENAMEX>. Benefits for higher gift levels are listed
      on the enclosed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acceptance Form</ENAMEX>. For example, for a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> your
      name will be permanently inscribed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Honor Roll of Charter</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associates</ENAMEX> housed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>.
      But whatever the size of your gift, your participation as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>'s mission makes a valuable difference. Your inspiration, your
      generous support and your active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> are crucial to our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX>.
      Please accept the invitation of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Board of Visitors</ENAMEX> and
      join <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren F. Ilchman</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
      P.S. I am personally counting on your immediate support as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charter</ENAMEX>
      Associate to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX> expand its crucial role in preserving the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American philanthropic</ENAMEX> tradition. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate</ENAMEX> offer ends
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 30, 1994</TIMEX>. Join us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>!
      
    
  
