
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 6, 1994</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name,
      As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> draws to a close, we at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Nursing</ENAMEX> pause to reflect
      on all we have accomplished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 80 years</TIMEX> since our founding in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>.
      At this time, we also turn to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> like you, asking you to show that
      you share in our sense of pride by continuing to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>'s
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> Fund.
      In a recent message to current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, I urged them, too, to take
      pride in being associated with one of the best nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and reminded them of our rich heritage: our role in founding
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sigma Theta Tau International</ENAMEX> and in launching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest Nursing</ENAMEX>
      Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest Alliance</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nursing</ENAMEX>; our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in
      bringing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Healthy Cities</ENAMEX> movement to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and designation
      as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> (and only) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization Collaborating Center</ENAMEX> in
      Healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cities</ENAMEX>; our ranking among the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> of nursing in the
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News and World Report</ENAMEX> survey; and our support for the numerous
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> who have won awards and held leadership
      positions in community, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>, and professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>.
      This past academic year, highlights have included the establishment of
      a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Visitors</ENAMEX>; the appointment of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus deans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marian</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pettengill at IU South Bend and Penny Cass at IU Kokomo</ENAMEX>; recognition of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Health Nursing Department</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Public Health</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>; sponsoring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse recipients</ENAMEX> for IU honorary degrees,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hildegard Peplau</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeth Carnegie</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Southeast</ENAMEX>; and
      celebrating the induction in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993 and 1994</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> into the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Academy of Nursing</ENAMEX>. We also take great pride in the innovative
      teaching of our award-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX>, who have developed the use of
      information technology in learning situations and earned recognition at
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Founder</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Day</ENAMEX> ceremonies for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX>, and in the everyday
      heroism of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, exemplified by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> of our "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Profiles</ENAMEX> in
      Courage" awards, an inoculation program organized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX>, and the contributions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU Southeast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. John's Day</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center</ENAMEX>.
      Reminding ourselves of our excellence isn't done to be egotistical.
      Rather, it allows us to feel energized and be pleased that we chose to be
      a part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that has achieved national recognition. Gifts to the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School's Annual Fund</ENAMEX> provide critical dollars for scholarships, student
      activities, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> development--areas not covered by tuition or
      state dollars. Regardless of the size of your gift, your participation in
      the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> drive is an indicator of your pride in association with the
      School of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing</ENAMEX>. If your gift has already been mailed to us, please
      accept our sincere thanks for your generosity. If not, I hope you will
      send in your renewal gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Barron McBride Distinguished</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University Dean</ENAMEX>
    
  
