
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 16, 1990</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Dr. Name</ENAMEX>:
      This has been an eventful year for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Nursing</ENAMEX> -the official
      closing of a very successful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">75th Anniversary</TIMEX> Celebration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, a
      record enrollment exceeding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> system-wide and a host of
      other new developments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Nursing</ENAMEX> is proud of the following
      facts:
      being the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Nursing</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>!
      the successful launching of a major recruitment drive to increase
      minority enrollment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>
      having attracted the distinguished and nationally known nursing
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researcher Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Elizabeth Carnegie</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visiting Professor</ENAMEX>
      providing several seminars on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast Asian</ENAMEX> nursing education
      practices and progress and hosting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegations</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse leaders</ENAMEX> from
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
      ...all this has been possible because of your loyal and unfailing
      support to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> and its programs.
      As you well know, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Nursing</ENAMEX> receives <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 30%</NUMEX> of its
      operating funds from the state appropriations. It is the significant
      gifts from our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, that make all the difference by
      helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>'s scholarship and financial aids program which is very
      important to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with limited means, interested in pursuing their
      nursing education. You are important to us and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U. School of Nursing</ENAMEX>
      needs your generous gifts to continue and uphold its educational
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excellence</ENAMEX>.
      It would be wonderful if you could take the time to visit your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>,
      and see for yourself the progress we have made over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and share
      in the pride of our heritage!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca T. Markel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EdD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RN</ENAMEX> Assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean/Development RTM</ENAMEX>/lv
    
  
