
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana The State</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicine The Campaign</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University School of Medicine</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 21, 1994</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heralding</ENAMEX> ground breaking achievement is a delightful task. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Medicine</ENAMEX> has been a tremendous contributor to the
      reputation of excellence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX> enjoys.
      Scientific investigation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>'s benefit is an integral
      part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Medicine</ENAMEX>'s mission. We take seriously our immense
      responsibility to push the boundaries of knowledge in our pursuit of new
      treatments and therapies for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> that negatively impact the lives of
      many.
      In that regard, we enclose information highlighting an exciting
      achievement in cardiovascular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Medicine</ENAMEX>. The
      work by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loren I. Field</ENAMEX>, Ph.D., and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> was a
      cover story in a recent issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> - the preeminent journal
      recognizing benchmark research.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the devastating consequences of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart disease</ENAMEX> is the
      irreparable damage it does to the heart muscle. When heart cells die,
      because of a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> or another cause, they cannot be repaired. The
      possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiac</ENAMEX> regeneration offers tremendous hope for the
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who have suffered grave damage to their hearts.
      The research published in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> gives evidence of progress by
      documenting the first successful transplantation of functional heart
      cells into an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> model. These transplanted cells line up properly,
      make the correct connections and function just like native heart <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cells</ENAMEX>.
      Thus, the prospect of heart <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell replacement</ENAMEX>, rather than a full heart
      transplant, may be in the foreseeable future. There is still much work to
      do, but, naturally, we are very proud of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>'
      pioneering work.
      Cardiovascular research has been an area of distinct strength at IU
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Medicine</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>'s cardiologists, cardiovascular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">surgeons</ENAMEX>,
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have made significant advances through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> against
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s number one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>. From the laboratory to the bedside, our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">physicians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> are dedicated to improving the care and
      treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> suffering from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cardiovascular disease</ENAMEX>. The research
      published in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> is additional evidence of our commitment to seeking
      new discoveries that will benefit many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
      As you know, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University School of Medicine</ENAMEX> is in the midst of
      a major fundraising campaign. A major component of the campaign is to
      support research activities like those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX>. In addition to
      funding work in cardiovascular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, the campaign will support
      initiatives in <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, pediatrics, genetics, as well as increasing
      scholarship assistance and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>'s endowment. Currently, over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> has been raised toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130 million</NUMEX> goal.
      If you would like additional information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IU School of</ENAMEX>
      Medicine campaign or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX>'s research, please call <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">274-3270</ENAMEX>. Your
      interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Medicine</ENAMEX> is greatly appreciated.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Perelman</ENAMEX>, Ph.D. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter J. Daly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.D.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Campaign Chair</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
