
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1, 1993</TIMEX>
      Dear:
      Birthdays are a time for celebration - a time to reflect on the past
      and anticipate the future. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">90th</NUMEX> birthday of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Medicine</ENAMEX> is no different. From a modest beginning to its rank
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as one of the best academic medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s only medical school boasts a proud heritage. It has educated
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hoosier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX>, treated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX>
      of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hoosier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, and participated in research breakthroughs which
      have advanced medical care far beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s borders.
      Take a moment to share <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few 90th birthday reflections</TIMEX>. School of
      Medicine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> have: developed treatments that
      turned a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> mortality rate for testicular <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> into a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90</NUMEX>
      percent cure rate; pioneered echocardiography, we use of sound waves for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">detecting heart disease</ENAMEX>; shared in developing "smart" pacemakers, which
      monitor heart rhythm and automatically shock the heart when it develops
      irregularities; founded the world's first <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, preserving genetic
      material for future study and diagnosis; pinpointed the defective gene in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Huntington's disease</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX>; and spearheaded
      the use of many New treatments for critically ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, including
      infant heart transplant and special therapies for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.
      The work goes on. Soon we will construct a clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> research
      and treatment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and a basic <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> .Our heart
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> continue to improve methods of heart transplantation and
      treatments for arrhythmias and atherosclerosis. We are expanding
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diagnostic</ENAMEX> and treatment abilities with our new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PET scanner</ENAMEX>. Our
      pediatric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> are studying birth defects, childhood <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancers</ENAMEX>, blood
      disorders, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone marrow</ENAMEX> Transplant techniques, and our medical and
      molecular genetics research continues to unravel genetic mysteries.
      But adequate funding is an ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $300 million</NUMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> required to operate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Medicine</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">less than 20 percent</NUMEX>
      comes from state dollars. Our teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> and research programs
      receive no state support. Only with the help of our philanthropic
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> have we been able to achieve so much. Private gifts enable us to
      recruit top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and continue the programs which promise
      the best health care for generations to come. I invite you to continue to
      be one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>. Celebrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Medicine</ENAMEX>'s 90th
      birthday with us by renewing your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean's Council</ENAMEX>. It
      will help assure our continuing work for many birthdays to come.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter J. Daly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">M.D.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Medicine</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
