
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 5, 1991</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Graduate</ENAMEX>:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Commencement 1991</ENAMEX> renews memories of student <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> fifteen new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> and join
      ranks with medical record <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">practitioners</ENAMEX> throughout the world, thus
      increasing the links between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U.</ENAMEX> and our professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Y. Engels</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85'91</NUMEX>} was chosen from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division of Allied Health</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sciences</ENAMEX> to receive the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scholar Award</ENAMEX> for academic
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excellence</ENAMEX>. She was honored at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chancellor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honors Convocation</ENAMEX>.
      We were very proud to have a medical record <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> student
      selected for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-91</TIMEX> award.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Program</ENAMEX> established the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton T. Ridley Distinguished</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service Award</ENAMEX>. Although retired from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ridley</ENAMEX> continues
      to lend support to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Record Administration</ENAMEX> Program. Many
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> may remember him as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>, others as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interviewer</ENAMEX> on the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Admission's Committee</ENAMEX>, and others as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moderator</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude L. Gunn</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> award will be presented at our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> luncheon.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s alumni luncheon is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 23, 1991</TIMEX>, during
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">AMRA Annual Meeting</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>. If you plan to attend
      the luncheon, please forward the enclosure and your name will be included
      in our mailing. Also, if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> would like to have a special event
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, we would be pleased to assist by providing a list of mailing
      addresses.
      Spring seems to be a good time to contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> to request
      contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude L. Gunn Scholarship</ENAMEX> Fund. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> tuition
      was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$69.65</NUMEX> per credit hour and books <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">approximately $500</NUMEX>. Housing, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>,
      and car expenses, especially for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> traveling some distance to
      their assigned clinical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>, are also costly items. Your contribution
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> allowed us to make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> awards of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ninth</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude L.</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gunn Forum</ENAMEX>. Since the monies are now in an interest bearing account, our
      plan is to award the interest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Groh Tower</ENAMEX>, entered the Medical
      Record Administration Program to become our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX>. Will you help
      us celebrate our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40th Anniversary</TIMEX> with your contribution to the
      Scholarship Fund?
      Please make your check payable to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U. Foundation Medical Record</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scholarship</ENAMEX>," in memo section -<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gertrude L. Gunn</ENAMEX>. An envelope is enclosed
      for your convenience. Sincere appreciation goes to each of you for
      including this Fund in your giving.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary L. McKenzie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RRA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
      MLM:mmg
      Enclosures: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U. Foundation Envelope and Alumni Luncheon Request</ENAMEX>
      Form
    
  
