
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Club</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Member</ENAMEX>:
      Your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Metro Athletic Club</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> is
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">renewable</ENAMEX> now. Please recall that we are on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1 - December 31</TIMEX>
      calendar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> basis, having made that transition beginning with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.
      We cannot afford to lose your valuable financial support and hope you
      might consider an increase in your personal or corporate gift for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>.
      Your contributions help fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> scholarships (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> = <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> student
      per year), awards, special events, program advertising and membership
      activities.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $70,000</NUMEX> to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IUPUI</ENAMEX> intercollegiate
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">athletics</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> moves to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big League</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX>) in
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-93</TIMEX>, our fund-raising goal will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> per year and a net
      increase of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">125</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> annually.
      A new membership brochure will be mailed to you under separate! cover
      within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX>. Contribution categories are:
      Red and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gold</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> and above)
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Champion</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000-$2,499</NUMEX>)
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sponsor</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500-$999</NUMEX>)
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100-$499</NUMEX>)
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50-$99</NUMEX>)
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> may join through a new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25-$49</NUMEX> level contribution.
      Please use the enclosed business reply envelope and make your tax
      deductible contribution by check to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.U. Foundation/Metro Athletic</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>. If you have questions or suggestions, please call either myself
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">924-5471</ENAMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Lovell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">274-0622</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Thank you!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Carroll President</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAC</ENAMEX>/je
      Enclosures
    
  
