
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6, 1992</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Club Member</ENAMEX>
      It is time for the proverbial LAST CALL! Please do not slide on to our
      "lapsed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>" list. We greatly value you and your continued support of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI Metros</ENAMEX>.
      Membership renewals have generated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $26.000</NUMEX> to date - our
      goal is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32.500</NUMEX>. We need you!
      By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1</TIMEX>, we must conclude membership renewal options for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>. Although renewals will certainly be accepted after that
      date, as will new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, annual benefits will have been reduced by more
      than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months</TIMEX>.
      Upcoming events you'll not want to miss include:
      .<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sports Award</ENAMEX> Program <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX> .<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golf Outing</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3</TIMEX> .<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gus Macker</ENAMEX> at
      IUPUI <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 13-14</TIMEX> .<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White River Park State Games</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17-19</TIMEX> .<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> v.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 12</TIMEX>
      Contingent on approval, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IUPUI</ENAMEX> will be competing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA</ENAMEX> beginning
      with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-94 season</TIMEX>.
      Enclosed once again is a membership application form and a business
      reply envelope. Please use them. You are vital to our success.
      Should you have extenuating circumstances, require special attention,
      or just need assistance, we'll do almost anything to accommodate you.
      Please call if you have questions or comments (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">921-7300</ENAMEX>). Thank you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael A. Carroll President</ENAMEX>
      Enclosures
    
  
