
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends of the Free Library of Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends of the Free Library</ENAMEX> is an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that
      works to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Library</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> through increasing
      public awareness, advocating before elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and supporting the
      growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> in all its activities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> operate at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
      levels -the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Citywide Friends and the Branch Friends</ENAMEX> -and you can become
      active at either one or both levels.
      You become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citywide Friends of the Free Library</ENAMEX> as a
      benefit of giving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> or more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Library Foundation</ENAMEX>,
      and you can also join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Friends</ENAMEX> in your neighborhood by paying a
      nominal membership fee at your local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Citywide Friends</ENAMEX> consist of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than 8,000</NUMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> and
      library <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> who support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Library</ENAMEX> and participate in its
      programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends</ENAMEX>' programs such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Library Leaders</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> is
      Reading Together Week target young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and instill library habits at
      an early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> run a bookstore that has some of the best
      bargains in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for new and used books.
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citywide Friends of the Free Library</ENAMEX> you will
      receive a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> newsletter informing you of library events and
      legislative issues. You will also receive a discount at the bookstore.
      Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends volunteer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>.
      With your contribution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>, you will become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Citywide Friends</ENAMEX>. We also encourage you to investigate and join your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neighborhood Branch Friends</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. For your convenience, there is a list
      of all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> on the opposite side.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Friends</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> are close-knit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that provide
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">volunteers</ENAMEX>, help plan programs and raise money for special needs of their
      local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>. Membership fees in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Friends</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are quite low;
      and the activities are very rewarding. You can become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branch Friend</ENAMEX> at
      your local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch Friends</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are organized into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> called the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance of Friends</ENAMEX> to provide mutual support and address issues that
      affect all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX>.
      You can make a contribution to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Library</ENAMEX> and become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Citywide Friends</ENAMEX> with the attached form. Contributions are made
      through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Library of Philadelphia Foundation</ENAMEX>, which raises funds
      for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
