
  
  
    
      Dear
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BA</ENAMEX> becomes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BAJ</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
      That's the plan for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Journalism</ENAMEX>'s independence. We're
      moving from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College of Arts and Sciences</ENAMEX>. More than ever we will be a
      school within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>, with our own identity and academic mission.
      And yet within change there will be continuity. I want to assure you that
      we'll remain a close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College of Arts and Sciences</ENAMEX>. We'll
      insist even more on the vital importance of the liberal arts for
      journalism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>. An IU-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> will understand the ties
      that bind the profession to the knowledge of the past, the problems and
      issues of the present, the ideas of the future.
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1729</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin Franklin</ENAMEX> said a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> ought to be qualified with
      an extensive acquaintance with languages, a great easiness and command of
      writing and relating things clearly and intelligibly, and, in a few
      words, he should be able to speak of war both by land and sea, be well
      acquainted with geography, with the history of the time, with the several
      interests of princes and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, the secrets of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, and the manners
      and customs of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX>. The essence of journalism education hasn't
      changed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">260 years</TIMEX>. It's only more expensive.
      You can help. And you know that line was coming. But yes, you can
      help. Indeed, I hope you will help.
      We need scholarships to inspire and reward the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. We need
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resources</ENAMEX> to recruit and develop outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>. We need books and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> to create the climate of learning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX>
      required. We need computers and cameras so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> can master the tools
      of their profession.
      You, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, have helped put this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">School</ENAMEX> at the
      forefront of journalism education in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. As we become
      independent, please help us strengthen the distinction of your degree.
      And please help us make our BAJ equal to the challenges of the 21st
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century</ENAMEX>.
      As always, we are grateful for your support.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trevor R. Brown Dean</ENAMEX>
    
  
