
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>:
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Historical Society</ENAMEX> comprises a diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of members
      who share the characteristics of intelligence, curiosity and pride in our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s history. That is also true of famous Hoosiers such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitcomb Riley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene V. Debs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madam C.J. Walker</ENAMEX>. Their stories
      provide a glimpse into the wonderful world of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> history-a world
      that, through its mission, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indiana Historical Society</ENAMEX> has been
      dedicated to collecting, preserving and promoting since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1830</TIMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indiana Historical Society</ENAMEX> would like you to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>.
      The advantages of membership begin now! By joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Society</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> sustaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> you will be rewarded
      with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Gift Certificate</ENAMEX> to spend as you like on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> books or
      merchandise. And, as an added thank you from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>, select a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">complimentary</ENAMEX> book or cassette with your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> sustaining membership or
      with your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> membership.
      Enjoy the benefits of membership year round.
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indiana Historical Society</ENAMEX> you can receive any or
      all of its regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>:
      The award-winning illustrated history magazine -<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Traces</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and
      Midwestern History; the scholarly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">journal- Indiana Magazine of History</ENAMEX>;
      the family history publication -The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hoosier Genealogist</ENAMEX>; and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hoosier</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-American</ENAMEX> history newsletter<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">- Black History News & Notes</ENAMEX>.
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> you will also receive the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">bimonthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newsletter</ENAMEX>, The
      Bridge, and you will be invited to join in workshops, conferences,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lectures</ENAMEX> and other special events. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> receive discounts on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>
      products and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> available through regular catalogs and at the
      History Market gift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>" located at our beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>.
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> your membership dollars help support
      important educational programs and activities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">museums</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> that preserve and promote our heritage. You can
      also enjoy changing exhibits and family programs held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> your membership dollars help
      support important educational programs and activities in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classrooms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> that preserve and promote our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heritage</ENAMEX>. You can also enjoy changing exhibits and family programs held
      at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Society</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> and explore history in our state-of-the-art
      research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>. You, along with other caring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, will be helping
      the effort to preserve and promote our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s proud heritage.
      Participate in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> celebration!
      Each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> we celebrate our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s heritage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hoosier</ENAMEX>
      History <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Festival</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hoosier History Festival</ENAMEX> will be held on
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 22</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> AM to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX> and will feature musical, dance and theatrical
      performances, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s activities, historical re enactors and
      storytellers, historical displays and much more. You won't want to miss
      the fun. This festival promises as much excitement as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX>
      Opening celebration, when we welcomed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to our new
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>!
      Become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> member <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>!
      If you enjoy reading the stories in the enclosed brochure, there is an
      excellent chance that you will enjoy membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Historical</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>. There has never been a better time to join than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>. The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> offers more opportunities than ever before to learn about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      history in fun and interactive ways. You can play an important role in
      preserving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s history by being an active supporter of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society's</ENAMEX> mission.
      Start enjoying the benefits of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> membership <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by completing
      and returning the enclosed reply card. Don't forget to choose your free
      gift when selecting your preferred membership level. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Society</ENAMEX> is missing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> important component...you!
      We hope you will join us.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne J. Cartmel</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Trustees</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter T. Hastad</ENAMEX>
      Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
      A membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana Historical Society</ENAMEX> makes a unique and
      thoughtful gift for many occasions and at any time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. Remember,
      whether you are joining for yourself or someone else, be sure to select
      your free book or cassette as our thank you for joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>.
    
  
