
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 6, 2000</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat LaCrosse</ENAMEX> asked me to send this information inviting you to join
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia O'Keeffe Circle</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Museum of Art</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Society</ENAMEX> (SCS). The SCS brochure I am enclosing will give you the
      historic significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCS</ENAMEX>, as well as listing activities and specific
      benefits awarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia O</ENAMEX>'Keeffe level. Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Keeffe</ENAMEX> membership, please note, includes free admission to all
      art-related activities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Friends of Art</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
      Additionally, I am sending traditional background materials on the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> latest issues of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Previews Magazine</ENAMEX> detailing
      upcoming events, exhibitions, and educational programs.
      These are particularly exciting times at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Museum of</ENAMEX>
      Art: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Progress</ENAMEX> continues on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.K. Lilly</ENAMEX> estate-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oldfields</ENAMEX>, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ravine</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garden</ENAMEX> has been restored to its original splendor, and there is national
      attention showered on our current exhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Japanese Painting</ENAMEX>.
      (please see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York Times</ENAMEX> article I have included.) With <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands</NUMEX>
      of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> in bloom, we are having a beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spring</ENAMEX>!
      Our extraordinary permanent collection, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>, and grounds, we
      understand full well, would not be possible without the philanthropic
      support of civic-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. In joining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCS</ENAMEX>, you join the ranks
      of those who believe that bringing art and art education to the city
      makes life better, richer, and more rewarding for the entire
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
      A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Century Society</ENAMEX> response card and return envelope are
      enclosed. Should you have questions or if I can be of assistance in any
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, please call me: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">317.923.1331</NUMEX>, ext. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">248</NUMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ARLETTA B.NEWTON Donor Relations Coordinator Enclosures</ENAMEX>/
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> .S. Both our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barefoot</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grass</ENAMEX> family picnic (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">July</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">23,2000</NUMEX>) and
      the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">SCS Founders Day</ENAMEX> celebration (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">October</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11,2000</NUMEX>) are free for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia O'Keeffe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> your calendars!
      
    
  
