
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27, 2000</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      I received the good news you are interested in receiving information
      on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Museum of Art</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Century Society</ENAMEX> (SCS). The
      <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Century Society</ENAMEX> brochure I am enclosing will give you an
      understanding of the significance and activities of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, as well
      as listing the specific benefits awarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> at the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Circles</ENAMEX> or
      levels of giving.
      In additional materials I am sending you will find traditional
      background information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> and news (in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Previews</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>)
      of our latest developments, scheduled programs, and special
      exhibitions.
      These are exciting times at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Museum of Art</ENAMEX>: Our Corot
      to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Picasso Special Exhibition</ENAMEX>, through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, is a great complement to
      our existing collection. There is tremendous momentum <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> as our
      recently-acquired <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese Paintings</ENAMEX> are readied for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX> inaugural
      viewing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trustees</ENAMEX>, special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dignitaries</ENAMEX>.
      (Please see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New York Times</ENAMEX> article I have included.) And, our grounds
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Spring day</TIMEX> are abloom with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>. The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, with a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one hundred fifty-acre</NUMEX> parklike
      campus, is one of the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
      Our extraordinary permanent collection, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>, and grounds, we
      understand full well, would not be possible without the philanthropic
      support of civic-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. In joining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCS</ENAMEX>, you join the ranks
      of those who believe that bringing art and art education to the city
      makes life better, richer, and more rewarding for the entire
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
      A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Century Society</ENAMEX> response card and return envelope are
      enclosed. Should you have questions or if I can be of assistance in any
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>, please call me: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">317.923.1331</NUMEX>, ext. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">248</NUMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ARLETT A B. NEWTON Donor Relations Coordinator</ENAMEX> Enclosures/
      
    
  
