
  
  
    
      May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30, 2000</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      Just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Museum of Art</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>'s) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2000</TIMEX> is filled
      with exciting developments, so, too, are your opportunities as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trustees</ENAMEX>
      for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> devoting your time,
      talent, and resources, you help ensure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>'s success in realizing its
      new vision to join the ranks of the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tier</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>.
      Already the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX> has joined the select ranks of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> with
      major collections of paintings from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s celebrated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Edo</TIMEX> period. The
      landmark acquisition in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX> rare and important hanging scrolls
      and folding screens is evidence of the commitment to build the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>'s
      permanent collection of world art. It continues the momentum of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
      acquisition of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> paintings and prints by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gauguin</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pont-Aven</ENAMEX>, and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> announcements of the promised gifts of the Glick
      Collection of contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clowes Collection of l00</ENAMEX> works
      by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Old Masters</ENAMEX>.
      Restoration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldfields Estate</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>'s largest work of art,
      progresses. With the reopening of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ravine Garden</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1999</TIMEX>,
      attention has now shifted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly House</ENAMEX>. When finished, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly House</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interior</ENAMEX> will reflect the quiet grandeur of its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1930s</NUMEX> appearance during
      the early era of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josiah K. Lilly Jr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s occupancy.
      Dialogue with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and other civic and
      community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>'s development of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX> &
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature Park</ENAMEX> continues. Even now, the potential for different types of art
      that may be exhibited in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park</ENAMEX>, and the range of educational programs
      and community events that may be offered promise to expand the horizons
      of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
      No matter which of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major art experiences you prefer,
      we depend on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Trustees</ENAMEX>' depth of commitment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> to
      build and maintain it. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>'s operating budget
      came from loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>' contributions. Even with the continuing
      generosity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> has programs and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> that go
      unfunded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>.
      As you may be aware, your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Century Society</ENAMEX> membership
      expires on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6/30/2000</NUMEX>. A contribution at your current level of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000.00</NUMEX>
      sustains your membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.M. W. Turner Circle</ENAMEX>. (For your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">convenience</ENAMEX>, we enclose a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Century Society</ENAMEX> brochure and response
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX>.)
      Thank you for your service and financial support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Art</ENAMEX>! Your investment continues the high quality of all aspects
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> and makes new achievements possible. If you have questions
      or need additional assistance, please reach <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arletta Newton</ENAMEX>, donor
      relations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX>, at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">317.283.1331</NUMEX>, ext. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">248</NUMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John L. Krauss Trustee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development Committee</ENAMEX>
      
    
  
