
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 18, 1999</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dear Mr. Forest</ENAMEX>:
      Thank you for supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Museum of Art</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. As
      our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal year</TIMEX> ends on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 31, 1999</TIMEX>, we recognize the support you
      have demonstrated for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> through your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> or by attending
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s special exhibitions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
      According to our records, you have not yet participated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>'s
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giving Campaign</ENAMEX>. Your gift will help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> prevent a
      projected operating shortfall of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$56,000</NUMEX>. The size of your gift is not as
      important as participation from all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.
      Your gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Giving Campaign</ENAMEX> will help by:
      Offsetting the cost of operating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, currently <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $30,000</NUMEX> a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, and keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Museum of Art</ENAMEX> experience accessible to
      the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 400,000</NUMEX> annual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX>.
      Enhancing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>-school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX> is a city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">delivering Distance Learning</ENAMEX> via video conferencing. In addition, the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Community Connection</ENAMEX> program uses a diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
      to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>'s permanent collection to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and
      community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. These programs have provided many
      young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with a strong foundation for future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> experiences-
      Daily maintenance and upkeep of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s property including;
      grounds, gardens, nature paths, fountains, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>. With
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, your gift supports the natural
      beauty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">150- acre</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> -like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>-
      Attracting special touring exhibitions such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Fantasy</ENAMEX> World of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Sendai</ENAMEX> (now through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 30</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corrupt</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picas</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
      Masterworks from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith College Museum of Art</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 13</TIMEX> through
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 30, 2000</TIMEX>).
      From negotiating art loans from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> nationally and internationally
      to purchasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> kits, flowering <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shrubs</ENAMEX>, and even lightbulbs -your
      gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Campaign</ENAMEX> makes possible all you do and see at the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>.
      As one of the many cultural <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that will appeal to you for
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> operating support, I hope you will reflect on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>
      means to you, your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who value
      its presence in central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and make your pledge accordingly.
      Respond by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 9</TIMEX> and we will recognize your support
      with a reception on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 11, 1999</TIMEX>.
      Following the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Holiday Concert</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:00 p.m.</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber Brass Choir</ENAMEX>,
      there will be seasonal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> and punch in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herron Hall</ENAMEX> for all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual</ENAMEX>
      Campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.
      Browse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum shops</ENAMEX> for a unique holiday gift or explore the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">museum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madeline F. Elder Greenhouse</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holiday</TIMEX> decorating ideas.
      Don't miss the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>'s special exhibition calendar for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>
      including <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Romance of Real Lace</ENAMEX> -featuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30</NUMEX> pieces drawn from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>'s
      extensive lace collection, considered one of the best in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> and grounds will be decorated with holiday lights.
      I appreciate your consideration and hope that you will participate in
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Campaign</ENAMEX>. Your support means so much! I will look for
      you on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">11th</ENAMEX>!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Hardwick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development & Membership</ENAMEX>
      P. S. A tribute donation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX> makes a wonderful holiday gift.
      Simply complete the requested tribute information on the reply card and
      return it along with your check by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 6</TIMEX>. We will send an
      acknowledgement to you, as well as a holiday card to the special person
      on your shopping list.
      
    
  
