
  
  
    
      Date
      Dear Name:
      When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX> unveiled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corot to Picasso: European Masterworks</ENAMEX> from the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith College Museum of Art</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 13</TIMEX>, it was be due in part to your
      support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Campaign</ENAMEX>. Our special exhibition
      features a collection formed with an ambitious aim -to document the
      development of modem art. See <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corot to Picasso</ENAMEX> now through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 30</TIMEX>.
      When you support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Campaign</ENAMEX>, your contribution affects every
      area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> from grounds, building maintenance, and security
      to educational programs and touring exhibitions like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corot to Picasso</ENAMEX>.
      Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual</ENAMEX> Campaign contribution provides comprehensive support.
      In appreciation for your contribution <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> or more to the campaign,
      you and a guest are invited to attend a special reception on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>,
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23,2000</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30- 8:00 PM</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Herron Hall</ENAMEX>. Enjoy a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> and cheese
      reception following a docent-led tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Corot to Picasso</ENAMEX>.
      Please consider increasing your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual</ENAMEX> Campaign gift to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> and join
      us for a special <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 23rd</TIMEX> that recognizes your support of
      special exhibitions - mounted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX> for you and because of your
      support.
      If you have any questions or require further information about the
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Annual</TIMEX> Campaign, please call me at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">317.923.1331</NUMEX> extension <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">258</TIMEX>. Thank you
      for your generous support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Museum of Art</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Hardwick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development & Membership</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Join us as we recognize your support of special exhibition
      -presented at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX> for you and because of your support. Reservations
      are required. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RSVP</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 30, 2000</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">317.923.1331</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">extension 268</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
