
  
  
    
      Dear Mr. and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Name</ENAMEX>:
      Would it surprise you to learn that some important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like
      Rembrandt, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rodin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seurat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cezanne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Gogh</ENAMEX>, and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Keeffe</ENAMEX>, rely on your support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Operating Campaign</ENAMEX>?
      Your contribution helps to conserve and protect these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>' great
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">masterworks</ENAMEX>. And now, the permanent collection continues its reputation
      of national importance with recently acquired works from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samuel</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josefowitz</ENAMEX> collection, featuring the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gauguin</ENAMEX>
      (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1848-1904</TIMEX>).
      Enjoy the inaugural viewing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gauguin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The School of Pont</ENAMEX>-Aven:
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samuel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Josefowitz Collection</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1</TIMEX>. This important
      exhibition features <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> paintings and prints by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Gauguin</ENAMEX> and the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> who gathered around him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a century ago</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
      village of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pont-Aven</ENAMEX>. View this impressive collection, installed in its
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entirety</ENAMEX>.
      " <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">...Vibrant color</ENAMEX>, decorative patterns, and vivid images. The
      paintings of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pont-Aven</ENAMEX> offer a superb look at a fresh and powerful
      approach to painting" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Curator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Lee</ENAMEX>.
      The paintings and prints come from the renowned collection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Josefowitz</ENAMEX>, considered one of the world's foremost
      art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collectors</ENAMEX>. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of works establishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX> as the leading
      <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> featuring art of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pont-Aven School</ENAMEX>. Your support of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Operating</ENAMEX> Campaign helps to attract significant works
      to the collection and present <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX>-wide special exhibitions.
      Your gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Operating</ENAMEX> Campaign helps to offset costs
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with presenting art that educates and inspires all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of
      central <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. When you give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> or more, you will be invited to
      attend an exclusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gauguin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>'s Reception on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6</TIMEX> from
      <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 to 8 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bret Waller</ENAMEX>, welcomes you with refreshments
      followed by a special docent - led tour of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gauguin</ENAMEX> collection.
      I hope you will support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Operating Campaign</ENAMEX>.
      Through your generous gift you verify the importance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Art</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and to your life.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Hardwick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development & Membership</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PS</ENAMEX>: To attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gauguin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reception</ENAMEX>, your gift must
      be received no later than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4, 1999</TIMEX>.
      
    
  
