
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 5, 1998</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">{Formal Name}</ENAMEX> {address} {<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, state, zip }
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear {Greeting}</ENAMEX>,
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> growing up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 5O's</TIMEX>, one of my happiest memories was
      attending <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Theatre</ENAMEX> productions. I remember admiring the many talents
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who performed on stage. I was especially
      enamored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s productions. Here were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> my own age,
      demonstrating such great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>. I was in awe.
      Since that time, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> has grown in many ways. Many more arts
      and cultural opportunities exist in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, yet none finer than
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Theatre</ENAMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX> has maintained its uniqueness by staying
      true to its mission:
      .To provide a professional atmosphere for many talented community
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> to hone and perfect their skills.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">.To</ENAMEX> consistently produce outstanding live entertainment.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">.To</ENAMEX> offer a year-round, theatre-based educational program, hat gives
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of all ages an opportunity to explore their natural
      creativity.
      Conceived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85 years ago</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Little Theatre Society</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Civic Theatre</ENAMEX> introduced community theatre to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience members</ENAMEX>, production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>,
      costume and set constructors, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ushers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> contributed to and still
      support the continuous success of the theatre.
      Your contribution has been important to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Theatre</ENAMEX>, and I hope you
      will continue your support again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. For your convenience, a reply
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> and return envelope are enclosed.
      To assist you with your contribution, please feel free to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX>
      Dannels, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">924-6770 ext.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">207</NUMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Katie Mothershead Kruse Annual Campaign Chair</ENAMEX>
      P. S. Your gift is important to our celebration of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85 years</TIMEX> making the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Civic Theatre</ENAMEX> the oldest continuously operating community
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theatre</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
    
  
