
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1, 1995</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name,
      I am sure that you are aware of the uncertainty many arts
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> are currently facing in regard to future funding. As a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Board of Trustees</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Civic Theatre</ENAMEX>, I
      believe that the dilemma we're faced with is not how we can afford to
      continue our programming at its current level of excellence, but rather
      how we can rally the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> to support these efforts that only serve
      to enhance the cultural splendor of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and provide educational
      outlets for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Civic Theatre</ENAMEX> has entertained her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> with
      professionally-produced plays and musicals for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">82 years</TIMEX> while providing
      an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s exceptional talent, but that is certainly not the
      extent of it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Youth</ENAMEX>-oriented programs like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Junior Civic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kid Connection</ENAMEX>
      and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Young Adults Summer Musical</ENAMEX> provide unequaled educational
      opportunities to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> who may not otherwise have
      exposure to the performing arts. The impact of these programs on the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> involved is immeasurable.
      I've enclosed a brochure which explains in more detail the many worthy
      efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Civic Theatre</ENAMEX>, as well as a pledge card and
      return envelope in hope that you will join me in supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX>'s
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, I hope you'll agree with me in that your continued
      support of the arts is an investment in the cultural heritage of our city
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX> yours,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bubba Tarkington Trustee</ENAMEX>
      enclosures
    
  
