
  
  
    
      I have a place where dreams are born And time is never planned; It's
      not on any chart You must find it with your heart Never never land.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear,</ENAMEX>
      As I settle into my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> as artistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s most treasured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Theatre</ENAMEX> embarks on her
      82nd <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> with a heritage built on dreams. The title of "the oldest
      continuously-operating community theatre in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>" means that
      through prosperity and depression, war and peace, through the best and
      worst of times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX> has continued to produce quality, family
      entertainment for our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. Also, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1940</TIMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junior Civic</ENAMEX> has
      been instilling in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> an appreciation not just for the arts, but
      for the dreams of which theatre is made.
      I made my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> debut as a stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX> with
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inherit the Wind</ENAMEX>, a classic of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>, attended by more than
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,500</NUMEX> junior high and high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. My <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> production at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic</ENAMEX>
      wi11 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">be Peter Pan</ENAMEX>, a tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and we're expecting at least
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,000</NUMEX> such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> to attend. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Theatre</ENAMEX>
      believe that the future of the arts is in the hands of these little
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and we strive to insure the future of live theatre with programs
      like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holiday Family Production</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Matinee Series</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Adult Summer Musical</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Junior Civic</ENAMEX> programs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Kid Connection</ENAMEX>.
      I hope that the theatre is still as important to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> as it
      was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX> when a group of dreamers got together to begin the legacy
      that is now the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Booth Tarkington Civic Theatre</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>. I hope
      that dreams of flying and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pirates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX>-dust are still part of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">magic</ENAMEX> of childhood. And, I hope that you will support the artistic and
      educational efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Theatre</ENAMEX> again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
      Yours sincerely,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Sorbera Artistic Director</ENAMEX>
    
  
