
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> 5,1998
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">{Formal Name}</ENAMEX> {address} {<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, state, zip}
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear {Greeting}</ENAMEX>,
      In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>, several business and community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> met to form the first
      community theatre in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, which has matured into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Theatre</ENAMEX>. In their enlightened self-interest, they supported this
      fledgling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, knowing it would benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as a whole.
      Since that time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> has grown in many ways. We all enjoy the
      flavorful blend of arts, sports and cultural opportunities in central
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Theatre</ENAMEX> among the finest in its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Civic</ENAMEX> has
      maintained its legacy, staying true to its mission to:
      Consistently produce outstanding live entertainment.
      Provide a professional atmosphere for many talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community actors</ENAMEX>
      to hone and perfect their skills.
      Offer a year-round, theatre-based educational program that gives
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of all ages an opportunity to explore their natural
      creativity!
      Conceived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">85 years ago</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Little Theatre Society</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>, the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Civic Theatre</ENAMEX> introduced community theatre to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>.
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience members</ENAMEX>, production <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>,
      costume and set constructors, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ushers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> contributed to and still
      support the continuous success of the theatre.
      Your contribution has been important to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Theatre</ENAMEX>, and I hope you
      will continue in the tradition of enlightened self-interest with your
      support again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. For your convenience, a reply card and return
      envelope are enclosed.
      To assist you with your contribution, please feel free to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX>
      Dannels, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">924-6770 ext.</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">207</NUMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rollin M. Dick Corporate Campaign Chair</ENAMEX>
      Your gift is important to the celebration of our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">85th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>. The
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Civic Theatre</ENAMEX> is the oldest continuously operating community
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theatre</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
    
  
