
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear ,</ENAMEX>
      "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philanthropy</ENAMEX> is the rent we pay for the joy and privilege we have for
      our space on this earth." Jerold Panas
      I can only hope that you know how appreciative we at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>
      Zoo are of your philanthropy! Indeed, your history of support of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lowell Nussbaum Society</ENAMEX> pays much more than your "rent". It pays for the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX>, feeding, and housing of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> at the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zoo</ENAMEX>.
      Your support has made so many things possible! As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nussbaum</ENAMEX> member
      you have helped us save endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>--and their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. And you have
      helped us educate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> on the importance of caring for
      this earth--our home.
      Thank you for paying the rent!
      I hope you will renew your membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lowell Nussbaum</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX>
      and, indeed, increase your gift to increased amount <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. We need
      your continued faith, involvement, and support as we strive to make the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indianapolis Zoo</ENAMEX> a place where <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are connected.
      Connected to each other and to you!
      Thank you again.
      Most sincerely,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Gammage-Tucker</ENAMEX>, Ph.D. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institutional Advancement</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">enclosures MGT/ewc</ENAMEX>
    
  
