
  
  
    
      It's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>! Born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 6, 2000</TIMEX>, and weighing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">201 pounds</NUMEX>! In honor of
      our recent arrival become a proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Zoo</ENAMEX>'s newest
      <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Elephant</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Amali</ENAMEX>" which means hope. For <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX>, you will receive
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cuddly plush elephant</ENAMEX> (this one you get to keep at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">school</ENAMEX>), along with
      the following:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">+ Official Amigo</ENAMEX> certificate + <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photograph of the Kubwa</ENAMEX> & her baby
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> + Fact sheet about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephants</ENAMEX> + <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recognition</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Animal</ENAMEX> Amigo
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Board</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Waters Building</ENAMEX> + <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsletter &</ENAMEX> releases about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> +
      Elephant quiz
      Amigos make great gifts for those "hard-to-buy-for" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>! Send to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis Zoo</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1200</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">W. Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, IN <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46222</NUMEX> or call
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">317/630-2925</TIMEX> if you have any questions.
      
    
  
