
  
  
    
      May <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3, 2000</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear,</ENAMEX>
      "Until he extends the circle of his compassion to all living things,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> will not himself peace." --<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Schweitzer</ENAMEX>
      In looking back at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last decade</TIMEX>, we at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> Zoological
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> (IZS) wish to express our sincere thanks to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> who
      have helped us to achieve so many successes at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Zoo</ENAMEX> and
      White <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River Gardens</ENAMEX>. As we enter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a new century</TIMEX> we hope that you too will
      wish to become a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>.
      There are many ways to become involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indianapolis Zoo</ENAMEX> and
      White <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River Gardens</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Corporations</ENAMEX> are involved in a number of projects
      that make a huge impact on our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>, including program
      underwriting, marketing sponsorships, inkind donations, volunteer
      activities, etc. We strive to create good matches for our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>
      -projects that fit your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> goals, themes and interests.
      Enclosed in this packet you will find recent information on our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> and some of the exciting things that are happening here. I hope
      that you agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Zoological Society</ENAMEX> enhances this
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX> and provides a safe and happy environment for those who live
      and work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      The mission of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indianapolis Zoological Society</ENAMEX> is to provide
      recreational learning experiences for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> through the
      exhibition and presentation of natural environments in a way to foster a
      sense of discovery, stewardship, and the need to preserve the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. In short, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> is about connecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX> formed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> are made
      possible through the support of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> operations by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> like
      yours!
      As one of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only a few zoos</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that receives no local,
      state, or federal tax support <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IZS</ENAMEX> must depend on donations for general
      operating funds from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> like yours that are committed to the
      extension of compassion toward all living things.
      The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporate Campaign</ENAMEX> will help to insure that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IZS</ENAMEX> continues to
      provide all the excellent programming, activities and exhibits that
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> have come to expect from our world-renowned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. I hope
      that you will consider renewing your commitment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Enclosed you
      will find a brochure that highlights the many exciting benefits that you
      can receive as a corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>. Please feel free to use the return
      envelope to mail your pledge card or gift right away.
      You can help plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> for a bright future. We have so many more
      accomplishments to strive for, I cannot imagine a better corporate
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> to help bring them about.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly S. Luppino</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporate Relations</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enclosures</ENAMEX>
    
  
