
  
  
    
      Date
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, Zip
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Salutation</ENAMEX>:
      As a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> who also donate), we truly
      appreciate your support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. We need your help more than
      ever to support our thrilling productions. To maintain our financial
      stability, we must raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$365,000</NUMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> like you! Why?
      Because our commitment to professional quality productions and strong
      educational outreach across the state requires strong community support.
      Although inflation is low, our productions are very labor intensive and
      most exceed the rate of inflation. We've kept ticket prices very
      affordable and, in fact, provide amazing student ticket discounts. If we
      keep our prices low, we need to come to you, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience members</ENAMEX>, to ask
      for a small contribution in order to help us meet this mission.
      It's just a play, right? Why so expensive? Here are just a few
      examples:
      -We use professional, career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, who belong to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> called
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Actors Equity</ENAMEX>. Unlike other not-for-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theatres</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> make their living from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>. We find these outstanding
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and right here at
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. This means not only salary, and benefits, but also housing and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transportation</ENAMEX> are primary expenses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One week</TIMEX>'s salary and
      expenses for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> Equity <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,100</NUMEX> (including rehearsals).
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">-The IRT</ENAMEX> is the only professional not-for-profit resident theatre in
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. This means our commitment to quality is shown <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">backstage</ENAMEX>, as
      nationally known professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> create the exciting
      theatre you enjoy. Elaborate costumes and sets are an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> trademark. The
      quality of our sets and costumes differ from other theatres in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>,
      too. To costume the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Pygmalion</ENAMEX>, a national search for the right
      fabric for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Higgins</ENAMEX>' suits took place and was finally found in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>. The materials for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pygmalion</ENAMEX> costumes will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13,000</NUMEX>! We
      don't just go to the nearest fabric <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and try to find the closest
      thing to what we want. Our artistic standards dictate that we look until
      we get it right.
      -Deeply discounting student matinee tickets for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to see a play
      - <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as low as $8.25</NUMEX> vs. a full-priced ticket of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17.50-$35</NUMEX> for an adult
      evening performance vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48-$65</NUMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> touring production. These
      matinees are coordinated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and unite a play with studies of
      classroom lessons in history, social studies, cultural diversity and
      literature for a full educational experience.
      You may have heard about our <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX> lobby restoration that will
      thrill you when you walk through the doors. What you may not know is that
      the money for that restoration came from a capital and endowment
      fund-separate from the money needed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX> to produce our plays and
      education programs. Your gift would go directly to the artistic product
      on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> and our nationally recognized education program which last year
      reached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 49,900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX>. This
      outreach is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10%</NUMEX> increase from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and it means our efforts are
      working.
      To continue to make it work we need YOU. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, you generously
      donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$-</NUMEX>. Please consider renewing that gift or increasing that gift by
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Help us continue to serve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s youth
      through the extraordinary experience of theatre <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> providing
      professional theatre handcrafted for our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. Thank you!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Allen Artistic Director</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> .<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. Please</ENAMEX> give <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to continue enjoying fully professional live
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theatre</ENAMEX> experiences!
    
  
