
  
  
    
      I'm In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> again for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few months</TIMEX> directing A
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Carol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candida</ENAMEX>, the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main-stage shows at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my
      favorite theatres, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>. As an associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> of the the theatre,
      it's my privilege to be aware of the great thing happening at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> and
      to encourage you to give generously to see the success continue. You need
      to know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> is talked about very favorably among theatre artists
      around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indianapolis</ENAMEX> is truly one of the best places for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> to work for many reasons:
      - the artistic quality is top rate - the education programs lead the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> (other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theatres</ENAMEX> wish they could reach even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45,000</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> does) - the treatment we receive here is the friendliest
      and most accommodating - the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> really listen and respond
      For those of us who travel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, these things are
      just as important as salary considerations when taking an acting job.
      I've been affiliated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 years</TIMEX>. I started my directing
      career here. This place is a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for me and I feel lucky to have
      it. "Hoosier hospitality" is everything they say - that's why so many
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> fall in love with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> and keep returning. They make visiting
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> happy with things such as emergency babysitting, transportation,
      and dinners in staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. They help us find fitness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>,
      yoga classes and chiropractors, they take care of our mail and packages
      for us. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> and its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">volunteers</ENAMEX> go out of their way to
      make us feel like we're special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> during our stay.
      I also know it costs a lot of money to run a theatre <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. I ask
      you to please give <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> and help them continue the marvelous
      work they have been producing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">26 years</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happy Holidays</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Wentworth</ENAMEX>
    
  
