
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 9, 2000</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
      Dear:
      As a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>, you may know that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> has enjoyed a strong
      start to our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>-and we thank you for your interest and support. We
      depend on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> like you to help us bring outstanding productions to
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX>. We just finished producing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Christmas Carol</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the fourth</TIMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">consecutive year</TIMEX>, enabling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> the
      opportunity to celebrate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holidays</TIMEX> together. It is your support and
      our commitment to low prices for youth (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5-$14</NUMEX>) that makes that possible.
      In total, because of the gifts given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, we were able to discount
      tickets for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 11,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who would ordinarily not be able to
      enjoy the wonders of live theatre. And - do our productions impact
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>?
      .By reaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> whom are not otherwise being reached through
      school and other community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>. It is a proven fact that the
      arts contribute to higher scores on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> and other standardized
      tests.
      .By transforming the environment for learning; school lessons become
      opportunities of discovery when performed live on stage.
      .By providing new challenges for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> already considered
      successful and helping them surpass boredom and complacency, which are
      barriers to success.
      So far, we've been very successful in our service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>,
      but we need your financial support right now to complete the season with
      the same gusto. Your last gift was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$</NUMEX> . We hope you'll help us with more
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Every dollar that you contribute makes a big difference.
      It's thrilling to have such a strong impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. It's now
      your opportunity to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in our work. We have been selected again
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to participate in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> special challenge matches: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>), who will match every contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar up to $33,000</NUMEX> and one
      with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly Endowment</ENAMEX>, who will match up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70,000</NUMEX> of new or
      increased gifts. This is free money that only you can help the IRT
      obtain. Your gift will assure us of receiving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $100,000</NUMEX> of grant
      money.
      You have heard from us twice by mail <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX> requesting your
      support. This letter is to let you know that we still need your help to
      continue our record of strong fiscal management, vibrant theatrical
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">productions</ENAMEX> and outstanding educational programs. We have a long way to
      go before we reach our goal of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$365,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> such
      as yourself. Your gift, and the doubling of these dollars through the two
      challenge matches, will help us reach this goal.
      Ticket sales and subscriptions cannot finance our complete <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>; in
      fact they only count for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53%</NUMEX> of our income. Soon, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> will be calling you to take your pledge over the phone. We hope you
      will enjoy talking to them, but you can save the IRT administrative money
      by sending your gift in the return envelope <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Either way, it's
      important that we hear from you during this last fundraising drive of
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999-2000 season</TIMEX>. Please consider sending your donation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Thank
      you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Payne</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Managing Director</ENAMEX> P.S. Your contributed support directly
      benefits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>'s outreach programs and leverages match gift monies.
      Please give generously.
    
  
