
  
  
    
      Date
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name:
      "But I am sure I have always thought of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas time</TIMEX>, when it has
      come round... as a good time: a kind, forgiving, charitable, pleasant
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>: the only time I know of in the long calendar of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>, when men
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> seem by one consent to open their shut-up hearts freely."
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-A Christmas Carol</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Dickens</ENAMEX>
      As <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoosiers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midwest region</ENAMEX> enjoy
      the timeless classic of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Christmas Carol</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>, we give thanks for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> like you, who value the experience of live professional theatre
      and understand the need to support it with both attendance and
      donations.
      As a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>/current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX>/current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX>, you
      know it takes a good deal of money to bring these stories to you. We
      recoup <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58%</NUMEX> of that money on ticket sales, leaving <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32%</NUMEX> to be garnered from
      donations and gifts from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> such as yourself.
      As <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the calendar year</TIMEX> and the deadline for tax-deductible
      gifts approaches, I hope you will think of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> and make a donation
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> . Every dollar counts and every gift is deeply appreciated. We
      need your help right now to continue to:
      -impact <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>' lives and help our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> through our
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>.)
      -conceive, design and hand-sew the many beautiful costumes, such as
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Todd</ENAMEX>'s period dresses in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Lincoln</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> and the ball gowns
      in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Christmas Carol</ENAMEX>.
      -hire the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> from across the nation
      and here at home.
      -design the beautiful sets and have our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carpenters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> craft
      the final result.
      -continue to tell meaningful stories that bring our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> together
      to laugh and learn from each other.
      It is truly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> to give. After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scrooge</ENAMEX> has been visited by the
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spirits</ENAMEX>, " ...it was always said of him that he knew how to keep
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> well, if any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> alive possessed the knowledge. May that be
      truly said of us, and all of us!"
      Please give now so we can go on giving back to you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>. Thank you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Allen Artistic Director</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> .S. Please consider a gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 31</TIMEX> to receive
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> tax deductibility for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Happy Holidays</ENAMEX>!
    
  
