
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1996</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>,
      For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years</TIMEX> I have had the tremendous opportunity to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> at
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indiana Repertory Theatre</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the joys of being an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> is
      having an opportunity to talk with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> following a
      performance.
      One such event occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX>.
      Following a show, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> came up to the stage to say hello.
      They said they both felt they knew me like an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> because they'd
      been coming to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> shows since their high school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. In fact, even
      though they had gone to separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, each one's first experience
      with live theatre was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> production.
      I was delighted at their vivid recollections of some of my favorite
      shows at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midsummer Night's Dream and You Can't Take It With You</ENAMEX>.
      They said that because of those high school trips to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>, they have
      made professional theatre an integral part of their cultural lives.
      So many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have told me that seeing a play as a student literally
      opened their eves and minds to a whole new world; a world of imagination
      more powerful than any futuristic movie or television sit-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">com</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>,
      they crave that potent mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, which is
      the magic of live theatre.
      It's that magic I am asking you to keep alive and well for all
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
      Fully professional, fully produced theatre has made a difference to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Emily</ENAMEX>, and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmates</ENAMEX> from
      across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. I've enclosed letters they, and some of
      their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, have written us. Please read them. They touched my heart
      and I know they'll touch yours.
      The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing I am most proud of is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> across
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in providing theatre experiences for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The work the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> does with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> has a profound impact on their lives.
      Most important is the fact that attending a performance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> is not
      just a field trip. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> has staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, and a statewide
      Student/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teacher Advisory Committee</ENAMEX> that carefully plan all the education
      programs. The plays which are performed are selected because they have a
      specific link to what is being studied in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX>. Whether its a
      literature topic, a humanities issue, or an important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in history
      -- every play has a direct tie-in to classroom curriculum.
      The education programs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> are more comprehensive than any
      other performing arts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and possibly
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
      A full array of educational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> are incorporated to enhance the
      learning experience for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, including:
      -Printed study guides and detailed audio/visual materials,
      -<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Docent</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> pre-performance classroom visits,
      -Behind-the-scenes tours of the theatre's workshops and rehearsal
      <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>,
      -An extensive slide show <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> on a variety of theatre topics,
      -Pre-performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> workshops, and
      -Direct contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> through post-performance
      question and answer sessions.
      I am writing to ask for your direct assistance in educating a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>.
      With a donation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX> or whatever you can give to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>,
      you can play a role in the development of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> through the
      educational outreach programs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indiana Repertory Theatre</ENAMEX>. Each
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 45,000 and 50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 800</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana counties</ENAMEX> culminate their lessons on a variety of topics by coming
      to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> to see a play.
      Because we're committed to provide these education services, donations
      must be sought to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>set ticket discounts we give to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. Ticket
      income doesn't begin to cover the cost of these programs. We need your
      assistance; as your generosity allows us to keep these programs
      affordable to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. You can help directly:
      -A gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> allows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to receive discounted tickets to an
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">IRT</ENAMEX> performance.
      -A gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> provides an entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> with study guides and
      other curriculum materials.
      Take a moment right now to consider a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX>, or
      whatever you can give, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>. It means everything to me to ask for
      your support. It means everything to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX>,
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> like them. You can make the difference <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TODAY</ENAMEX>!
      I look forward to hearing from you!
      Best <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wishes</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Priscilla Lindsay Actor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Educator Indiana Repertory Theatre</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> .S. From the bottom of my heart, thank you! You can make the
      difference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with your check. Theatre allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to experience
      worlds outside their own and to see their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> studies come to life.
      To continue to impact the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theatre</ENAMEX> productions that support and enhance their academic and personal
      growth, your support is needed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">TODAY</ENAMEX>!
    
  
