
  
  
    
      Dear:
      Every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> case in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> that affects him
      personally. This one's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX>, I guess. You might hear some ugly talk this
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. But do one thing for me if you will: keep your head high and your
      fists down. No matter what anyone says to you, don't let'em get your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">goat</ENAMEX>. Try fighting with your head for a change, it's a good one.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atticus Finch</ENAMEX>, To Kill a Mockingbird
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atticus Finch</ENAMEX>'s speech to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Kill a Mockingbird</ENAMEX>, the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> season opener, is one that you may remember. Perhaps you can hear
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Peck</ENAMEX>'s voice saying it now. Because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>'s educational
      program, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will see the show and learn the simple
      lessons of this classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> story:
      use your head
      learn to walk in someone else's shoes
      bad things will happen--how will you react to them?
      be of solid moral character
      The lessons of old are still the lessons we're trying to teach our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. And that's the wonderful tool of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT Education</ENAMEX>
      Programs--it lets <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children witness</ENAMEX> stories that teach them tools for
      everyday living and surviving. We also emphasize plays that directly
      relate to history, literature and social study topics. We are proud to
      continue to be a part of the educational "system of so many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, but we need your help right now to continue to provide this
      most important service. Did you know:
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">63</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> will be visiting the IRT this
      year
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> attending our shows prepare in advance for their
      theatrical experience through their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>'s curriculum
      New educational programs have been created <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">schoolchildren</ENAMEX> who are unable to attend a production. We'll bring the IRT
      to them through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> and two-way video
      conferencing
      Our artistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Priscilla Lindsay</ENAMEX> and new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate</ENAMEX>
      Artistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Risa Brainin</ENAMEX>, is developing a new theatre education
      curriculum for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next season</TIMEX>, with classes for youth and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> to be
      implemented in the near future
      <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">39%</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> performance schedule is dedicated to student
      performances
      As you can see, our educational program has been growing and will
      continue to increase in the upcoming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. These programs take resources
      that only you can provide. I know you've purchased tickets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and
      I thank you. But ticket sales only account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51%</NUMEX> of our <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.785 million</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">budget</ENAMEX>. We must raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.89 million</NUMEX> from other sources, including
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$327,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> such as yourself. To help us reach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>, please consider a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> or more. You can make
      the difference--please respond with the enclosed pledge card and return
      envelope.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Allen Artistic Director</ENAMEX>
    
  
