
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 9, 1997</TIMEX>
      Dear:
      Our season continues to amaze. After record-breaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">To</ENAMEX>
      Kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mockingbird</ENAMEX>, and opening our newly renovated <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Upperstage</ENAMEX> theatre
      with the critically-acclaimed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Sweeney</ENAMEX>, we just finished the run of
      A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Christmas Carol</ENAMEX>, which was seen by a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over 24,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
      including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 9,000</NUMEX> school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>.
      Others continue to notice our success. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> has awarded us very generously for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second year</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX>, with a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grant</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $42,000</NUMEX>. This money is earmarked for our education
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Discovery Series</ENAMEX>, which is dedicated to our curriculum-based
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">productions</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>.
      It's thrilling to be having such an impact on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. It's now
      your opportunity to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in our work. We have been selected to
      participate in two challenge matches: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>, who will match
      every contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollar up to $50,000</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lilly Endowment</ENAMEX>
      who will match up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70,000</NUMEX> of new or increased gifts. This is free
      money that only you can help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> obtain.
      You have heard from us twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time was to tell you
      about the impact of our educational program and, more specifically, To
      Kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mockingbird</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> appeal was to let you know about some of
      our artistic expenses you may not normally consider, such as the cost of
      hiring professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>!) This letter is to
      let you know that, while we've experienced some success <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>, we
      still need your help to continue our record of strong fiscal management
      and vibrant theatrical productions. We still have <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $200,000</NUMEX> left
      to raise from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> such as yourself. Your gift, and the
      doubling of these dollars through the two challenge matches will help us
      reach this goal.
      Very soon, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> will be calling you to take your pledge
      over the phone. We hope you will enjoy talking to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>, but
      if you wish to give immediately, please send your gift in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by using
      the enclosed envelope and pledge card. You also help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> save money
      by returning your gift in the mail. It's important that we hear from you
      during this last fundraising drive of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>. Please consider sending
      your donation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Thank you.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Payne Managing Director</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> .S. If you wish to not be contacted on the telephone and want to
      help us save money, be sure to send in your gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>!
    
  
