
  
  
    
      Date
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, Zip
      Dear:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX> is a mirror of society. Through the action on the stage, we
      are able to see -really see -ourselves reflected; how we think, how we
      emotionally react. Our failings, shortcomings and hesitations, are on
      display, as are the remarkability of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> and energy. The IRT takes
      advantage of the "mirror" concept to let <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> take a look at
      themselves. With your involvement, we can help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> - like the little boy
      pictured on this page-become better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>.
      On our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stage</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early November</TIMEX>, we are producing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>. If you haven't yet seen the show, let me tell you
      that it is a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Lincoln</ENAMEX> than you have ever seen. This shows a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">young Lincoln</ENAMEX> before his status as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> legend. This demonstrates
      a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who is fighting with all of his might to make honorable decisions,
      face down personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX> and accept a mantle of responsibility he really
      doesn't want to assume-the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidency</ENAMEX>. In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> is
      portrayed as a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human being</ENAMEX> - mirroring all of us that would find
      ourselves in his shoes.
      Over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will see this play through our
      student-matinee program. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>'s education program is one of the
      strongest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>-a fact that has been validated and proven by the
      support given to us by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment of the Arts</ENAMEX>. In addition to
      the matinees, the education program provides tours, playguides for the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to use with their curriculum, and technical and artistic
      discussions. Outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> go directly into the
      classroom to work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and introduce them more personally to the
      world of theatre. Our distance-learning project can bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> together
      from coast to coast to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> thanks to
      fiber-optic technology.
      Now back to the mirror of society. Imagine if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> can see him or
      herself in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s shoes, facing the same kind of doubts, fears and
      self-criticisms that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe</ENAMEX> saw in himself prior to his presidency.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mirroring Abe</ENAMEX>'s actions and seeing the results, he or she can become that
      much more confident, that much more able to face a difficult world and
      that much more willing to face personal responsibility. Maybe this little
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> on our stationary will see himself as the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abe Lincoln</ENAMEX>. Live
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theatre</ENAMEX> is an amazing character-builder disguised as entertainment.
      You can help be a part of this magic. We need your help and
      participation in our acclaimed education program. Please use the enclosed
      pledge card and return envelope to become part of the mirror that IRT
      provides. You can help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> see and imagine amazing things for
      themselves. Please send a gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and become a partner
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Payne Managing Director</ENAMEX>
      P.S. Please send in your gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and help us reach <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousands of</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
    
  
