
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 5, 1996</TIMEX>
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State ZIP</ENAMEX>
      Dear Name,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Happy Holidays</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indiana Repertory Theatre</ENAMEX>!
      This is a wonderful time of year for storytelling. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX>, of
      course, is the transformation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scrooge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Christmas Carol</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> knows something about telling stories - we're in that business.
      It is our distinct pleasure to bring to life tales to make you laugh,
      experience unfamiliar situations, or warm your heart. Hopefully, you
      leave our theatre entertained, with a new perspective on life.
      We are proud to serve this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> as the best storytellers
      around!
      I have enclosed a story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> and encourage you to read it and
      see what we do to put a high quality production on the stage. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Hours</TIMEX> of
      dedicated artistry go with each of fabric and every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2x4</NUMEX> to make the story
      you see the best possible all-encompassing sensory experience.
      To continue to tell our stories, we ask for your help and support.
      Buying tickets enables us to cover <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62 percent</NUMEX> of our costs. We rely on
      you and other generous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> to provide <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">the remaining 38 percent</NUMEX>. We
      need contributed support to bring the best professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> here, to
      maintain our reputation for beautiful sets and costumes, and to subsidize
      our education program which reaches <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> each year .
      I thank you for your last gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$-</NUMEX>. I hope you will remain a
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contributor</ENAMEX> and even consider honoring our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> of storytelling by
      increasing your gift <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Your gift will directly fund our
      artistic and education programs -- tangible examples are outlined in the
      enclosed brochure.
      Please send your gift in the enclosed envelope with the response card
      attached to the brochure. Your generosity will help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> continue to
      tell the best stories in the finest manner possible. Thank you!
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Payne Managing Director</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P</ENAMEX> .S. Please support our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25th Anniversary</TIMEX> by making a gift to the IRT
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>!
    
  
