
  
  
    
      Date
      Name Address <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City ST Zip</ENAMEX>
      Dear:
      My love affair with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> is a long one. I joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> with my first show, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey</ENAMEX>" and I can't believe it, but I
      just completed my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">45th</ENAMEX> production at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indiana Repertory Theatre</ENAMEX> in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pygmalion</ENAMEX>. I am very proud of my association with such a dynamic regional
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theatre</ENAMEX>. Our growth has not stopped. And it's all due to you.
      Now, as an associate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> with the theatre, I see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> the impact
      that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> has on our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. We employ more professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>
      from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, ones whom we have helped train, than ever in our
      history. We now have grown to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5,154</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>'s
      <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>. But what I'm proudest of, is that our education program has
      become a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> among fully professional not-for-profit regional
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theatres</ENAMEX>. You are responsible for helping us introduce the amazing,
      magical experience of live theatre to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>-programs that
      are not only an arts experience, but help teach history, literature, and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> studies. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, you could buy an individual ticket anywhere from
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4-$5</NUMEX>, and a subscription for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16</NUMEX>! Ticket prices have risen, but they
      still only account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53%</NUMEX> of our budget. And, of that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53%</NUMEX>, education
      program ticket revenue is a mere fraction of that, so our contributions
      from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX>, foundations and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> - like you - enable us to
      continue these critically needed services. I am writing to ask for your
      direct assistance in our education programs and artistic product.
      What began as a touring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> that played to
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elkhart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terre Haute</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> education
      program <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> now provides:
      -<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Classroom</ENAMEX> programs where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community artists</ENAMEX> teach
      creative dramatics and theatre to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who can't attend the IRT
      because of location or, unfortunately, because of finances.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-The Discovery Series</ENAMEX>, which produces theatre for youth, began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>
      where around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> see a live production.
      -Discounted student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">matinee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mainstage</ENAMEX> performances, where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pygmalion</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11 ,400</NUMEX> are scheduled to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Christmas</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carol</ENAMEX>. What a delight it is for us to introduce the magic of live theatre
      to such eager faces <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">each morning</TIMEX>!
      In all, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 50,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> are
      reached by an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> education program <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> and what's more, every play
      has a direct tie-in to classroom curriculum. As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>, my primary
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">joy</ENAMEX> is the communication that occurs between an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>.
      Now, I'm communicating to you as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donor</ENAMEX> who loves the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX>. You wouldn't have been able to experience the joys of plays I have
      been in (and those I haven't) without donations other than ticket
      purchases. Your last gift to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRT</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$-</NUMEX>. As you consider your
      charitable aiding as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> ends, I ask you to consider increasing that
      gift by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> or more. Every dollar counts. I look forward to hearing from
      you and seeing you at the theatre!
      Best wishes,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Priscilla Lindsay Associate Artist</ENAMEX>
    
  
