
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Birthplace Foundation</ENAMEX>, Inc. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.O. Box 1925 • Hope,</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Arkansas 71801 • Phone: 870-777-4455 • FAX 870-722-6929</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birthplace</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">42nd</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> The wood frame <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and</TIMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">one-half</ENAMEX> story <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American Foursquare</ENAMEX> design built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>, but has not been
      owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 30 years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is now owned
      by the non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>. For his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
      lived with his maternal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eldridge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Grisham Cassidy</ENAMEX>,
      at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">117</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Hervey</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX>. It was in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> spent his
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">formative years</TIMEX>, learning to walk, talk, laugh, play, read, and pray.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Oval Office</ENAMEX> carpet was designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaki Hockersmith</ENAMEX> and
      woven by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Scott Group</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> felt strongly that the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">redecorated Oval Office</ENAMEX> should reflect the cultural strength and
      diversity of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. The deep blue rug is emblazoned with a
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX>-color <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential Seal</ENAMEX> encircled by fifty white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. The American
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eagle</ENAMEX> holds an olive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX>, signifying peace, in its right hand. A
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golden</ENAMEX>, double rope <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>, signifying domestic and international unity,
      frames the seal and the border of the rug. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurel</ENAMEX> wreaths, symbolizing
      victory, and olive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branches</ENAMEX> symbolizing peace, also adorn the rug's
      border along with acanthus leaves. The thirteen yarn colors of the
      magnificent rug symbolize the original thirteen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> of this
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>.
      Items include: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coffee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mugs - T-Shirts - Puzzles Caps - Cookbooks</ENAMEX> -
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Posters - Cards</ENAMEX> For more information about these and other items, you may
      write call, or send us an e-mail. We welcome your correspondence.
      Admission Rates: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adults - $5.00 Sr. Citizens</ENAMEX> - <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.00</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">18yr</ENAMEX>. - <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6yr</NUMEX> -
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.00</NUMEX> Under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX> yr - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Tour</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military Rate</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.00</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Spring/</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer Hours</ENAMEX>:
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:00 p.m. - 5:00 p.m. Tues - Sat: 10:00 a.m. - 4:30 p.m.</TIMEX> (Closed
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mondays</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fall/Winter Hours: Tues - Sat</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:00 a.m. - 4:30 p.m.</TIMEX> (closed
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX>)
      Steps to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Future Brick Project</ENAMEX> You may purchase a brick to be
      placed around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Virginia Clinton Kelley Memorial Garden</ENAMEX>. You may have
      bricks as memorials, for celebrations of birthdays, to acknowledge
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or just because you want to. Your contribution is tax-deductible.
      To receive a copy of the brick form, you may call, fax, e-mail or simply
      send in your <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25.00</NUMEX> per brick. Include the names to be honored.
      (Remember:<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">One Name Per Brick and No More Than 18 Spaces</ENAMEX>.) Your generous
      support is sincerely appreciated.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Birthplace Foundation</ENAMEX> is a non-political 501 (c) (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>)
      non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> dependent on your contributions. Contributions
      may be sent to:
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Birthplace Foundation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.O. Box 1925</ENAMEX> Hope, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> 71802
    
  
