
  
  
    
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Birthplace Foundation</ENAMEX> offers full membership privileges to
      those who pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $10.00</NUMEX> per year. This enables you to become a member
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>. If you choose to go this route, you will receive a
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> newsletter, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> pass to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">birthplace</ENAMEX>, and
      notification of upcoming events. I encourage you to do this, because the
      <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10.00</NUMEX> is considered a tax deduction, and you will get so much in return.
      This also means that you will be invited when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> returns
      for any event. You may send a check payable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Birthplace</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX>.
      Thank you,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beckie Moore</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birthplace Foundation</ENAMEX>
    
  
