
  
  
    
      May <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,2000</NUMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear ,</ENAMEX>
      Thank you for your interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute for Global Ethics</ENAMEX>.
      Membership includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insights</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Global Ethics</ENAMEX>, our semi-annual
      publication providing in-depth coverage of ethical topics and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Institute</ENAMEX>
      programs; periodic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s Letters from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rushworth Kidder</ENAMEX> to keep you
      in touch with vital and cutting edge ethical issues; and our newest
      publication, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethical Connections</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> newsletter providing
      highlights of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>'s programs and activities. You will also be
      entitled to special discounts on books, audiotapes, and videotapes from
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> and a reduced rate to participate in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethical Fitness</ENAMEX> TM
      Seminars.
      I have enclosed information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX> and copies of the
      latest issues of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Insights on Global Ethics and Ethical Connections</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Hensler Membership Coordinator</ENAMEX>
    
  
