
  
  
    
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaua</ENAMEX>`<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">i International Theatre The KIT</ENAMEX> e-news
      "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Irresistible</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Delicious</ENAMEX>, adorable, finger-snapping laugh-out-loud
      fun!" Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> Don't miss the glorious musical "FOREVER
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">PLAID"</ENAMEX>!
      
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOREVER PLAID</ENAMEX> is dedicated to the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>: · To the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who
      wheeled the projector <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX> for the audio-visual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>. · To the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
      who carried <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an extra</NUMEX> white handkerchief in the back pocket of their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chinos</ENAMEX>. · To the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who saved their allowances to give their
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> an extra special <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for their anniversary. ·
      To the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who sang around the piano in the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> just for the
      love of it. · To the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who never went beyond <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> base (and if
      by some miracle they did, they didn't tell anyone).
      We salute you!
      Once upon a time, there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sparky, Smudge, Jinx</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankie</ENAMEX>) who loved to sing. They all met in high school, when they joined
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audio Visual Club</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>). Discovering that they shared an affection
      for music and entertaining, they got together and dreamed of becoming
      like their idols - The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Four Aces</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Four Lads, The Four Freshmen, The</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hi-Lo's</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">The Crew Cuts</ENAMEX>. They rehearsed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smudge</ENAMEX>'s
      family's plumbing supply <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. It was here they became
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOREVER PLAID</ENAMEX> - a name that connotes the continuation of traditional
      values, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, home and harmony.
      Although <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock 'n' Roll</ENAMEX> was racing down the fast lane like a candy
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">apple</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">VETTE", FOREVER PLAID</ENAMEX> believed in their music. As their sound
      developed, they sang at family gatherings, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund raisers</ENAMEX> and eventually
      graduated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">supermarket</ENAMEX> openings and proms. Then, finally, they landed
      their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> big gig at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Airport Hilton Cocktail Bar - The FUSEL-LOUNGE</ENAMEX>
      (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 9, 1964</TIMEX>).
      En route to pick up their custom-made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plaid Tuxedoes</ENAMEX>, they were
      slammed broadside by a school bus filled with eager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>
      were on their way to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX> make their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> television debut
      on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Sullivan Show</ENAMEX> and, miraculously, escaped uninjured. However,
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Forever Plaid</ENAMEX> were killed instantly. It is at that moment
      when their careers and lives ended that the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOREVER PLAID</ENAMEX>
      begins.
      Continued...
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plaids</ENAMEX> cover a wide range of popular music from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>. Here is
      just a sample: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">v Catch a Falling Star v Chain Gang v Cry v Heart and Soul</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">v Love</ENAMEX> is a Many <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Splendored Thing v Moments to Remember v No Not Much v</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rags to Riches v Sixteen Tons v Three Coins in the Fountain</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOREVER PLAID</ENAMEX> has performed for many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> with their
      corporate awards, anniversaries and holiday celebrations such as; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIGNA</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dupont Company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IGA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson & Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kraft</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI Telecommunications</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M&M/Mars Corporation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nissan Motor</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporation</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsico</ENAMEX> and more.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KIT</ENAMEX>'s production of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">FOREVER PLAID</ENAMEX> directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven D. Kline</ENAMEX>,
      stage managed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Bolosan Campo</ENAMEX>, set design, construction, lighting
      design and technical support by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derron Peterson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technical</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>.
      Costume by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brigitte Doth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jade Stice</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny Laimana</ENAMEX>. Music by
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> (piano) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Odo</ENAMEX> (bass).
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plaids</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis McGran</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sparky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob Meyers / Mitch Ouye</ENAMEX> as
      Smudge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay Hansen / Joshua J. Bennett</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jinx</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Chaffee</ENAMEX> as
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankie</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOREVER PLAID</ENAMEX> will open on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25th</TIMEX>. Shows are Thursdays
      thru <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30pm</TIMEX>.
      Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23</NUMEX>. for advance & <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>. at door, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$59</NUMEX>. for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dinner & Show</ENAMEX> package (dinner at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Pacific Café</ENAMEX>), and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$99</NUMEX>. for
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flex Tic</ENAMEX> (Good for any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> shows or bring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> / <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> to one
      show, value <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$121.50</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KIT</ENAMEX> is offering a Special <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> OFF <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Opening Night</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ticket Price</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12.50</NUMEX>) for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25th</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 26th</TIMEX>.
      
    
  
