
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Keepers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lore</ENAMEX> <story@tellink.net>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Sunday, June 18th</TIMEX>, the rain came and severely curtailed
      attendance at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Keepers</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lore/Joseph Campbell Festival of</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Folklore and Story</ENAMEX>. Suddenly, our non-profit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> has been
      confronted with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> deficit, with no other financial resources to
      draw upon. Without financial assistance, some of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX> may not be paid. And everyone will have to take far less than
      we agreed upon. This situation could also impact our ability to mount
      another festival <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
      That's why I'm turning to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> like you for help. You already
      understand the importance of storytelling, poetry, song, and theatre in
      fostering empathy, compassion, and the imagination. And you probably also
      have a keen appreciation for the role of the oral tradition in bringing
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> together from diverse cultures, nationalities and
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religions</ENAMEX>--bridging the gap between our differences and helping to foster
      peace instead of conflict and misunderstanding. This is what it means to
      keep the wisdom-lore alive, and right now we need your help to do it!
      A donation of any amount would be deeply appreciated. Or perhaps you
      know of someone else who shares these same values who might be willing to
      help. Please, if you can, send your tax-deductible donation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Keepers</ENAMEX> of
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">P.O. Box 453</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milford, NH</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">03055</NUMEX>. If you would like to speak
      with me directly with any questions or suggestions, please call
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">603-654-5944</ENAMEX>, or send an email to story@tellink.net. If you would like to
      introduce our work to anyone who might be interested in helping us during
      this financial crisis, I am readily available to speak with him or her by
      phone or in person. Please give me a call so that we can discuss.
      Help us keep the wisdom-lore alive. Your gift of any amount will be
      greatly appreciated. I hope to hear from you soon.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Nelson</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> KEEPERS OF THE <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LORE</ENAMEX>
    
  
