
  
  
    
      Very <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev. Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Gabriel Karambis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1999</TIMEX>
      Dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>,
      A gift-wrapped box under a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> ...
      Ordinarily this is such a happy sight - an image of the anticipation
      that we feel inside as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday season</TIMEX> approaches once again.
      But in certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Christmas</TIMEX>, the sight of unopened gifts under
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> will bring tears of grief and sorrow. For these boxes will
      remain in their wrappings long after all of the other presents are
      opened. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> will come and go, and these gifts will sit untouched.
      The boxes will be marked with the names of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cassie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Isaiah</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX>, and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbine High School</ENAMEX> who lost
      their lives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>.
      All around our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> presents bearing the names of school
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will stay in their ribbons and wrappings under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> because
      of the escalating epidemic of violence against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in recent
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.
      It's my guess that you are asking yourself, "What is happening to our
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>? What is wrong with our world?"
      In our public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> are forbidden to discuss religious
      topics on school grounds, even in after-school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">societies</ENAMEX>. Young
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are exposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> to violence, pornography, and other unwholesome
      influences over the internet.
      It's my guess that you are also asking yourself, "What can I do to
      help?"
      My intuition, of course, has a very specific basis-you are a person
      who cares, as demonstrated by your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> stewardship donation to your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parish</ENAMEX>. I know that you make it a point to be involved in your community
      and to support a variety of worthy causes. Consequently, I know that you
      go to extra lengths to be compassionate and caring to others. And that
      suggests to me that you may well be interested in joining a program that
      tries to help our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the face of the problems I mentioned
      above.
      On the chance that my guess is right, I am writing to you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to
      invite you to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOGOS-the League Of Greek Orthodox</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewards</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOGOS</ENAMEX> is comprised of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who wish to contribute to the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ministries</ENAMEX>, especially the youth programs, of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Orthodox</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Archdiocese of America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOGOS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministries</ENAMEX> for
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> over and above their other contributions to their local
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">parishes</ENAMEX>.
      There is so much that needs to be done in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministries</ENAMEX> that at times
      it may seem overwhelming. But another way to look at it is to consider
      that there is so much that we can accomplish together. Through your
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tax-deductible</ENAMEX> donation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOGOS</ENAMEX>, you will open a universe of
      opportunities to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>.
      You can provide the safe and loving environment of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox</ENAMEX>
      after-school program for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who might otherwise have nowhere else
      to go.
      You can educate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth workers</ENAMEX> on the best ways to counsel
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> about the frightening issues facing them, like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use and
      premarital sex.
      You can aid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ionian Village</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>, where
      they can strengthen their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Christian</ENAMEX> faith while enjoying the
      beauty of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hellenic</ENAMEX> culture.
      You can establish and support <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Orthodox Campus Fellowships</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX>
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, so that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are away
      from home for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time can have the support of others who share
      their beliefs and values.
      You can train <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Church School</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to provide the highest
      level of instruction in religious education.
      You can provide for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> who attends <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">St. Basil Academy</ENAMEX>, a ministry
      of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek Orthodox Archdiocese</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">needy children</ENAMEX> are given the love
      and security of a home away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
      You can give all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> a truly wonderful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> gift-the
      gift of your love and attention and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, so that they may enjoy this
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas season</TIMEX> and many more in health and safety.
      You can do all this with the simplest gesture. Your membership
      donation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LOGOS</ENAMEX> will help fund all these programs and more. Every penny
      counts in the fight to save our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.
      Simply check off your tax-deductible contribution on the enclosed
      membership invitation. Please mail it back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the envelope provided
      for your convenience, so that we can continue to carry on this vital
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ministry</ENAMEX>.
      With love in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christ</ENAMEX>,
      P.S. There are many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who have been helped by the youth
      programs of our Holy Archdiocese. But there are many more who still need
      our help.
      Thank you for your time and considering my appeal.
      
    
  
