
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Friend</ENAMEX>,
      Have you ever wondered why the performances of our <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>
      fills us with such emotion?
      It's because pride, dedication, sacrifice, and the will to win are
      embodied in all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. We have a uniquely <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>, indefinable,
      unshakable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> within us which is brought to life through the
      performances of our <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>.
      Do you remember how wonderful and how proud you felt in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> when the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">young United States Hockey Team</ENAMEX> beat the powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4-3</ENAMEX>, and
      then went on to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">4-2</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX>; the sight of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Craig</ENAMEX>
      skating around the arena with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Flag draped across his back,
      tears of joy streaming down his face, looking for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>; or in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Lou Retton</ENAMEX>, needing a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">9.95</NUMEX> in her
      final event to tie for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place in the all around Gymnastics
      competition, vaulted her way to the gold by scoring a perfect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>?
      I remember these moments, as I'm sure you do, and I also recall many
      other moving performances when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> reached deep within
      themselves to overcome what appeared to be insurmountable odds.
      The story of our <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> is one of personal sacrifice,
      dedication to be the best in the world, and a desire to represent the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> with pride. But, our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> can't do it
      alone. The success of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's Olympic Movement</ENAMEX> depends
      on the support of proud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> like you who know what it takes to be
      the best.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Olympic Committee</ENAMEX> is funded by private donations,
      and provide esessential support services for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> on a continuing
      basis. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> include coaching, training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX>, housing,
      medical treatment, and other support which is necessary for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>
      to reach their full potential.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> in the world, and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>
      continually prove to the world how great a nation we truly are, thanks to
      the generous support of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> like you. Please accept
      the enclosed <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> lapel pin as my gift, and wear it with pride. I hope
      you will help us continue the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> tradition of excellence.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William J. Hybl President</ENAMEX>
      P.S. My dream is to see every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> become part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX>
      family, so please give whatever you can. Thank you in advance for your
      support, and I hope you enjoy your <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> lapel pin.
      Your generous gift of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> or more will earn you a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX> T-shirt with
      the official <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Games</ENAMEX> logo!
      Visit our website for the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> news, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> profiles
      and apparel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">usoc</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>
    
  
