
  
  
    
      (Name) (Address) (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City, ST Zip</ENAMEX>)
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear,</ENAMEX>
      Thank you for your interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aloha</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX>.
      I am enclosing our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annual Report</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoaloha</ENAMEX>, our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> report;
      and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year 2000 Report to Donors</ENAMEX> to introduce you to some basic services
      <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AUW</ENAMEX>.
      (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">808</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">543-2213</TIMEX>, or e-mail me at: deborahm@auw.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">org</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah M. Sanders Murray Aloha</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Way</ENAMEX> Assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX>
      Marketing/ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communications Enc</ENAMEX>.
    
  
