
  
  
    
      <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dear,</ENAMEX>
      I am delighted to inform you that at the last meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Senatorial Inner Circle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX>
      placed your name in nomination for membership and you were accepted
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unanimously</ENAMEX>.
      This honor could not come at a more exciting time --<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election year</TIMEX>,
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National Convention</ENAMEX> is set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 16-20</TIMEX>, in
      <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>. Let me take this opportunity to invite you to join me at the
      Convention.
      Throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Convention</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">members</ENAMEX> will take part in a
      number of unique events, including a tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>, and
      the formal event of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White & Boots</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gala</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX>
      may also attend political briefings delivered by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX>, top
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">level Administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>.
      Most importantly, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">members</ENAMEX> will receive credentials to
      attend all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> working sessions. In addition, by
      accepting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> membership, you will share in the world's greatest
      celebration of democracy, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 52nd</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Presidential Inaugural</ENAMEX>. As an
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> you will take part in a variety of unique political
      events and black tie events.
      Shortly, you will receive a formal invitation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX>,
      ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. I hope you will join this
      powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.
      Again, let me congratulate you on your unanimous nomination for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> membership and urge you to accept this honor as soon as possible.
      On behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, I look forward to working with you in the
      future.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
    
  
