
  
  
    
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29, 1992</TIMEX>
      Dear Name,
      It gives me great pleasure to extend to you this invitation to Join
      the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Senatorial Inner Circle</ENAMEX> in a celebration of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> at
      our <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National Convention</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 16-20</TIMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Gramm</ENAMEX> placed your name in nomination because he feels
      your accomplishments and commitment to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> prove you worthy of
      membership in this prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Senatorial Inner Circle</ENAMEX> is made up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> who
      meet on a regular basis to discuss national and regional topics in a
      series of business, political and social gatherings. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> election
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> offers some extraordinary membership opportunities.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> meeting will be centered around the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National Convention</ENAMEX>. Your membership will provide you with
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">admittance</ENAMEX> to our "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> only" activities as well as full credentials
      to all official <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Convention</ENAMEX> sessions. We expect the highlight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner</ENAMEX>
      Circle event to be an exclusive luncheon with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>.
      Added to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Convention</ENAMEX> and the luncheon will be an optional tour of
      tickets to the premier social event of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Republican National Convention</ENAMEX>
      --The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White & Boots</ENAMEX> gala; and participation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX>
      closed door discussions and briefings.
      Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> discussions and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> briefings allow give-and-take
      between top level Administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">members</ENAMEX>.
      Each regular meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> focuses on specific, timely
      issues facing our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> are always among the foremost
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> in their fields.
      Past <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> briefings have been conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing and Urban</ENAMEX>
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kemp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Skinner</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cheney</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President's Council</ENAMEX>
      of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Advisors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Boskin</ENAMEX>.
      As an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> you will receive select seating during the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention</ENAMEX>, and special invitations to dinners, receptions and activities
      throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>.
      Since reservations for our stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> are limited, I hope you
      will return your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nomination Acceptance</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
      Of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX>'s list of meetings doesn't end with the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National Convention</ENAMEX>. As an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> you can expect
      some of the finest seats on the reviewing stand for the world's greatest
      celebration of democracy --the 52nd <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Presidential</ENAMEX>
      Inauguration.
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This coming January</TIMEX>, you will take part in all the glitter and glamour
      of the official <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Presidential Inaugural</ENAMEX>, including the swearing in
      ceremony, <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Inaugural Parade</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle Black Tie Ball</ENAMEX> on
      <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 19th</TIMEX>.
      When you accept membership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX>, you will become an
      integral part in what is fast-proving to be an historical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election year</TIMEX>.
      The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> is looking at an unprecedented opportunity --in
      recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> liberal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> have announced they will
      not seek re-election.
      These open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> --coupled
      with the ousting of long-term <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Dixon</ENAMEX>, have greatly increased
      our chances for victory.
      Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> in these races, and in the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>
      campaigns across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, are strong, bright, and talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>.
      The strength and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> will not be ignored by
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> who are fed up with an inept <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
      That is why joining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> can do more to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> than at any
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> in its history. By accepting your nomination and joining with us,
      you not only become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the most prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, you
      also help finance the races of our field of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.
      Many other benefits are made available to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. These
      are explained more fully in the enclosed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner Circle Membership</ENAMEX>
      Prospectus. The financial details of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> membership are also
      covered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prospectus</ENAMEX>.
      I hope you will give careful consideration to your nomination. You
      certainly deserve this honor, and I believe each of us will benefit from
      your involvement.
      Since our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention</ENAMEX> plans take a great deal of preparation, please
      fill out and return your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nomination Acceptance</ENAMEX> no later than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 3rd</TIMEX>.
      It is important to fill out all of the information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nomination</ENAMEX>
      Acceptance reply form --including your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> number. This is
      required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> for clearance to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Convention</ENAMEX> events and
      the special luncheon with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX>.
      On behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX>, my
      fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX>, and the current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX>,
      I sincerely hope to see you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> --as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
      Senatorial <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX>.
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sincerely</ENAMEX>,
      <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX>
      P.S. During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this election year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Executive Committee</ENAMEX> is offering
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Junior</ENAMEX> memberships for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">aged 12-18</TIMEX>,
      of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inner Circle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">members</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> will be particularly meaningful for
      our young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>. Experiencing the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Convention</ENAMEX> will leave a marked
      impression on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior members</ENAMEX> --an impression that could lead to a
      future of service to this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and to a better understanding of the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> process. The details of junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> are discussed in the
      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inner Circle Membership Prospectus</ENAMEX>.
      In you have any further questions, please do not hesitate to call our
      Membership <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services Coordinator</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Young</ENAMEX>, at (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">877-6773</ENAMEX>.
      
    
  
