
   
   
      
         
            Even <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">More "Proving Rape</ENAMEX>"

coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s rape charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> (see
"Proving
Rape ," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"More Proving</ENAMEX>
Rape," as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kinsley</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Readme"</ENAMEX>column in the current issue) cries out for the introduction of the
Scientific Method into the usually mushy business of assessing press
responsibility. With that in mind, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> hereby inaugurates the
Intellectual Dishonesty (henceforth to be known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indis</ENAMEX> )
Index . Here's how it works: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publications</ENAMEX> that refuse to acknowledge
(even if to refute the importance of) highly significant but inconvenient facts
in their news or opinion coverage of controversial events will score <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
point for the initial offense. They will then score <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point for
every subsequent issue or broadcast or Internet posting after the first offense
is noted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> if they continue not to report said inconvenient
fact--and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an additional two</NUMEX> points on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> when the news organization
runs a follow-up without making note of said inconvenient fact.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publications</ENAMEX> receiving a score of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> will be inducted into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indis Hall of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fame</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publications</ENAMEX> that get all the way up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> will be faxed a likeness
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Stalin</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would prefer not to invoke the phrase
"intellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dishonesty</ENAMEX>," because it's pompous and falsely suggests that only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> can be intellectually dishonest. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doesn't know any
other easily understandable phrase that describes this particular kind of
offense.)

            For the purposes of this survey, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> will be
counted as a separate and distinct <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's
editorial page, because, in essence, it is.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page continues not to acknowledge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma</ENAMEX>
Kelsey, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX> who is one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> people
partially corroborating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s rape accusation, is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> of a man
whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> was pardoned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. (A responsible account of the
whole controversy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsey</ENAMEX> says the pardon
had nothing to do with her corroboration.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page
gets <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point for failing to note the pardon in its initial Op-Ed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Rabinowitz</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>. Because it has published <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times since the
initial omission, it scores <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an additional three</NUMEX> points. And because it
published an editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 22</TIMEX> taunting the rest of the press for not following
it on the story--and still didn't mention the pardon--it scores an extra
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points. That comes to a total of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> feels
certain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page will provide some follow-up
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> broadcast of its own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> interview, which
means that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page continues to take no action it
will be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indis Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at the latest!

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> considered but rejected the idea of awarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabinowitz</ENAMEX> bonus
points for having "eventually convinced" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> to grant an interview to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> (as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s story). But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific Method</ENAMEX> does not permit any tinkering with the Indis
Index 's scoring procedures. And besides, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabinowitz</ENAMEX>'s efforts on the
Times ' behalf weren't really unethical, just puzzling, given the two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>' intense rivalry. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Murray</ENAMEX>, who exercised good judgment in not breaking
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> story (and--full disclosure-- is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>), to
comment about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>'s feeding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
he replied: "I don't really have any comment on what the edit page did. They do
their thing, we do ours." Which is what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> are
instructed to say whenever the editorial page causes them cringing
embarrassment.

            For her part, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabinowitz</ENAMEX> explains to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> that her efforts on behalf
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> were more indifferent than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> made them
sound. "Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> told me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> had appeared
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the a.m.</TIMEX>, and that she had refused an interview," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabinowitz</ENAMEX>
writes in an e-mail message. "I asked her why she had decided to talk to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Dunleavy</ENAMEX>, and refused a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. She
said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunleavy</ENAMEX> caught her by surprise. She asked if I thought it would be all
right to talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. I told her it would be--certainly
as all right as talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunleavy</ENAMEX>. She said, 'Well, I'm sorry I didn't.' She
said she would if he called again. I passed this on to [ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>]
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicity Barringer</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our second day</TIMEX>'s interview chat. So--that's how it
happens that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> I'm
described--solemnly--as having 'eventually convinced' her to repeat the story
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
