
   
   
      
         
            HMO-phobia

            A bit of a health and safety theme <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a story about how managed care health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, who
now cover <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, face a state government review
and many possible legislative reforms, all arising from widespread patient
dissatisfaction with their rules. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times is above the fold with an account of how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> will launch a
lobbying blitz <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> against current congressional proposals for deep cuts
in the payments they receive for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>. Their big message: if any
of these are passed, plan <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> will have to start paying for their
prescriptions.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's main front page feature examines the
trend of nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> retaining their tax-exempt status while straying
pretty far from their original charge of using their assets for such charitable
purposes as caring for the indigent. The piece focuses on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> that has a lavish plastic surgery <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> catering
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and will soon own a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">18-acre</NUMEX> office
and training-field <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> that it will rent to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> coming to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the news that during the period when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> raised
their speed limits, traffic fatalities actually fell slightly. The paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reminds</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of higher speed limits had claimed they would
result in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6,400</NUMEX> more fatalities per year.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's top story is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the recent coup in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun Sen</ENAMEX>, "promises free and fair elections and urges human rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organizations</ENAMEX> and the media to continue their work." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> reconsidering its
long-held goal of integration at its convention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.

            The front pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and WP make plenty of
room for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX>'s trip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pinkas Synagogue</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prague</ENAMEX> where for
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time, she saw the names of her paternal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> in an inscribed
list of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>-gaysing . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries a piece way inside with the
suggestion that some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> recently asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
Hattoy, a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, if he had been successful hiring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> in to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> says that the question was never put to
Hattoy, but that when in the course of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> interview, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hattoy</ENAMEX> was asked
about his general government duties, he volunteered that, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s words, "it
was his job to locate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX>" for administration jobs.

            Guess which major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> isn't reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> carefully enough?
This very issue of this very magazine contains a piece by ace foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">correspondent Peter Maass</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> "s"s) concerning his persistent experience of
being confused with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Valachi Papers and Serpico</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Maas</ENAMEX> (one "s"). And yet, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s on-line version of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page, there appears a piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> over the byline of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peter</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maas</ENAMEX>." Although it's possible that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull</ENAMEX>'s collaborator has branched
out, it's not likely--after all, the piece's credit line is all about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter "Maass</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
