
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bear Butts and Ballots</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> is still the biggest story, but shares the spotlight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with some
international developments. The saga of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> mission leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA TODAY</ENAMEX> cover
story, but moves over to top center front in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>, which
leads instead with developments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>, the story which also tops the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>'s front non-financial news column. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> election is top of the page left at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and (naturally
enough, given its large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>) leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> coverage is dominated by depictions of the excitement inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mission</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> and of the various features of the planet that are about
to be investigated. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> describes a "geological cornucopia" there,
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, includes a topographical feature resembling "the backside
of a bear." (How would the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> know?) Just in case you
were wondering if there was political correctness on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rover vehicle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sojourner</ENAMEX> is not so-called because
of its function, but is actually named for the black abolitionist Sojourner
Truth.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> describes the mission's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$266 million</NUMEX> cost as "bargain-basement,"
but redeems itself by being singularly sensitive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> efforts, noting
that the mission <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> had been "coached on how to respond to possible questions
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> about little green <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> or the 'face on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>' (neither of which
came up). They were instructed how to avoid using acronyms and [about] what
sort of clothes look best on camera."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> election is news because it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">68</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> is a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> that has
dominated the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s corrupt politics for generations. The vote is being
widely viewed as the cleanest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s history. And political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">north</ENAMEX> of the border, take note: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that "some foreign news
broadcasts to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> were halted. The interior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ministry</ENAMEX> said it was enforcing
an election law that bars the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> here of any election polls for one
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> before the vote."

            It's pretty hard to tell from the majors what's going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> as
relations between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime ministers</ENAMEX> worsen. The headline
above the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead story reads "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cambodia Faction Declares Victory As</ENAMEX>
Fighting Halts." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chaos Mounts in Cambodia: Armies of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Feuding Premiers Battle for Capital</ENAMEX>."

            Another interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (played big on the front by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , which carried the watershed vote inside): it seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s
most wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>, on the lam since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, died after a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine-hour</TIMEX>
plastic surgery operation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX> confirms
the death. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is more cautious, asking in its headline, "Is it the
Drug <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boss?</ENAMEX>" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> was for extensive facial reconstruction to change the
wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s appearance, and also for liposuction. Were his hip measurements on
his wanted poster?

         
      
   
