
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Fugitives</ENAMEX>

            As is often the case on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, there's no single story dominating the
news. But there is sort of a crime theme. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the arrest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> on charges of smuggling into
this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and then virtually enslaving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of deaf <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> selling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trinkets</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subways</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Taylor</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warlord</ENAMEX> who started and dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Liberia</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX> civil war (estimated
deaths: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150,000</NUMEX>) is winning his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s presidential election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>, the
paper notes, is a fugitive from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, where he broke out of jail while
being held on embezzlement charges. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , the big story is that state and federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> suspect that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s private methadone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX> are overbilling state
health insurance programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s hunt for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cunanan</ENAMEX>.

            The deaf <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> story probably has legs because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX>
has made it a personal cause (he's already visited with them) and because, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smugglers</ENAMEX> have scammed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deaf people</ENAMEX> into similar
situations in other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> as well.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> continues the series on mismanagement in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that it started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s front page story covers
the featherbedding that seems to be a feature of almost all city <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>.
For instance, states the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , most <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">municipalities</ENAMEX> use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> per
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 500</NUMEX> to monitor the time cards of other city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> has one
for every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>.

            The main news in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cunanan</ENAMEX> hunt, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
is now warning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who knew the fugitive that his murder spree may be a
matter of seeking revenge against those he thinks crossed him. Also, that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> is reviewing photos taken by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that she claims show Cunanan
together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Versace</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami Beach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">estate</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> before
he was killed. Additionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> are also considering the possibility
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cunanan</ENAMEX> is now dressing as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. (Unfortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> doesn't have
as much expertise in this area as it used to.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a good front-page piece about the juvenile court system,
making the point that it is so overwhelmed by the increase in juvenile crime
and the breakdown of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that almost no one believes it still serves a
useful purpose. But there is also something quite interesting that the article
doesn't say. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, the piece quotes a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernadine Dohrn</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Justice Center</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwestern University</ENAMEX>" as saying
that high rates of prosecution of juveniles overwhelm the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>, "and when you
do this wholesale, you drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> into the system who don't belong there, and
you don't find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who aren't in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and are getting into serious
trouble. They are able to pass through for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> without being stopped."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> doesn't mention that once upon a time, Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> was in favor
of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in serious trouble being able to slip through the system like
that--when she was, like Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunanan</ENAMEX>, on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Top Ten Most Wanted List</ENAMEX>,
because of her activities as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Weather Underground</ENAMEX>.

            Think that the deinstitutionalization of the mentally ill is mainly just an
inconvenience to those who use the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subways</ENAMEX> and the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>?
Well, according to an op-ed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> are murdered by severely mentally ill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are not receiving
treatment."

         
      
   
