
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court Gridlock</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decisions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. Which to lead with? The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> all choose the ruling that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> may ban assisted suicide.
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Help For Dying</ENAMEX>," is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> plaintive subhed. A sidebar analysis is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headlined</ENAMEX>, somewhat tastelessly, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Issue that Won't Die</ENAMEX>.") The unanimous
ruling that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Communications Decency Act</ENAMEX> (banning smut on the Internet) is
unconstitutional makes page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times es</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .
But the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> decision--rejecting a challenge to the line-item veto--didn't
even rate a front-page teaser in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> brings a characteristic "human touch" to all the dry legal
news, noting that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> announced the Internet ruling, "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> opposing the law popped a disk containing the opinion into
his laptop computer outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and transmitted it by cellular modem to
an Internet site."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> allot the top of column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> (journalism's
traditional spot for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> story) to the tax cut bill that passed the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> local-interest stories with national implications. The LAT
reports that because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>'s recent abandonment of
affirmative action in admissions, its incoming law school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> is likely to
include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> page-ones a story that
publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX> is reacting to the slump in book sales by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">canceling</ENAMEX> completed books, including some already advertised in its catalogs.
Among the casualties mentioned are a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jell-O</ENAMEX> cookbook and a book about celebrity
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
