
   
   
      
         
            Gipper the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ripper</ENAMEX>?

            The leading lights of the journalistic right, the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , are
beside themselves over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s lackadaisical response to Juanita
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> raped her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades ago</TIMEX>. In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
Standard lead editorial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> writes,
"The accused ... is now the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> he get away with what no other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> could get away
with--not having to answer the accusation directly?"

            No other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>? Almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years ago</TIMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> of great repute ducked a much-publicized rape rap without answering
the accusation directly--and the press quickly abandoned the story.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelley</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX>: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unauthorized Biography</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selene Walters</ENAMEX> claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>
forced her to have sex with him in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '50s</TIMEX>. According to the book,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Screen Actors Guild</ENAMEX>, met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nightclub</ENAMEX>. He asked for her address, and she gave it to him. Later at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 a.m.</TIMEX>,
he arrived unexpectedly at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX>' door and forced himself on her, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX>
alleges.

            The press ridiculed this and other passages from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> : <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reagans</ENAMEX> smoked pot with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Benny</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Burns</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX>'s implication that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX> boffed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX>. But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX>'s sourcing of the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> rape is not much worse than the
sourcing of the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rape.

            What's more, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> to
repeat the story almost verbatim. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> denied <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> key element of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX>'s
version to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> --that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> forced his way into her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX>--but
reaffirmed the rest. It sounds remarkably like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s
story:

            "I opened the door," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>. "Then
it was the battle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>. I was fighting him. I didn't want him to make
love to me. He's a very big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, and he just had his way. Date rape? No, God,
no, that's [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX>'s] phrase. I didn't have a chance to have a date with
him."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX>--like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>--did not file charges. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> maintains that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX> shared contemporaneous accounts of the encounter
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX> successfully stonewalled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX>
story when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> picked it up briefly in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1991</TIMEX>. And remember, this
was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three and a half years</TIMEX> before his <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX> diagnosis. The
weekend the book was released, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> for a comment about it
as he entered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX>. "I don't think a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> would be the proper place to use
the word I would have to use in discussing that," he said. Not exactly a
denial.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> doubts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> raped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walters</ENAMEX>. But
where was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Barnes</ENAMEX> and where was the Wall 
               Street Journal
back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>? Were they outraged by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s refusal to answer the rape charge
directly? Were they accusing the press of
partisan bias for refusing to confront the accused? Not exactly. A quick shake
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nexis</ENAMEX> produces this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX> appearance on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12, 1991</TIMEX>, edition of
The MacNeil/<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lehrer NewsHour</ENAMEX> .

            "This is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> journalism," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnes</ENAMEX>
said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX>'s book. "It's the kind where you look for everything, you vacuum
up everything that's unfavorable, use all of it, whether it's rumor, fact,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">innuendo</ENAMEX>, hearsay, use all it, and don't let a kind word get in the whole
thing."

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
