
   
   
      
         
            Mourning in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>

            The lead story all around--and then some--is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s funeral. Earlier in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> it was often claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>'s death was getting so much ink because of
her charitable works. But this was refuted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s coverage, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>
claimed whole front pages, but Mother <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa</ENAMEX> was relegated to the inside.

            The papers generally agree on what was most noteworthy about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s
events in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>: that the outpouring of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> public emotion hadn't been
matched since the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, that, with its engaged participation in
the ceremonies, the royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> seemed to bounce back into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> favor, and
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s remarks were probably among the most frank ever made
inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westminster Abbey</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
describes his eulogy, with its description of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> as "the most hunted woman
on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX>," as "passionate," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says it was "barbed and biting." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> refers to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s angry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>."

            Some of the reporting on the service is quite a nice throwback to the days
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> everywhere depended on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to know what such events were
like. However, this one was seen by perhaps half the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the planet, so
it's hard to justify the lengthy descriptive articles that are so prominent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            And it's definitely hard for a paper to justify <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wordfests</ENAMEX>. But that's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> gives us. Not only do we get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoge</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Buried</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation Mourns</ENAMEX>," but also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Apple</ENAMEX>'s "Through
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Streets</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sounds of Silence Toll</ENAMEX>." The overkill is particularly
obvious when both pieces etch the same details. Hoge: "When [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX>] ended his talk <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> later...there was spontaneous applause in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and on the expansive meadow of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde Park</ENAMEX> jammed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were watching the service on giant television screens." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>:
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spencer</ENAMEX>'s castigation of the news media as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s
death, relayed by loudspeaker to those outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abbey</ENAMEX>, brought applause."
Hoge: A wreath on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casket</ENAMEX> had a "white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">card</ENAMEX> stuck in it with the word
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Mummy</ENAMEX>' written on it." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> threw blossoms at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX>' casket
as it rolled by on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun carriage</ENAMEX>, draped in a royal standard with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sprays</ENAMEX> of
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX>, tulips and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lillies</ENAMEX> atop it, one of them bearing the single word,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Mummy</ENAMEX>.'"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX> included, besides such
obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> as former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Ministers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Major, the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Kidman</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> doesn't bother to explain whether these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glitterati</ENAMEX> were
there because they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s or were simply exercising the modern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">celebrity</ENAMEX>'s nearly universally-recognized right to get any hard ticket.

            An early-bird edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> gives a revealing insight into the
priorities of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dodi Al-Fayed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. In reporting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz Hotel</ENAMEX> released
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> video tape that show <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> in an
apparently orderly manner, the paper quotes an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Fayed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>'s explanation
for doing so: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz Hotel</ENAMEX> has been accused of what amounts to negligence or
worse."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s contest: What could the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alessandra Stanley</ENAMEX> possibly
mean in this exit line to her "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" appreciation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>? "At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>,
she died a horrible death, and one that seemed portentously linked to her
extraordinary life."

         
      
   
