
   
   
      
         
            All <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>

            Today, it's pretty much all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, all the time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> had "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the
lawful level of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> in his blood" as he raced through the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
"at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">110 mph</NUMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> runs a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-column headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DIANA'S DRIVER</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LEGALLY DRUNK</ENAMEX>"--across its top front, and gives the whole rest of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 1A</TIMEX> over
to various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di-gressions</ENAMEX>: not just the drinking and the speeding, but also the
funeral plans, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prince William</ENAMEX> profile and a detail about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> it
credits to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times of London</ENAMEX> , reporting that just before speeding away
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ritz</ENAMEX> he taunted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> by telling them "Catch me if you
can."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> also has a lot on the drunk driving angle,
but quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> as insisting that the revelation
"changes absolutely nothing" and that it was an "ambience of harassment" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodi Fayed</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> that was the key. But the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , alone among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>, also manages to find room for a story that
might reasonably be thought equally important: that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> Bosnian
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX> attacked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 300</NUMEX> heavily armed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.

            There being no obvious business angle to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> contents itself with a long-front page
feature answering a question no one is asking: Could the accident give rise to
any legal proceedings that would be "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">OJ II?</ENAMEX>" The answer, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , is no.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
tries to rise above the vulgus by giving its lead space to a piece about the
coming session of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Mistake! <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> of all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> piece is
virtually news-free: it's conjecture, after all, about what may happen there
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between now and January</TIMEX>, and secondly, some of the material in the three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>-related front-page articles is really good. There's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> saying, "Holding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> responsible when the cause was
clearly excessive speed is absurd." (Do you think there's a chance that now
instead of, or in addition to, inspiring a campaign against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX>, this
tragedy might spur a renewed campaign against drunk driving?) There's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
photojournalist saying, "Those who denounce the paparazzi today will be the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to buy the photos of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princes</ENAMEX> crying at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Di</ENAMEX>'s funeral." And
the revelation that although <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> photo <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> is said to be offering
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> rights to color photos of the crashed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX>, showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> covered in
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> turned down the deal and urged other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">publications</ENAMEX> to do the same. (Of course, those pictures will surface, and don't
be surprised if they also eventually make their way into a "mainstream" paper,
probably over a caption like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> debate: Was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX> wrong
to publish these pictures?")

            If that's not enough, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> op-ed pieces.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that local <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> prevention programs reflect different
standards of expected conduct. In suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>, for instance, the advice
tends towards abstinence. But in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, a pamphlet about the dangers
of oral sex with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> advises <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to look into condoms and dental <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
