
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Briefings Encounters</ENAMEX>

            Nobody has the same lead story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with "the most extensive and
far-reaching reforms" ever proposed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>--which means, it turns out,
neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> nor budget cuts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
saves its top right for the first-ever comprehensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> audit, which
reveals that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> overpaid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and other health care
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">providers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23 billion</NUMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX> of all the money spent in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">standard Medicare</ENAMEX> program." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Wilson</ENAMEX>'s proposal of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
billion dollar state tax cut. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the benefits would extend up
to those who earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, then calls it a "middle class" tax cut.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s big news on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall St.</ENAMEX>--the Dow breaking
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8000</TIMEX>.

            But there's a lot of agreement about what belongs on the front page. Dow
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8000</TIMEX> is there also for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> . (But not, somewhat surprisingly, for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .) The campaign fundraising hearings make it at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Versace</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer manhunt</ENAMEX> makes it at each of those
papers and at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> each have
front-page stories on whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are trying to oust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> aren't saying).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> cover story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Versace</ENAMEX> case has the disturbing news
that serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> are hard to catch, mainly because they traipse through a
lot of jurisdictions that can't or don't communicate with each other, and
because they're smart. Their downfall is often, says the piece, that they like
to taunt their pursuers. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that the
suspect, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cunanan</ENAMEX>, may have met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Versace</ENAMEX> previously, each crediting that
tidbit to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Orth</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has the
detail that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are studying the videotape from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Versace</ENAMEX>'s security
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, which does have coverage of the murder scene. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's slant is
to go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cunanan</ENAMEX>'s old haunts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La Jolla</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>, describing a posh
and partying upbringing there. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of a hangout that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cunanan</ENAMEX> frequented
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that recently his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> showed a disturbing change: "The
hair was pretty screwed up."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> putting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s session at the fundraising hearings on the
front all note that they featured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> testifying from behind a screen.
They were talking about the regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> briefings <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> received while he
was at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>. These <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also report that a superior of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX>'s at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Garten</ENAMEX>, felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> was "totally unqualified" to do
anything besides administrative tasks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garten</ENAMEX> was surprised
to learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> had visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> at least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times while at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> didn't apply for
a top secret security clearance. But further on, it quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang "</ENAMEX>had received a full security clearance." Which
is it, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ?

            The coverage of Dow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8000</TIMEX> is perfectly ordinary--the usual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quote-a-bear-quote-a-bull</ENAMEX> format. With <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> exception: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> takes a
closer look at the investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> who have spent most of the nineties
telling their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> to sell. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Prechter</ENAMEX> of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott Wave</ENAMEX>
Theorist" newsletter, who has been claiming for some time that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> is
headed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">400</NUMEX>, and who, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports, has lost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscribers</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
