
   
   
      
         
            Merger and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Settlement</ENAMEX>

            It's refreshing to be reminded every so often that there is still at least
one thing that can put the brakes on our warp-drive news cycle--the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-day</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>. So what's news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is whatever could get done with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> off barbecuing in droves. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes clear across its top with the news that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney general</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX>, who pioneered the idea of suing
the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to recoup state health expenditures, has reached a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$170</NUMEX>
million settlement with them, one that goes into effect even if the proposed
big national tobacco deal falls through. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Fordice</ENAMEX> denounced the agreement as 'a dangerous
precedent' that is 'about big bucks and big publicity.'"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> puts
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi</ENAMEX> tobacco story above the fold but leads instead with the
announcement that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> intends to buy a rival defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrup/Grumman</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> plays that story lower, but above its fold.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> describes the acquisition as part of a consolidation trend in
the defense industry and says that the trend is encouraged by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration, but never says why. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
also leads with the story, and as might be expected, bemoans the likely closure
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop/Grumman</ENAMEX> corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>, and possible local
layoffs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reviews the virtues of the various <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> produced
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX>, but can't seem to recall any actual accomplishment of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-14</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>, so instead merely describes it as "of 'TopGun' fame."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story about the deal in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA TODAY</ENAMEX> makes it clear that consolidation is good for
business in all kinds of ways, explaining that if it falls through, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>
nonetheless collects a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX> breakup fee.

            All these stories note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX>'s stock price went up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly 25 percent</NUMEX>
on the news, but none delves into the question of whether any of the major
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in or out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> who affect defense procurement are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s surge in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Jones</ENAMEX>, fueled by a slight rise in the latest
unemployment figures, is dutifully reported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the financial markets "reveled" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s chief
economic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Yellen</ENAMEX> "exulted" in the news--that the ranks of the
unemployed grew by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">302,000</NUMEX>. This is typical of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>: they usually
report these jobs numbers as if it were perfectly obvious that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> cause
of inflation is full(er) employment. Is it?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> places its story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s first formal
legal response to the substance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX>'s lawsuit against him--he
"adamantly" denies the charges--on the bottom of its front page. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
doesn't even put it on the front. Think how this story would have been played
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just ten years ago</TIMEX>! Does the current relaxed treatment say something about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, or about us?

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead editorial isn't your usual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX>
clich,-fest--it calls for not erecting a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> memorial on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Mall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>

         
      
   
