
   
   
      
         
            Does <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money Buy Happiness</ENAMEX>?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is mesmerized by a cover
story in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15</TIMEX> issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> on how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">world</ENAMEX>'s richest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, invests his money. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> stock is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$76 billion</NUMEX>. That money is, of course, invested in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. But another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.5 billion</NUMEX> in pocket change, managed by someone named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Larson</ENAMEX>, is scattered between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.5 billion</NUMEX>) and
his personal investment portfolio (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 billion</NUMEX>). The latter alone is "roughly
the same size as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fidelity Value</ENAMEX> fund, a big mutual fund with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">412,000</NUMEX>
shareholder accounts."

            But is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> happy? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> suspects he is, and he suspects at least in
part it's because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> has more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lettuce</ENAMEX> than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sultan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brunei</ENAMEX>. However,
this rash conclusion flies in the face of social science research. We turn now
to page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Samuelson</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Good Life and Its Discontents</ENAMEX> . Samuelson, here and
throughout the book, argues that money doesn't buy happiness. "It's
family, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and work that contribute most to well-being," he quotes
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Lane</ENAMEX> saying. To support this view, Samuelson
reprints some fascinating data from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
Opinion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Center</ENAMEX>. The numbers are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years old</TIMEX>, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> haven't
been wildly inflationary. Here they are:

            

               

                  

                     
                        Income
                     

                  

                  

                     
                        Very Happy
                     

                  

                  

                     
                        Pretty Happy
                     

                  

                  

                     
                        Not Too Happy
                     

                  

               

               

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$0-$14,999</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">58%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21%</NUMEX>

                  

               

               

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000-$24,999</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">13%</NUMEX>

                  

               

               

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24,000-$34,999</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8%</NUMEX>

                  

               

               

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000-$49,999</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">36%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX>

                  

               

               

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000-$74,999</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>

                  

               

               

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX> or more

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49%</NUMEX>

                  

                  

                     <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6%</NUMEX>

                  

               

            

            While it's true that, overall, these data show that money doesn't
dramatically affect the distribution of happiness, let's examine some of the
nuances. One is that you're nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times as likely to be miserable if you
make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $15,000</NUMEX> than you would be if you made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $35,000</NUMEX>. True,
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">79 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than $15,000</NUMEX> still consider themselves "pretty
happy" or "very happy." But what if you don't happen to belong to this
naturally buoyant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX>? Clearly, for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 15</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX> (i.e., the
proportion of unhappy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> exceeding the "naturally unhappy" baseline of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX>), the lack of money buys unhappiness .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is also intrigued by what happens when your income rises above
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX>. If you were unhappy before, apparently you're likely to stay unhappy.
But <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">11 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were "pretty happy" will become "very happy."
Money may not buy happiness, but if you're already happy there's
a decent chance it will make you more happy!

            Does the likelihood of such a "happiness boost" increase when you graduate
from prosperous to out-of-sight rich? The data doesn't say, but Chatterbox bets
it does. By creating the broad category, "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX> or more," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figures lump</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX> with lowlifes like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>.
Also, there really ought to be a category for "ecstatically happy," which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> suspects rises precipitously when you get above <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> would appreciate hearing from any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> who have research to back
up or refute these hypotheses.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
