
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smoked Again</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> settlement leads all around. Everybody has the same
basic details: the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seller</ENAMEX> of
smokeless <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX> have agreed to pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.3 billion</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> in
compensation for its previous tobacco-related medical expenditures and to fund
and/or enact various public health measures, including an anti-smoking campaign
aimed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will also cease most outdoor advertising. And
everybody notes that the deal could help cement the proposed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$368 billion</NUMEX>
national tobacco settlement, although none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> gives the most obvious
explanation for this, namely that at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 billion</NUMEX> a state and climbing, fifty
separate settlements would be far more expensive.

            Everybody also notes that if approved, the national settlement would
supersede this deal. But it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> that explains that the public health
aspects of the state agreement would still remain in force. And it's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
that explains that this agreement will benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>, which in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> made
a purely financial settlement with the major tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, but also
secured the benefit of any additional public health concessions made in other
deals with other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>. And it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> that reveals that, according
to the deal, the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> will be paying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' legal fees.

            On the heels of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> magazine cover piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
welfare reform comes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s WP front-pager on the same topic. But where
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> emphasized the elaborate support system the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has erected,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , while recognizing that aspect, emphasizes instead <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>'s
tendency to cut <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off who've demonstrated the most minimal ability to hold
a job, regardless of whether they currently have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column reveals a new and
surprisingly lucrative job category: Year <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> conversion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>. It turns out
that the need of business to change mainframe computers so that they don't
freak out when they come across the millenium is so wide and so pressing that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are getting hired on at a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> immediately after
completing a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six week</TIMEX> training course, with others in the field making twice
that much. The column reports that in a survey of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">128</NUMEX> large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60%</NUMEX> say
they are hiring more Y2K (the hot new acronym, apparently) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>.

            
               But if you try to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>, you're ejected into deep
space. If you've been up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> worrying about the disenfranchisement of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">astronauts</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says relax, reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> announced
a technology that will allow space-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronauts</ENAMEX> to vote via email from
their laptops.

            In his column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Glassman</ENAMEX> gives his reason for
thinking that the current economic boom is nearly over. While playing on a
"swanky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">verdant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Trent Jones</ENAMEX> golf course" he noticed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">helicopter</ENAMEX> lifting
off from the clubhouse pad, taking a business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
after a round. When you see excess like that, writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glassman</ENAMEX>, a downturn isn't
far behind. Gee, I don't know--I bet the old boys with the old money probably
thought the same thing when they heard that their swanky verdant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> was
letting in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
