
   
   
      
         
            Want <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Spoiled Fries With That</ENAMEX>?

            Bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">burger meat</ENAMEX> dominates, leading at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> heads up its top-of-the-page
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World-Wide</ENAMEX>" news box with another pretty important health story, the admission
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> that his product may have
killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with state charges being
filed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Ridge</ENAMEX> case.

            Everybody has the same basic details on the recall of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">25 million pounds</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">burger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX>: It was produced at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson Foods</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nebraska</ENAMEX>. It was the
largest meat recall in history, prompted by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> getting food
poisoning from a strain of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli bacteria</ENAMEX> that can lead to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">kidney failure</ENAMEX> and
death. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Agriculture</ENAMEX> doesn't have the legal power to close a
suspect food <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> or unilaterally recall its product, but gets its way on
these matters by threatening to pull out its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>. It is widely reported
that because of this episode, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> now intends to ask
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for that closing power.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes a little further than the others in describing the meat
regulatory system, pointing out that, concerned by problems of contamination,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have recently approved a new more stringent system of
controls, but adding that the new system is not scheduled to be in place
anywhere until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>, and not at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Also,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is alone in explicitly stating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>
survived. On the other hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> puts the relevant consumer
information--the lot number of the suspect <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and government
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">800</ENAMEX> numbers--at the very bottom of the story, where, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> know from long
experience, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will never see it. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> mentions the
various places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> area where the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> might have ended up,
including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>, but is mum on whether any got near the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">burger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. (But don't bet against an eventual
presidential connection. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson Foods</ENAMEX> is headquartered in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>. Can
a political payoff or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rose Law Firm</ENAMEX> connection be far behind?)

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s papers provide vivid examples of how much headlines and placement
can vary, leading to widely different impressions about what's important. Why
is it, for instance, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> puts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s biggest social
impact story in a generation, the upholding by a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of the
proposition that overturns virtually all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s affirmative action
programs, in a tiny box nearly at the bottom of the front page? (Especially
curious given that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has given previous, less-definitive court
decisions concerning this proposition huge splashes.) And why is it that no one
but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> has that tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s confession on the front page?

            And why does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> headline its inside story about what he said,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smoking May Have Killed Thousands</ENAMEX>" when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> said "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX>"? And why, even
though the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ruby Ridge</ENAMEX> development involves the highly unusual event of homicide
charges being brought against an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, is that story left inside the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ? (It's on the front at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .) And the headlines over that story tend to befog rather than
clarify. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> tags the story this way: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FBI Sniper Charged</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs it under "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">FBI Sharpshooter</ENAMEX> charged in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ruby Ridge</ENAMEX>." The
Times heads it with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Two Men Charged in '92 Idaho Shootout</ENAMEX>." These are
all unnecessarily off, kind of like running "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Man Bites Something</ENAMEX>" without
mentioning that the bitee was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> should definitely be mentioned in
the headline, and so should the fact that a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, a survivalist, was also
charged. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> gets it right: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Idaho</ENAMEX> Charges <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Agent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Activist</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ruby Ridge Deaths</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
