
   
   
      
         
            The 'Post' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Withholds Credit Where It's Due</ENAMEX>

            It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual dishonesty</ENAMEX> time again! <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indis</ENAMEX> citation
goes this time to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> reports on Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> the firing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Taiwanese</ENAMEX>-born
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> who's suspected of turning over nuclear
secrets to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> got fired after
failing a polygraph test <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> and after complaints from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Shelby</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelby</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>.)
That's true. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> will be forgiven for wondering whether the firing has
anything to do with a splashy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> front-page story that
appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> before and identified (but did not name) a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Alamos</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who was believed to have passed along nuclear secrets to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story's impact was mentioned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s
firing by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPI</ENAMEX>, but it wasn't mentioned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter Pincus</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Newspapers</ENAMEX> hate to credit other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX>. They will do it when they have
to, which is why, in its initial follow-up story to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> scoop two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> did cite the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . Because that piece was
also by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pincus, Chatterbox</ENAMEX> won't bother to set the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indis Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>
timer a-ticking this time out. But the fact remains that the appearance of the
Times piece was surely a precipitating event, perhaps the
precipitating event, in the firing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX>. It had a big impact. It was
hyped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> on his Web site. It landed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Shelby</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet</ENAMEX>
the Press <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day later</TIMEX>, giving <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shelby</ENAMEX> a highly visible <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">platform</ENAMEX> from which
to scream and yell about the alleged security breach. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>
credited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> generously, too.)

            Whether the disproportionate attention given to the front page of the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ought to be a major factor in government decisions is, of
course, another question. One can argue, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has more or less
been doing in its coverage of the ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> technology-transfer story, that
questions about what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> should be selling to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> are very murky,
and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>-hungy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has been hyping this scandal's
importance in the series of pieces that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Gerth</ENAMEX> has been grinding out.
(That's the subliminal message of an accompanying story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). But if the
Times ' take, even if it's wrong, really is driving events, shouldn't the
Post acknowledge that?

            On a less lofty <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, it does seem a bit unfair that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> gets
to cover itself with glory over exposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wen Ho Lee</ENAMEX> when the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ran a piece on page A3 (for breaking news, its version of "page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>")
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla Anne Robbins</ENAMEX> conveying essentially the same information on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 7</TIMEX>.
This fact seems to have eluded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, as do many facts that appear in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , for the simple reason that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> is not available
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nexis</ENAMEX>. (This used to drive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> crazy when he worked in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>.) Assuming no one else had it before
Robbins, shouldn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gerth</ENAMEX> have credited her?

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
