
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>'s Chance

            The post-bombing developments in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> provide <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s most
important stories. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu Puts Onus on Arafat</ENAMEX>" is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's lead, and both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> have front-page stories covering the
various diplomatic, military and financial pressures <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> is now bringing to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bear</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX>. But after that, diversity breaks out: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> now doubt
they will reach an agreement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to admit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> because they have failed to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> to
meaningfully open his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s markets to foreign competition. The LAT
leads with the most ambitious plan yet to use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> ordered injunctions against
ordinarily legal behavior (such as using cell phones, and gathering in groups
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or more</NUMEX>) to control <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> activity. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's lead is that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Institutes of Medicine</ENAMEX> is going to try to determine whether
fallout from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War atomic</ENAMEX> tests may have caused <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 75,000</NUMEX> cases of thyroid
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> repercussions depicts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX>
attributing the current situation to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>, quoting him saying that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>
must make a choice" about whether he wants his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to "behave like a
terror-sponsoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>." The story adds that there is a good deal of support
for this view in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>: "...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel R. "Sandy" Berger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>, put the onus on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>. In comments to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berger</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX> needed to do more to share intelligence with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Israel</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's front-page "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook"</ENAMEX> column addresses
the likelihood that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> will try to push free political ad time on the TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">broadcasters</ENAMEX> will fight back hard. Already, notes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , they've tried to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Ornstein</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise Institute</ENAMEX>, a free-ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX>, from an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>. "I can
really understand why a poor, defenseless little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> like the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Broadcasters</ENAMEX> would feel threatened by a big powerful academic
like me," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ornstein</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> takes a lot of top-front-page space to detail the plight of
those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> who will, under the new provisions about to be signed into law,
pay more tax when they sell their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. The article even takes several
paragraphs to explain how to legally beat this new tax. Who are these, as the
Times puts it, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>"? Struggling single working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>? Young,
heavily mortgaged first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homebuyers</ENAMEX>? No--they are the "extremely rich, who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> homes for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX>" and their downmarket <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX>, "those who
have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> trading up from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> home to another and now have homes
worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $500,000</NUMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WP</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> comments <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on "the story that
every <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> believes but few have dared to hint at in print,"
namely that, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Hanover</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>, has not only abandoned the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reelection</ENAMEX> campaign of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph Giuliani</ENAMEX>, but also is said to
be on the verge of leaving him--largely because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s close
relationship with his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32-year-old</TIMEX> communications <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX> notes a
non-prurient justification for doing the story: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanover</ENAMEX> has a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-person
staff that costs the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$165,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, yet she has all but
stopped being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> or making appearances with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
