
   
   
      
         
            Smoke and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike makes everybody's front page, but only leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s passage of a welfare reform bill
that would for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever subject state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to strict time
limits and work requirements, along with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX> measure that would ban
from the rolls for life anyone convicted of a drug felony. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with word that "a federal
advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> has decided to recommend abolishing the troubled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immigration and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naturalization Service</ENAMEX> and assigning its duties to other government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>."
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s decision to
sign an executive order <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this week</TIMEX> dramatically broadening the ban on
smoking in the federal workplace.

            The presidential smoking ban would, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , "set a standard
policy across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and extend existing prohibitions to places
currently exempt, such as military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX>." Some exceptions would
remain, such as military <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX> and "undercover, military or diplomatic
situations that are essential to accomplish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> missions." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spies</ENAMEX>, thank
God, can still smoke.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a front-page piece that may signal the beginning of a
major environmental development. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Petroleum</ENAMEX>, the world's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest
oil company, announced that "there is now enough scientific evidence to warrant
concern about whether human activity--primarily the burning of fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuels</ENAMEX>
like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal</ENAMEX>, oil and natural gas--is changing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>'s climate." This is a break
from oil and gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' monolithic denial of a global warming problem and
thus may have policy ripples akin to the separate catalytic course taken in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tobacco</ENAMEX> and health issues by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liggett Myers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> front features a behind-the-scenes account of the
negotiations leading to the budget deal. Top revelations include that at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> was so stressed out that he went off his diet, and that at
another, he successfully smoothed over ruffled <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> feathers by sending
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">inscribed</TIMEX> copies of his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books. Also, in one phone call, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasich</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hilley</ENAMEX> that, "...if we don't get a deal by
the beginning of the recess, I'm [expletive] coming over and burning your house
down!"

            In other congressional news, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's main front-page feature takes a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-year-later</TIMEX> look at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>'s reform of doing away with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> deliveries to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>, a move that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> claimed saved <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>. It turns
out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> is still being distributed, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> wonders how
any savings have been accomplished since the delivery work is now done, not by
the maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> who used to do it--and who still watch over the ice
and log its movements--but by higher-paid congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page piece describes the efforts being made on behalf of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Shabazz</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> and family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Dinkins</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Percy Sutton</ENAMEX>, revealing that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, in attempting to favorably work out
details of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shabazz</ENAMEX>'s upcoming juvenile sentence, have been "sharing the back
seat of a chauffeured black <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX>,...combing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for a place secure
enough to satisfy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, therapeutic enough to satisfy the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrists</ENAMEX>
and academic enough to satisfy their ambitions..." The paper quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sutton</ENAMEX> as
saying, "I tell him he can be a king, he can go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Point</ENAMEX>, he can do
anything he wants if we can get through this problem we have now." But the
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year old</TIMEX> wants something else, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> --to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
