
   
   
      
         
            Scams and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smokes</ENAMEX>

            Corruption and cigarettes dominate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. There's even corruption involving
cigarettes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the call by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> union
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James P. Hoffa</ENAMEX> for a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> to look into
allegations that union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> may have
been illegally funding each other in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with rampant abuses of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
employment disability system. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page "World Wide" news box refers
cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> now under increasing restrictions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> should not be
allowed to expand into other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with a lengthy expose charging that the world's largest tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>
are selling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX>' worth of cigarettes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each year</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> who funnel them into the black market. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead is that according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX> projections, a steady
rise in births and a continuing stream of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> will add <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 18 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s population by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2025</TIMEX>.

            Although the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> deny doing anything to abet the smuggling of
their product, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> piece surveys recent criminal cases in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> that show otherwise. The reason this is an important story is
directly connected to the WHO <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s remarks. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> can't regulate
the illegal inflow of cigarettes into their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, they can't generate
effective health programs for discouraging smoking, especially, notes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , because smuggled smokes tend to be cheaper, which means teenagers
can buy more of them.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front page has a story sure to further turn up the
temperature about the ease with which potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> of dubious backgrounds
have gained access to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. It seems that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> of a Ponzi
scheme based on jewelry sales were, through a third-party political donation to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>, able to wangle a photo op with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and then used the
resulting photo in their promotional literature to snare more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is using the occasion of the recent takeover of many
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">departments</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> by a new governing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> as an
opportunity to look carefully at some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> messes that need cleaning up.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s lead details how since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> has spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $170</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> on salaries and long-term medical expenses on city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who file
disability claims. The article reveals that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> allows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to
file false claims with virtual impunity, because of generous rules and a lack
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>. Often <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> never have to go any further to get the money
rolling in than getting a note from their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>.

            A letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> provides a picturesque example of
the mentality that drives many such a problem inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> happened to be in a city water department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to discuss a water
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> when she noticed what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> were drinking from a large commercial
tank supplied for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>'s use--imported bottled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
