
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani Time</ENAMEX>

            At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the formal sentencing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>
leads. This is also the top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with a follow-up to a story the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>--that the general public
tends to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strikers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the unfolding scandal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> police brutality case,
supporting it with a second front-page piece on the political dangers the case
presents to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> and with a big photo of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> hulking cops standing
in front of the precinct <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> where the abuse allegedly occurred, looking
none too friendly.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> appearance was brief, low-key, and enigmatic. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says
the convicted bomber appeared "animated and jovial" until right before he was
formally sentenced. When given the opportunity to address the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, he cited a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> dissent by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Brandeis</ENAMEX>, saying, "Our government
is the potent, the omnipresent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>. For good or ill, it teaches the whole
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by its example." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that adjacent unquoted
passages from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brandeis</ENAMEX> make a very clear point--that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> may not
commit crimes to enforce the law, but nobody wonders why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> opted for the
murky portion instead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has the detail that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> quoted the
opinion from memory.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> scandal is a tremendous hazard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>, who was swept
into office promising tougher law enforcement, a promise his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is
widely believed to have kept. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the need for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> to distance himself from the cops on this one was made paramount by the
news that during the rampage one of the abusers in blue shouted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>,
"This is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> time..."

            With cops sodomizing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> making big news, you'd think that in the city
that had to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> for beating up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX>, the new police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> might
use the occasion of his first policy announcement to address the serious
subject of police conduct. But what the hey, this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>, so instead he's on
the front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> debuting a new departmental program that will
use medals and financial incentives to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to drop those ugly excess
pounds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> plays right into all this lookism, describing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> it
quotes as "fit-looking" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> himself as "<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 feet</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">2 inches</NUMEX> and...a lean
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">210</NUMEX> pounds."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs a follow-up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bombshell</ENAMEX> about the existence
prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> of a classified report indicating clear hazards to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> of bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>. It asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Schwarzkopf</ENAMEX>
about the report. He tells the paper he never saw it, and that he repeatedly
received assurances that there was no hazard of this sort. The article goes on
to quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Powell</ENAMEX> as saying that he doesn't recall the report and couldn't
comment about whether he actually received it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX> of the benefits of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-approved tax bill flow to the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of earners and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">78</NUMEX>
percent go to the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>.

            Not too long ago, "respectable" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> steadfastly
ignored cyber <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, even as they were openly referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloids</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> for front-page stories. But a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> bothers to
advise Internet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> to be more careful with his facts in the
future. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> saga has legs--after all, it could be the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> Internet libel suit, with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> connection, no less.

         
      
   
