
   
   
      
         
            Cunanan the Barbarian

            This is the kind of news day when it's nice to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> .
Because that way, you don't have to lead with a proposed youth health insurance
plan (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s New York
Times ), with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>'s acceptance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing/McDonnell</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas</ENAMEX> merger (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ), or even with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> seeking calm
among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). You can lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cunanan</ENAMEX>.

            Below the "important" stories, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cunanan</ENAMEX> does get front-page space at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and most of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Report</ENAMEX>" inside at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . The story presented a challenge to all the east coast papers,
breaking as it did just about at closing time. At about the time the cops were
zipping up the body bag, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> was describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunanan</ENAMEX> as "now a
phantom"--but meaning he was still on the loose. Most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s accounts have
been substantially rewritten between editions and the final versions still
feature a lot of sourcing to television broadcasts. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> could
cut right to the (end of the) chase: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Serial Killing Suspect Cunanan Is Found</ENAMEX>
Dead in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami Beach</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that in a private caucus meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> has explained that there is a single line of authority in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and that he is it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> called the intrigues of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>
"childish, silly and self-destructive." Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s attitude, there will
apparently be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> more meeting among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to discuss the
events of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry J.Hyde</ENAMEX> tells the
Post why he's looking forward to the session: "The entertainment
value."

            The middle top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> front page is dominated by details from
memos turned over to congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, apparently from the files of
former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX>, which illustrate the extremely
active role <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> had in their re-election campaign's
fundraising. The story is topped by a large picture of portions of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the
memos.

            A tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front informs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon/CIA</ENAMEX> study
concludes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> may have been exposed to nerve gas
during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>. The story itself is on page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A12</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has a story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about a program that sends troubled kids
from inner city <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>. The piece opens with "before"
and dramatically improved "after" writing samples by a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who just
returned from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> there. He'll be going back. (Was there some good reason,
by the way, why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> couldn't bring itself to mention that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the program are black?)

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> last year
to set up vending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operatons</ENAMEX> are so disgruntled by the financial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX> they
took--they've filed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 200</NUMEX> lawsuits in local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX>--that after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cleared Richard Jewell</ENAMEX>, it began wondering if the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> bombing could have
been the work of an outraged <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vendor</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page continues to turn the heat up on an issue nobody
cares about--keeping foxhunting legal in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time in two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. And for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time, by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>. Hmmm--plotting problems with
their current projects?

         
      
   
