
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Indis Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">We Have a Winner</ENAMEX>!

            The editorial page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> enters
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Indis</ENAMEX> (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intellectual Dishonesty</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>
for its persistent refusal to make note in its coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s
rape allegations that a key corroborating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> has a serious potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grudge</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>: Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> had his sentence commuted by
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            "You will note that my piece reported <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
editorial page's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Rabinowitz</ENAMEX> writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Er</ENAMEX>, whoops, that's
right. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Previously Chatterbox</ENAMEX> had suggested that the existence of the
additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> had gone unreported until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> broadcast.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> acknowledges and regrets this error.) These <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>
they heard Broaddrick talk about the alleged rape around the time it allegedly
occurred in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> is better than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, and the number does
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diminish</ENAMEX>, somewhat, the significance of any potential grudge that may be held
by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them. (Or, actually, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> will get to that in a
bit.) Still, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page should have mentioned the
potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grudge</ENAMEX>--if not in its initial story then in one of the two follow-ups
that have appeared since--just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX> did in their more responsible coverage.

            (This might be a good moment to review <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chatterbox</ENAMEX>'s scoring procedure. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's editorial page scored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point for the original
omission in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX> piece; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> points for the continued omission in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> follow-ups; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> more points for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> of publication since
the original offense. That's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Ten</NUMEX> gets you into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indis Hall</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fame</ENAMEX> . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty</NUMEX> points gets you a faxed likeness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Stalin</ENAMEX>.)

            Incidentally, in overlooking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabinowitz</ENAMEX>'s mention of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> also overlooked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabinowitz</ENAMEX>'s inaccurate description of them. "They
[i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>] had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> giving corroborating testimony--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> with
nothing to gain [<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">italics mine</ENAMEX>] and possibly much to lose by going
public," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rabinowitz</ENAMEX> wrote on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>. Nothing to gain? What about
vengeance? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Kelsey</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> had his sentence commuted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelsey</ENAMEX> is the only witness
who allegedly saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the alleged rape, and witnessed the
bruised lip, torn panty hose, etc.) Another was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Kelsey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. Based on
what we know, then, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> can really be said to
have "nothing to gain."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anagram</ENAMEX> update: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Tunstall-Pedoe</ENAMEX>, who maintains the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Anagram Genius</ENAMEX> site (and
whose own name sounds like an anagram for something else) informs Chatterbox
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anagram</ENAMEX> praised in this space <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> (see "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beyond</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'God</ENAMEX>' and 'Dog' ") is one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Eiger</ENAMEX>. Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eiger</ENAMEX> published his
discovery in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1998</TIMEX> edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Puzzlers' League</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Enigma</ENAMEX> .

            As a tribute to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eiger</ENAMEX>'s achievement, and to the distinguished reportage
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> ranked--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Rabinowitz</ENAMEX> and several other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>--as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> best works of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX> journalism,
Chatterbox offers the following anagrams for "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Harvest of Shame</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s justly
celebrated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> documentary on migrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> (anagrams courtesy of Anagram
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genius</ENAMEX>):

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hash Fearsome TV</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haves Hate Forms</ENAMEX>

            Oh! Save the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farms</ENAMEX>

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
