
   
   
      
         
            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> Press

            Not a lot of consensus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on the top story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the situation on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mir</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> goes
with the push for new ways to keep sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> away from the rest of us even
after they've done their time, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> chooses a review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s
just-concluded term.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also does a front-page review of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s
performance, emphasizing the many ways in which its decisions stymied positions
near and dear to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's treatment focuses not
on the political, but the personal, noting that in considering medically
assisted suicide, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justices</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> no doubt drew on their own
brushes with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, and that for the decision overturning suppression of
cyberporn, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> logged on to the Internet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also reports
that by the time the last of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s decisions was announced, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> had already left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> give above-the-fold treatment to the tax
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> just passed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's take sees the big
picture of the budget deficit and of the long-term prospects for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, and credits those who worked on the bill with "political
nerve" while finding the budget process <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> marked by a "notable
credibility." This is just what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> doesn't find. It sees the bills
as a triumph of "small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX>," noting that they contain special provisions
for the likes of "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bakery companies</ENAMEX>, apple cider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distillers</ENAMEX>, low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>,
luxury boaters, sky-diving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructors</ENAMEX> and even whaling captains." Not to
mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX>'s efforts on behalf of arrow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also goes top of the fold with the story of how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>, hoping for new overseas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>, are lobbying
both here and abroad for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> expansion. A sample revelation: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral Space and Communications</ENAMEX>, personally donated
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$601,000</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1996</TIMEX> election cycle.

            And by the way, exactly what point is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> making about new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> in the following paragraph<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>
pushed numerous policies on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s agenda before being banished
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in a sex scandal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>. 'Sidney,' he said, 'is
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">well-positioned</ENAMEX> to play much the same role that I did.'"

         
      
   
