
   
   
      
         
            Burying the Lead

            At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the top story is that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">safety experts</ENAMEX> are concerned that a
new soon-to-be-mandatory emissions control device could start fires in crashes.
At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
the lead is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s ban on public program racial preferences goes
into effect, and it's accompanied by a big picture of a protest march organized
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> proceeding across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Golden Gate Bridge</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> it's that many top jobs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration remain unfilled. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with developments in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cardinal</ENAMEX> sin of news reporting is downplaying the real news of a
story--this is known as "burying the lead" and once upon a time it was
considered an even bigger disaster for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> than having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> not get
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">into Sidwell Friends</ENAMEX>. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> not one, but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> do it, and with the
same story, no less. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's lead is that senior <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
including former special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX>, have supported
using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to defend the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republic</ENAMEX>, Biljana
Plavsic, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hard-liners</ENAMEX> tried to overthrow her. Then the piece goes on to say
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> have helped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plavsic</ENAMEX> consolidate her control over her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and broadcast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> and that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, while continuing to conduct that
campaign, they got into a violent confrontation with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demonstrators</ENAMEX>. But the story delays the news that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> were
wounded in the melee until after the "jump"--the continuation of the story on
an inside page. But wait!--there is another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> story on the LAT
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front</ENAMEX>, near the lead, in column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>, just a little lower down. Yet its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headline</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">US Soldiers Clash with Irate Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX>," doesn't mention the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX>, and the piece itself doesn't get to them until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the third</TIMEX>
paragraph. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> downplays the casualties as well, running its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>
story at the bottom of the front page, omitting mention of them in its
headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bosnian Serb's Backers Stone American Troops"</ENAMEX>--and not getting to
them in the piece until the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> paragraph. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Headline</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX>, please note:
not mentioning the known outcome is like saying "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees Played Red Sox</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> plays the story lower on its front page, but gets
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">casualties</ENAMEX> into the headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2 G.I.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Are Hurt Confronting Pro</ENAMEX>-Karadzic
Bosnian <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbs</ENAMEX>."

            The really big story on the USAT front is the revelation that the
provision in the new budget bill that allows tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to reduce their
liability in smoking-related lawsuits by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 billion</NUMEX> was written by.the tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. "The industry wrote it and submitted it, and we just used their
language,'' is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Kies</ENAMEX>, staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Committee on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taxation</ENAMEX>, is quoted as saying.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> column is another in his recent series of pieces
excoriating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX>. He tells the story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who falls in love
with and marries an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> while on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitor</ENAMEX>'s visa and after getting some
bad advice from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> while her application for a
permanent visa is still pending. The result? She ends up in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and then is deported. So far the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> has burned up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> in legal
fees over this, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had to abandon his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> here to rejoin his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. "Is anyone in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX>," wonders <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>, "ready to call our tin-pot
immigration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX> to account?

            And right next to that piece is an op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-based public ethics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">maven Charles Lewis</ENAMEX>. For those inclined to cut <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Espy</ENAMEX> some slack because
he's only charged with taking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX> worth of stuff, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> makes the point
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">poultry</ENAMEX> and processing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Espy</ENAMEX> was once supposed to be looking
out for make, on average, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,374</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
