
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Line King</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s intent to use the line-item veto <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
ever leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and gets front-page play at the other
majors. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the standstill in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS/Teamster</ENAMEX> talks and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>'s increasing involvement in them.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the renewed shuttle diplomacy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Maddux</ENAMEX>'s new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$57.5 million</NUMEX>
contract.

            Last week <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> announced his intent to use the line-item veto
on some provisions of the budget and tax legislation just enacted, but by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s accounts, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> of scrutiny revealed that this was easier said
than done--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports, for instance, that a tax break concerning
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee</ENAMEX> stock ownership plans and another concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> were dropped
because they had been agreed to during the budget negotiations with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
Except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> come up with various predictions about
which provisions will get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>, but they agree that the choices will be
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the bill's tax breaks benefiting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> or fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>.

            Perhaps the most worrying detail of the attempt to get negotiations between
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Authority</ENAMEX> jump-started is this remark of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ezer Weizman</ENAMEX>'s reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> : "We will do everything
to avoid going into a hot conflict, and right now I fear it's headed in that
direction."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> piece uses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korea Air</ENAMEX>
crash in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guam</ENAMEX> as the point of departure for a general discussion of airline
safety. The story notes that some types of accidents that used to plague
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>, such as wind <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shear</ENAMEX> and midair collisions, have
become much less common, but accident rates for approach and landing remain
high.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's cover story is a fairly optimistic look at welfare reform one
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year later</TIMEX>, which notes that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1.2 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got off the rolls
within the reform<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'s first eight months</TIMEX>. That's a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a day,
twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>'s pace. "The most noteworthy aspect of welfare reform
so far is," the piece explains, "what hasn't happened. Poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> threatened
by the new law, the most sweeping changes since federal welfare was created in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>, have not flooded child welfare rolls, homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shelters</ENAMEX>, food pantries or
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup kitchens</ENAMEX>." But at this point, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , this is all attibutable to
the soaring economy and no one knows what will happen when it falters.

            A piece inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out that the current spate of political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fundraising</ENAMEX> scandals has been a boon to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. (The only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> who haven't
profited during the late unpleasantness are those who left deep-pile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> to
work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX>. They've taken pay cuts.) For
"are already <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.5 million</NUMEX>--nearly triple the amount of questionable
contributions the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>' legal costs
have included <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $800,000</NUMEX> for copying and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> in document
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retrieval</ENAMEX> and scanning. And, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , this is a bipartisan
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX> testified <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>, he was accompanied by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> billing at an
aggregate rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> an hour.

         
      
   
