
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> Buffet

            What's news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>? Depends on which of the majors you pick up. They each
have a different top story and they each ignore or bury inside what their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">competitors lead</ENAMEX> with. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the revelation that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> has granted immunity from prosecution to a top research
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson</ENAMEX> create a tobacco strain with an
especially high level of nicotine. The move means that despite the proposed
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$360 billion</NUMEX> litigation settlement deal, the feds are still proceeding with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> probe into the tobacco industry. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that grand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">juries</ENAMEX>
have been convened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> to look into possible
wrongdoing by cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and their trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX>, and that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> has mounted a special tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX>. What's really weird is you just
know some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> are taking breaks from sifting through company
documents and interviewing industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whistleblowers</ENAMEX> to go have a smoke.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the news that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> after vowing to overhaul its citizenship
program, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> is "still struggling to put new procedures in place to prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> with criminal records from becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>." Meanwhile,
applications for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizenship</ENAMEX> are on the rise, so the waiting time for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> to hear back has doubled to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a year</TIMEX>. It doesn't help that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over a third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s field <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are not linked to its computer
database.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the report that in a speech
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> held open the possibility that he will order <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> to remain in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> in some peacekeeping capacity even after the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> mission of which they are a part is terminated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. Defending <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
participation in the effort thus far, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said, "It's been much less
expensive and much less hazardous to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> than a resumption of full-scale
war would be."

            A little further down on the page, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> saying
that before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX> opened his hearings with the charge that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
had funneled money into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> election campaigns, his "statement was cleared.by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Agency</ENAMEX>."

            The top left-hand piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> recounts the struggle of tiny
(pop. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montoursville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> to put the pieces back together after
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sixteen</ENAMEX> of its young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> were killed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> aboard <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX>
Flight <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">800</NUMEX>. Initially, the high school that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> attended tried
to avoid dwelling on the tragedy via such measures as removing from circulation
any textbooks with their signatures in them. But school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> eventually
accommodated the desires of surviving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to be protected less and used a
showcase in the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> for weeklong displays about each crash <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> remarks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Copenhagen</ENAMEX>, and the WP
quotes some of the toast he made at a dinner there hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX>'s royal
family. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rasmussen</ENAMEX> on her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s side, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treasury secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Bentsen</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dane</ENAMEX>." Now there's a close cultural connection. Much better to just admit, "I
got my management style from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
