
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Husbands</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Wives</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> feels a little dense for not realizing sooner that the subtext
(and hence much of the appeal) of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Giuliani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race
would be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wronged Wife</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neglectful Husband</ENAMEX>. By running against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> (who
has been reported in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX>--he denies it--and,
by all accounts, has a sham marriage), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX> could exact symbolic
revenge on her philandering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> while advancing the fortunes of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> at the same time! That's almost enough for Chatterbox
to jump on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bandwagon.

            The media conventional wisdom is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> would make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
marital problems a major campaign issue. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> look like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">patsy</ENAMEX>," cried <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. But, er, wouldn't that be kind of a risky
strategy, given his own problematic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>? Many have already opined that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> is too vituperative, too much of a loner to practice the congenial,
teamwork-oriented politics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>; other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doubters</ENAMEX> have pointed to his
hardhearted, uncaring social policies. The last thing he needs is to draw more
attention to these qualities in his personal life.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX>'s estrangement from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Hanover</ENAMEX>, is made clear in an
interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanover</ENAMEX> that appears in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanover</ENAMEX> "would not say
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> would run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, whether she would like him to run
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, or whether she would campaign for him if he did. But she did say in
the interview, which was conducted before the recent frenzy of speculation
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>'s interest in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat, that
Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is a 'very interesting' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. 'I think she's dynamic, and I
think she's very smart, and she's an amazing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>,' Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanover</ENAMEX> said." And,
for a punch line: "Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanover</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press secretary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joannie Danielides</ENAMEX>, said this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> that Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanover</ENAMEX> had no comment on Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s potential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
campaign." Does she have any comment on whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ms. Hanover</ENAMEX> plans to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indis</ENAMEX> Index 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Update</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX> broadcast
last night, turned up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an additional three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> who recall being told by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1970s</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> raped her. This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">diminishes</ENAMEX>-- slightly-- the significance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Kelsey</ENAMEX>'s possible
motives in verifying parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s story. (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsey</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>, whose motives can be similarly questioned; the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> heard
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> tell her story but did not see her bruised lip, as only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelsey</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> claim to have.) However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, like
every other responsible news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> that's covered this story, reported
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Kelsey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s killer was pardoned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, and
remains perplexed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page won't. Its Indis
Index is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>.
            

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi Kantor</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
