
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sterility: What Did He Think, When Did He Think It</ENAMEX>

            Perhaps the most puzzling element to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s story, as related
on the editorial page of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 18</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , is her claim
that after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> allegedly raped her in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, "he looked down at her and
said not to worry, he was sterile--he had had mumps when he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>." (See
"Proving
Rape," <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"More</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proving Rape</ENAMEX>," and "Even More
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Proving Rape</ENAMEX>." ) Subsequent events (e.g., the birth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX>)
suggest that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did say this, he was lying. That wouldn't do
much to prove or disprove <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s rape accusation, but it's mildly
interesting to think about in the context of what we know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mendacity</ENAMEX>.

            It may be, however, that (assuming he really said it) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> really
did think in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> that he was sterile. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James B. Stewart</ENAMEX>, a
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>,
published a book about the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandals called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blood Sport</ENAMEX> . On pages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">66, 80</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">81</NUMEX> of the hardcover
edition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> reports that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> were "trying to conceive. It
seemed to be a subject of considerable anxiety for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>, who worried out
loud to a few close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that she might find it impossible to become
pregnant because of a medical condition." Although that sentence seems to imply
it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> who was presumed to have the "medical condition," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stewart</ENAMEX>
doesn't really say. If it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> who was thought sterile, conceivably
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> wouldn't have wanted to admit that even to close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>, because he
was running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> at the time in a campaign that emphasized his youth
and vigor. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>'s account, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> continued to fret about
their ability to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX> even considered visiting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> learned she was pregnant--famously, while they were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prompting Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> to sing, while strolling through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joni</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitchell</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chelsea Morning</ENAMEX>."

            So: Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> really did think he was sterile when he
allegedly raped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>. That tells us <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> had access to a
fairly intimate detail about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s sex life--which she might have
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">gotten 1</ENAMEX>) after being raped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) before or after having
consensual sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>; or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">3</NUMEX>) while reading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blood Sport</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is ready to concede that there is a little more evidence
supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s story than there was when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX> broke it. In addition to the sterility business, there are, as previously
noted here, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> who say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> told them of the rape
back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>. (This was reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">page</ENAMEX>, writing before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> interview aired, accused of expending too much
effort trying to check out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s story.) There are also <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s suspiciously sullen, give-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">no</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX>-details-than-necessary denials;
apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s finger-wagging days are over. (Of course, no one is
likely to believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> no matter what he says.) But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> remains
pessimistic that he will ever be able to draw a truly responsible
conclusion about whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> raped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita Broaddrick</ENAMEX>. Moreover, since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> has already concluded that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, being morally unfit to
remain in office, should resign, he doesn't really know how his political world
view would change--beyond, of course, concluding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was an even
bigger creep than he thought--in the unlikely event <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> could
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">verify Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s story. (It's too late for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> herself to take any
legal action.)

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> is wondering when the news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> of the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> will write about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> controversy. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Murray</ENAMEX> was right not to break <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juanita</ENAMEX>'s story, now that it's "out
there," the news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is in an awkward position. Clearly, the best way for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> to write about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX> would be the way the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> have--partly sifting
evidence concerning a widely publicized accusation, and partly examining the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ethics</ENAMEX> and motives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's editorial page for printing it in
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. But while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> remains free to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report on Broaddrick</ENAMEX>, it is presumably not free to really report on
(i.e., question the ethics and motives of) the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's editorial
page.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
