
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puppy Alibi</ENAMEX>

            The tentative settlement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and tops the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page news digest. (The strike
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> does not make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-edition front, nor oddly, that of the
paper with the most time to handle the late-breaking story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times .) The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads with the widening probe into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> police
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">brutality</ENAMEX> case, which, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, produced the arrests of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more cops
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and which will now include a federal civil rights investigation. The
decision by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> in the largest breast implant class action
suit to date that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Chemical Co.</ENAMEX> knew that silicone was potentially harmful
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and conspired to withhold relevant safety data from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> gets a lot
of front-page play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An</ENAMEX> award of actual damages will require the further
showing that actual harm resulted.) But it leads the home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicone</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .

            In a sort of law of conservation of implants, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> also
brings word that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has just approved a new kind of surgical implant for
hands that is said to allow quadriplegics to grasp and release objects.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> has this story on its front page too.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> deal is for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> contract that increases
the base wage for part-timers and expands the number of full-time slots yet
maintains the current multi-employer pension plan structure, although,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , with some changes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> wouldn't
describe. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> have also just reached a
contract with the unionized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> at its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>, who have been handling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike logistics, had been in difficult
negotiations with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> over wages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says relations remain
tense at union <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> despite the accord.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that as a result of the NYC
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brutality</ENAMEX> scandal, all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">38,000</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s cops will be required over the next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three or four hours</TIMEX> meeting with community <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> to
discuss police behavior. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of the beaten
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> announced plans to file a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55 million</NUMEX> lawsuit against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>. The
Times coverage seems particularly well wired inside the
investigation--it reveals that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> arrested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Wiese</ENAMEX>,
denied involvement and moreover originally seemed to cooperate in implicating
other cops. The paper states that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiese</ENAMEX> claimed to be playing with an abandoned
puppy elsewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station house</ENAMEX> when the attack allegedly took place.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> sports section reports that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> have complained to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Mets</ENAMEX> are using video cameras positioned at
various points around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shea Stadium</ENAMEX> to steal their signs. The story states
something that is probably not known by many a serious baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>--namely,
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> rules do not address sign-stealing, and that no one has ever been
ejected from a game or suspended for engaging in the practice.

         
      
   
