
   
   
      
         
            Be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Magnet Like Bill</ENAMEX>!!!

            Lonely? Depressed? <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Overweight</ENAMEX>? Given up hope that babes would give a
loser like you the time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX>? DON'T GIVE UP!!!! Hi, I'm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Morton</ENAMEX> , and I want to share a few presidential pickup
lines that REALLY, REALLY work! They're 
                  actual quotes
               
from my new book , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monica's Story</ENAMEX> , available at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain bookstores</ENAMEX> now ! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> used every last
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of 'em! Try them and I promise you'll be beating chix back with a
stick! *

            

               "
                     Come on in here for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> ."

               "
                     Come into the back office ."

               "
                     If you want to meet me back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">George's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or ten</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> you can ."
               

               
                  "What kind of a name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, anyway<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"
               

               
                  "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kiddo</ENAMEX>."
               

               
                  "Did you get the picture of me in the tie?"
               

               
                  "You look really skinny."
               

               
                  "I saw you in the hall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. You looked really skinny."
               

               
                  "You have no idea what a gift it is to me to get to spend time with you
and talk to you. I cherish the time we spend together. It's very lonely here
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't really understand that."
               

               
                  "I've been sick about it [i.e., the death of the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">serviceman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>] . 
                  
                     It's really hard to know that
someone died because of your executive order."
                  
               

               
                  
                     "Just like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX>'s
                   [i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s combat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boots</ENAMEX>]
                     ." 
                  
               

               
                  
                     "He's such a jerk
                   [i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Bleiler</ENAMEX>, her previous married
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>] ." 
                  
               

               
                  
                     "I don't ever want you to feel that way
                   [i.e., that
the relationship is purely sexual]
                     . That's not what this
is."
                  
               

               
                  
                     "Don't worry, I'm going to take care of you. I don't want you to be
unhappy."
                  
               

               
                  
                     "I wish you were here to give me a big hug."
                  
               

               
                  
                     "She
                   [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>] 
                     would have liked you. You are
very much alike."
                  
               

               
                  
                     "You looked stunning."
                  
               

               
                  
                     "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hi</ENAMEX>, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Bill</ENAMEX>. I have laryngitis."
                  
               

               
                  
                     "Try a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Little Tenderness</ENAMEX>"
                   [sung] .
               

               
                  
                     "Wait, just wait. Be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. Be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>. This
                   [Leaves of
Grass] 
                     is for you."
                  
               

            

            
               *
               The only catch is that first you have to get elected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>
               .
            

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
