
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Means Streets</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> to give up on
proposing a means test for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> premiums is the top story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . Surprisingly, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
this doesn't even make the front page. The lead there is the report being
released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> which sharply criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> for its
treatment of religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also
continues ample front-page coverage of the just-discovered deaf <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX> ring. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with "color"--coverage of the 200th
anniversary celebration of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX>'s oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warship</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> move shows that premiums are still a political third
rail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tex.</ENAMEX>) and many others feared that by tampering with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
premiums, they would rekindle <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> charges that they were 'cutting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>' to pay for tax cuts." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says he supports means
testing but only if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> can collect the extra premium, and that's not going
to happen either. This non-decision along with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> prior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
non-moves--not adjusting the eligibility age and not charging any co-payments
for home health-care--means the current budget deal will not be the vehicle for
any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> restructuring.

            In a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" section piece about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> have taken to turning on
each other, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> reveals that "when the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> declared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> was in danger of becoming 'inconsequential,' the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>
sent every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> a letter saying he was disappointed in
them." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> editorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> Fund's reaction: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A</ENAMEX>
lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have grown up with this liberal media culture and are
suspicious of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, so they have an exaggerated expectation of the few
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> they have. They don't understand the distinctions. They don't get it."
Maybe Fund doesn't either--he recently came close to taking a job as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>.

            How are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> handling the problem of delivering health care to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that increasingly has difficulty paying for it or getting insurance
to do so? Well, according to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s front section cover story in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ,
one thing they're doing is delivering it to more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>. "More precisely,
well-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> who are willing and able to pay top dollar for care they
either can't get at home or prefer to get in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> are making
aggressive marketing and service moves in this direction. For instance,
Muslim prayer <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> manned a
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arab Health Expo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dubai</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Arab Emirates</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is carrying an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story inside <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> stating that, despite
initially agreeing to be questioned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>, has now, like him, decided to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 5th</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Amendment</ENAMEX>. Also, she has
invoked the spousal privilege, which protects her from being questioned about
conversations with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>.

            This from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86 percent</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>
surveyed say the quality they value most in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX> is loyalty. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only 6</NUMEX>
percent say it's integrity.

         
      
   
