
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Rules</ENAMEX>

            Everybody leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s historic use of the line-item veto.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> rules have changed for good," is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> line quoted all
around. Other staples in the coverage by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
include: the amount of money saved by the veto--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $600 million</NUMEX>--doesn't
make a dent in the budget deficit, there was much internal administration
debate about whether to use the veto, and its use <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> is almost sure to
end up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> case.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> said through a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s action was "petty politics" even though he has been
a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> of the line-item veto.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a second front-page line-item story suggesting that the
excitement over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s action is probably premature: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s use of his
new veto powers simply means the old game will now require a bit more skill."
The line-item law limits the veto to tax measures benefiting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 100</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, and the paper notes, it shouldn't be hard to make sure special
deals favor say, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX>. On the spending side, the trick will be to group the
contested provision together with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> favors within a single line
item. The availability of this gambit is also noted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead editorial takes a strong stand against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LIV</ENAMEX>, calling
it a "benighted" idea.

            The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>-wonder entrepreneurs
have run into an unanticipated problem: being under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX> means they have to pay
exorbitant surcharges to rent <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> for business travel, or take the bus even.
The solution: their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> set up corporate rental car accounts for
them.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> brings word that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 12 years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>
killed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled passenger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Klinghoffer</ENAMEX>, by pushing the wheelchair bound
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> off the hijacked cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Achille Lauro</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palestinian Liberation</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> has settled for an undisclosed sum a lawsuit brought by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klinghoffer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Both sides described the resolution as "amicable," which
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says is "strange." What is just as strange is that the
Times states that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> was represented in the case by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramsey Clark</ENAMEX>,
but doesn't mention that he is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX>. Obviously, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> with the burnooses and bazookas have watched car and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> in
action: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLO</ENAMEX> says the settlement is not an admission of wrongdoing.

            One courtroom door closes, another opens. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> plans to sue Internet gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX>
over statements <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> made about him in a recent emailed column. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Drudge Report</ENAMEX>" repeated unattributed allegations that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> "has a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spousal</ENAMEX> abuse past that has been effectively covered up." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Drudge</ENAMEX> retracted the
story <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> he will take
"'appropriate action' unless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> disclose[s] the names of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>."

         
      
   
