
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aides</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says it's the booming dollar. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want
to count heads, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want to use statistical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sampling</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s support of a bill that would bar health
insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> from discriminating against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because of their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>.
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor pilots</ENAMEX>
strike--they're asking for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72 percent</NUMEX> raise to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$195,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> (hence the
term "TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX>?).

            Away from the lead story positions (top right, that is) there is more
agreement about the news. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> each have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front-page</ENAMEX> pieces about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s announcement that primarily because of
treatment advances, deaths from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> continue to drop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. The
point is made though, that worldwide, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> deaths are still increasing, and
will probably continue to do so, because of the difficulties involved in
bringing better therapies to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> give front-page play to another medical story: the development of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">nasal flu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccine</ENAMEX>.

            And those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> has
complained via letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of the just-released space movie
"Contact" about the manipulated use of footage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in the film.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> involved, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>, says it just wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to see the movie
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> before passing judgment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reveals that it was former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> press <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dee Dee Myers</ENAMEX>, a technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> on the film, who
initially gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>-up about the sequences. If so, you have
to wonder why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> didn't have the story too, since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX>'s
significant other is its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> bureau <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Purdum</ENAMEX>.

            A quick point about that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> dollar story. The piece says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
currency is up against most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currencies and down against the yen, and
that both developments are good news for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S</ENAMEX>: "For the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rubin</ENAMEX>, a slumping mark is much
less worrisome than a slumping yen would have been, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> said
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> goes on to explain that the trends mean more buying
power for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the prevention of further deterioration in
the trade balance with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. But it doesn't explain why their other
consequences--less buying power for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and further slippage in
the trade balance with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>--aren't of equal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>.

            According to the front-page "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , workplace equality still has a way to
go when it comes to job-related injuries: <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">71 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32,000</NUMEX> cases of carpal-<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> syndrome involve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, but of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11,308</NUMEX>
amputations, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> involved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
