
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX>

            Political in-fighting, the economy, religion and war--all get their due
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the anger of most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s leading nonprofit advocacy groups
over being subpoenaed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> investigating political
fundraising. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with new reassuring government
statistics on inflation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s imminent
announcement of religion guidelines for the federal workplace. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> has
a big revelation about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s knowledge of the battlefield dangers
posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> chemical stockpiles.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's scoop is that contrary to previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> announcements, a
report was prepared for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> before the outbreak
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> indicating that bombing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s chemical weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> was
"certain" to release deadly nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX> in patterns dangerous to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. Noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> have been seeking such information
for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>, the paper reveals that it was finally released to a former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> in response to his repeated <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Freedom of Information Act</ENAMEX>
requests. The development drew the ire of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Shays</ENAMEX>, who tells
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> that it "indicates a cover-up."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> does a good job of crystallizing the main issue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>
strike--employee pensions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> wants to pull out of the multi-employer
Teamster plan it's in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> in favor of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s proposal,
explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , puts <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Carey</ENAMEX> in a tight spot,
pitting his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, many of whom are attracted to the apparently more
lavish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> proposal, against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> working elsewhere, who fear that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> pull-out could jeopardize their pensions. No wonder, says the paper, that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> tends to downplay the pension debate, saying instead that it's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s heavy use of part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> that is really the core issue. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> suggests that ultimately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> will give on pensions and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> will give on part-timers.

            One thing quite unusual about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> stoppage, observes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , quoting an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC News</ENAMEX> poll and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX>, is that for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> seems to be
siding with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strikers</ENAMEX>. The main reason for the sympathy vote, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , is that "just about everyone knows a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> delivery <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.." (Send
those letters of gender complaint to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> --not here, where a very fit
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in brown shorts visits regularly.)

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , those forthcoming presidential guidelines
about religious expression at government jobs will be rather specific, stating
for instance, that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> "are allowed to wear religious medallions
over their clothes, conduct lunchtime prayer sessions in unused conference
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rooms</ENAMEX>, distribute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proselytizing</ENAMEX> brochures to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> and keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> or
Koran on their desks." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy</ENAMEX>, those lines at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post Office</ENAMEX> will really be a
party now.

            Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>:

            

               Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> can once again purchase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX> . A federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> ruled that a ban on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX> violated
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> rights of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> also
stated that there is no reason to believe that these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> "are any
more or less rehabilitative" than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Illustrated</ENAMEX> swimsuit issue or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Secret catalogue</ENAMEX>.

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that became high-fashion menswear purveyor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo Boss</ENAMEX>
manufactured <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX> uniforms during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX>, probably using slave
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boss spokeswoman</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying, "...We're currently trying to
find what was going on."

            

         
      
   
