
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang Jury</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s news attention is primarily divided between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s decision at its
meetings to expand and the opening of congressional hearings into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign
fundraising irregularities. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s decision to grant membership to former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warsaw Pact</ENAMEX> members
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hungary</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the hearings.

            The general account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> decision is clear: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> doesn't like being
dictated to by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> on the particular choice of the added <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> doesn't like the idea of expansion, period. There is, however, one
little bump in the reporting road regarding other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> business. The WP
sums up discussions among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alliance members</ENAMEX> concerning what to do about the
failure to bring accused <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> war criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radovan Karadzic</ENAMEX> to justice
this way: "They refused to propose any changes in the mandate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>-led
peacekeeping force to hunt down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karadzic</ENAMEX> and others who are wanted to stand
trial at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX> war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>." Does that mean, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> naturally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wonders</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peacekeepers</ENAMEX> are allowed to hunt war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>
or not? Fortunately, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> makes it clear: they are not.

            The papers generally agree that committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thompson</ENAMEX> struck a dramatic note when he opened the proceedings by saying that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have concluded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> tried to influence the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>
presidential campaign, as well as congressional and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> elections, and that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX> was just as dramatic when he announced that the key
figure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundraiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>, was willing to testify
if he is given limited immunity from prosecution. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> takes the minority position that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> carried <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, thanks to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>'s smooth presentation and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' jagged one, which, Dowd
writes, consisted "mostly of arrows pointing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>'s name," and "a
Byzantine theory linking Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo Group</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX>, to the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Fugger</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Augsburg</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothschilds</ENAMEX> and the election of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emperor Charles V</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hapsburgs</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> reviewing the
proposed tobacco industry settlement have concluded it puts too great a
restriction on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s power to regulate nicotine, and thus that this deal is
not likely to receive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s support.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> all run front
page stories about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX> previously healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forties</ENAMEX> who have used
the combination of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> diet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> known as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fen-Phen</ENAMEX> and who have now turned up
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> very rare kinds of heart damage. The drug combination was never
approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> and is believed to be prescribed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 18 million</NUMEX> times a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s immediate reaction: send out a warning letter to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report on their front pages that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Bureau task force</ENAMEX> has proposed a modification in the racial categories it will
use in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year 2000</TIMEX>. Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> can choose from among "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Alaskan Native</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pacific Islander</ENAMEX>," "black," or "white,"
and also from the ethnic categories of "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> origin" and "not of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>
origin." The change would be to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to check <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> race <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">block</ENAMEX>.
This adjustment might, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , significantly affect affirmative
action hiring goals or the boundaries of congressional districts. The paper
goes on to report that "civil rights <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> were generally pleased with the
proposal, particularly because many feared the alternative--adding a separate
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">'mixed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX>' category--would dilute their numbers."

         
      
   
