
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Light</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> all agree: the top story is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s
statement to a congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy is perking along
so nicely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> won't be raising interest rates any time
real soon. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
plays that story above the fold, but reserves its top right spot for the news
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> yesterday renewed his call for means-tested Medicare
premiums. Another bit of news convergence: both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and WP
have front page stories reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>'s major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are publishing
a list <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 2,000</NUMEX> of their dormant <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">WWII-</ENAMEX>era accounts that may include
the assets of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s comments to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Banking</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subcommittee</ENAMEX> were a green light
for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wall St.</ENAMEX>, which responded with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> percent run-up to a new high of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8,061.65</NUMEX>. The only slight damper was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s remark that the money
supply will have to be tightened "at some point to foster sustainable growth
and low inflation." Such comments prompted some committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to criticize
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> for being insensitive to working <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>. Indeed, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , "The true constraint on the economy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>,
is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> does not have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't have jobs...."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s stance on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> comes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> budget
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX>, fearing the election consequences of raising anybody's premiums,
abandoned means testing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s explicit intent is to give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">budgeteers</ENAMEX>
political courage: "I would be happy to defend the vote of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>, who votes for this."

            Much of the current political maneuvering has to do with the trivial-seeming
detail of who gets to collect the extra premiums. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, responding to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> complaints that premium
increases would look like tax increases, also proposed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX>, rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Internal Revenue Service</ENAMEX>, collect the payments for
higher premiums from elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>, who would make the checks out to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Trust Fund</ENAMEX> instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> goes on to quote the
skeptical response of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Archer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX>: "The only collection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> I know at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>." Even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> admits, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> payment suggestion "is a cosmetic solution to a cosmetic
problem."

            In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" piece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Grove</ENAMEX> profiles self-appointed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Carpenter-McMillan</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>-based former
anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activist</ENAMEX>. She tells <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grove</ENAMEX>, "I will never deny that when I first
heard about this case I said, 'Okay, good. We're gonna get that little
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slimeball</ENAMEX>.'" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter-McMillan</ENAMEX> goes on to give her opinion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX>:
"I love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Matalin</ENAMEX>. I don't know what she sees in him. He must be great in
bed."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "Tax Report" states that according to
the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> statistics, the threshold for making it into the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX> is an adjusted gross income of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $195,726</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> mark
is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$91,226</NUMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> figure is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21,802</NUMEX>. The column also reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Schaffer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> opposed to the estate tax, describes
his position as "No taxation without respiration."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>'s column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> today offers a peek at some of the
slogans to be featured in upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC-TV</ENAMEX> spots. Slogans like, "Don't worry,
you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of brain cells."

         
      
   
