
   
   
      
         
            Money Talks

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> raid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . New revelations about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> fundraising lead at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The upholding by a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> of
"<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Megan's Law</ENAMEX>" leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> action, an assault on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banja Luka police HQ</ENAMEX> and several other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police facilities</ENAMEX>, all thought to be centers of support for war criminal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suspect Radovan Karadzic</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biljana Plavsic</ENAMEX>, met
with no resistance and resulted in the confiscation of truckloads of weapons
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karadzic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>. But according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , it nonetheless
represents a "far more muscular, interventionist role" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, which, in the
words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , amounts to "clearly taking sides in an explosive
crisis."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's lead reveals that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last January</TIMEX>, as part of an attempt to woo
a potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had
agreed to decree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> would no longer accept "soft money." But says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> declined, citing family obligations, the idea
went away.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> story, written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Devroy</ENAMEX>,
adds a few more <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">warts</ENAMEX> to the presidential portrait with its revelation that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">45-minute one-on-one</TIMEX> meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Express</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Smith</ENAMEX>, to discuss a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> trade barrier that was costing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX>. And, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">less than three weeks</TIMEX> after
that tete-a-tete, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Express</ENAMEX> gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>, part of a total of
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$275,000</NUMEX> in soft money that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> ponied up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> during the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last</TIMEX> election cycle. This all happened after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was advised in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> memo
to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> personally to solicit a contribution. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> memo, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , advised the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> to "ask him for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150,000</NUMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> that the money contributed "had nothing to do with
the meeting he had with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>." And yet just a few sentences later, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> states, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> said that it would be unwise for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> revenue not to make the requested contributions. 'Sure,
you're darn right, you better be responsive,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> said. 'Whether you use the
language of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and call it a shakedown or whether you just call it our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, however you put it, it's a messy system.'"

            A common <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">press syndrome</ENAMEX> is immense interest in the politics of a bill, but
almost no interest in the workings of the law it becomes. So it's refreshing to
see articles like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> lead, which looks at what happened when
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> tried to hire welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> to gain tax credits under a bill
passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> as part of welfare reform. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX> in theory, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , but in practice, it's very hard for a business to scare up
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">meaningful</ENAMEX> numbers of eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and even harder to retain them for the
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">400 hours</TIMEX> the law requires for the awarding of the credit.

            I must not be cosmonaut material, because I'm drifting in deep space after
just narrowly surviving a collision, a total power failure and a heart problem,
I'm not thinking, okay, let's at least do the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> commercial. But according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , that's exactly what former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vasily Tsibliev</ENAMEX> did.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> long-life <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk product</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tsibliev</ENAMEX> drank on
camera inside the rapidly disintegrating craft says a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450,000</NUMEX> fee was paid to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>. No word on whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tsibliev</ENAMEX> saw any of it.

         
      
   
