
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parsing Kendall</ENAMEX>

            A cry has gone up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to comment less obliquely on Juanita
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s rape charges. Thus far, his only comment has been through his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX>: "Any allegation that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> assaulted Ms.
Broaddrick <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than 20 years ago</TIMEX> is absolutely false." Should the president
provide a little more in the way of explanation? Sure. Will he? Chatterbox
seriously doubts it. Given this harsh reality, how about a little textual
overanalysis of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> offered up? Prospecting for
hidden meaning, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> fed the phrase "absolutely false" to his new
favorite Web site, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Anagram Genius</ENAMEX>. Here are some of the more suggestive anagrams it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spat</ENAMEX> back:

            
                
            

            Anagram: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foul</ENAMEX> beastly sale.

            
               Possible meaning: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> our words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broaddrick</ENAMEX>'s bucking for a book
contract."

            
                
            

            Anagram: Safely able louts.

            
               Possible meaning: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s guilty, but you'll never nail him (or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">us</ENAMEX>) for this."

            
                
            

            Anagram: Flatly abuse lose.

            
               Possible meaning: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had sex with her, but it wasn't rape."

            
                
            

            Angram: Foully steal base.

            
               Possible meaning: "He's guilty."

            
                
            

            Anagram: Yell usable fatso.

            
               Possible meaning: "We don't care what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rush Limbaugh</ENAMEX> says."

            
                
            

            Anagram: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loyal</ENAMEX> felt abuses.

            
               Possible meaning: "You think it's fun working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>?"

            
                
            

            Anagram: A lousy fate bells.

            
               Possible meaning: "The jig is up."

            
                
            

            Anagram: Beauty! so self all.

            
               Possible meaning: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is too narcissistic to remember what
happened."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy Noah</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
