
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican Watershed</ENAMEX>

            Everybody leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> elections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA TODAY</ENAMEX> each put the story at the top right and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> gives
almost the entire right side of its front page to it. And the top of the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World-Wide" News</ENAMEX> column notes "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
Stocks Surge." As of press time, it remains unclear exactly what the balance of
power in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislative branch</ENAMEX> or in the various states will be between the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, but the news is that for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s modern history, there will be a balance of power. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> quotes
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">political scientist</ENAMEX> as saying, "This was a revolution, the beginning of a
new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has another saying, "If votes begin to count in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>, then this is a revolution."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX> on the front above the fold, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> put it inside. What happened there is that one of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>--as established by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>-brokered elections in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>--conducted a coup when the other one was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has delayed
taking sides. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX>'s official
position: "I think the origin of the fighting is sufficiently murky so that we
don't want to shoot arrows at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side or another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>." If nothing else, the
episode allows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> to trot out this foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX>'s staple
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">phrase</ENAMEX> (found, I believe, on key F7): "the capital appeared calm but tense
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>." By the way, what does that actually mean?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's front page "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> rather
interesting items <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. One details that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> federal appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> has
ruled that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> demoted while on maternity leave wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of
pregnancy discrimination. The story notes that a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> federal law bars
discrimination based on "pregnancy, giving birth or a related medical
condition," but that the court ruled that it didn't apply to her case because
caring for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is a gender-neutral "social role," not a condition related
to childbirth. The other item relates how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Mason</ENAMEX>, a self-described
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">numerologist</ENAMEX> and astrologer, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, have asked the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broward County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> to look into why the psychic phone
network where they dispensed visions of the future to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">callers</ENAMEX> had stopped
paying their salaries. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> is investigating. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
wonders why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> didn't see trouble coming.

         
      
   
