
   
   
      
         
            Rush to Fudgement

            The budget deal still dominates. It leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead spot (i.e., top right) is given to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> state budget accord, the
paper's front page is dominated by a large photo of deal players <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>,
Kasich, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Domenici</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> budget-related articles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> decision giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> more
power to fire older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, but has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> budget articles on the front--one
about how the deal might defang <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s welfare reform law, the other about
how it might stimulate real estate sales in such welfare-free zones as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newport</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beach</ENAMEX>.

            The reporting makes it clear that right now, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is too busy
bi-partying--the stories describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> celebrating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Lawn</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> steps--to think much
about the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> after. The papers note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> is one of the few who skipped his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. "This agreement
sacrifices <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s hopes for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s headlines," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> says in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . The deal is expected to be voted into law <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> so that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> can start their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> vacations right on time.

            The front section cover story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Budget Bill Skirts Some Hard</ENAMEX>
Decisions"--does a good job of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">articulating</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX>-style concerns: "Left for
another day are the specifics of which domestic programs will be cut to meet
tight spending targets to balance the budget in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. What's more, the budget's
most serious looming problem--the cost of runaway entitlement programs,
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>--was put aside in favor of yet another bipartisan commission
to study the issue." The piece explains, as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , that the budget
deficit projections for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> have dropped so much because of the strong economy
that it won't take much incremental change to balance the budget for that
target year, which of course won't mean much if the bill's tax cuts then
"explode in cost down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> observe that the deal is
anything but tax simplification. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> calls the bill's tax
provisions "an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500-</NUMEX>a-child tax credit that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
fought so hard to get into the deal was the "crown jewel of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">1994 Contract With America</ENAMEX>," and that in boasting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> about the bill's
college subsidies, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were referring to the same feature they "had
derided <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> as a device for little more than tuition inflation."
In fact, it gets even more confusing: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Kamen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out that
none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> pushing for easing inheritance taxes and capital gains
cuts is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX> (if you don't count their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>), while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> who
had opposed these ideas include "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert E. Rubin</ENAMEX> (worth as
much as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90 million</NUMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erskine B. Bowles</ENAMEX> (who could
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin D. Raines</ENAMEX> (who might top out at a paltry <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX>)."

            Vacations are obviously needed all around at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed desk,
where concept fatigue has broken out big-time. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s humor piece about the
stock market in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2067</TIMEX> has its moments ("'The absence of liquidity is bound to
result in a drop in demand for stocks,' explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang 3d</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman,</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sachs/Time-Warner/Defense Department</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Company</ENAMEX>."), but it's also the third
piece on the page in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two months</TIMEX> based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bogus Fast Forward</ENAMEX>
conceit.

         
      
   
