
   
   
      
         
            Everybody Budges

            It's nearly unanimous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: the big story is an imminent budget deal. The
different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX> is the New York
Times , which gives front page space to the budget story, but leads with
the announcement of new federal aid for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>.

            As even the headlines suggest, there is some variance from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> to paper
about what exactly is happening with the negotiations. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Near</ENAMEX>
Agreement on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> header is: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX> Sees <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Doesn't."

            Even though a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> traveling with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> does
tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that there are still "significant issues" to be resolved,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> cautions that "Those involved in the
talks.describe the emerging deal as fragile and caution it could easily
collapse," the general view in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> is that substantial progress has been
made and that an actual deal could be struck between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as today</TIMEX>, with final passage coming by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.

            And the broad shape of the likely deal is widely described. The LAT
account is typical: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Negotiators</ENAMEX> appeared ready to make the [<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX>-per-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>]
child-care credit available to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had
wanted and more upper-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> had sought. They seemed to
be heading toward a capital gains compromise that would reduce the tax rate but
not shield inflation-generated gains from taxation." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
adds: "And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>
agreed on extending disability benefits to legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> left out by last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s welfare reform law. Both sides also are resigned to an increase in
cigarette taxes to offset costs of health care for uninsured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>."

            What's a little alarming about the budget deal reporting is how
straight-faced the coverage is of its proposed feature of balancing the budget
within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. This was the claim made, if memory serves, for the budget
hashed out between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> in the extended wrangle of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>.
Indeed, wouldn't it be instructive to see a list of all the budgets of recent
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that have had this promised feature?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> story states that the new injection of federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monies</ENAMEX> would require most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3.1 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to join
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of the deal point out that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> has a glut of empty hospital beds and that allowing some of the underused
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">facilities</ENAMEX> to close would cut costs just as well without forcing so many people
into managed care. But the piece also observes that if the free market is
allowed to determine which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> close, poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> are the
likely losers.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX>'s media column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reveals that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>
trotted out by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> just over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week ago</TIMEX> as a specimen of the kind of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who would most benefit from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> tax plan has a swastika tattoo
on his arm. At a press conference featuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trucker</ENAMEX> held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 18th</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Rockefeller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> ornament
was admittedly seen by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and undoubtedly also by others
covering it. And yet, neither <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> did the story, which came out only in the
inside-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> newsletter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Hill</ENAMEX> and on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> radio. In this case,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX>, the press "clearly gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> a pass."

         
      
   
