
   
   
      
         
            Strike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> and Downs

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s most detailed public comment to date about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>
strike along with some signs of progress in the negotiations is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s news
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. The only difference between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> is emphasis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> headlines focus on the increased presidential pressure while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> headline highlights the increasing chances for a
settlement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> emphasizes both with its "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> Says Deal
Near in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Strike</ENAMEX>." Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> gives much high exposure to strike
pessimism: its front-page news digest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> item, after noting the progress, adds
that "both sides indicated they are prepared to escalate the conflict if a deal
isn't reached soon."

            What's driving all this are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two Sunday</TIMEX> developments. First, upon his arrival
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a three-week</TIMEX> stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said, "It's my gut feeling
they'll settle," and called on both sides to "redouble their efforts." And
meanwhile, on separate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> chat shows, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> and of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>
acknowledged progress. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s decision to speak out
was a calculated gambit to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiators</ENAMEX> a push and was also conceived as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">signal</ENAMEX> that he is not neglecting the situation even though he's on
vacation.

            Details in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> coverage include this comment made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> on
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>" that is repeated in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and LAT : "A lot
of.business has gone away and a lot of business isn't coming back." The strike
has made many aware for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time just how central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> has been to the
daily workings of the economy (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of all package delivery) and if this
is true and not just tactical posturing, then that economy is in for a
noticeable change. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> chooses to point out the importance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> by
noting that the because of the strike, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> have complained of being
forced to destroy blood" they couldn't ship and that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of school systems
are worried that they will not receive shipments of books before the school
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> begins." Does that depiction of the strike's impact function as implicit
support for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s position? And if so, is that okay in a news
story?

            Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is a story about pocket lining at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. No,
nothing to do with the travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>--just the little matter
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an estimated 2,600</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> just at the formal dinners there) leaving
a little heavier than when they arrived. Commonly appropriated items include
silverware, plates, and even drapery tassels. The piece tantalizes with the
news that during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camelot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Salinger</ENAMEX> hired a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pickpocket</ENAMEX> to
quietly recover spoons on their way out the door, and that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> was convicted of stealing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $7,000</NUMEX> in presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">china</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, in a piece about new presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Mitchell</ENAMEX> wrote that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> referred to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> with the line, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A beat</ENAMEX> is just an assignment but a slut is who
you've become maybe." Today, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> corrections page says this "was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">truncated</ENAMEX> and misattributed because of an editing error. One word was
incorrectly transcribed, compounding the misimpression." What they're trying to
just barely admit is this: It seems that in fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> had
nothing to do with the quote, that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blumenthal</ENAMEX> said it, but (obviously) not
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> himself, and only via a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> in a work of fiction that he wrote and
that actually that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> didn't use the word "slut" but the word "slot." So
to review the bidding from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> of record": A single sentence
with the wrong subject, the wrong source, and the wrong quote.

         
      
   
