
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Care</ENAMEX> and Carelessness

            Health and social issues make the biggest impression <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> bills passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will fall far short of
their announced goal of guaranteeing health coverage to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now uninsured. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA TODAY</ENAMEX>'s front section main story makes the point that although
the conventional wisdom is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s health care proposal was a
colossal failure, he has actually in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX> gotten <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to pass
many provisions congenial to its concepts, one bill at a time. The piece calls
this development "stealth health" care.

            In its page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> lead feature, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports on a little-noticed consequence of the
cost-cutting brought on by managed care: the rise in free-lance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autopsies</ENAMEX>. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> figuring in the piece, who paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> to an
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pathologist</ENAMEX> (she reached him by dialing <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1-800-AUTOPSY</ENAMEX>) to perform a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-mortem</ENAMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> where her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> died declined to do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, says,
"I really felt like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> was listening to me and my concerns. Every time
I paged him, he returned my call. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> doesn't do that. Not even my pool
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX> does that."

            The lead story in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is a local one that could presage a national
discussion. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland counties</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> passed laws requiring safety locks
to be included with every handgun sale. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also fronts a piece
underlining the intractability of the problem of single motherhood. A
multi-year, rigorous study to be released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> finds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> enrolled in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s best-funded programs for disadvantaged teenaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
still failed to improve their chances of becoming self-sufficient.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> in her column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, maybe the
problem is that too many women these days are sex-addled and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-crazy. In the
course of her protest, she takes her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> swipe in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> at feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">writer Naomi Wolf</ENAMEX> and notes that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Estrich</ENAMEX>, a leading feminist, top expert
on rape law, campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Dukakis</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential</ENAMEX> bid and the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Law Review</ENAMEX>, has written a screenplay with
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty Kaplan</ENAMEX>, about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX> who teaches her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> girlfriends
how to lure and hang on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> by learning erotic techniques." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> concludes
by listing some of the latest offerings from the brand-name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>,
articles like "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild Sex</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">10 Things You Should Have Done by Now</ENAMEX>" and "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Men</ENAMEX>
Tell <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">You How to Flip Their Switches</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
