
   
   
      
         
            The Loan Arranger

            Domestic issues reign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>'s open-ended loan to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>
to help during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the steep decline in the welfare
rolls in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> since welfare reform went into effect--a story <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
already did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">USAT</ENAMEX> leads with findings that a new
heart <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is extremely effective in saving the lives of angioplasty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>.

            However, the whole point of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> piece is that the drug's expense
could limit its availability to only the very sickest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. But it's hard to
evaluate this claim because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's only statement about expense is the
unqualified assertion that the drug "costs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,350</NUMEX>." For how much? And does that
amount yield the life-saving result? (If so, it seems like a bargain.)

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> each report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sweeney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,
announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> affiliated with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> would lend
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX>--to be used for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strikers</ENAMEX>' benefits--for "many,
many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>." Both papers quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweeney</ENAMEX> saying, "Because their fight is our
fight, we are making this strike our strike." The loan shows how high the
stakes are, not just for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>, and for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX>, but also for the entire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Kelly</ENAMEX> responded with the warning that a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-week</TIMEX> strike could mean the layoff of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> and once again
called for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to intervene.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> is losing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $30-$50 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX>, and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the dispute "is on its way to becoming the biggest and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">costliest</ENAMEX> strike in a generation."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> welfare piece includes this statement made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: "But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>, I think it's fair to say the debate is
over. We now know that welfare reform works." There's also mention of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> study's conclusion that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 40 percent</NUMEX> of the decline in welfare rolls
is attributable to the economy, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31 percent</NUMEX> based on state welfare policy
changes, and the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29 percent</NUMEX> being caused by "other factors."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Medical Association</ENAMEX> has agreed for
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time ever to allow its name to be used in paid endorsements of
health-related products--made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam Corp.</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "Tax Report" reports that corporate
taxes now account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 13 percent</NUMEX> of total <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> collections, down from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">24</NUMEX>
percent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>. The column also reveals that since the tax bill began taking
shape, the price of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H&R Block</ENAMEX> shares has gone up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 30 percent</NUMEX>.

            In her column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> assumes the persona of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JFK Jr.</ENAMEX> to explain the editorial stance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">George</ENAMEX> magazine thus: "I've
heard about substance abuse, and I'm staying away from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">substance</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
