
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black</ENAMEX>

            A suicide bombing in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> market leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> gives the entire top of its front page to
sweeping changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> governance system coming with the new budget bill,
(which was uneventfully passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>). Its coverage includes
the reaction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>, who calls the measure "re-colonization" and
says it has "raped democracy and freedom."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> bombing, apparently the work of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, left <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> dead and
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">wounded 150</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> immediately suspended peace talks with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> peace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> postponed a scheduled departure to the
attack. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yassir Arafat telephoned Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> to express his
condolences, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , "responded angrily."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a little more about this, reporting, "'I am not prepared to
be satisfied with expressions of regret,' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the prime minister</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arafat</ENAMEX>,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. 'You have to completely change what you are saying
and doing. You must change your policy <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">180 degrees</NUMEX>.'"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has particularly powerful on-scene reporting of the carnage:
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> of the two presumed suicide <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>, young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> in black suits, were
the last to be taken away. They were said to have carried their deadly charges
in attach, cases, with the result that the lower parts of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> were
torn away but their faces were curiously intact. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> were shown later on
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> television. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> evidently hoped that they would be
recognized, giving the police a lead." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is aware of how
sadly routine such events have become, referring to the episode's "familiar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">agony</ENAMEX>," and reporting that "fifteen suicide <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> have struck in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three and a half years</TIMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 140</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and wounding
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX>."

            Under the headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Assails</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Thompson</ENAMEX> "bitterly denounced the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> for
stalling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s investigation into campaign finance abuses and announced
that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> will subpoena the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> for all outstanding
documents relative to its inquiry." The paper quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> as saying, "They
have no credibility as far as I'm concerned."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Federation of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blind</ENAMEX> is demanding that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> pull the plug on its planned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
release of a Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magoo</ENAMEX> movie (starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Nielsen</ENAMEX>), saying that bringing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Magoo</ENAMEX> back implies that "it's funny to watch an ill-tempered and incompetent
blind <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> stumble into things and misunderstand his surroundings." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Vogel</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, has this response: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magoo</ENAMEX> is not blind. We would
think about it as an issue more if he were blind."

            The strangeness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX> mission continues as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> announced the upcoming participation of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy Lawrence</ENAMEX>, and
then <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> later said never mind because she was too small for the space
suits on board the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>. Somehow this hadn't come up at any time
during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">her year</TIMEX> of training for the flight.

         
      
   
