
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dial Tomes</ENAMEX>

            After a lot of consensus lately, the majors go their separate ways <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the defection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with some new details about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> phone fund-raising. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> bill that would significantly cut into the legal rights and
funds of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s proposal for providing health care
coverage for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working poor</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that the defections of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> were "daring, synchronized" and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>'s son
disappeared from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> and is believed to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> describes the move as an "intelligence bonanza" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>,
pointing out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> was familiar with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s sales of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>.

            When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> broke the story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> telemarketing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s press conference in response was a salute to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legalese</ENAMEX> and flop sweat. No wonder, according to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , which,
based on documents possessed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>, reveals that between
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 1995 and May 1996</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> spoke to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 46</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to solicit individual contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">between $25,000</NUMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">46</NUMEX> contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost $3.7 million</NUMEX> in unregulated "soft
money."

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , some wrongs have already been set right in the
matter: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> has agreed to reimburse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Treasury</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24.20</NUMEX> worth of
calls that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> apparently made but which do not appear on his credit card
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead covers a conflict between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX> over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> riders <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorton</ENAMEX> got attached to a federal
spending bill (full of provisions favored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>) that
would strip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> of their current immunity from most lawsuits and would also
subject federal aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> to means-testing. The piece says that what's
driving all this is the perception that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> are getting rich off casino
gambling. "I find nothing in any <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> treaty," the story quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorton</ENAMEX> as
saying, "that says they must be continuously supported by the federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>." It also quotes "the only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>" (apparently "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>" is not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> style book) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Nighthorse Campbell</ENAMEX>,
as saying the bills would only be passed "over my dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> has subpoenaed publisher
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wm</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrow & Co.</ENAMEX> for records relating to a book being written by former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> intimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morrow</ENAMEX> will fight this in court starting
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> representing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morrow</ENAMEX> describes the breadth of the subpoena
this way: "You might as well connect the modem between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>."

            By now the drum beat of welfare reform stories has no doubt made it clear
that the dole is shrinking from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wyoming</ENAMEX>. Well, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s WP
points out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> isn't part of the trend--there, welfare rolls are up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX>
percent. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says it's because of a stagnant state economy and a
welfare system still needing an overhaul. Maybe another reason is that when the
weather is perfect and you're <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> from the beach, you don't feel like
working.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "Tax Report," the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schedule D</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> filed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> had only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">23</NUMEX> lines, plus a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>-line worksheet in the
instructions. The new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Schedule D</ENAMEX> probably will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 56</NUMEX> lines, says an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>
official, including a worksheet of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 30</NUMEX> lines that will be part of the
form itself."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>'s column in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports that the good liberal
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX> have come up with a way to justify trying to make a
killing with the upcoming movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Primary Colors</ENAMEX>" while still staying
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>-Bedroom-close to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> Couple. The movie, goes the studio line, "is
certainly not based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>. It's based on the book."

         
      
   
