
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">EARTH INVADES MARS</ENAMEX>!

            Did it just happen that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodie Foster</ENAMEX>'s "Contact" is revving to
open, a mission to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> is grabbing the headlines? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> of the majors
working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> are leading with the story of how <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lander</ENAMEX>'s communications problems with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rover vehicle</ENAMEX> it will deploy were
solved.

            There being no way into this story other than through the briefings and
access provided by the mission's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jet Propulsion Laboratory</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mars</ENAMEX> pieces in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
are relentlessly similar. Still, here and there individual touches emerge. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> were able to solve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pathfinder</ENAMEX>'s
initial problems in part because they had, before the landing, replicated them
in a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30-by-50-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sandbox</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> captures an example of what
apparently goes for rocket <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> humor. The paper mentions a mysterious
object in the landing area that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> are anxious to investigate with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rover</ENAMEX>, and quotes mission team <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Smith</ENAMEX> as saying that it
"appeared to be something long, dark and shaped a little like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX>. 'Someone
suggested that was a homeless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> out there,' the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> joked." I guess
destitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are pretty funny when you're federally subsidized.

            Meanwhile, back on earth, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> fronts an interesting piece
revealing that "the last great <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> rush of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>--targeted at a
potential <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4 trillion</NUMEX> patch in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Asia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian Sea</ENAMEX> region--has lured a
prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> prospectors: former high-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bent</ENAMEX> on winning a stake in the bonanza for themselves or their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>'s subhead mentions lobbying by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> national security
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">advisor Brent Scowcroft</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief of staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sununu</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Baker</ENAMEX>, and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bentsen</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of the piece also reveals the similar activities of former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cheney</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> national security
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">advisor Zbigniew Brzezinski</ENAMEX>. It's not clear why the latter <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were left out of
the bold type. This is tricky because it's also not clear whether in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
it's bad to be prominent in articles like this. After all, being certified by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> as working on something big could be great for business.

            The piece mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scowcroft</ENAMEX> has already made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130,000</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pennzoil</ENAMEX> in
connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caspian</ENAMEX> site. Of course, for him, money has nothing to do
with it. He tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> he's on the case "because the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
has big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">interests</ENAMEX> out there." Incidentally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scowcroft</ENAMEX> is fresh from a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> paper profit as a result of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX>'s announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> of its
intention to purchase <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX>, where (a few Web keystrokes quickly revealed)
he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> holding shares and options worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a quarter</NUMEX> of a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also has a scoop on the front <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--the revelation that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> have worked up a plan for nabbing former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> leader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Radovan Karaszic</ENAMEX> to bring him up on international war crimes charges. The paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hasn't approved the plan yet, but that he's not
ruling it out either.

            Remember that study a while back that concluded that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65 percent</NUMEX> of teenaged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> were impregnated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult men</ENAMEX>? It prompted much discussion of a
theretofore-unnoticed problem. Well, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">section</ENAMEX> brings the news that the study was wrong. Seems that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>
neglected to mention "that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62 percent</NUMEX> of the teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 or 19</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and, therefore, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>." Never
mind.

         
      
   
