
   
   
      
         
            File before Reading

            A surge of news variety <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the development that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and several
other "downwind" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are pressuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> to crack down on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX>
utilities to reduce current high levels of wind-borne smog. The top national
story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have found the first
clues to the precise way that the gene responsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Huntington's disease</ENAMEX>
causes its devastating effects, which could quickly lead to successful
treatments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's top national story is the very delayed
appearance of key fundraising files that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> investigating committee
requested from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than three months ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> leads its front-page "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>"
column with a brief mention of the files. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the news that defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Florida</ENAMEX> tops the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> preseason college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> poll.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Woodward</ENAMEX> has the byline on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> file delay story. He writes
that the files include paperwork on such controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Tamraz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Chung</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> fund-raising call sheets prepared for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX> to use in phone calls requesting donations in the range
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000-$100,000</NUMEX> from the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph Lauren</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> were found in a drawer in the only file
cabinet in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">finance director</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, where, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said, they
had been sitting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least five months</TIMEX>. Oddly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> doesn't mention the
similarity between this episode and the sudden re-appearance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> billing records.

            And speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> delay, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that a "recorded
phone message at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> begins, 'The campaign is still open
for business.'"

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> both give front-page space to stories about
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">102</NUMEX>-count <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> fraud indictment handed down against a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
home health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> law enforcement official
as saying, "We have not found <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> who actually received home health
care services from this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also runs a separate
overview piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> fraud.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes top of the page with its report that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> Sen.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lugar</ENAMEX> has threatened to make trouble for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>' tobacco interests in upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> hearings if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>
doesn't grant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador-nominee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Weld</ENAMEX> a confirmation hearing. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helms</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesperson</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , responded this way: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helms</ENAMEX>
would never suggest doing anything harmful to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs a piece inside about the newest humor trend in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>--jokes about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s nouveau riche. "Look at this tie I bought in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>," says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,500</NUMEX>." The other says, "What a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fool</ENAMEX>! Here, you can get
it for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX>." Another: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Devil</ENAMEX> meets a new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">capitalist</ENAMEX> and
offers him anything he wants. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> says he wants to pay no import tax, he
wants oil fields, he wants tax breaks, etc. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Devil</ENAMEX> says his wish is granted
provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> turn over his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>. "So," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, "what's the catch?" I
think I have heard these very jokes told about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yuppies</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>--which raises an interesting journalism question: How close can the butt
of a joke genre get to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> won't actually
repeat the jokes? And should that matter, or should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX>
give rich <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> the came courtesy they give poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>? When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Butz</ENAMEX> was
caught regaling someone with an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>black joke, you may recall, the mainstream
papers didn't actually tell the joke.

         
      
   
