
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Winners</ENAMEX> and Sinners

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> strike settlement is everybody's lead. The coverage generally has
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> components: describing the deal and then saying who won. The press
consensus is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> did what no labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> has done since PATCO
was crushed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>--gone to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat</ENAMEX> for its membership and gotten up a clear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>. Showing a bias towards politics and power figures, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says that the "indisputable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">victor</ENAMEX> in the strike" is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman</ENAMEX>. But even with that bias, a better case could be made for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Carey</ENAMEX>, who
has probably deflected membership dissent and has become emboldened to
immediately set his sights on unionizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Express</ENAMEX>.

            A big difference between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and those of a generation
ago is a concerted effort now to explain events. Accordingly, the papers
also take a shot at What The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strike Settlement Means</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
says the result is widely viewed as a "psychological victory for the labor
movement." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> expand on the same theme,
with the latter saying that virtually every labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> hailed
the settlement as a "watershed."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> hedges its bets on this, saying that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>'s Win May be Brief" because the trend towards part-timers continues
unabated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> is a more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> dissenter. It's
meaning-of-it-all piece is headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS Pact</ENAMEX> Fails to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shift Power Back Toward</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Workers</ENAMEX>." It says a lot more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> strike will be needed to do that.
The problem, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , is that union success hinges on
penetrating the service sector, where jobs are transient and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> scared.
And those who aren't scared because their special skills put them at the top of
the labor market already have too much bargaining power to need a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other observations about the significance of the strike bear repeating.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> will never again rely solely on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX>. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> makes the point that the strike demonstrated just how dependent
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> have become on the "just-in-time" economy.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> have front-page coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NTSB</ENAMEX>'s
findings that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">ValuJet</ENAMEX> crash could have been avoided, with its particularly
stinging criticism of its longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rival</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>. But it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">properly</ENAMEX> emphasizes that the sort of illegal shipments that caused the crash
are still going on. There have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 15</NUMEX> illegal shipments of oxygen
canisters, says the paper, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">ValuJet</ENAMEX> disaster.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> dedicates its news section cover story to Web sex sites. The
story has its share of amazing statistics, such as: "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28.2%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> visited
adult sites in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>," and "sex-related searches make up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10% to 20%</NUMEX> of requests
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">visitors</ENAMEX> to search sites." Besides describing a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">X-rated</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> in
some detail, the piece is practically a how-to, pointing out for instance, that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">X-rated</ENAMEX> photos of the sort in demand are readily available from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Usenet</ENAMEX>.
After "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nation</ENAMEX>'s Newspaper" runs a piece like this, do you think those stats
are going to go down ?

         
      
   
