
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stealth Health Care Reform</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> operations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , it's a surprising element of the
just-passed budget bill. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
advocacy of a fast-track trade bill.

            This choice by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is curious. The topic of a fast-track trade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> is technical--it's a guarantee that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will act quickly to vote up
or down any new trade accord rather than lay on amendments--and it's
non-pressing--it's something that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has tried to
secure since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> and won't actively be pursuing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several more weeks</TIMEX> until
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> return from their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> vacations. Meanwhile,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> relegates a far more important story to the second <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana</ENAMEX>
position, on the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">left quadrant</ENAMEX> of the front--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Crackdown on Assault Weapons</ENAMEX>
Has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Missed Mark</ENAMEX>." This piece makes the point that despite a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> ban
against assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> put into effect in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> and a similar federal statute
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years later</TIMEX>, "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> are changing hands
because of gaping holes in the laws." What happened, the story explains, is
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> got around the intent of the laws by flooding the
market with copycat <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> that differ from the particular banned ones only
cosmetically, and by substantially increasing the volume of assault <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>
they manufactured before the ban became law, because the post-ban continued
sale of such <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> is allowed. This bass-ackwards news judgement comes from
being too attached to "presidential" news---after all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> mentioned the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> bill in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> radio address--and to "breaking" news--the radio
address is something that "happened" on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, while the disaster of the gun
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> is not.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> lead emphasizes the risks being taken by the current
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> policy of backing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> against another, and reports
local sentiment that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radovan Karadzic</ENAMEX> will probably respond with intimidation
and violence. On the other hand, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> feel
that if they pull out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summer</TIMEX> as scheduled under the status quo, there is a
strong chance that war will resume. (In short the situation is much like the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 1980s</TIMEX>, an analogy the piece surprisingly
didn't make.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead draws attention to an initiative buried in the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">federal</ENAMEX> budget agreement that will pay teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to
reduce the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> they train in various specialties. This is in
effect, an example of stealth heath care reform, as reducing the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> health plan goals. All the more remarkable
then, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> signed on. But some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> are less than
thrilled. "I don't know where the hell a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> gets off doing
labor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">force</ENAMEX> planning for the medical profession," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert E. Moffit</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts and Leisure</ENAMEX>" section points out just what a big
comeback smoking has made on the big screen. "Half the movies released between
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990 and 1995</TIMEX>," says the paper, "featured a major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> who chose to light
up on screen, a significant increase compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">29 percent</NUMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>'s,
according to a recent study at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
