
   
   
      
         
            Done Deal

            The big story is a done budget deal, which leads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads instead with fraud in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> home
health care billing--which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days ago</TIMEX>.

            Euphoria is the coverage's main mood. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, briefed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> shortly before he went to play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>,
pronounced the deal 'fabulous.'" And, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Budget</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kasich</ENAMEX>, it was "a dream come true."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> each have the detail that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>, but none captures <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s reaction.
Presumably, he was even more thrilled, since this deal will save him
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kajillions</ENAMEX>. The key provisions: tax credits for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 billion</NUMEX> in education-related tax credits and deductions, including for
interest on student loans and penalty-free withdrawals to pay education
expenses from IRA accounts, an increase in cigarette taxes the added revenue
mostly going towards state-chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> health programs, a drop in the capital
gains tax rates--including for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX>, no tax on home sale
profits--and reduced inheritance taxes.

            Although this deal is widely described as balancing the budget by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> while
offering the first major tax cut since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, there is scant discussion today
about how this feat can really be achieved, when for instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">budgeteers</ENAMEX>
abandoned proposals to charge wealthier senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> higher Medicare
premiums and to raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> eligibility age from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">65 to 67</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Shapiro</ENAMEX> as
saying that the post-budget-bill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> will be "a whole new typography." Does
that mean stand by for the fine print?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> have front-page stories about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">just-concluded</ENAMEX> trial of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pol Pot</ENAMEX>, held somewhere in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cambodian</ENAMEX> jungle (a
videotape was made available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> headline states that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot</ENAMEX> was "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Near Tears</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pot</ENAMEX> received a sentence of life imprisonment. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> saying, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> point of
discussion we want to have with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hun Sen</ENAMEX> is to say he can work his way back into
the world's good graces by turning this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> over."

            Everybody makes front-page mention of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s surprise resignation by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Fogleman</ENAMEX>. The explanation is widely
held to be that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fogleman</ENAMEX> thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> general in charge of security at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barracks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX> bombed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was blameless but
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fogleman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX>, is likely to punish
him. In his resignation statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fogleman</ENAMEX> also mentioned that his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> stance
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">adulterous</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">bomber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Flinn</ENAMEX> "may have put him out of step with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> adds a more prosaic motivation: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fogleman</ENAMEX>'s
"displeasure over cuts ordered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> in the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-22</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX>."

            Deep inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> there's word that despite earlier denials,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>'s largest bank <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> admitted that documents discovered in its
shredder <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> by a night <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchman</ENAMEX> who then disseminated them may in fact have
been related to dormant accounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>'s initial
reaction had been to investigate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christoph Meili</ENAMEX>, for violating
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> banking secrecy rules. This isn't the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time it took a night watchman
to reveal a disgraceful truth fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with day jobs knew all about.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watergate</ENAMEX>, remember, started with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Wills</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
