
   
   
      
         
            Mir Mortals

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the ongoing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX> saga. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mir</ENAMEX> on the front but below the fold,
while making its top national story the sudden departure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Paxon</ENAMEX>
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
also has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mir</ENAMEX> on the front below the fold, but leads with the looming trouble
between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Economic Union</ENAMEX> over the proposed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing-McDonnell Douglas</ENAMEX> merger, which he supports and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> is likely to
reject as being a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX>.

            The papers give the general impression of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> that is getting more
stressed out by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the minute</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> mistakenly unplugged a
critical cable, thereby disabling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>'s guidance system and causing a
power loss. Despite this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> announced that it was going to allow the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Foale</ENAMEX>, to begin training for a repair
space walk. The actual decision on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foale</ENAMEX>'s participation in the walk itself has
yet to be made. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> attributes the view to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rep</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Sensenbrenner</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Science Committee</ENAMEX>, that, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s paraphrase, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>
is now putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foale</ENAMEX>'s life at risk."

            As to which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> pulled the cable, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> simply reports that
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> would not say." According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the word from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> was, "We have not asked them yet and it does not matter for us."
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> mission <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> says the reason for the silence
about the crewmembers is, "I don't want them executed in the mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Paxon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX> is widely seen as fallout from his participation in a failed
attempt by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unseat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> from his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>'s post. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headlines say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paxon</ENAMEX> quit. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> header says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> ousted him. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> the stories
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paxon</ENAMEX>'s anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX> moves to "many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> speaks
instead vaguely of "disclosures." Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> comes out and admits that
the revelations were prior stories in the newsletter <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hill and The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> all cover <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s Internet
breakdown, which played havoc with email and Web site access. It seems the
trouble was a software glitch at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Network Solutions</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that manages
email addresses, which was then ignored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s system <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX>.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Network Solutions</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> that the company employee
who dropped the ball "is being dealt with very appropriately." Executed in the
mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>?

            Speaking of which, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> has this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">factoid</ENAMEX> tucked in at the
bottom of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> budget for
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX>] subscriptions tops <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX>, almost triple the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s subscription budget." Wouldn't you love to see those lists?

            All in all, a fine <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page. I don't mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forsyth</ENAMEX>'s loopy defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fox</ENAMEX>-hunting ("Not only are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50,000</NUMEX> hounds and about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20,000</NUMEX> fine <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> at stake, but equipment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">suppliers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">merchants</ENAMEX>, saddlers,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clothiers</ENAMEX>, farriers, blacksmiths and riding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> would go down the tubes.").
I mean law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Rips</ENAMEX>' argument that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX>
extortion case wasn't doing anything illegal--at least she wouldn't have been
if she'd done what more sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do for money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>--have a
lawyer threaten to make the disclosures. And there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Herbert</ENAMEX>'s
indictment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> for not talking tough about irresponsible
black male sex. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kweisi Mfume</ENAMEX> is not well
positioned to lead this fight, having fathered "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 months</TIMEX>."

         
      
   
