
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here and Everywhere</ENAMEX>

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, as in life, new deaths <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> in on the old. So we have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> dedicating its entire front to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, with a cover story about
the global village funeral to come, and anchored by a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> shot of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">princess</ENAMEX>, but we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leading with the news of yet another suicide bombing in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>.

            This time it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> scumbags, a record number apparently, killing
themselves and others in a popular public place with bombs spewing nuts and
bolts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> that claimed the last bombing, of a crowded <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>
market in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, claimed this one too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> issued a deadline for freeing
all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> held by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 14</TIMEX>. The coverage is similar from paper
to paper, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> more clearly communicates the pent-up anger
felt by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> goes in for the most grit,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">repeating AP</ENAMEX> dispatches <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX>'s spine flying through a shop
window and a severed head laying in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>.

            
               What is the sound of one hand shredding? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> each have front-pagers about the testimony at
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s fund-raising hearings by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> nuns involved in an
Election <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> fund-raiser held at their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">temple</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nuns</ENAMEX> had
identical bright robes, glasses, and shaved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX>, and were each <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than five</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">feet</NUMEX> tall, so the papers go more for laughs than they otherwise might. But it's
a natural tendency: after all, the hearing room featured nearly life-sized
blowup photos from the event, of the nuns and of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> making a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>
gesture. Also, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nun</ENAMEX> who identified herself as
the temple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treasurer</ENAMEX> said that when she oversaw the collection from nuns of
checks made out to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DNC</ENAMEX>" totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55,000</NUMEX>, she didn't know what "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">DNC</ENAMEX>" stood
for.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which has been spearheading another story also posing trouble
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>, namely, that of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> rainmaking phone calls, sees the
story a bit more gravely than the others. Its headline reads, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nuns Tell</ENAMEX> of
Panic about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fund-Raiser</ENAMEX>," and it puts their admissions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of covering up
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>'s financial tracks by altering and destroying documents right into
the sub-headline. And it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that calls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s hearings
"perhaps the most striking testimony" yet presented. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> carries a
completely different unseemly tale about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VP</ENAMEX> and fund solicitations. The
heat on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> is definitely turning up.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> media oil slick continues to spread. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and LAT
each run front-page meta pieces about the significance of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">royals</ENAMEX>' behavior
in the wake of her death. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also throws in a <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">meta-meta</ENAMEX>
front-pager on how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> read so much into the behavior of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royals</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">And American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> don't?) And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pocket Books</ENAMEX> will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">850,000</NUMEX> copies of various <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> books
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>, even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by her astrologer (if he didn't tell her not to get in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, what good is he?). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also reveals that gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bio queen Kitty</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX>'s long-in-the-works book on the royals is done but couldn't be rushed
out in time for the current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dianamania</ENAMEX>.

            Remember that first joint <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> study of illegal immigration that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> wrote about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , you'll recall, saw the
study as proof that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> were overstating the problem of illegal
immigration. Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> does its piece on the study <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>--under the
headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Illegal Immigration Hurts U.S. and Mexico, Study Finds</ENAMEX>."

            Rarely able to resist a cheap shot at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says he
was disappointed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> wasn't granted a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">funeral</ENAMEX>, because if she had,
he could have made the trip.

         
      
   
