
   
   
      
         
            Hard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Landing</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the remarkable Mir cosmonaut
press conference. The top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times is one that was covered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> by the New York
Times --the conflict between, on the one hand, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> fundraising
investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> and, on the other, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> advocacy organizations
across the political spectrum that have been subpoenaed by that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with a look at the current state of health plan coverage.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mir</ENAMEX> press event was a platform for the just-returned and much-maligned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cosmonaut Vasily Tsibliev</ENAMEX> to defend himself and to vent about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> space
program, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economy, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> life. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cosmonaut's</ENAMEX> in-orbit performance has become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Topic A.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
papers have been all over him, and upon his return, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> took a swipe
at him as well. The problems on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">board Mir</ENAMEX> during his tenure, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tsibliev</ENAMEX>,
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , were not his fault, but rather stemmed from
"problems on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. It's connected with the economy, with our affairs in
general. Even the equipment needed to live aboard the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and that we
requested to be sent--and we're not talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX>--they
just don't exist..The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factories</ENAMEX> don't work, or have insufficient supplies, or
they ask for, excuse me, crazy prices." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's account quotes an
additional cause here, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dostoevskian</ENAMEX> proportions: "our poor lives."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> pieces on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cosmo-conference</ENAMEX> are
so focused on the chaotic and deteriorating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> space program that they all
miss an important point: namely, that this latest development shows that their
space program is more open than ours. Imagine a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> having the nerve
to say such things! You'll have to, because it's never happened, even when
things went as awry as they did with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Challenger</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a piece on an important change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgetown</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> basketball program--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Thompson</ENAMEX> no longer seems to emphasize
graduation for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recruits</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> now
achieve only a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59 percent</NUMEX> graduation rate compared to an overall rate for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshmen</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 90 percent</NUMEX>. In the piece, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s
long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of admissions calls this "clearly disappointing."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> continues to pursue the police brutality scandal, with a
front-page account of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haitians</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> led by mayoral
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX>) street protests against the cops. Additionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert</ENAMEX>'s column addresses the issue, pointing out along the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> is already averaging payouts in police brutality cases of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $20</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the costs of just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
