
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> Handover

            No doubt about it--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s top story is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
puts it across <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all six</NUMEX> columns of the top of its front page and puts <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more
related page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> stories below. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA TODAY</ENAMEX> leads with it and has a news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> "cover
story" on it as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> dedicates its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Wide News</ENAMEX>" front page
space to the topic and does a column one take on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> columns at its top over to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
stories about the event. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> runs a
banner headline across its top front and just underneath that, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> big
pictures: on the left, exiting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Patten</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> bowed,
holding his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s folded flag, and on the right, newly arrived <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> raising theirs.

            In general, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> reporting focuses on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> themes: the pageantry of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">handover</ENAMEX> ceremonies and the open political questions that remain. There's
some pretty efficient limning of the historical context, but some linguistic
and reporting overkill too. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> for instance, tells its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
that, "awash in fireworks and fired-up patriotism, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> celebrates the end of
156 years of 'national disgrace,' regaining a tiny patch of land ceded after a
humiliating war and eyed enviously for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> can't
keep to itself about the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band members</ENAMEX> at the ceremonies in their "snow
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tunics</ENAMEX>" and the attendance there "of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> of each of the
territory's services, from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Correctional Services Department</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Auxiliary Medical Service</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also tells us that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patten</ENAMEX>'s favorite song
is "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highland Cathedral</ENAMEX>" and that the last ceremonial meal under a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> flag
was "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salmon</ENAMEX>, stuffed chicken <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast</ENAMEX> and a red <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit pudding</ENAMEX> with
raspberry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>."

            There are certain staple <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> turnover details every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> tells us:
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX>, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> snubbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> snubbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>,
and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> are saying they will preserve <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s free economy and
open political system for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX>. But none of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s accounts really
explains where this number comes from.

            Among the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> is alone in keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Tyson</ENAMEX>
story on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, detailing there how on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX> apologized to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evander</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holyfield</ENAMEX> for biting him on both ears. Here too, there seems to be more
reporting than the story needs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> tells us that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>'s prepared
statement lasted "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 minutes 16 seconds</TIMEX>," and includes the detail that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, an admitted boxing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>, expressed revulsion at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyson</ENAMEX>'s
actions in the ring." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> then goes on to relieve whatever anxieties are
currently being suffered by libertarian fight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, however,
stopped short of suggesting federal intervention in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
