
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbour's Chair</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with black--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cunanan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with white--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Brennan</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> opt for gray--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Barbour</ENAMEX>.

            Within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">48 hours</TIMEX> after the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Versace</ENAMEX> murder, reports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , Cunanan
called someone he knew for help getting a passport. That <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> did not notify
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> at the time, but did offer the information sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> contacted him. The cops are still trying to determine if any associates
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cunanan</ENAMEX> helped hide him while he was a fugitive. Adds <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> : At the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> of the suicide, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trail</ENAMEX> was turning cold, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">case investigators</ENAMEX> had
never even considered suicide as a possibility. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">front-page Cunanan</ENAMEX> story under a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> "Wanted" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">flier</ENAMEX> with a slash marked
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Found Dead</ENAMEX>" running across the suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>'s face.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> columns across at the top, all under a banner
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headline</ENAMEX>, in its coverage of the death of retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brennan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at
age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">91</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brennan</ENAMEX> left his greatest mark, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , as "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>
of rulings that expanded rights of racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; led to
reapportionment of voting districts guaranteeing the ideal of "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>, one
vote;" and enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">First Amendment</ENAMEX> freedom for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that during his tenure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brennan</ENAMEX> had signed his name to
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,360</NUMEX> opinions.

            According to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbour</ENAMEX>
was in the witness chair at the fundraising hearings to discuss a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.1 million</NUMEX>
loan guarantee from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ambrous T. Young</ENAMEX>, to an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization Barbour</ENAMEX> started up called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Policy Forum</ENAMEX>. Barbour
claimed that the transaction was completely legal and just like those made by
such research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookings Institution</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage Foundation</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> suggest it was a scheme for channeling foreign money into
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> coffers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbour</ENAMEX> also testified that he didn't know the money had
come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. "It's hard for me to accept that you didn't know this
money was coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>," committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lieberman</ENAMEX> is
quoted as saying. "My God, you went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> to see Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Young</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BTW</ENAMEX>, according to the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire"</ENAMEX> column in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , "A memo prepared before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barbour</ENAMEX>'s trip
to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> reminds an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> to brief him on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> 'protocol' including
'burping, spitting, hookers in hotel, chopsticks, gifts, etc.'"

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> are on the front page with the news that
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> found the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic diocese</ENAMEX> liable for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120 million</NUMEX> in damages in connection with a sex abuse complaint brought
against a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of another who committed suicide.

            Tucked deep inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s quick
recovery from his knee injury "was the result of his using a new hot tub on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Lawn</ENAMEX> out by the swimming pool." The device was donated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watkins Manufacturing</ENAMEX>. It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s biggest--a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-seater that retails for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,100</NUMEX>--and comes with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Moto-Massagers</ENAMEX>. "Those
are," explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jets</ENAMEX> that go up and down your back and
make you so mellow that it's advisable not to enter budget talks for at least
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> afterward, lest you agree to scrap capital gains taxes
altogether."

         
      
   
