
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serb and Destroy Mission</ENAMEX>

            The biggest news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is a startling development: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commandos</ENAMEX>, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> logistic support and full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hague</ENAMEX> backing, moved in on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> Bosnian
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serb</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> accused of war crimes, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in a firefight and capturing
the other. It was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s first attempt to arrest suspected war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Balkans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> also puts it high on the right-side of its front,
although its top story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s decision to draw down the criminal
investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">800</ENAMEX> crash. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads instead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s revelation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s
campaign fund-raising hearings that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$650,000</NUMEX>
via separate wire transfers from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of making
major donations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>, and relegates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> to
a little box below the fold. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also gives prominent above-the-fold
space to the hearings, but in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , they don't even make the front
page.

            The LAT senses a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>-like trail of money here, quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">watchdog group</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Public Integrity</ENAMEX>,
saying, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wire</ENAMEX> transfers of the kind described are Exhibit A of
criminality."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is also above the fold with the news that, despite initial
reservations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has decided to support a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> proposal that
would raise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> premiums for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $50,000</NUMEX>. The piece
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> this stance could set off a rift within <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranks</ENAMEX>.

            Back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Bosnian</ENAMEX> operation: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that the captured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was
taken at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> where he worked by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> who entered "under
cover." But you have to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> to find out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brits</ENAMEX> were
"posing as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> on a humanitarian aid mission." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hey</ENAMEX>, wouldn't we
complain about that?

            Some great details <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's front-page feature about the road to
the tobacco settlement. For instance, the breakthrough notion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> suing
cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> for the recovery of public funds spent on
tobacco-related medical expenditures didn't come from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> Attorney
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX>, but from a law-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of his, a small-town lawyer
named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael T. Lewis</ENAMEX>, who cold-called him with the idea. And when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey T.</ENAMEX>
Wigand, at the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of research at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown and Williamson Tobacco Corp.</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> began making insider revelations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>, he was known at the agency
only by a code name--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research</ENAMEX>."

            Atop its piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about the just-announced new TV ratings system, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs a graphic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> featuring the new content guidelines that will be
added to the age-based ones currently in use: V-Violence, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S-Sexual Situations</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L-Coarse Language</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suggestive Dialogue</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">FV-Fantasy Violence</ENAMEX>. (How could
they leave out <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fantasy Sexual Situations</ENAMEX>?) And then illustrates the new ratings
a few current shows might have. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYPD Blue</ENAMEX>," for instance, would have a rating
with more syllables than its title: "TV-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>-S,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">V</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.</ENAMEX>"

         
      
   
