
   
   
      
         
            IRA Withdrawal

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> agree that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s top story is the IRA's announcement
that it would reinstate the cease-fire it had observed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between August</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> and
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February, 1996</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads instead with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> columns--the
beginning of a multi-part series, with related articles inside--on the sad
state of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> municipal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion Barry</ENAMEX>. The
piece runs under a banner headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From the Top, a City That Doesn't</ENAMEX>
Work."

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the IRA cease-fire "announcement came after
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX> had made several important concessions to
[the IRA's political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> to obtain the new cease-fire, notably
saying that disarmament of [IRA and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paramilitaries</ENAMEX> would not have
to start before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> talks." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Adams</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> all said they hoped the
cease-fire would mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinn Fein</ENAMEX> would be joining upcoming peace talks.

            Neither the words "bomb" nor "murder" appear in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> account. (A
concession to a large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readership</ENAMEX>?) By contrast, the LAT
coverage is pretty explicit about what the IRA's been up to lately. Its second
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paragraph</ENAMEX> states that the cease-fire means the IRA is "renouncing a terrorist
campaign that has included bombings, the killings of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> and the
disruption of public services in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX>." Which is why it's surprising
that the LAT commits the unclarity of saying that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> cease-fire
"ended without warning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February, 1996</TIMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> truck <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> that killed
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>," without mentioning that the explosion was attributed to the
IRA.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is a tale of resources amassed but not
delivered. The paper reveals that despite having the highest rates of new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
infection, tuberculosis, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> mortality in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s
Commission on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health</ENAMEX> fumbled spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$89 million</NUMEX> in federal grant money
targeted to just these areas. Additionally, in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with "acres of abandoned
and decrepit housing," local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> failed to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions</NUMEX> in federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">block</ENAMEX> grant money intended to rehabilitate housing for the poor. Meanwhile,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> chronically pays high rents to politically
favored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlords</ENAMEX>. In fact, "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Housing and Community</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Development</ENAMEX> spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> above the market rate to rent its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office..</ENAMEX>"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that despite revelations at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
fundraising hearings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his senior foreign policy advisors
still believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> did not have a plan to influence <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> elections
illegally, and hence that "there is so far no cause for taking punitive steps
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports on its front page that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> announced
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> will be added to a computerized law enforcement
tracking system that helps cops catch illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traffickers</ENAMEX> by tracing guns
sold to juveniles. In making the announcement, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> stated that "over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past decades</TIMEX>, the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> murders by juveniles has skyrocketed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300</NUMEX>
percent." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that according to data already collected in
that system, "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">More than half</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">958</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> recovered at crime scenes in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>] in a recent period were in the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> younger
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25.</NUMEX>."

            Guess what's one of the hottest shows on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> cable television. According
to a piece <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" section, it's "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Heroes</ENAMEX>." Touchy plot lines have been softened with creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dubbing</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">camp</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>'s stiff-armed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salutes</ENAMEX> are never accompanied by "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heil Hitler</ENAMEX>."
Instead what they say is, "This is how high the cornflowers grow!" Meanwhile,
"Seinfeld" was just canceled.

         
      
   
