
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oy Veh</ENAMEX> Is Mir

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> top stories <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are the murder of fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX> and
shot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in front of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> beach <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, and law
enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> announced that the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexual prostitute</ENAMEX>
already being sought as one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ten Most Wanted</ENAMEX>" in a nationwide hunt
arising from the recent murders of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            The newest trouble aboard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mir</ENAMEX> is that cosmonaut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vasily Tsibliev</ENAMEX> is
experiencing a heart <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">irregularity</ENAMEX>, and therefore may not be able to undertake
the space walk needed to repair the damage suffered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.
As a result, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> are appealing to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British-born</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut</ENAMEX> aboard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mir</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Foale</ENAMEX>, do the job instead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> is
weighing its options and should decide soon. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> at
times appear to be attempting to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foale</ENAMEX> directly to undertake the
repairs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't put too fine a point on what's at stake for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> is the heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s manned space program. To
abandon it would leave <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cosmonauts</ENAMEX> jobless."

            Everybody lavishes attention on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Versace</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami Beach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manse</ENAMEX>, with for
instance, the WP noticing its "huge shower" which it quotes a source as
saying is "big enough for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to share simultaneously." The WP
says that just before he died, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Versace</ENAMEX> had gone to a caf, near his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> where
he spent "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14.89</NUMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says it was "<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15.01</NUMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vogue, Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX>."

            Also receiving much front-page play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: the continuing developments at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> campaign funding hearings. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> learned that in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX> was working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo</ENAMEX>, he sent a memo back to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> asking to be reimbursed for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> gift
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> also heard expert testimony
to the effect that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo</ENAMEX> had in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> evolved from a family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> to
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> all cover this ground, but it's the
latter that seems particularly attuned to the quantitative details of Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX>'s own finances, revealing that he received a "salary of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $90,000</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> bonuses of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $230,000</NUMEX>," and that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>, "he was given severance pay of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $450,000</NUMEX>,
a figure that included the book value of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> car he was allowed to
keep, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes Benz</ENAMEX>."

            Is another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> recovery strategy against the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> being
quietly hatched? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Affairs Department</ENAMEX> has begun processing the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in a potential tidal wave of
compensation claims for smoking-related diseases and deaths that could cost the
government <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> a year over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next decade</TIMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with a report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Transportation</ENAMEX>
sent letters to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> asking them to explain the
procedures they use for making seats available for frequent flier awards. The
request was a response to increasing complaints by frequent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fliers</ENAMEX> who say they
are too often told they can't redeem their <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> to go where they want..
Answers are due <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">back August 31</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
