
   
   
      
         
            Hearing Impaired

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s political fundraising hearings continue to play big. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the report that at the hearings, "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Party</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">finance director</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Sullivan</ENAMEX>] testifies that
top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> helped install the central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX> in the controversy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX>, as a top party fundraiser; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, attending a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> summit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, acknowledges that he may have helped play a role in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX>'s hiring." The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> puts this same story at the top
of its "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World-Wide" news</ENAMEX> column. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
also leads with the hearings, but prefers to stress that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> have learned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> is
opposed to giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> immunity from prosecution. But there is a little
variety <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with a likely change in airline security
procedures, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with a likely change in the TV rating
system.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's hearing coverage has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> giving the following
testimony about a memo apparently describing a schedule of fund-raising coffees
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, even though these are barred by law from being conducted on
federal property: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX>, the coffees helped us with our fund-raising. I was
the fund-raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. But they were not fund-raisers. They were not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fund-raisers</ENAMEX>." Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sullivan</ENAMEX> explained, the "coffees were a tool in helping
us motivate and energize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we needed to motivate and energize to
help us raise the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130 million</NUMEX> that we wanted to raise."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> each give
above-the-fold coverage to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> boxing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fine Mike Tyson</ENAMEX> nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> and to revoke his boxing license for at least
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> as punishment for biting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evander Holyfield</ENAMEX> on both ears during their
championship fight <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. The papers indulge in much speculation about
whether or not this means the end of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>'s career. The bald, brawling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boxer</ENAMEX>
known as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Butterbean</ENAMEX>" tells USAT that he's willing to fight <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>, "if I
could put duct tape on my ears."

            There's also a lot of coverage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s change at the top at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>
Computer: the departure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert Amelio</ENAMEX>. All the stories agree the
development means an expanded role at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Jobs</ENAMEX>, who
recently rejoined its management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> after being forced out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>. But they
don't all agree about what actually happened. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelio</ENAMEX>
stepped down. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says he was ousted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headline says
he quit, but its text says he was ousted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> headline says he was
ousted, but its text says he quit.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries a story deep inside that's sure to move up at least a
little in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> ahead. Seems that at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Madrid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> meetings, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Chretien</ENAMEX> was kept waiting for a tardy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, he vented a bit about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, and a
television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>'s audio system picked up his comments. "Take the quarrel
over whether to admit the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baltic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chretien</ENAMEX> said, in remarks that were
aired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Broadcasting Corp.</ENAMEX> "That has nothing to do with world
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX>. It's because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> controls lots of votes
for the [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX>] nomination."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page continues a disturbing trend. Earlier in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Baldwin</ENAMEX> got prime space on the page to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX> a rehash defense of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>. Today, it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX> with a piece
about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> discovers kittens there that are just like earth
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kittens</ENAMEX> except that they remain kittens forever and can parse sentences in the
newspaper. Really. Jeez, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX> wants a change of pace, he doesn't
get a part in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Father of the Bride</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
