
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>-versity

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX> still dominates, but other stories get their due. For instance, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">257</NUMEX>-point gain on Wall <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">St</ENAMEX>, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with a piece about how private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, with the advent of managed care
and lower <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s fees, are now courting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> because of the
guaranteed government dollars they represent, while shunning uninsured patients
more than ever. The nightmare scenario, says the piece, is that "desirable"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> will altogether abandon public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, with the "desirable" doctors
following suit. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> 's decision to lead with a trend piece--that
is, a piece that could have run just as well a month from now--suggests a deep
desire not to wallow in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evidently</ENAMEX>, this desire is not universal at the
paper, however; for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second day in a row</TIMEX>, the op-ed page runs three
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> screeds.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the latest news in the death of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">princess</ENAMEX>--the
decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> to investigate <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> to see if they
committed involuntary homicide or violated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good Samaritan</ENAMEX> law, and the
revelation that a new round of toxicology revealed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> was even
more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX>-impaired than originally reported. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> also give prominent front-page space
to these developments.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> will attend the funeral
service and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX>'s oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son Prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX> is insisting on walking behind
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s coffin in the ceremony. The following passage from the WP
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> under investigation shows the meta-levels the story has
now ascended to: "As they were released and their handcuffs removed, the
suspects slipped out side entrances to the huge <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse building</ENAMEX>, avoiding
the waiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of television and still cameras. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> said
they would not have taken pictures of them anyway, out of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">'solidarity</NUMEX>.' The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> also were said by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> to have avoided the spotlight because
they had sold their stories of detention to tabloid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and wanted to
preserve exclusivity."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , while keeping up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX> front, manages to find more
front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> than most for other hard-news stories. It's on this front that
you'll find out about how <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, surrounded by a stick-wielding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>,
returned the use of a TV transmitter to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian Serbs</ENAMEX> loyal to war criminal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suspect Radovan Karadzic</ENAMEX> in return for promises to tone down propaganda
emanating from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and to provide political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> access to it. And
where you'll be provoked by a piece about a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> killing involving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bounty hunters</ENAMEX> to realize that this field is preposterously
under-regulated.

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's coverage of the big stock market move, there's the usual
dueling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> explaining that this is either the sign of bigger things to
come or the end of the good times. But there's also this says-it-all sentence:
"[A] typical stock investment grew <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nearly as much</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> as a simple savings
account grows in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>."

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> audited about
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14.5 percent</NUMEX> of the estate-tax returns filed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>
doesn't say so, but the overall audit rate is more like <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>. So the
message is clear: still one of the best ways to avoid taxes is to avoid
death.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that a study just out concludes
that new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, steeped though they may be in high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX>, can't
properly use a stethoscope. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> in the survey only identified <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of
the heart problems that can be routinely diagnosed via the instrument. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Doctors</ENAMEX>
who play a musical instrument did better.

         
      
   
