
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wonderful Life</ENAMEX>

            This is one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those days</TIMEX> where what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are telling us is most
newsworthy via their use of the traditional tools of placement and headline
size is mostly spinach--important sure, but...yecch. Yes, the top right-hand
column of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> tells
us that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> will give in to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and agree to limit the
expansion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just three</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Bloc</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> (that's the
national edition--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metro</ENAMEX> edition uses that prime print estate for a story
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pataki</ENAMEX>'s decision to abandon a major welfare cutback).
Sure, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA TODAY</ENAMEX> give
prominent play to an oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanker</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diamond Grace</ENAMEX> making a big mess in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo Bay</ENAMEX>. And yes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> uses its top right to report "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
Close in on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tax Deal</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> also dutifully tell us that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England Journal of Medicine</ENAMEX> concludes that power lines probably don't give
you <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">leukemia</ENAMEX>. But, c'mon, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s real news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is a little further down on
the front page--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Stewart</ENAMEX> (except at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
that is, where naturally, it leads). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> front the story as high as
they can because they know there really was a loss here, of a combination of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and a larger sense of purpose that is utterly absent from entertainment
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

            And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">obit staffs</ENAMEX> do some good reporting. (Although there is a discrepancy
about the cause of death. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say it was cardiac arrest. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX> go with a blood clot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lung</ENAMEX>.) USAT
relates that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> won his first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX>, for "The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
Story," he had voted for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Fonda</ENAMEX> (in "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Grapes of Wrath</ENAMEX>"), and
reveals that for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX>'s famous filibuster scene in "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith Goes</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> apply a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mercury solution</ENAMEX> to his vocal
chords to give him a raspy throat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stewart</ENAMEX> left
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> stardom to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine months</TIMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>,
and that one of his stepsons was killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>.

            Down below the fold on the front page, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> breaks the story of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kite</ENAMEX>, who faces a court martial for fraternizing
with an enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and lying about it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX>. Who did he fraternize
with? His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> story illustrates the sense in which the
military has lost perspective on personal relations (if it ever had it). It
reports that the investigation that led to the charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kite</ENAMEX> was
initiated by the base chaplain, and that Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kite</ENAMEX>'s mental health records and
even the date of her last menstrual cycle have been entered into evidence. Keep
an eye on this one: after all, it's by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Sciolino</ENAMEX>, who
uncovered the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Flinn</ENAMEX> case in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last May</TIMEX>.

            In a related story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX> asks a really
good question in his op-ed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s search for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> with no sexual baggage: "Would you choose your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> on
this basis?"

         
      
   
