
   
   
      
         
            Death and Taxes

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Korea Air</ENAMEX> crash on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guam</ENAMEX>, and the disaster gets plenty of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">front-page</ENAMEX> space at all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> each lead with local stories--the former with a city
proposal to allow early retirement for public school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>, the latter with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>'s pick of a black <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32-year</TIMEX> department <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> to be the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAPD</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KA</ENAMEX> crash was of a relatively low-mileage <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">747</NUMEX> on final approach to the
Guam <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> during a rainstorm. The toll was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 200</NUMEX> dead, but the
accounts of the precise number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> vary, as do reports of how many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> were on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. With facts such as these scarce, the papers
have plenty of room left over to speculate. So previous terrorism-related <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Korea</ENAMEX>
Air crashes and/or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWA</ENAMEX> 800 get trotted out, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> wonders whether
the aircrew was familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s signing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> of the budget bills also gets big
play. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> seems to maintain the most detachment from the hoopla, saying
that the celebration capped "a week of self-congratulation." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
notices that likely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> wasn't there. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s claim that "the sun is rising in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> again" was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reaganesque</ENAMEX>. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s promise to work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> on a bipartisan basis to
reform the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> system is duly reported without any of the papers observing
the occasion's eerie similarity to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton-Gingrich</ENAMEX> handshake pledge of a
few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years back</TIMEX> to once and for all come up with real campaign reform--an area
where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> has been achieved.

            Indeed, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> have front-page pieces based on a
report released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Cause</ENAMEX> stating that, despite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s
many fundraising scandals, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> have raised record amounts of soft
money, with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> bringing in twice as much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "Tax Report" notes that the new tax
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> means <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 800</NUMEX> changes to the tax code--the most changes since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>.
That column also quotes the suggestion of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> that given this
trend, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> ought to try to raise money for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal treasury</ENAMEX> by
offering to name new tax provisions after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.

            In the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living Arts</ENAMEX>" section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Weinraub</ENAMEX>, notes that after a flirtation with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>
and other sorts of non-standard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>, action movies have once again
installed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX> as the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> of choice. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX>
don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lobby</ENAMEX> capable of making <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> nervous, and another is summed
up by a film studies <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinraub</ENAMEX> quotes: "For most of us, it goes back
to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>. I gave my moviegoing life to the red menace. Now they're going to
snatch them away from me and replace them with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX>? I don't think
so."

         
      
   
