
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Razing Arizona</ENAMEX>

            On a typical news day, the felony conviction of a sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> is news
leader stuff, as is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Justice</ENAMEX>'s decision to look into the Vice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising practices. But when these stories break on the same
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">day</ENAMEX>, and under the pall of the sudden death of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> who was probably one
of the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the planet, everything changes.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the conviction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fife</ENAMEX>
Symington on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> counts of fraud having to do with his business practices as
a real estate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">developer</ENAMEX>. The paper explains that the verdict means that
Symington must resign immediately, and also probably means lots of jail time.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> points out, referring to former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Governor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Meacham</ENAMEX>, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symington</ENAMEX> thus becomes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> to be ousted.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is a little stronger on context, pointing
out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Symington</ENAMEX> was a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the impeachment and removal from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meacham</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
also note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meacham</ENAMEX>, while impeached under a criminal cloud, was eventually
acquitted of the charges against him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> adds that, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> have been indicted while in office and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> have been convicted
or pleaded guilty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> observes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Symington</ENAMEX> is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> governor
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX> to be forced from office because of a conviction.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> revealed that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $120,000</NUMEX> of the money <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>
raised in those phone calls from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> ended up in an account
for "hard money" subject to federal election laws, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
leads with the news that this has prompted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> to authorize the initial
stages of an investigation into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising that could result in a
special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> being named in the matter. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> phone call controversy
was first broken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in their stories
on this latest development, neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
(which placed it prominently: front page, column <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>, above the fold) could
bring themselves to acknowledge this. The former states that the cause of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s action was "news" and the latter goes with "accusations."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX> story has shifted into thumbsucking mode. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> all have front pagers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> about
how the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> royal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> appears to have underestimated the public
affection for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Di</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> worry that, as a result, the royals may never
again enjoy true mass appeal.

            It's bad enough that we had to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakov Smirnoff</ENAMEX>, but now comes word from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> that retired <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> espionage ace Maj. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oleg Kalugin</ENAMEX> is
seeking a green card. The trouble is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalugin</ENAMEX> helped plan the kidnapping of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Shadrin</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> naval <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> who was a highly-valued double
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. And not only did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shadrin</ENAMEX> die in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kalugin</ENAMEX>'s custody
(accidentally, he says) but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kalugin</ENAMEX> helped create the cover story that kept the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> from finding out what really happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shadrin</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>. A number
of retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operatives</ENAMEX> are very unhappy about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kalugin</ENAMEX>'s effort to gain
permanent residence status and want to know why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> would help him get
it.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that a growing number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are
coming to the view that the proposed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$368.5 billion</NUMEX> tobacco settlement is too
big and too complicated to be enacted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Nobody's saying so
yet, but there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four little</NUMEX> words that should come to mind with this news:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> health care plan. On that one too, there was great initial enthusiasm,
followed by earnest pronouncements that more time was needed, followed by a
slow legislative death. The only difference would be that this time, it's the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of reform that might well harness the traditional mechanisms for gumming
up the works. Don't be surprised if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kessler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Everett Koop</ENAMEX> become
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
