
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indictment du Jour</ENAMEX>

At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision holding that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> who are discriminated against on the basis of age have the same legal
rights as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of race and gender bias. (Given the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s rising median
age and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s trend-setting status, this means stand by for lots of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ageism</ENAMEX> suits.)

            The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">39</NUMEX>-count indictment handed down against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX> charged that the former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> solicited and received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $35,000</NUMEX> in
gifts, trips, game tickets and other gratuities from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> doing
business with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> points out that regardless of the
outcome, this is political death for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> once thought to be destined to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>.

            Everybody reports that the charges come after a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9 million</NUMEX>
investigation by a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> makes the point that
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> has also collected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.5 million</NUMEX> in criminal fines from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> of his investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story covers much the same ground
as the others, but breaks out with its observation that the indictments mean
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX> is "the highest-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> to be
charged with a crime." Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX> can't have enjoyed reading in the
Times that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Tyson</ENAMEX>, the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> Espy is
accused of receiving an illegal gift from, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyson Foods</ENAMEX>, "has been talking to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> in exchange for immunity.and he may be called to testify at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Espy</ENAMEX>'s trial."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports on its front page that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> have charged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the news bulletin service they work for, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">outfit</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breaking News Network</ENAMEX>, with mail fraud, conspiracy and electronic
privacy violations in connection with the interception of pagers' display
messages. Included among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the news gatherers were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> who, in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> have taken to using the pagers to protect some of their more
sensitive communications from media scanners.

            What do <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Miramax</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harvey Weinstein</ENAMEX>, investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rattner</ENAMEX>, publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk Ziff</ENAMEX>, Wall Street hedge fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kramer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Friedman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Xerox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Allaire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GE</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Welch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Studios</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Biondi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dreamworks</ENAMEX> partner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geffen</ENAMEX>, and television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exec</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Diller</ENAMEX> have in common? According to the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , they have all had play-time
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Vineyard</ENAMEX> since the start of his vacation
there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , in contrast to the wonks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> who
were the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOBS</ENAMEX>, are the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FOBs</ENAMEX>.

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rhodes</ENAMEX>
argues that the solution to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s huge tainted <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> scare and other
similar problems with the food supply has been sitting on the shelf ready to go
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX>. It is, he says, food irradiation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhodes</ENAMEX> says continuing to
eschew the technique's use because it involves radioactivity is the sort of
fanatic thinking that plagued the introduction of vaccination, water
chlorination, pasteurization and fluoridation.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Blumenthal</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
filed suit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, asking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> in
compensatory damages and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> in punitive damages. Bringing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">AOL</ENAMEX> into it
just adds more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> to the world's first-ever Internet libel case.

         
      
   
