
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		um serious problems in the public education and what can be done about it
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		well what do you think
 	
 	
 		well i that's funny because i just um quit my job to stay home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and um i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> in the public schools
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i know a little bit about it not a whole great deal
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well tell me about it what are what are the problems with public education
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well um there there's some there's several  it's such a a broad
 		you know topic that you you you need to boil it down but um one that um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i thought was a problem that it's a it i thought it was a serious problem that i'm not sure it's being taken care of right now uh was like bilingual education
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for um different um minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians</ENAMEX> and um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican Americans</ENAMEX> and and just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in general that speak other languages that
 		sometimes come from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> or coming from different areas and they and in this area and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> as the school district i'm not sure how to go about it because it's hard to get one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> that speaks all these language and so most of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are put in um either special ed or a bilingual program
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then for just a small amount of time and then they're into their regular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classrooms</ENAMEX> the remaining of the part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are not sure how to teach them math when they don't read or speak
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so um a lot of the moneys isn't put into that and so these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are just kind of sat in the corner and um
 		you know it there's only so long you can do that and to me that seemed like a big problem in the school districts and a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it not it was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s fault a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> were just not getting the backbone or support that they needed or the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> or the extra help that they needed for these specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you find that those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i've seen the same thing and heard the same things and at the same time i've heard that it's even harder when both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are required to work and can't spend
 		you know that that time you know typically the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was at home with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and and at least could kind of keep up on what's going on and really society sort of dictates that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> work and and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i know i've heard some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about just the fact that even as far back as the you know the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade uh if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> had you know proper reading skills or learned proper reading skills that that would make a lot of difference
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh definitely definitely and it and it teaches language too which is really good um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i work at a university and and it's really tough when we're uh uh i i uh work at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we have uh some pretty selective admissions requirements for incoming freshmen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who are in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> even some who are maybe
 		you know in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> uh of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S A T</ENAMEX> scores are very low and a lot of it has has to do with their uh
 		their reading ability you know their their language and
 	
 	
 		yeah oh definitely yeah
 	
 	
 		it uh makes it tough because when when you know when they come in with scores that low
 		they may be uh good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> but they just haven't achieved to their fullest potential and they're gonna fail unless some sort of remedial uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX> is given to them so
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and then it then it comes into well who's supposed to give it to them the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> or
 		are they supposed to get that  back in the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and the junior highs
 	
 	
 		well i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> school district has a has a wonderful program in the remedial reading um where
 		you know of course all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are tested in some time at portion of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and and uh
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who need extra help are put into this um reading program and it is just excellent it is i wish that
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> could be exposed to that program
 		you know and then there i know that there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that say how do i get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in that and yet they don't qualify but unfortunate that they don't qualify because i think everybody would benefit from these programs
 	
 	
 		yeah it sounds like it
 	
 	
 		it is excellent so
 	
 	
 		so how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have at home
 	
 	
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little ones and that's why i i quit my job uh you know i've been teaching since they were gosh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">newborns</ENAMEX> and  and it just wasn't adding up and you know
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and you see all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who are working and working and working and just you know don't have the time time time time it was kind of getting to me where well i'm doing the same thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and so um you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are getting older and i was missing out on a lot so i just decided to stay home for a while i don't know how long   as long
 	
 	
 		well that's good what when
 		
 		
 	