
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay now what is your favorite TV show
 	
 	
 		well it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhart</ENAMEX> and it's gone now and i miss it real bad
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well can't you find anything else to um to replace
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i think so i like the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Improvement</ENAMEX> sitcom i like any i like most of the sitcoms if they keep me entertained for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half an hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you don't watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Exposure</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do watch <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern Exposure</ENAMEX> and  also for for ever how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> it's been on TV i've been watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knots Landing</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay you're having to be in reruns for that one have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Bridge</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i haven't seen that one yet
 	
 	
 		that is one of it's so clean and so laid back and i'm awful tired of
 		some of the things that they have on TV  but this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> minute story is i would certainly recommend that you try it
 		it
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> i don't know but you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> watches all those <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rescue 911 Unsolved Mystery</ENAMEX> things
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		drives me nuts
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i just don't even like to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> when all of those are on it's like too much real life
 	
 	
 		and i think it's a shame that our life has to be i mean so many of the tragedies that we have on the movies or on TV no we need something lighter than that  have you seen um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hm i'll Fly Away
 	
 	
 		i'll Fly Away i think i watched that that's where there there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> and he has a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> or a nanny
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		i watched that once when it i think when it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode and it just didn't grab my attention
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		i felt like it was kind of they were trying to copy To Kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mockingbird</ENAMEX> without all the suspense or something
 	
 	
 		um it's not
 		i don't know it it's clean it there again you don't have the violence
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um i'm surprised it's even still on because coming at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock in the evening</TIMEX> that's when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> want to watch
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that is not part of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		actually it's
 		the best time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> for me for watching TV is is starts around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and will end in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> and that's for the college basketball
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um really get involved in that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> played basketball when she was in high school and college so that's something we can both watch and keep up with which is pretty interesting at time
 	
 	
 		well i'm let's see i believe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> lost <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> is that correct
 	
 	
 		you know i'm not sure if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> won or lost i can't i don't even keep up with them or either my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> goes there i just don't keep up with them
 	
 	
 		well you don't have to
 	
 	
 		no my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are back east and they seem to be the best ones anyway so
 	
 	
 		well don't you ever forget that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> is not bad but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>'s doing good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">State</ENAMEX> though is the better of the two so
 	
 	
 		yeah is that where you are from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		that's right um-hum i'm a transplanted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> Okie um-hum
 	
 	
 		well aren't we all are from somewhere
 	
 	
 		well we've from somewhere is correct so i hope you can find enough TV to keep you happy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well there's always actually i'll probably watch too much TV and and
 		uh i think that probably effects me too from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">just</NUMEX> from watching too much
 	
 	
 		well i have recently retired and i find that this is the most boring thing in the world is to sit and watch TV
 	
 	
 		so yeah well i'm at home all the time myself and uh i don't work
 		and i never ever turn the TV on during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you don't well
 	
 	
 		uh just just something i i can't do i won't do and when someone else is here during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and and like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s been out of school for a month drives me nuts when he turns that thing on during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		it's
 		oh it's nice to have the noise  sometime it's nice that you don't need that noise
 	
 	
 		well
 		i'm just afraid i won't get things done if if i if there's something there that keep me busy
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do you work out of the home
 	
 	
 		uh no i have a medical problem and i don't haven't worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so that that just i just stay home and
 		run errands do chores keep you know do the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> work for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> she still works and uh that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		what kind of a job did you have when you were working
 	
 	
 		i was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> at the medical school here for the food service
 		and it was a very heavy desk and a very busy desk  and i'm awful sorry that i'm no longer gainfully employed but they're
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		
 		
 	