
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well you got a topic
 	
 	
 		well you know there's uh the uh the the the one that's burning in everybody's uh
 		in everybody's mind the uh break up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and it's a
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i i think that's the obvious one in't it
 	
 	
 		ah it's it's it's effects here at home
 		i mean it's gonna have effects all over the world and uh
 		course you know i i expect uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few days</TIMEX> when uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> gives his uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address
 		he's got to have to uh
 		pull some uh
 		real drastic changes in what he's doing to to promote some
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> and enthusiasm behind his reelection race
 	
 	
 		yeah well it it's truly amazing to um see how rapidly um uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> fell apart um uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it makes me wonder i'm not saying that i'm uh i'm certainly not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hawk</ENAMEX> necessarily
 		but it makes me wonder i've thought about this if the idea of uh uh the the arms race while granted it has practically practically bankrupted this country
 		uh perhaps it did bankrupt uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and was you know as a as a way of making a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a political change was certainly preferable to a war
 	
 	
 		yeah well they they they focused all of their economic capacity on on on their military
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean if they had focused the same capacity in their uh commercial stuff they would've been a lot better off as a society probably uh
 	
 	
 		yeah with the right kind of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> for example
 	
 	
 		yes like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		i don't know what we've we've seen so many changes just in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past five years</TIMEX> uh it makes me think it reminds me of that book uh Future Shock
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where the the future is coming at us uh at such an accelerated pace <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> after day
 		that only the most adaptable are gonna be able to uh survive and and keep from just being overrun by the changes
 	
 	
 		well uh you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five five years ago</TIMEX> could you have have imagined in your in your your wildest dreams that something as as a change as rapid as this would've occurred
 	
 	
 		oh no no
 	
 	
 		it's just you know it it's almost unthinkable but it it is hey in a i i still wonder whether you know that it's going to be stable and then what's going to happen there
 	
 	
 		it really is
 		well  and that's just it i i have some
 		i have doubts that uh
 		that it can be ah stable number one you've got uh you know you see on the news
 		the the stories the stories and the and the sights of these these the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are standing in line
 		uh for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> on end and have for you know bare shelves at  in these hugely you know uh higher prices that they have to pay now that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> controls are off
 	
 	
 		but i don't think the shelves is bare anymore
 	
 	
 		oh are they are they back are they have they got some um
 	
 	
 		i think there's now you know i think all the time there were goods
 		to to be distributed that were being held off
 	
 	
 		but they're on the black market
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know i i i think that uh
 		there's still but but you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have a lot of money to pay for them there there's a tremendous uh
 		gap in their ability to to supply themselves uh uh that could create a tremendous amount of political stability instability in fact they said <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> on the on the radio uh that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		some some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">in in of</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is calling for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> to essentially throw out all of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> and replace them
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		because of this this tremendous supply demand uh type gap that they have there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't know it it's it's
 		it's hard to imagine managing such a rapid change
 	
 	
 		yeah and i don't i don't that's just it  it's funny it's inconceivable inconceivable to me to think that anyone or any entity i don't care
 		what it is could actually manage i mean it would it's kind of like damage control and maybe putting out the biggest fires but i don't think that it's really a manageable uh of set of circumstances
 	
 	
 		well and and i think that you know we we stand uh
 		in in in the possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">of in of</ENAMEX> of being confronted with a similar kind of thing here uh everybody is is calling for you know this this this this
 		uh peace dividend and
 		it the with with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election year</TIMEX> coming up there's the uh that there's the the
 		the possibility of everybody proposing something radical to to
 		appeal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> to to to get elected but you know how how rapidly can they change and how rapid can they move
 	
 	
 		well as far as i'm concerned i can change pretty doggone rapidly and i'm all for something radical because i think it's gonna take something radical to turn this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> around um
 		
 		
 	