
 
     		
 	
 		do work in a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um well i i work in a actually it's sort of an odd situation right now but uh
 		i have until recently been working in in a uh in a large organization
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i currently maintain an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> still at at the place even though i i officially quit there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's it's not really a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> but uh nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly five hundred</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah that's pretty big
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah how about yourself are you
 	
 	
 		i work in a hospital and i think probably there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess um the thing i was thinking about as i was pondering this question is um
 		besides salary it seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if it's a large enough place need to feel that their job's an important one you know that they have the respect of their fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah not lost in the in the crowd huh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's it's more probably an issue in a large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> than it would be in a small one
 	
 	
 		ooh yeah i i think it it's probably the thing is that it's always fairly obvious in a small <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right because um yeah
 	
 	
 		right everyone's so integral
 	
 	
 		yeah everybody knows what everybody else is doing and and knows that it's
 		it's generally important
 	
 	
 		um-hum upward mobility or an opportunity to grow and learn different job tasks is probably an important one but it seemed to me that the respect of others is probably real important too
 	
 	
 		but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what what about what about uh advantages of large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> i mean benefits and things
 	
 	
 		well i definitely think that health care packages and that sort of thing are probably gonna be easier to coordinate you know in a larger
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah when it when i've worked with a with i mean the the small things i've worked with really haven't had any uh any consistent
 		yeah or any any kind of quality package right i mean it just kind of leaves you on your own yeah i i've had my own little business and then i've worked for small businesses
 	
 	
 		really in health care uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and yeah the the the only ones that i've had large uh uh i mean i've had health care and and and other kinds of benefits with have been large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> vacation and
 	
 	
 		also i work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX> and that that's a is very large organization
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		and were those good um considering the the size of that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> did you feel like that you had good benefits
 	
 	
 		i you you know relative to nothing of course you know i mean it it i think so um the question you know i mean it's it's it's handy to have them i just had gotten used to just not having insurance benefits and things um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX> did you pay for them on your own or did you just go without
 	
 	
 		um typically let's see uh typically the myself i i was covered myself but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> wasn't you know i had to chip in to for them to be covered but it was pretty economical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um especially relative to just buying your own health care package
 	
 	
 		right that really gets prohibitive
 	
 	
 		yeah and so you know so that's that's handy uh you know i think that it i'm amazed that uh of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place i was working uh what they calculate to be their overhead
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because of benefits they figure uh i mean it's something like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five forty</NUMEX> or fifty percent of of salary
 	
 	
 		yes i've heard that too
 	
 	
 		and  which is which is pretty amazing
 	
 	
 		it is especially especially if you consider in some situations <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might actually use that much hopefully they budget for that and it doesn't get used up entirely but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's a lot i think that those sorts of advantages are nice i know um
 		my benefits through the hospital cover my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> since my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works for himself out of our home and and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> that's elsewhere but he doesn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he didn't really ever pursue individual benefits and i think it makes a difference to be able to have the security of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>'s benefits
 	
 	
 		i i think so yeah it really does um do you get other benefits besides health do you have life insurance and things like that
 	
 	
 		it it actually it's interesting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just this last week</TIMEX> um they introduced what the nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> package was gonna look like and while the life insurance that we have free from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> is limited to it's uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they offered for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time a life term that would be up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and fifty but you have to pay into it
 	
 	
 		right are
 	
 	
 		the rest of the package is pretty good it's vision and dental and you know all the full medical
 	
 	
 		oh well um-hum yeah that's good i I just had uh dental insurance for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time uh from from an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> which i thought was was pretty handy really took advantage of it i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um do are you finding that that uh the packages uh that your benefits packages are shrinking
 	
 	
 		you know i've seen that all over the bay area in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> bay area at least and probably true in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i haven't yet at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> we've kind of been waiting with baited breath we're the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> that i know of that doesn't have uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a partial payment or i don't know if you call it copayment or premium by the the consumer
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh copayment uh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so as as of this date  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are free because they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX> but i know a lot of other place like you were mentioning you know you pay if
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i i mean i
 		typically you typically pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dependents</ENAMEX> and and not for yourself but i i've the you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i was working with really has has been um
 		you know they don't wanna cut back benefits but on the other hand they're real concerned about the rising costs and and sort of scaling uh uh you know keeping
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		
 		
 	