
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because uh discuss crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and what we might be able uh do to uh help stop it
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		um well you're in quite a um interesting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for um crime <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and all kinds of things that we hear about aren't you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well actually i i i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> on business
 	
 	
 		oh i see uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh but i've i've been down here quite a bit for the past oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> on and off
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i see
 	
 	
 		and yes there is plenty of crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> uh  but you know um i don't know that it's any worse than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		well it's probably each <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> i guess has its own specific type of difficulty
 	
 	
 		and i know there's plenty of crime in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		oh there's a lot of homicides in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that seems to be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh well a lot of it is drug related but i i think that there is just an excessive homicide rate and an excessive amount of arms bearing uh you know personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> bearing
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and it it seems to just lend itself to instantaneous um  if you're don't feel good about a certain thing there you go and the crime is committed so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i have uh i was talking with some with with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine not too damned long ago and i'll tell you it it's you know i don't expect this would ever happen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> but i'm almost of the opinion
 		that the only way that a change is going to come about is if uh we really put some teeth into the law and and make it such that uh the punishment fits the crime and uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		have a a swift and and sure justice that uh you know do away with some of these automatic uh appeals when uh i think that guilt is proven
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see um-hum
 		i'm not sure i know sufficiently about the ins and outs of the law to um
 		know exactly what that brings about you know the the appeals and things like that as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being um retrialed and maybe get an alleviated sentence
 		it does seem though that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> capacities are stretching to the fullest and uh
 	
 	
 		well in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> it's absurd they are letting uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have been convicted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times for armed robbery
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for example and this was they had a big article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> about it
 		because of the overcrowding they're being released from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Huntsville</ENAMEX> they're given <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred dollars</NUMEX> and put on a bus for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> with instructions to turn themselves in to a parole officer
 		less than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty ten</TIMEX> percent it was a ridiculously low low number actually do ever report to a parole parole officer
 		and the vast majority of them are then caught again go through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> back to jail well it's ludicrous and absurd
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i just don't think that you know we as a society can afford to continue to have these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> being paroled after serving
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a fraction</NUMEX> sometimes you know a quarter of their sentence
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's right
 	
 	
 		but uh i i don't know it's uh i don't own a gun
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh  i you know i believe and i adhere to the thought that
 		you know if you so often i mean it's it's having a gun leads to tragedy
 	
 	
 		that's right i believe that
 	
 	
 		and at the same and at the same time
 		i think i have thought before what would i do if i were accosted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 		a a fellow i work with uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> he told me uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just this past week</TIMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was walking out of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and was robbed
 	
 	
 		oh my in the parking lot oh yes uh-huh um
 	
 	
 		broad open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daylight</TIMEX> in the parking lot
 		so anyway it it is it's a scary situation and i really don't know what this what the answer
 	
 	
 		um
 		it's very difficult to know what the answer is and uh along with that there's a lot of poverty poverty a lot of homeless and
 		and a lot of um i guess um discrimination is still around and
 		i i suppose until somehow or another we can straighten out all of those things <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just going to take an extreme  uh measure and um uh protect themselves in one way or the other
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i'm i'm a firm believer though that uh  our justice system has has no teeth any longer that the idea of getting a sentence
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and knowing that the parole uh will come uh uh just in a short matter of time not only that we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in jail now that i mean had a program on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> i mean that they have telephones
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail cells</ENAMEX> it's absurd
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		yeah so i mean i don't know
 	
 	
 		oh that's very strange
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know it's yeah
 		
 		
 	