
 
     		
 	
 		did you see in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or on the news when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> fainted at a dinner it was was that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> uh i didn't get to see that uh we've uh just gotten back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and so i was bumping up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> in a camper and uh i didn't get to watch any television so i've just been finding out about this once i got back
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well i thought it was pretty scary i i missed it uh i mean i when they were rerunning rerunning it like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> or something i mean i didn't hear about it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> it happened but i
 		it was interesting you know that when he fainted and every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind of jumped up on the table and surrounded him and it's really amazing that that would happen and then of course all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> discussion comes up again
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well i was kind of pleased that uh when i got back that that was the hot <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> on the news that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> had fainted at dinner because that means that nothing else happened anywhere in the world
 	
 	
 		that's uh that is true that is real good well he you know as for as young as he is he seems to have had several health problems you know health uh incidences if not problems
 	
 	
 		yeah well you need <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> running around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh you you'd have your share of health problem too
 	
 	
 		right that's right well i um
 		i guess i haven't really been  i've been trying to tune out a lot of the political issues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> when because the campaigning is starting and uh so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think the key issue that's going on at the moment is the uh uh current economy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think there's a lot of things that need to be done to to rectify that situation i'm not sure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is the key player
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		it is scary
 	
 	
 		i think one of the statements that was made uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> by uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX>
 		when he was announcing some of the problems that existed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> he made the comment he said well our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> may be bankrupt but referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> he says your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are bankrupt
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh that's been a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> for me
 		and i noticed that uh when i go into the tougher <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> at some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organic Chemistry</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh you don't find very many white <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> taking the tough courses
 	
 	
 		right they're foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you find you find a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> uh you find uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> in the class
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in all of the tough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> that i have taken the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> that i've found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> have have generally been from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX> or some other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> they're foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's i think it's kind of pathetic that uh
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are not motivated to uh
 		to study in depth and uh to take the hard courses and i'm i'm concerned that that is our economic problem not not how much money is being spent at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		well they seem
 		well that's really true and but i have noticed from uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">associations</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> in high school that they are really motivated by how much money they can make and when they hear on the news about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being laid off
 		and uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> and things i mean i feel like they don't wanna make the effort out of um their own personal interests to follow a particular field or they wanna think you know how quickly can they make money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're not attracted by the the work that has to be done to achieve
 		uh you know a position like that
 	
 	
 		yeah well i know when i went through school uh i went through an engineering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and of all my close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> they were all there because they loved engineering
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they loved building things they loved solving problems uh they liked
 		you know being creative and there was another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> there that were there to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> because they heard that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> made a lot of money
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and we didn't mix very well you know there was a a total difference in attitude and we felt very
 		isolated or uh discriminated against in not being you know separate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> in terms of attitude
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well you're right when you say that um
 		the important issues need to be not so as much what's going on other places i mean that it's important for us to do
 		i mean we we can't be isolated here but um you know we do need to pay more attention to our own economy and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and our own civilization because we've seen how quickly and it's almost unbelievable the fall of the um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">um Berlin Wall</ENAMEX> and all of that's almost unreal to me still
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that was a terribly precarious economy economy uh i've been kind of watching it over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and observing that the the amount of bureaucracy over there
 		
 		
 	