
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		are you there okay now tell me your favorite team
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh baseball
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well i've been kind of  been intrigued with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 		more so with uh
 		uh their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> than anything else i'd i don't follow baseball that that closely
 		but uh since you know since i live here so close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> uh
 		that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that i've been kind of following
 	
 	
 		okay i think it's a little bit late in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> for them to assign us where do you think they're headed
 		so we'll have to talk about the future with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		what are your thinkings on what they can do what they'll be able to do
 	
 	
 		well i think that uh
 		you know with uh
 		so much controversy over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruben Sierra</ENAMEX> not signing and asking us for so much money it's um
 		you know i think
 		i'm not real sure about that do you know anything about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruben Sierra</ENAMEX>'s uh
 	
 	
 		well i heard <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> on the news that he is willing to come down on his
 	
 	
 		yeah that he was willing to come down a little bit and uh if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> will go up a little bit
 	
 	
 		yes and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> go up a little bit um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah but a little bit from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> you know from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thirty million dollars</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five million</NUMEX> that's a lot of money
 	
 	
 		i think the entire baseball yeah they're the ones that probably are paying the highest
 	
 	
 		yeah they are
 	
 	
 		and i think this is absolutely ridiculous
 	
 	
 		um-hum and i really think i really think that uh that they ought to
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i'm not real sure that they should pay him that much money i think they should uh
 		uh pay him what his salary's going to be
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and let him because he's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> before he turns into a a free agent
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and then uh who knows if he produces <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> they may have to end up paying him anyway
 		but if he doesn't then his market value will go down and they can pick him up for for a lot less than than they would uh if they paid him the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> you know the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six million dollars</NUMEX> a year this year
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what i saw on the news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buechele Buechele</ENAMEX> was back just to visit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm awful sorry he's not still
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but you know what he that was a great deal for him
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure it was
 	
 	
 		yeah it was a great deal for him and and uh he just signed on uh i think it was like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year</TIMEX> deal with uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> so you know he's real happy there as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> are concerned i think
 		i think they need some definitely need some pitching
 	
 	
 		yes sir
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and so i you know i
 	
 	
 		well what do you think of Howse
 		who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um the pitching coach
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well you know i was just looking at the news <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> and they showed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that was going was helping out uh
 	
 	
 		his assistant
 	
 	
 		his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> and i think that's a a great addition i mean he seemed to know what he was doing and and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i really wish they could
 		see fit to get rid of Howse
 	
 	
 		oh you don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howse</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		no no i really don't
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i'm not going to stand up you know on my soapbox and say that but i'm not fond of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howse</ENAMEX> and i'm not fond of Grieves
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Grieve</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i'm not sure that um that they're ready to get rid of of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Grieve</ENAMEX> yet
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howse</ENAMEX> might be a different uh situation and i think you're probably right that they
 		that they need some you know some changes in uh pitching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> maybe and
 		um
 	
 	
 		well i'm just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gullible</ENAMEX> enough that i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Valentine</ENAMEX> is um uh doing all right
 		and i'm sure well
 	
 	
 		you do huh
 		that's contrary to uh popular belief you know
 	
 	
 		oh i know i know so but i would like so much
 		for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> to get their act together and give um
 		oh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX> the support he needs
 	
 	
 		oh i know you know it's too bad that uh it has to be a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> to to lead the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		i understand
 	
 	
 		they need to have some some young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that can take the lead and
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		well
 		i just  oh i have so many mixed emotions about all this but i think with their new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> they should go and let's us have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	