
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i subscribe to a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> on a regular basis how about you
 	
 	
 		oh yes i do um i always enter those things that come through the mail you know  that's right yeah  yeah they do
 	
 	
 		oh really  they like you
 	
 	
 		so i have just about everything  at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sometime</TIMEX> or other
 	
 	
 		really how many how many uh would you say at any given time you tend to subscribe to
 	
 	
 		oh probably no more than say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> at the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh what are your favorites
 	
 	
 		well i like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCalls Reader's</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we subscribe to that one now too
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest Redbook</ENAMEX> um Good uh let's see Good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housekeeping Better Homes and Gardens  um</ENAMEX> and uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you like that one
 		i had i had started that one <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> thinking that it would be a nice way to get some decorating tips and and more interior kinds of things but um
 		it's really a collection of everything it has got a lot of um
 		home making kinds of things too you know food as well as indoor and outdoor stuff
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i i love to get recipes you know out of the magazine i cut them out put them in a book and  yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah uh-huh  me too  i'm not sure that i use them as often as i think that i will but i sure uh pay attention to them and cut them out
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh i also um usually get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> about travel and um
 	
 	
 		do you use the tips and a suggestions do you do you travel often enough that you are able to to  take advantage of it
 	
 	
 		not not really  um uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		just fun just sort of
 	
 	
 		i i read them and you know get ideas but um i don't  travel that much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so but i
 	
 	
 		the thing i like about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> is that they are a wonderful diversion for a brief period of time if you feel like you are not in the mood  to really sit down with a book for a long time it's it's a perfect short
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh
 		attention getter
 	
 	
 		yes it really is yeah and um oh i like the uh beauty tips and you know all that fashion stuff and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX> do you do you have favorite fashion oriented magazines
 	
 	
 		no not really  i i just read them a from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that i get i don't really take a fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh uh-huh none that are specifically focused on fashion
 	
 	
 		oh no just just what's in the regular magazines
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who works for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> that's based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		and and i remember seeing it enough times at her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that
 		i wondered how often <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> subscribe to those kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> because you almost have to be in the business to be as intrigued with some of those fashions they're so bizarre
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true  it's
 	
 	
 		we all have to change our wardrobe regularly enough to invest in the magazine
 	
 	
 		that's uh that's right you sure would  oh yeah i you know keep entering these contests taking all of these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> thinking i'll win that big
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clearing House</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah right  oh and there's several others that uh i get through the mail and uh you know they have contests like that not as big as that one but
 		anyway i've always been kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sucker</ENAMEX> i guess for magazines
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's sort of another uh added attraction of those uh contests i guess you could probably enter the contests without getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> but it's not much fun
 	
 	
 		yeah you can yeah that's true  um Redbook i've always taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redbook</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they used to have a novel in the back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah but they quit doing that and i sure miss it
 	
 	
 		hm i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Redbook</ENAMEX> very well what what does it tend to be a mix of uh fashion and and recipes and that sort of thing or what what did
 	
 	
 		yeah it's similar to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCalls</ENAMEX> or something like that yeah
 	
 	
 		oh is it uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah not too much different
 	
 	
 		
 
 		tend to focus more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s issues than
 	
 	
 		yes definitely uh-huh yeah  but they have some good short stories too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh but i really miss that novel it used to make to take me oh say a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> you know i'd crawl up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Redbook</ENAMEX> and read the novel
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's interesting i always thought that that was a big enough attraction in a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> that they i'm surprised that they would get rid of it
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know why they did i never did hear anything at all about it all of a sudden it was just gone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um-hum  McCalls</ENAMEX> certainly has changed a lot of over the years
 	
 	
 		yeah they used to be a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> and you know they cut the size down and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all but uh
 	
 	
 		i used to get one called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Savvy</ENAMEX> that went out of business or merged or something and
 		since i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> the subscription through they automatically switched all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX>
 		instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savvy</ENAMEX> got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCalls</ENAMEX> and that's how i got introduced to it
 	
 	
 		oh is that right  well i can remember yeah seeing Savvy i don't know that i ever subscribed to it but i've seen it you know in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i liked it i thought it was kind of a nice
 		
 		
 	