
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no we just uh i guess i'm hot on this subject because we just spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks</TIMEX> camping
 		in a recreational vehicle
 	
 	
 		uh where did you go
 	
 	
 		we took a tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well  interestingly enough i'm calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well i was down there visiting the uh the orchid jungle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homestead</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		came back with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> that i hadn't planned on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah we were down past <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> went down into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you know that's something i've never done is go down to the Keys although i i'm just here on business but uh i would love to go down there
 	
 	
 		um well we found it a little bit of a disappointment uh we had expected some nice warm sunny <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> we got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> above seventy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we thought the beaches would be nice but uh
 		uh well <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Key West</ENAMEX> was uh just coral rubble
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we did find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahia Honda</ENAMEX> was a fairly nice state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> it had a nice beach
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was running <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about seventy five degrees</NUMEX> so it was kind of hard to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to to go in and and snorkel and and do those sort of things
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well i've never done any motor home camping although uh uh it it is more attractive to me now than it used to be
 		when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> uh we used to go camping up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ozarks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh  we found a pretty remote campground uh uh actually whenever we first started going to it you had to drive <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about twenty five miles</NUMEX> on a gravel road
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to get back up into it and uh it had uh no electricity and uh it had a hand pump for water
 		but it was on a lake that was just crystal clear and we would spend a week up there you know and they had a a little country store about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles away that you could get you know minimal provisions so you pretty much had to carry everything you needed with you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh that was it was great fun but since then i honestly have not done much what you could call camping
 	
 	
 		hum
 		well my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> talks a lot about camping and uh she's taken the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> uh on off to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> camp a couple of times
 		but my idea of camping is in a either an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">RV</ENAMEX> or in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty thirty five</TIMEX> foot sailboat
 	
 	
 		yeah well now  yeah you kind of remind me of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who who said her idea of roughing it is slow room service
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but uh yeah i've got a uh i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> who has a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty two</NUMEX> foot uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tartan</ENAMEX> sailboat
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh it which has for me has been the best of all worlds because he's got the expense and i get the pleasure of going out on it
 	
 	
 		yeah i did that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> i crewed for a fellow that uh was doing a lot of racing
 	
 	
 		well that's hard work
 	
 	
 		and uh and well it was fun it was quite enjoyable
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've been with it on on several uh races we've run the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">yacht</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh but no i love to sail and i agree i had never thought really thought about that as camping before but that is that is probably one of the best ways to go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what did you do did you rent a motor home when you came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah we rented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruise America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was it what is that expensive
 	
 	
 		uh it was  running about eighty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">seven dollars</NUMEX> a day
 	
 	
 		well that's cheaper than a hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> really
 	
 	
 		that's cheaper than a hotel and you add uh oh maybe another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five</TIMEX> dollars for that for a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> site
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know the hookup and water and sewage and so forth
 	
 	
 		how big was the one you rented
 	
 	
 		we had a uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two footer</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah was that uh any problem driving or
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well it's it's a big truck uh but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when you get that big a truck the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">fuel</ENAMEX> economy goes to pot if you try to push it at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty five</TIMEX> and you get pretty decent fuel economy at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifty five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so uh i just uh had a change of mind set and i would set the uh autopilot on fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and just cruise down the highway well everybody else wants to speed so they wind up passing you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you just stay in the right lane and there's nobody in front of you and all you have to do is guide it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so it's kind of a pleasant way to drive you
 		uh i've found that i get there just about as fast as anybody else because there will be some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that i'll pass <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> the same one
 	
 	
 		oh sure yeah yeah that always irritates me when i pass somebody several times i've i've been in the other in the other uh uh uh had the shoe on the other foot
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah because you go down there and some hotshot will go by you that you know he's got a colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that you recognize and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the next thing you know you know it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunchtime</TIMEX> he's got to stop for lunch and you just holler at your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to make you a sandwich
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah right right right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and uh well we enjoyed it uh one of of places we visited was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walt Disney World</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 		
 	