
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what kind of music do you like
 	
 	
 		well seeing as how i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX>  i like all kinds of music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah we
 	
 	
 		all very very kinds
 	
 	
 		um-hum me too i mostly like classical and jazz
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i like everything from hard core <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wagner</ENAMEX> and  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahler</ENAMEX> and i like new age stuff i i basically have a wide range of musical likes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do you um
 		are you musical uh are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		yeah i play the trumpet uh-huh
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		most of the trumpet music's um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Baroque</ENAMEX> and um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um  um Romantic Baroque</ENAMEX> and Romantic
 	
 	
 		jazz
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's not there there's um things written for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Severinsen</ENAMEX> and a few other people
 		but uh
 		they're just uh as far as solos and concertos are concerned but the rest of them are just parts
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and all um
 	
 	
 		well i love Baroque music so it's one of my favorite periods
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and and
 	
 	
 		in fact i  i sing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Baroque</ENAMEX> ensemble
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		who are the trumpet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in that
 	
 	
 		well we used to have um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Dutchen</ENAMEX> but now he's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> he's come back a couple of times then there's a trumpet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Texas</ENAMEX> the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> the main teacher
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Candelaria</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah  and he's played and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them have played natural trumpets  and occasionally when she can't get those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we'll use you know just uh E flat trumpets
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with valves and like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen Bell</ENAMEX> plays and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Rick</ENAMEX> um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bogart</ENAMEX>'s played too so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but actually i like i like trumpet and organ together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a nice combination
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Jung Julio</ENAMEX> recorded an album at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Aquinas</ENAMEX> didn't he  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i think he did with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> yeah
 		he's wonderful both of them are
 		so do you like Romantic music
 	
 	
 		well that's what that's mostly the rest of good trumpet marks are Romantic music <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mahler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruckner and and Strauss</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you like opera
 	
 	
 		uh i like i'm liking it more and more now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		getting used to it
 	
 	
 		there's a
 	
 	
 		and mostly uh mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean there's not there's not any kind of trumpet parts but uh you know the
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i just like the melodies more and and and uh the libretto
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puccini</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um yeah well i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossini</ENAMEX> better than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puccini</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like more comic than
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> are you going to go see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Elixir of Love</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		do you ever go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Opera</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no i've never been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Opera</ENAMEX> only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Worth Opera</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my trumpet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> used to uh play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Worth Opera</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who was your trumpet teacher
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh John Nelson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i know him i kind of know him is he still around here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah he played in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Worth Symphony</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> mostly
 	
 	
 		because i don't i've not seen him playing anywhere lately but maybe it's because he's playing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i'm basically a church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> i do a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> and we do all  kinds of music at my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and we hire lots of instrumentalists off and on for different things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm always making music of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind or another
 	
 	
 		which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> is it
 	
 	
 		uh it's at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christ United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> in Plano
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it seems like a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> are hiring more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musicians</ENAMEX> now than they used to
 	
 	
 		yeah most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> have the well there's some of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that have the funds to you know to do like big big works
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but we hire you know we hire an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">orchestra</ENAMEX> at least twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and then different instrumentalists off and on throughout the year
 		that we have you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cuminado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		he plays at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in fact he is playing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sunday</TIMEX>  at our church
 	
 	
 		but he's still teaching at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhaven</ENAMEX> isn't he
 	
 	
 		but he plays pretty regularly
 		uh i think so he teaches a lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> at high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but i think he teaches at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhaven</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah because i heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen Bell</ENAMEX> taught at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> as well
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen</ENAMEX> teaches here too they're the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them are mainly pretty much the i think they've cornered the market on trumpet students
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	