
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh
 		what kind of fishing is there up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well there's quite a quite a bit of different kinds lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go uh stream fishing
 		and we have a a few lakes uh right now they're uh doing a little bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> fishing on some of the lakes i personally don't fish a lot fish a great deal uh
 		got kind of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> it's
 		you know it's not something that we're really into there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trout farms</ENAMEX> that are close by that we go fish at just with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> for fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how about yourself what do you enjoy
 	
 	
 		well i was i was raised on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> coast and i like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt water</ENAMEX> fishing
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is there's quite a few lakes around here i've
 		done some fishing from the shore i don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> which you really need to get out into the lakes uh you know really do any good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've
 		i've caught a few striped bass from the shore some of the small ones
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> and stuff i haven't done a lot since i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how long you been there
 	
 	
 		oh
 		off and on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> we were here
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> got homesick we moved backed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama Mobile</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight months</TIMEX> and moved back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> because the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		wages and all were better up here
 	
 	
 		oh i have a the only reason i'm in the program is i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and a well a sister that lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> and so they uh they uh get involved in this we went out to a lake <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time when i was visiting them i can't even remember what it was called it was a pretty good sized one
 		seem like there were a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> fishing there from the shore is all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i never caught anything or never been uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt salt water</ENAMEX> fishing that sounds like you know kind of be a lot of fun i've seen these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that
 		well you go on a vacation and they go out in the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		go deep sea fishing you ever done that
 	
 	
 		yeah i did that a couple of times the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i had worked for in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mobile</ENAMEX> they had a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of bunch of us <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> got together and we and chartered a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		went out caught red snapper and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> caught a ling
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i caught a few what they call trigger fish
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the it wasn't
 		some of the snappers that much not that much fun they don't really i mean uh yeah they they don't fight at all it's just pulling dead weight you know
 	
 	
 		they don't fight
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah and we'd constantly getting our lines tangled up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> fishing on both sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it was one uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> were good but it was kind of a hassle
 	
 	
 		i got a brother-in-law just got back from a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh he said that was quite a bit of fun uh i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">salmon</ENAMEX> are pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> and uh they went uh out in the you know more of the deep sea fishing as well caught a fair amount of halibut
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they say the halibut are are a pretty good fighter too
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		they're an odd fish i don't know if you ever seen i guess they lie on the flat on the bottom of the ocean and they only have one eye or or just a small eye on the other side
 	
 	
 		okay well we we catch flounder on the coast which is about the same thing
 	
 	
 		as halibut
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		do they put up a fight or not
 	
 	
 		uh well they hug the bottom they
 		they don't run that much but they they
 		somehow they hug the bottom and it's kind of you find it's a pretty good struggle to put them in you know pull them in once they get
 	
 	
 		once you get them over to over to the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> because they're they're pretty pretty weighty <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> are they yeah do you net those or i guess you have to huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		uh
 		i've caught i've caught <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on a hook with live shrimp i've
 		caught several of them in cast nets
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah about yeah you would have to net them to get them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> because they really have a small mouth and all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i've i've fished mostly you know
 		when i was on the coast in the in the bays and stuff in a little you know plywood skiff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		well the  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>'s kind of brackish so i
 		i catch a mixture of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt water</ENAMEX> and fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> fish right with
 		right on the coast you know i catch
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">catfish</ENAMEX> in the bayou and go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">half a mile</NUMEX> and catch a you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt water</ENAMEX> fish
 	
 	
 		you know i've never eaten <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">catfish</ENAMEX> are they good eating
 	
 	
 		yeah they they real good they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so that i guess
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the coast and all consider them that's the best around
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		kind of an ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">looking fish</ENAMEX> are they  great big whiskers on them
 	
 	
 		yeah they they
 		yeah they are and they're bottom feeders if you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you get them out of real muddy water then they got a muddy taste to them but if you
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know catch them out of clear running <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> they they're pretty good
 	
 	
 		taste a little better yeah well these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">trout</ENAMEX> that we catch are real good i i quite enjoy those uh they this place where we go with uh with my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six year old</TIMEX> they uh filet them for you right there for only like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> cents a fish i mean it's well worth it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you just fry them up right
 		
 		
 	