
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		um we have small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and so we our dining is very limited  oh we're past that now we're a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sick</ENAMEX> of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i bet you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> fan
 		are you gosh where do you go Whataburger
 	
 	
 		no um
 		we're more like um you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyatt's Cafeteria</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah that way and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just love everything that's there so we're pretty fortunate kind of um buffet style um so you can go in and go out and the food's already served and you don't have to wait and
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's good
 	
 	
 		and it's already in front of them when you sit down and things like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um Super Salads</ENAMEX> you know it's again it's buffet and
 		it's already prepared and just things any any eating area that you just don't have to wait uh an extremey amount of time
 	
 	
 		i can understand that we've had we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> too and uh when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are small if you're gonna wait you don't go out
 	
 	
 		we
 		no
 	
 	
 		they won't put up with that stuff
 	
 	
 		we tried a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bennigan</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and it was terrible course it was just probably one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the worst days</TIMEX> to go anyways we we waited almost oh forty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> before everything was brought out and it was we were ready to go home
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and you and you had your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with you and they waited forty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no  we fought with them for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't doubt that one bit
 	
 	
 		yeah so we we we rarely go eat in those kind of eating uh situations any more but we do love to eat out and um
 		and we do it as often as we can and and times that we do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitters</ENAMEX> we we try and catch um some things that we normally wouldn't do yeah
 	
 	
 		where where do you like to go when you got a baby sitter
 	
 	
 		oh um let me see uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">New Year</TIMEX>'s we went to eat at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Julio</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		where's that i never heard of that place
 	
 	
 		it's um
 		on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Walnut</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what's the name of that again
 	
 	
 		it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncle Julio</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		what what are the what kind of food
 	
 	
 		um basically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food and it's supposed to be very similar to um uh what is that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> off of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> it's a
 	
 	
 		yeah okay
 	
 	
 		um it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> off of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> like
 	
 	
 		oh there's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a zillion</NUMEX> of them you ever been to Mercado Juarez
 	
 	
 		no but i've heard about it
 	
 	
 		that's a good place i they got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> too now but the original was on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Highway</ENAMEX> uh just the other side west of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Loop Twelve</ENAMEX> that's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> place good good prices good good food there
 	
 	
 		really
 		really um-hum
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> stuff it's it's a good place
 	
 	
 		we like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um seafood</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		you you you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		and um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent</ENAMEX>'s no we haven't
 	
 	
 		that's a good seafood place yeah
 	
 	
 		really
 		really
 	
 	
 		you ever been tried a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana Purchase</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		well this is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> they might have another one but it's on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> Expressway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know it's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cajun</ENAMEX> yeah it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cajun</ENAMEX> type stuff if you like it kind of hot that that is good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that's good stuff
 	
 	
 		okay i've seen it
 		yeah yeah we've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">um Chefalia's</ENAMEX> that's it's basically the same thing seafood <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cajun</ENAMEX> style
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		where's that place
 	
 	
 		that's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> off of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belt Line</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah okay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belt Line</ENAMEX> and what i get over
 	
 	
 		Midway like around i think it's a little past or it's right before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX> or it's right at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midway</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay yeah okay
 	
 	
 		and um
 		excellent food
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		we got this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Premier Dining Card</ENAMEX> thing and we've we've been going to all sorts of weird type places with it
 	
 	
 		what what is that
 	
 	
 		well you get uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> free and you you you pay for one now and type thing and
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we've been to from barbecue to there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swan Club</ENAMEX> which is off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that is if you like continental stuff that is really nice talk talk your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> into taking you there some night i mean it's not a cheap place but uh it's very nice you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really and where is that
 	
 	
 		uh it's on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> it it's north of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> but uh off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh it used to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Telecom Building</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> in the ground floor i don't know what they call it now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Telecom</ENAMEX> kind of moved
 		over in their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> but it it's a big tall it's tallest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">west side</ENAMEX> northwest side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX> and just before you get to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Campbell</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's in the lower floor but really a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> if you if you like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> stuff
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have him tell him to take you there for your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">anniversary</TIMEX> and then they got a place where you can dance you know and all that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well my birthday's coming up so
 	
 	
 		there you go all right you got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> coming
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i need an excuse
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ewaldes</ENAMEX> now there's if you like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> i I like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> stuff myself my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> doesn't necessarily like that stuff but i i like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's down in uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoneleigh Hotel</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that is really super kind of stuff too
 		take if if you like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> at all i mean and that kind of stuff either one of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> you go through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> bucks without <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> trying but it it's it's it's nice really nice place oh you don't have to spend that much i'm kidding you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		oh
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i mean
 		
 		
 	