
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Carolyn</ENAMEX> what kind of dress do you have to wear when you go to work
 	
 	
 		uh i can actually wear anything i want to however i generally wear uh suits or dresses
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		uh well in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> we do have to dress up and they don't say that you have to um dress in a dress for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> but they strongly urge it
 		so it's it's kind of an unwritten law
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that i work for uh we it's very casual we don't see any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> out in the back and then i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> section
 		and we always had casual day on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> which meant you could wear jeans or whatever you wanted to which to me dressing down is you know like wearing pants and a jacket or something
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		even though i don't have to dress during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> you know in anything that dressy i still feel better i feel more professional when i'm dressed up
 	
 	
 		exactly it's puts puts forth a better image it's uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> doesn't usually have casual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> we had our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> at least since i've been there which is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> not too long ago and
 		i didn't feel comfortable dressing like many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> came in like warm ups and no and i
 	
 	
 		you're kidding that's casual
 	
 	
 		yeah and i don't feel i i wore you know a nice pair of pants and and blouse but i i i just couldn't feel comfortable in my warm ups around everybody at work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		would i assume that perhaps they did that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and that was it
 	
 	
 		oh well it was just recently so i don't know if they'll do it again the way some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> looked i would doubt it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's what i always thought actually uh the gals in our customer service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> quite honestly came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> in what i considered casual but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know i it just seems if you want to get ahead or even if you just want everybody to think of you you know as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a</TIMEX> professionally you you don't just want to have the real casual look all the time
 	
 	
 		um-hum do you work for a large company
 	
 	
 		well we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> but we're the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> so um it's it's relatively large but i mean i have a job very much longer so i i don't want to say too much
 	
 	
 		well and it and it affects uh you know being in the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> how you have to dress too do you
 	
 	
 		exactly we have to hold the image for everybody
 	
 	
 		do you tend to dress up toward your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superiors</ENAMEX> as the books kind of
 	
 	
 		i would like to you know i dress as nicely as my budget allows
 	
 	
 		i understand
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and and you know i mean it's it's a lot better than some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there and it's not as nice because i don't have the money of others you know what about you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh i have never i really have not worked for very many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that i had a female role model
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um the we have some i'm sure in our corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> but i've not met them yet but uh the last few jobs i've had well there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jobs ago there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in the office uh that i tended to try to emulate somewhat but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so you don't work with many women
 	
 	
 		no not too many
 	
 	
 		and i work with all women
 	
 	
 		i've
 		do you really
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> does well not all but the majority and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he works in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and he works with all women
 	
 	
 		majority
 		i'm sure that's true i used to be in banking and you're right the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		at least at the lower levels you know
 	
 	
 		uh
 		exactly
 		
 
 		what oh someone never mind that's a call coming in but
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		we'll pass that
 	
 	
 		what about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> to season do you change
 	
 	
 		um i probably get a little bit more casual in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>
 		in then in that i would wear a more casual top under some of my suits
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		than i would wear in the winter
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> are rather cold so i i'll tend to try to dress warmly too
 	
 	
 		exactly i i do the same and that's what basically keeps my wardrobe i may wear a few really warm dresses in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> but i don't i don't change a whole lot because it's it's we're environmentally controlled you know
 		you end up wearing the same thing
 	
 	
 		well tell  me another thing
 		uh how do you wear your skirt lengths
 	
 	
 		below the knee
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i i i don't have nice knees  they're kind of knobby so
 		
 
 		on the knobby side i what about you
 	
 	
 		well i they go from everywhere to just like halfway up the knee to uh mid calf
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		halfway up the knee
 		you must have better
 	
 	
 		not halfway not halfway up my leg halfway up my knee
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		okay my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of my knee might
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		i i i'm thinking halfway between the knee and your say your hip
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and my
 		i'm a little too old for that for one thing and it's terribly unprofessional
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it that it is but i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who who do wear those skirts and they have been reprimanded in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> before
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		also i was going to just mention that i wear what you know my my wardrobe my wardrobe how should i say it i wear what i can fit into
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you mean you have fat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and thin days
 	
 	
 		oh yeah fat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> thin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		well right now i'm having a fat month i know half of my clothes don't fit me since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		exactly the same for me but i'm working on it but i'm not doing a very good job at this point
 		i haven't gotten serious yet
 	
 	
 		well we have to get all of this junk food out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right but i'm so used to eating now it's hard to get out of the habit
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 		
 	