
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh personal computer i don't have a personal computer i'd like to have one if i had more money i'd have one
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  i've got one
 		i do have one but it's a kind of an old one that uh they didn't use at work any longer it's not the  not the greatest one but uh i use <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at work quite a bit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> long in fact
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		is it is it hard to find uh compatible pieces for your the one you have at home
 	
 	
 		yeah because it's a little bit older  and uh  it's a it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX> machine and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX> was you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> a while ago but now they're kind of out of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		yeah
 		um i would think that would be the hardest part about having a home computer is the it seems like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX>  they're coming out with something new and so then you're not compatible oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what's that
 		oh yeah constantly constantly changing
 	
 	
 		uh even with like the computer games <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX> and that kind of stuff i mean they change it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous game</TIMEX> or the previous program or whatever isn't compatible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		most of the uh  you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WordPerfect</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> and those kinds of programs you can subscribe to an update service for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about fifty dollars</NUMEX> a year i think they'll give you the the next release of their software
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and but uh
 	
 	
 		well that isn't that doesn't sound too bad
 	
 	
 		yeah do you use one much
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um not really not in my work um i did try and take a class um i think last was it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no actually it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> it was at at i took desktop publishing i just wanted to get sort of a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">a slight</NUMEX> feel for it and it was just an introduction course
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		sure uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and it was pretty fascinating we we learned how to do how to make a brochure type thing out out off off the computer so it was pretty interesting
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah  oh i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> and i use it almost all the time for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> program i'll have  well lot of good applications for what i have to do
 	
 	
 		oh so you've yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lotus</ENAMEX> is for mostly numbers and graphs and things like that right yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah or uh spreadsheets and that type of thing yeah it's
 	
 	
 		i'm not real good with computers at all and that's mainly because i don't use them i wish i did i'd be you know
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		more up on it
 	
 	
 		well they they've sure come down in price uh in your you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years ago</TIMEX> they were  probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> times what they are now
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness yes
 		yeah
 		have you heard about the phone that uh believe it's AT and T
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is it AT and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> that's coming out with the phone with the like on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jetsons</ENAMEX> when you could see the you could see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s face
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh when you have a vision with the sound  uh-huh
 	
 	
 		have you seen that yeah
 		yeah yeah i saw that in a in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> recently i was really shocked yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure i'd like that once you get those calls <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> when you're just out of bed
 	
 	
 		oh i know  hopefully you can
 	
 	
 		decide if you wanna have a picture or not  yeah
 	
 	
 		have control over whether they can see you or not
 		but it looked pretty nice and it's only gonna be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand dollars</NUMEX> so which is not bad for something new like that so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well you know they've got these uh  all these modems uh computers have modems in them now where you can call all over the face uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i can do a fair amount of work from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and tap into our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s main computer system without much trouble
 	
 	
 		oh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> does a lot of work on computers and she taps into computers all over the world she works at at she works at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh this is uh how you got signed up for it uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh and uh you know she talks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> through the computer from everywhere so i think i think that's really neat too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i have a sister lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> that's my connection with the project
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">okay uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		maybe she knows my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> used to work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> now she works in uh north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i think so
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		but i you know there are  i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six year old</TIMEX> and i think he's
 		he's got quite a bit of interest in uh in playing around with the one we have at home and it's not a  it's not a real fun one it's not a color or i don't have much in the way of game software
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i visited with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and nowadays a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have computers and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are really they're more interested in their schoolwork
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		with the computer you know they can also play games but then they can help them write papers and helps with their math and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah  i think it
 		yeah  you know adds a dimension that uh probably makes learning a little bit more fun if you get to you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		try things a little different than just the standard pencil and paper and crayons
 	
 	
 		and there's always something new even if you know even if you think you know everything about the computer there's always one button
 		that you never quite use and you don't really know what it's for and you know it can be fascinating in that way too especially for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that you know is just learning so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well hopefully i'll be able to get a computer at some point i don't know when but i don't need <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but there's gonna come a time i'm sure when everybody's gonna have to have one
 	
 	
 		oh i think that day'll happen i'm hoping and perhaps uh what'll ultimately happen is you won't have to commute as much  but you'll be able to do so much from home
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that uh you know you won't have to be driving around like
 		
 		
 	