
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		what kind of crimes you have in Hattiesburg
 	
 	
 		uh
 		actually about anything you can imagine uh from you you know this petty theft kind of crud going around vandalism up to  uh certain amount of organized crime where uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> are starting to  you know show up and actually you know qualify as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hattiesburg</ENAMEX>'s not that big is it fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> or so yeah
 	
 	
 		uh about fifty yeah right around fifty thousand we i think we this census we just missed fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> by a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah it's it's right at fifty thousand
 	
 	
 		yeah  we're real disgusted around here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> we live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and  on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> were murdered and mutilated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> blocks from our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at a yogurt shop
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		murdered and mutilated
 	
 	
 		
 
 		mutilated uh they cut them up and they  put ice cream inside their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> and  then they burnt the place down or tried to burn the place down as they left
 	
 	
 		uh what these are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who worked at this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream parlor</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them worked there and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them came to pick them up when they got off their at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at eleven o'clock that night</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		all right so this so this is a place the the place had shut down already
 	
 	
 		right or just shutting down just closing and  i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> have a clue  uh they've had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> here and  have some sort of analysis of who might have done it what type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> might have done it but
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah character profile psychiatric profile
 	
 	
 		yeah but
 		it's just they're still begging for help and and and i just feel like some of they're helpless at uh trying to solve this one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		ah shoot the the big problem is there's no real punishment for crime anymore i mean the bigger the crime the less likely you are to get punished for it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i read a lot of uh  true crime books and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> cases things like that
 	
 	
 		i mean get adequately punished anyway
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it boy it just upsets us when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get off with little or nothing they're they're on they're out on probation probation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen years</TIMEX> after murdering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just not fair
 	
 	
 		well they slaughter innocent innocent lots of innocent lives and they get you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> and a slap on the wrist and  someone else turns around and you know embezzles a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> from the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and they you know they practically get fried
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 
 		yeah  i think about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> they were we were uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> problem was getting real bad  and they hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX>  and a lot of them were dedicated just to the crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> or to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> unit
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and just  recently they announced that they've pretty much got it under control  there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> related murder <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's good if nothing else they've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gangs</ENAMEX> pushed down to where they're  you know not going to be very active at least as far as you know murders or open crimes are concerned
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think one of the things that  they need to do more of which i seen a little bit here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> though is getting  actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in neighborhoods involved
 	
 	
 		yeah the neighborhood watch type programs  yeah that's one that's the one thing that starting  you know the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> things that are really making a difference
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		are when the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get involved  and when they start doing something positive with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families families</ENAMEX> have gone in the toilet in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		and it's as though they're really trying to push to make sure they go down the toilet lot of people lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>  they seem to be fighting against family
 	
 	
 		seems to be that way i seems like everybody that  we've heard of or know that  go for any kind of psychiatric psychiatric help  uh every problem you've got is blamed on your parents
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that to me that's just defeating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> right there
 	
 	
 		yeah well to a certain extent it can be traced back there  and and and that's okay to say so as long as you understand that you got to forgive
 	
 	
 		i mean if you can
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's not like they doing it on purpose usually very seldom are they doing it on purpose
 	
 	
 		you know
 		you know out of my own family i  i guess  maybe i didn't have everything i wanted when i was growing up but i've as i've gotten older i've learned to  accept the fact that i got what i needed  i was clothed and sheltered and educated and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i had some modicum at least of acceptance and support
 	
 	
 		i haven't blamed any of my future problems on on on the family upbringing or whatever
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well that's the way it was with us we had i had a pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> life by comparison i had an excellent family life by comparison to a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there
 		it may not have been perfect but  they did what they knew how to do and they did it the best they knew how so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's just  i like i can't ever imagine my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> committing a crime
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i think he knows that you know that that's just something that not in in his world but there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that  do commit violent crimes and and small crimes and think nothing of it it's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i mean considering the conscious it seems to go  it it it almost invariably does start with the destruction of the family  i mean
 		almost invariably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> aren't taught respect they're not taught discipline they're not taught the need to
 		
 		
 	