
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah as far as i'm concerned and
 		probably apt that your call's at this time because we just got through watching uh Reasonable Doubts which had a you know capital case in it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh  my i personally have uh my own feelings about uh the capital punishment is i think it should be mandatory upon a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> conviction felony
 	
 	
 		i do too
 	
 	
 		mandatory i mean summary execution on the steps that day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		why is it you know i i'm i'm in that same i think if it's uh
 		if it's a convicted  if it's a convicted uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> on parole
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and he goes out and and commits another crime or kills somebody i you know i i feel the same way i don't think i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is is beyond uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rehabilitation</ENAMEX> and and he should be
 		taken out
 	
 	
 		well
 		i i also firmly believe that no one is beyond reclamation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i do know that some people
 		almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> usually die before that point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they just get too old
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		as far as capital punishment on on it's own merits
 		i have the trouble with the way it's applied
 		i think it should be applied  on a little bit more fair manner
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX>  and i've i've said this very often and i believe it to be the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a very true axiom so i would be rather be white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rich</ENAMEX> and guilty than black and innocent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because if you're  if you're black and you kill a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you're going to fry period they will kill you
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		if you're black and you kill a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you know it's you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of community service
 	
 	
 		yeah you don't hear you don't hear too much of that of those cases
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it's a social disease that we have called one upsmanship
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know we're the majority so we can do whatever the hell we wanna do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and you're the minority and you're stuck with it
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you know we had this in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX> you know we had  you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> among military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> was about eighty percent
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> in the military was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about twenty two</NUMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		the handwriting's on the wall there isn't it
 	
 	
 		yep it sure is
 	
 	
 		you know
 		but that's another issue altogether
 	
 	
 		yeah it's
 	
 	
 		as as far as capital punishment
 		i think that uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> on death row is cruel and unusual punishment i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> should have ninety days
 		and if he can't produce evidence not argument but evidence
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		see the only thing i don't you know i don't understand i guess i i don't understand our judicial system uh as it is right now because i
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		you know if somebody has been convicted and has been sentenced to be put to death
 		how is it that they can appeal and appeal and appeal
 		and get stays of execution execution i mean how you know is there
 	
 	
 		well that that goes back to when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> was a a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">colony</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> you went to court you were assumed guilty until proven innocent
 		and
 		once they found you guilty you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> said he's guilty kill him
 		well there there were some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh had a problem with that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they found out later on that jeez you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> will lie rather than get killed and he'll say you know hey that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> did it you know not me
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh or he'll have somebody lie for him you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lie it's a strange thing but they do that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		to prevent that kind of misuse of power
 		they wrote into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> a protection against judicial mishap
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and the judicial mishap in this event would be hey you got the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> look at that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> uh at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E Systems</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		they were going to they convicted him
 		of a robbery that he could not physically have been able to commit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he was too far away when it happened he had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> that were you know they weren't dope <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> they weren't drug fiends they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> of a
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX> that had a very high level of security sensitivity and these were really responsible people
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		you know and they convicted this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> because somebody says well he looks like the right guy
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know they all look the same to me you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		big lips flat nose yep that was him
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yep
 		what do you think about um uh
 		convicted um
 		
 		
 	