
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> what do you think about our public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> today
 	
 	
 		um well i have i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and
 		and in comparing it with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live in other parts of the world one of the things that things wrong is that our our schools our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> seem to go to school less
 		of of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> than than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in other countries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um it seems like uh the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long summer break</TIMEX> is something that
 		only
 		uh only occurs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in school
 	
 	
 		no i don't
 		so i'm a little bit out of it i can look back to my  to when i was in school which is getting further and further away and also i have a niece and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> that are in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and i hear a little a bit about from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		things going on yeah
 	
 	
 		well some of the some of the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are trying to go to more of a year around system
 	
 	
 		yeah they're moving to that out there
 	
 	
 		and uh i guess there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> and cons to that too i know if if if it happened here i would hope that uh you know i have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> a part i would just hope they were in the same system so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you wanna take a vacation you could
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i hear that they that in at least in the system that's going out um  in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> where that i'm familiar with that they do put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> on the same schedule
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so seems like that could get a little difficult to do that but
 	
 	
 		it could it could one of the other um things is that um
 		uh there's been a lot of talk about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> uh getting behind in science compared to uh lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are teaching uh more of the science sciences and putting out better
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> when in math and science uh for the future you know technology in various countries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's not a favorite subject for either of my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it's probably not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for anyone but it just seems like uh those are the criticisms criticisms you hear over and over about the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> public school system and this is probably why a lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  go to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> instead
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah well i hadn't thought about those things but those are problems um
 	
 	
 		some of the some of the  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i work with uh they're they're some from various parts of the of the world and and uh course everybody likes to think their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX>'s the best but the the ones in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">England</ENAMEX> and and then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> seem seem to uh have some logical points about
 		you know why do why do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> need a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three month</TIMEX> break in the summer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i think that dates back to
 		when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> was agricultural and nature and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> needed to help on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> and it's been quite a while since that's been the case for most part now
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah there's no need for it anymore
 	
 	
 		and it seems though that's one of the things that ought to to change
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i'm not i'm not that happy to always be uh limited to just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> for most vacations and
 		and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time for the other you know the other one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and compete with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> since all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> going on vacation
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		tends to make some crowds
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		did you go through the public school system
 	
 	
 		yeah i did
 	
 	
 		uh uh uh yeah i did too and everyone else in  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but seems like uh
 		uh if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can afford it the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> route but that's of course not available to to the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with
 	
 	
 		right i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are home schooling their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know just teaching them at home and
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and for lots of different reasons you know
 	
 	
 		that i have mixed feelings about that too i guess whether or not they miss the social interaction a part of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i know that a lot of them um they hook up with like a home schooling system and they get together the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get together for lots of activities and outings and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah that that would help
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that helps yeah i wonder too i have mixed feelings about it but um
 		i know that uh you know i spot when i thought of problems in the school system it's not really the fault of the school system but there's a lot of
 		you know it's just uh
 		
 
 		i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are exposed to a lot that you can't shelter them eventually eventually but it's hard at a young age some of the pressures and
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		yeah the i i think that's why a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go to the home schooling they they disagree with what they're exposed to either for religious reasons or or other reasons
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		the other thing that's happening now i guess is is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	