
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what was the last vacation you went on anyway
 	
 	
 		well we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that was nice we traveled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> though and that wasn't real nice because i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh that's a long trip with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the car
 	
 	
 		it surely was
 	
 	
 		yeah uh that sort of a trip can be kind of long just by yourself
 	
 	
 		well yeah we went to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> with my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> there and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um girls</ENAMEX> are real involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> and so we had a soccer tournament there also but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		well that works out
 	
 	
 		yeah it was real nice the weather weather cooperated and and it was real pretty there how about you where have have you gone mostly East
 	
 	
 		uh yeah
 		uh yeah so far the about as far <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> as i've gone uh trip  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years ago</TIMEX> up to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX> uh flew up and then drove back
 	
 	
 		oh
 		how was the drive back
 	
 	
 		uh well uh the weather was wonderful the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> were fine  uh the car i was driving back was a problem it kept wanting to fall apart
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's no good
 	
 	
 		basically i was bringing it back for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of a the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> i was renting from
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> living up there owned it wanted it rebuilt uh and restored and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> back here was going to do it but couldn't get loose for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple few days</TIMEX> to go up and get it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		what time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> did you drive
 	
 	
 		oh that was uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>  the weather was wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah i was gonna say the weather probably was real pretty then
 	
 	
 		yeah um  flew up it was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i'd flown and uh flew up just above uh thunderstorms that stretch from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> at least up into uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Lake</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		yeah they have some whopper of thunderstorms  out on these plains
 	
 	
 		so we're watching
 		oh yeah yeah we got to watch i got i got to watch uh thunderstorm from the other side for once unique experience yeah the lightning from the top side is a unique experience
 	
 	
 		lots of lightning
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i always enjoyed watching it from the bottom side but it's even more fun from the top
 	
 	
 		huh now
 	
 	
 		um most of our vacations though have been you know camping trips of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sort</ENAMEX> or another or just going home to see family
 	
 	
 		and now i hear that you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in the background
 	
 	
 		i well actually i'm at a pay phone the post office
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um no i do have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> he's about twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks old</TIMEX> twelve and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks old</TIMEX> now
 	
 	
 		oh congratulations you'll be taking him on some of trips then i guess
 	
 	
 		why thank you
 		yeah yeah from looks of things  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i are both in school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the next trip is probably going to be next <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> uh several of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> have decided that it'd been too long since we were home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		now where's home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh West Virginia</ENAMEX> uh that's home for me
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i met her down here so her home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only about uh an hour and half</NUMEX> drive away
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but uh i'm a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand miles</NUMEX> from home so they're supposed to they're they're trying to arrange to get us train tickets uh to go up home <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us
 	
 	
 		oh
 		like an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		huh have you been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yep
 		i've been through the northwest corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> that's been it uh that's pretty much in route between here and home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so there's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a nine mile</NUMEX> stretch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interstate</ENAMEX> fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> that cuts through the northwest corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well we went there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> again for a soccer tournament and it was just beautiful there
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they have some kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">vine</ENAMEX> there that grows up and down and up and down trees
 	
 	
 		kudzu
 	
 	
 		yes that was it
 	
 	
 		yes this stuff is an absolute white on humanity it seems
 	
 	
 		yeah but it's so pretty
 	
 	
 		is it's pretty it it's it when it's genetically engineered
 		that's the that's the southern version of what they've got up north called multiflora rose which is also engineered and it's almost indestructible
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i mean you about have to expose the
 		you know the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four feet</NUMEX>  of the soil to you know  high levels of radiation to kill it off it this stuff is incredibly durable
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah see i kept talking about how beautiful it was and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">natives</ENAMEX> there just would roll their eyes like you're crazy  this is awful stuff but i remember calling home and saying it's too pretty here all i'm staying forever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah its
 		well you see that stuff what eventually take over everything and literally kill off large old <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> if it gets the chance
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so most that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast</ENAMEX> have uh spraying programs where they go in with defoliants and try and kill it off
 	
 	
 		so do you have that there
 	
 	
 		here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hattiesburg</ENAMEX> area no not yet  but apparently it moving this direction
 	
 	
 		and me yeah
 		not yet uh huh it's coming huh
 	
 	
 		actually up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Delta</ENAMEX> you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four or five hours</TIMEX> drive north along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi River</ENAMEX> they've got it there too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but right now it hasn't really hit the uh the the general area around here place
 	
 	
 		yeah so what about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX> have you been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh one trip i used to be an auto mechanic
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one evening</TIMEX> i got sent down into let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Walton Beach</ENAMEX> with a wrecker to tow a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> back for a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	