
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um are you from this area
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh okay i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> so well i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> right now but i'm living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i don't know if you know but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garland</ENAMEX> has got a real big recycling center
 		that in fact we went to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> you drive up and you take the stuff out of your trunk and they have different bins for the different materials like
 		clear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and colored <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> and uh they have all the different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> separated by those little symbols on the bottom
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's pretty neat my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and she's real interested in recycling  so we're we're trying to promote that because she thought we just put them in a special trash can and threw them away but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we went to the recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> to show her what we actually did with them
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> have a curbside recycling program yet
 	
 	
 		um well i don't know if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> does
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		um they started with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and uh of course aluminum cans and and bottles and plastic
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i didn't know there were different types of plastic though
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah um like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> bottles are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kind <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and milk jugs are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> type of plastic you can tell it's got it'll
 		most of the recyclable containers have a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">symbol</ENAMEX> on the bottom with little with the arrows around it that tells whether it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's it's just different kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> like the clear plastic is different from that milky looking plastic know that's what the different types are
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		yeah it seems to be made out of something different
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yes i i know there's a long scientific name but it's like polytechnochloride and all that fun stuff um i like
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if if they do it all over but our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kroger</ENAMEX> does a a newspaper recycling every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> you can drive up and they have one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> out there no the bag <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> out there
 		um that will take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers newspaper</ENAMEX> out of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and they'll put it in their little bin
 		and they do the recycling i mean they collect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and their plastic the plastic grocery bags
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which i think is pretty neat that's something since we all have seem to have an abundance of those plastic grocery bags  i know we use them for trash can liners and a lot of other things
 	
 	
 		
  
 		hum
 		that's right yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		lunch bags and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah in fact i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's um-hum the only problem with those is sometimes they get holes in the bottom
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah they didn't
 	
 	
 		and  it's like whoops there goes my chips okay fine
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		now i  in fact did you happen to see <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty the other night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no
 	
 	
 		they did a program or the one of their articles was on recycling and or it was actually on a a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that has a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dump</ENAMEX> that
 		they charge other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> to come in and dump their trash there they have made so much money from that
 		that they built they bought a brand new fire engine and when the fire engine was delivered the fire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> wasn't big enough so they mought bought a new or built a new one paid for it in cash with the money that they've earned from this landfill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they have built up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> mountain they call it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Trashmore</ENAMEX> they built up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> mountain covered it with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> and put ski lifts on it and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> they put snow on it and they charge to ski on it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> gets the money from that they built a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> at the bottom and they get the money from that it's like that's it's a it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Riverview Ohio</ENAMEX> or some place up there
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it was i thought it was a pretty neat idea they i mean their city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> looked better it was nicer than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>' and they only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the city
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and they like the trash so i like well
 		okay
 		but i thought that was pretty neat it it would be nice if more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> could do that but you have to know from beginning and you have to have the space to do it and
 	
 	
 		yeah they'll run out of space before long
 	
 	
 		yeah see that's well they're already planning a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> mountain so they're gonna get going to be called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twin Peaks i</ENAMEX> was like uh-huh go back to the TV shows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this it would be nice if more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> could get really involved in recycling
 		oh it's we i know like i said i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> and that's
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> thinks that anytime she sees newspapers bundled up they're being recycled so it's like well no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX> so that like so that was one reason we went to show her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did with their their stuff when they recycled it and try to explain well yeah you melt down the cans and you make them into new things and you get the paper all wet and you make it into new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's fun trying to explain that to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX>  oh so do y'all go ahead and
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		they don't even know that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> comes from trees yet so
 	
 	
 		well yeah she that was the her next question was how do you grow paper
 	
 	
 		how do you grow paper
 	
 	
 		was like well from <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees um</ENAMEX> that's why you have to cut down <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and why you have to plant more trees
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and how do you grow aluminum
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly um well let's see um  we really don't but and then she was like well what do you do with the glass well
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you crunch it up real small and then you melt it down well what if it breaks well okay  it it it was an interesting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> trying to explain all that fun stuff to her
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but at least she knows that that is something that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to be doing and she got our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX> to start recycling her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and cans because that's all she talked about so i guess what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	