
 
     		
 	
 		um well i'm glad i got a male because  i'm gonna need some help um i haven't really given any dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> but um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've had you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> over for lunch that kind of thing but i promised my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> that i would throw him a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and so he's real excited about it but i don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> like to eat because  it's different from women
 		so um maybe you could help me out here in this sense and i keep i keep asking him you know what what what do you think we ought to have you know but i was thinking of like you one of those subway sandwiches those long subway <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX> and maybe uh
 	
 	
 		well i
 	
 	
 		um a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pasta salad</ENAMEX> and some chips and some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coke</ENAMEX> and um i thought a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> and he said no and so we're just going back and forth so
 	
 	
 		you you could probably probably get  uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sub</ENAMEX> might work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> will definitely work a lot of that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh chips and dips will probably work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah he's i don't really think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> care do they
 	
 	
 		uh not really to be honest with you i mean i i've never i've never really cared i just like little munchies and stuff basically you know just dip chips and dip usually do it if there's enough of it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's what he said
 		right
 	
 	
 		but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> usually aren't into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> you know like more than and not as much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> you know like just sitting around and eat the finger <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sandwiches</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and  but uh i've always i've always you know just had chips dip and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and just gone for it from there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah so that oh okay i'll guess i'll do something like that but um
 	
 	
 		i got a i got a good dip
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah i i stole it from a restaurant
 	
 	
 		okay what is that
 	
 	
 		it is uh you get a can of can of uh chopped spinach
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you get uh fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parmesan Cheese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you get uh uh artichoke hearts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay you get uh a whole can of artichoke hearts
 		you take about out of the i tell you out of the it's about a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four ounce</NUMEX> can of spinach out of that you take about an ounce and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two ounces</NUMEX> of spinach
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay you stick all of it in a food processor
 		okay you need to get uh
 		and you grind mix it up real good it's almost pureed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to a degree and you heat that up
 		and you take uh i'd say approximately <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eight ounces</NUMEX> of the fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parmesan Cheese</ENAMEX> and you uh put it in there while it's heating up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you mix it up
 		and this is a recipe from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s restaurant
 	
 	
 		oh really is this an artichoke dip because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine had that at at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and it was really good but when she told me it was artichoke dip i was going oh no
 	
 	
 		that i stole yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah this is artichokes spinach and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">parmesan cheese</ENAMEX> and that's all that's in there
 	
 	
 		as i'm not much of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> for artichoke
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sorry and heavy it has heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> in it too
 	
 	
 		that one see i thought that was something else
 	
 	
 		i forgot forgot about that
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		it has heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cream</ENAMEX> in there i i i just i fling it every time i do it i
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		mean i don't have anything written down i just kind of know it from i just go by taste and texture
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i've never really written it down but they never give me any specs on it i've just kind of
 		had a variance of it you know every time i go in and it gets pretty close you've just got to watch how much spinach you put in there you've got to put it a little bit at a time it should be a uh
 		uh uh like about a guacamole lighter than a guacamole color
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a party it sounds like the same thing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> served and it was really good but when she told me it had artichokes in i thought oh God
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's served
 		yeah and it's served hot
 		it's served hot
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh it was
 	
 	
 		it yeah and it's real good i don't know if they'd go for that or not but it's just a real good dip
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> loved it yeah he really did
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a fancy i think in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>'s it's called a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> dip
 	
 	
 		oh really huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		if you ever go there try it that's the stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah okay yeah and he wanted uh uh some uh chili dip that i usually make too so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chili</ENAMEX> is usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> usually go for chili now that you now that you mention it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		probably go for chili and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> that's always a good gas burner
 	
 	
 		and no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> allowed  and i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 		plenty plenty of  ceiling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> going
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess so well um let me see we went to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> party and uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine had this and it was she had the she was the one that had that dip
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and another thing that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> really liked that i and i liked too that i would have never thought of serving and it was really easy
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and it sounds it doesn't sound good but when you all put when you put it together and you taste it it's real excellent it's um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mexicorn</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn chips</ENAMEX> you mix all that together with a bottle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catalina</ENAMEX> dressing and you and you just mix it all together and you serve it like that and it is really good
 	
 	
 		right
 		huh
 		
 		
 	