
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> or do you have anything to do with anything in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no i don't no
 	
 	
 		no huh
 	
 	
 		not that really much exposure in the in the recent past either how about yourself
 	
 	
 		no uh not a lot i've got a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that work uh as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> or you know in in different school districts and different things but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only eighteen months</TIMEX> though so we haven't got exposed too much to that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you can sure see where it seems like uh
 		there's a lot of concern for everything going downhill and they blame a lot of it on education i i kind of wonder i don't know if you blame the system or if you blame the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> for not studying or making the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> study hard enough or exactly what
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i think it's probably a combination you know i think probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> expect a lot more out of the school system than it's realistic that that the school system can provide
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		for them to get
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in conjunction a lot of um school districts' funds have been cut because of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> that's the case it's probably the case elsewhere too
 	
 	
 		sure
 		yeah
 		well they've been cut yeah i just it seems like more and more with uh more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> having to resort to you know to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incomes and stuff there's not the time that they spend and so they like you say they expect the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to do more of it but hell there's only so many in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours a day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't even know if it's just because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> are working you know both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are working outside the home as much as it it's a matter of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it's kind of a philosophical philosophical expectation about who's responsible for discipline you know it's
 	
 	
 		oh you know i think that's a good point it's really a good point
 	
 	
 		it
 		you know you you could be working full time and um still be able to work with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and provide some guidance at home and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in terms of homework as well as the the you know discipline for what's important in terms of values and i think that's probably something that not as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get i mean just i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i say that because you see it reflected in the society at large there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out there who seem more troubled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than they used to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i uh you know it seems like i remember on school <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> you know i was never outside past eight you know maybe <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine o'clock</TIMEX> at the very latest
 		whether i was in doing homework or not you know i may not have been but yet there was that influence in the home to where i was at least you know getting prepared for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> or whatever and and you're you know you're right in saying you don't see a lot of that there's out running around and uh doing a lot of different things that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		maybe TV's a bigger um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		TV and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		competitor for their time
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's probably true there's a lot more uh
 	
 	
 		and when we were kids
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true i know you know i didn't appreciate i
 		i was you know fortunate to where i could i kind of breezed through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> without too much problem stuff and and didn't really learn how to study that much until i hit college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i sure wish now that i had picked that up earlier because you know took me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> in college before i really started getting the grades going and
 		you know it affects your whole life especially when you hit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> if you don't you know do as well as you can it can it can follow you for quite a while so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's a good point just learning the discipline to to to study
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		to sit and study and i don't know it's it's you know i only have the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and she's quite young but it makes you a little nervous to
 		know what they have to deal with you know in the future and get prepared for them but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well probably having gone through that experience you'll be likely to want to speak speak with her uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and really try to communicate with them to find out what it is that you can do to help her at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at all or
 	
 	
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s two so i'm in sort of in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> that you are
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		same boat
 		yeah have you uh have you ever considered private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> at all or
 	
 	
 		well you know we're coming up on the time she's probably going to be ready for she's in a day care situation now because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i both work full time but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think she'll probably be ready for preschool around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or three and a half</NUMEX> and after that time we really do need to think about it because in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 		in our neighborhood there's actually a good public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> at the elementary grade there's not a really decent middle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or high school i'm not sure we'll be in the same area when she's that old but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have to really do the research to find out
 		whether or not the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> stand up to the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and what the costs are and all that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's really the the expense is a real issue  when you think about
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that's true yeah i i am i like a lot of the times you know i think the social aspect can be maybe as important and in a lot of ways as the education they get uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sometimes i wonder if they can get that same thing in a in a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		well i don't know how it is in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> i know that um
 	
 	
 		or not
 	
 	
 		in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> well actually it's not so much in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> actually it's outside more in the east <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> or east bay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are so poor that the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have just really grown as a response to the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> don't feel that they're getting getting what they want in the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> so they're almost like public
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	