
 
     		
 	
 		any vacations recently that you would highly recommend
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well
 		that is like my favorite hobby  so yeah i travel everywhere and i've been all over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so when i can that's what i do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh  what what has been your favorite trip do you think
 	
 	
 		well i'm not sure um i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> is one of my favorite places
 	
 	
 		really better than <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well no that's exciting you know i've been several times so after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time it's like anywhere you know it loses that newness but
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah i love it i love to go over to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> i do and mostly i've traveled through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> so i've been there quite a bit and i just love it all i love to look at the different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the different cultures and to see how different things are from the way we do them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the most interesting part more than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so how about you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well uh  i have never been i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> several times but uh that is about it for me i'm i'm from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> and so uh growing up uh  we would spend most of our vacations right there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is uh uh real into camping and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheeling and so um several i i think maybe uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four summers</TIMEX> in a row
 		uh we spent uh our vacation time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheeling through uh  portions of uh the southern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> uh and
 		and uh every time uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had uh uh i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had us uh do some studying of the the area which we were going to visit and then we had to write uh
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		uh reports reports about it during during our vacation which which was really fun it was really fun we we we each got to write little books uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and  uh it it had sparked an interest that uh uh of of mine that uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> is a is a um very very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> that's what she had originally gone to school to do was photography and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i'm close to receiving my <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> degree uh as as well as my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> degree so so i uh
 		uh we've thought very seriously of trying to to uh incorporate travel into writing and and writing a book about uh uh some portion of travel
 		uh so  we're hoping soon uh not soon maybe within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next ten years</TIMEX> to get to take a trip over from uh over over to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and take a trip from the northern portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh down to the southern tip of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> uh  and follow uh it there's kind of a backward S shape uh
 		trail that the pilgrims use to take uh in in  uh back in the medieval times uh to see the relics uh in in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Spain</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we would like to take pictures of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gothic</ENAMEX> uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanesque</ENAMEX> uh monasteries and uh just take that journey all the way down and then right a book about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that would be quite a project
 	
 	
 		yeah it would be  it's it's our big dream
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it would be a lot fun you know there's there's good and there's bad and my experience in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> wasn't my favorite for sure but
 	
 	
 		oh sure really
 	
 	
 		well i flew into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is uh a twirling champion
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	

 		and she had to perform over there and in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Turin</ENAMEX> and so we had to fly into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX> and we got on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> after so much trouble because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> even if they speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> they don't wanna let you know
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		and they gave us all the wrong directions and there were just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> they put us on the wrong bus but finally we saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> he put us on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">subway</ENAMEX> we sat there um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we didn't know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> we looked at each other we said things like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spaghetti</ENAMEX> you know things like that and we finally followed some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> he told us where to get off we followed these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with uh gym bags and we figured that must be the sports arena
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we lucked out and then when we needed to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> there was nothing but a whole in the ground i mean it was just it was kind of a nightmare but  that was our experience and i guess all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> isn't like that
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but where we were it certainly was and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> that we stayed in we stayed with our <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in the hotel and it was beautiful it was very modern
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it was very far away on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> so  you know it was it was really uh it was interesting you always learn something
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and you will always have a fun experience so it it's great you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you said you've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> several times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i wonder have you ever been to a uh a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> uh well it's it's actually about uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salisbury</ENAMEX> it's called uh Bemerton
 	
 	
 		no i haven't huh-uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> live like an hour outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ash</ENAMEX> around there so um-hum
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh okay all right yeah i i i the reason i'm curious um i uh that's the other place i would like to visit uh most
 		
 		
 	