
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> did you watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know what i watched a little bit of uh of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> game and i uh had to leave um in fact i i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> were ahead when i uh when i left who won the game
 	
 	
 		they won in a squeaker they won by they won by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> points uh they were behind as they headed into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each quarter</TIMEX> and then they came back  in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> and at the end i think they were
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		uh looked they looked like they were closing it out and then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> kept coming back and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaiah</ENAMEX> missed a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> point attempt at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> and uh i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> won by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		wow they've got the don't they have the best record now
 	
 	
 		i think they do as a matter of fact one of the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> said that they expected that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> would uh if they continued at their current pace  uh set an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> record for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy</TIMEX> wins in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		wow
 	
 	
 		yeah they looked real good and
 	
 	
 		they they do and they uh you know  i think by uh by relieving some of the pressure off of uh
 		of uh  uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> really helped them out you know he doesn't have they don't have to rely on him to score <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every</TIMEX> you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> points at every at every game so
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah well they they're they're balancing their attack and i think they look like uh
 		they'll repeat although uh here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay Area</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are real impressed with what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Nelson</ENAMEX>'s done with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warriors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i know i'm yeah i saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Warriors</ENAMEX>  i saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Warriors uh</ENAMEX>  just a little bit of the highlights of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Warriors</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		i saw the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half</TIMEX> of the game last night and they were impressive
 	
 	
 		they look good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Owens</ENAMEX> looks like he was that was a good move for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Warriors</ENAMEX> to trade for him
 	
 	
 		yeah now i don't uh i haven't kept up with what was going on with uh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warriors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well they traded away uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX> or is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Hardaway</ENAMEX> one of the two
 		uh who along with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Mullin</ENAMEX> was you know though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the best in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> and and they made a heck of a threesome and they traded either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hardaway</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Owens</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		good move
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah he's really worked out well they've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">the Warriors</ENAMEX> have got a team uh and uh
 		i think that'll be real interesting to see what they can do they're ahead and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> are down i guess in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> uh position in the west and i don't know in the east i don't know uh is it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> in uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>'s in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> um
 		i you know i haven't kept up with any of the other uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> uh i'm so depressed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mavericks</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		boy they've had a hard time they said they've lost a lot of squeakers
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that well yeah but i mean just this whole year has been just disastrous for them and uh
 		you know they're going i i think they're going for an all time record of how many losses you know losses in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX> they can they can they can uh pull out  it's unbelievable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		how do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> deal with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Houston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> do you for example like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh  actually actually the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area here uh pulls for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> pulls for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> pulls for for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there isn't much crossover huh you
 	
 	
 		they're really i mean not a whole lot you know i mean  you find them they're  find them be to be pretty loyal uh you know with with the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know it's kind of i guess it's kind of like uh there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bay area</ENAMEX> you know you don't find a whole lot of uh  uh of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX> fans
 	
 	
 		yeah it's true because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San San Antonio</ENAMEX> isn't that close to you are they
 	
 	
 		really isn't huh-uh it's you know it's it's about the same uh  same distance from here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> as it is from there to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sacramento</ENAMEX>  so it's yeah it's not really a local you know
 	
 	
 		no
 		is it
 		yeah so it's not something you'd drive
 		yeah i was thinking maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Robinson</ENAMEX> made a bit of a difference with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		um he does a lot of local stuff there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and they i mean they have got a great club  you know
 	
 	
 		they've done a good job i mean of course drafting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> like him certainly
 	
 	
 		uh yeah yeah that always makes a big difference so
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean that's i think the way it uh i think that's the way it works now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> you you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX> was a franchise for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> and you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bird for the for the uh Celtics and</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and you know uh you know i used to think that that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> really doesn't make the club
 		but it really does you know you get somebody like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX> and you can see the decline of that team
 	
 	
 		well it it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>
 		well yeah i
 	
 	
 		once he left you know i mean it's it's just not the same uh it's not the same team there's not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> there that they used to rely on him for
 	
 	
 		well i think you're right and i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaiah Thomas</ENAMEX> would fit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> and i think those things do make a difference and there are  marquee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> and the and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> have to be
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh considered the likely favorites i don't know who would meet them in the west um i don't know how good <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> will turn out to be by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> they were so disappointing
 	
 	
 		who won that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		you know i wasn't i i didn't i watched <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few minutes</TIMEX> of it and i wasn't paying attention uh  so i don't know uh but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> have both been very good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 		
 	