
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i pressed the button so
 	
 	
 		okay let me tell you i haven't been too many places
 	
 	
 		you haven't been to too many places
 	
 	
 		no no i haven't
 	
 	
 		okay well i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see now that's where i wanna go that's where i've always wanted to go i've never been there
 	
 	
 		oh it's
 		it's beautiful
 	
 	
 		i know ah is it is it um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i had an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> that lived there and she she couldn't stand it anymore she moved out because she said the whole island was taken you know being taken over by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well there is there is a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> over there and they're
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah and she and um she also told me that well not her uh necessarily other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have been there said it's it's too commercialized
 	
 	
 		um-hum ooh well yeah there's it's commercialized but there's still a lot of beautiful places to go and see
 	
 	
 		is it
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know uh on all of the islands you know now the gisland of of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oahu</ENAMEX> naturally has got more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on it than the other islands but
 	
 	
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's still beautiful you've got to see it at least once you know
 	
 	
 		oh well i will eventually  what well what is what's the most uh you know the nicest island
 	
 	
 		so
 		uh i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maui</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maui i</ENAMEX> think that's usually what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh say they didn't they like the best
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i mean i like it because the beach is nice and white and you know it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um Oahu</ENAMEX> you can go over there lay on the beach and it's really nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where the island of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> you really can't lay on the beach over there you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kauai</ENAMEX> it's
 		and i mean their beaches are nice but i don't know just not nice as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maui</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then uh have you where have where have you been
 	
 	
 		well i have been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> i loved it i absolutely loved it
 	
 	
 		oh you have
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah and um
 	
 	
 		how long ago
 	
 	
 		oh uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm okay
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives out there my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i know where that's at because i used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh oh well that's right near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah right right
 	
 	
 		yeah well yeah that's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> or something what is that oh yeah okay well she lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> also and she
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		let's see i went when she
 		was uh living when well like when i went out there she was in um
 		now i can't oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lafayette</ENAMEX> she was living in Lafayette
 	
 	
 		oh yeah right
 	
 	
 		and then they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i uh i haven't seen uh  you know her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Piedmont</ENAMEX> but
 		but i love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> i'd like to go back
 	
 	
 		yeah did you go in the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and everything yeah isn't that fun
 	
 	
 		oh yeah went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alcatraz</ENAMEX> you know we did the whole bit and then we went to the wine country
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah up by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Napa</ENAMEX> yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah oh beautiful and uh we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carmel</ENAMEX> you know and we took the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eighteen mile</NUMEX> drive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		isn't that pretty i love it down there
 	
 	
 		oh it's beautiful it's really beautiful my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> was down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> first time she's been down there and they wanted to take that drive and they had closed the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> because of of fog yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh what the weather
 	
 	
 		so then she they never got to do that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um well i have also been to the Carribean
 	
 	
 		oh i haven't been there either  you name it i haven't been there  i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i've i been there a couple of times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i went on a cruise
 	
 	
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		the last time i went i went with my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we really had a good time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well they
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> had this cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> dress up like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> and we went to the beach and they had put a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> on the beach decorated it up and it was it was a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's nice is is that cruise nicer than it if you just go on a regular you know to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> or you know it is now i've heard it is yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 		yeah because you don't have to worry about unpacking or anything like that you know you put your clothes in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and oh you'll have to go on one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you don't get seasick  that's what i'm afraid of
 	
 	
 		no no i mean there was some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did
 	
 	
 		no huh
 	
 	
 		um on that last cruise that we took because they was having a storm come in but that's unusual
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> got sick but the other one didn't and i didn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 		but um it's really nice and they just they just do so many things for you you know to make you enjoy the trip and everything
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		so you'll have to do that once i wanna go on another one but i wanna go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yes now someone i know was was on a cruise to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		was it Alaska yeah i'm pretty sure that's right my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hairdresser</ENAMEX>  she went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> she said she went on a cruise and i'm thinking you know cruise i'm thinking
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX> and she's laying on the beach i said well you're not very tan for someone who's been on a cruise she says we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		you know and uh that that's uh i'd like to go well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> would is my uh is my is number one i'd also like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> have you
 	
 	
 		oh i  i think i would like to too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i keep hoping to win the lotto for i can do all these things you know
 	
 	
 		oh well see i i'm just into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Publisher</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clearing House</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reader's Digest</ENAMEX> because we don't uh right now the lottery here
 		
 		
 	