
 
     		
 	
 		i don't know about you but i haven't had any trouble having any fun on vacation
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i can't think of any place i wouldn't want to go to take one
 	
 	
 		um well where are some of the places you've been
 	
 	
 		oh i know a real good place is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>
 		it's real nice
 		it has mountains beach whatever you want
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you been in any great places lately
 	
 	
 		well i've been a lot of different places uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawaii Japan Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh now i haven't been there
 	
 	
 		and and
 		most of the fifty
 		i haven't been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alaska</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really
 		you plan on going
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought we might go up on the uh inland ferry that goes up there from uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah now i'd like to go uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> on the boat
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> went not long ago
 		or to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Key West</ENAMEX> have you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Key West</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		is it pretty
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's a long desolate stretch but  well desolate in that it's all uh the same scenery after a while just like driving in the desert you know  after a while it all looks the same
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh no
 		no i've never been huh is it very expensive
 	
 	
 		huh
 		no no
 	
 	
 		not compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		well actually <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> is getting cheap too because uh
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		with the economic uh
 		situation uh situation we're in they've lowered the prices uh quite a bit
 	
 	
 		well that's nice to know
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		where do you stay when you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> on the beach
 	
 	
 		um yeah i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia Beach</ENAMEX> and i've been up to the uh homestead in hot springs in the mountains it's real nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh oh let's  see i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlottesville</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Monticello</ENAMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s a a landscape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> and he uh he really liked that and to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>'s home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i bet
 		well if he's a landscape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> he ought to like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daylight hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah now we we went there went there to stay at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and that was real nice that was real nice
 	
 	
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s in the military
 	
 	
 		uh no he used to be he he's a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> now uh but he was the uh he was uh uh
 	
 	
 		retired retired
 	
 	
 		in the reserves for quite a long time and uh he's active in something right now i forgot what it is
 		that's how close i am no i don't mean that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but um  i he's somehow connected still with it
 	
 	
 		well being from uh living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> you probably like cool weather on your uh vacations at least we do
 	
 	
 		yeah sometimes sometimes you know when it in when it's getting really hot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> you know you want to go someplace cool
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 		well usually vacation time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July August September</TIMEX> it's time to go somewhere else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		have you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		now i've i've been but not to way up at near <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Branson</ENAMEX> oh i hear it's just booming up there now
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		up around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver Silver Silver Dollar City</ENAMEX> have you been there
 	
 	
 		no no i haven't
 	
 	
 		i heard on uh what was it <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> or something a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> are starting to build their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclubs</ENAMEX> up there
 	
 	
 		yeah i saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we went to uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> coast and and that is really beautiful
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh really
 		really
 	
 	
 		and that is really beautiful and it's also unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> completely because it's cool enough that you don't have uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surfers</ENAMEX> much because they need protective clothing you know
 	
 	
 		how about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is it very uh crowded
 	
 	
 		and and uh there's really uh several nice places to stay along the coast there
 		we stayed at what was called the uh kite capital of the world what was the name of that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> place
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it is really nice uh we a very nice place on the beach and very reasonably priced compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> particularly
 	
 	
 		oh i bet
 		really i bet but but it's not as crowded either
 	
 	
 		so in fact most of the
 		that's right most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californians</ENAMEX> that uh want to stay on the coast apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and so forth they come up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> coast to stay because it's much uh more economical
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah i'd like to go up around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> sometime to see
 	
 	
 		yeah we've we've been up that way and well this that trip we also went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vancouver</ENAMEX> and out to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Victoria</ENAMEX> which is very nice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think the furthest west i've ever gotten is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you got  you haven't been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> either then
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh no
 	
 	
 		well if you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> don't go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>  unless you really want to just see the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> set up and so forth
 	
 	
 		oh i won't
 		no no no
 	
 	
 		but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> are both very nice right
 	
 	
 		really
 		i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> have been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and they said it was real nice
 		
 		
 	