
 
		
 			
 				are you Bob
 			
 			
 				
 				i am in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> where are you
 			
 			
 				oh okay i am in Waco
 			
 			
 				is that right oh okay
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				right down the street
 			
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				oh credit cards my favorite subject
 			
 			
 				you mean you use credit cards
 			
 			
 				oh do i uh
 			
 			
 				i bet you used them all up over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 			
 			
 				yeah mostly over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> uh i get in a rut with credit cards cause they get me kind of in a vicious cycle where you use them a lot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX> and then you have to use whatever money you have to pay those off
 			
 			
 				
 				
 				and then your are in debt
 			
 			
 				and so then you have no money  so you use a credit card
 			
 			
 				
 				i understand that
 			
 			
 				so yeah uh i probably have one of every credit card there is
 			
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				do you use them a lot
 			
 			
 				well uh it kind of comes and goes uh i use uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citibank</ENAMEX> uh the Advantage one pretty much because you get
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				Advantage points for every dollar you spend and once a year i get a free airplane ride that way
 			
 			
 				oh
 			
 			
 				so
 				as long as you pay it off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> it doesn't cost you anything
 			
 			
 				yeah yeah well that is a good idea
 			
 			
 				so
 				that is what i
 			
 			
 				that through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				huh
 			
 			
 				but uh
 				i got all sorts of credit cards for my business that i use but uh
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				if i can get away with paying them off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> it is alright if i don't then it gets expensive
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				yeah that is my problem i don't try and pay them off i pay like the minimum but i know  so i have got myself
 			
 			
 				well you shouldn't do that you you you never you you you never get out of the hole that way
 			
 			
 				exactly i have got that is why i have got myself with all this trouble now
 			
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				but i pay most of them on time and everything it is just the i always have them
 			
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				so it is kind of strange
 			
 			
 				kind of like the federal government right
 			
 			
 				oh yeah exactly like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>  in
 			
 			
 				
 				never never get out of debt
 			
 			
 				in debt for
 			
 			
 				and any time you try to get out of debt the economy goes to pot because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are spending money right
 			
 			
 				yeah yeah
 			
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				have they put the cap on the interest rates
 			
 			
 				so
 				no
 			
 			
 				i didn't know if they actually did that or not i know they were  i know they were considering it
 			
 			
 				no
 				just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't need credit get the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four and a half</NUMEX> percent the rest of the uh and me we got to pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> and eighteen percent so
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				funny how that works isn't it
 			
 			
 				
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thou</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thou</ENAMEX> who doesn't need credit gets cheap credit
 			
 			
 				i would be interested to find out how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or how much uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use credit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> say in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> as opposed to nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety one</NUMEX> even nineteen ninety
 				i think i think it be amazing how much how many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use it
 			
 			
 				well i think so because the
 			
 			
 				because of the economy yeah
 			
 			
 				that's right right you have got to use everything you have got just to stay where you are at
 			
 			
 				exactly
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				i would be very i would like to see some numbers on that i think that would be interesting
 			
 			
 				do you do you have any uh credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> or anything where you work or anything like that do you
 			
 			
 				yeah i have a credit union
 			
 			
 				we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master Card</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> too
 			
 			
 				yeah they do uh-huh
 			
 			
 				you got that one
 			
 			
 				yes i do  yes i do a matter of fact
 			
 			
 				
 				who who do you work for
 			
 			
 				uh i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Channel</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six</NUMEX>
 			
 			
 				oh
 			
 			
 				it's it's an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliate</ENAMEX> down here
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				i do a lot of work down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> a lot of i call on a lot of my business is down there
 			
 			
 				oh really
 				oh okay where do you work what is your
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				i sell metal fabricating equipment and tooling and uh
 			
 			
 				oh okay
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tyme</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tempco</ENAMEX> and all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down there
 			
 			
 				oh okay
 				so you probably work with uh
 			
 			
 				GNK
 			
 			
 				uh what is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> from here
 				you ever work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis Iron</ENAMEX> yes yep matter of fact i just saw them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> yep
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis Iron Work</ENAMEX> yeah
 				oh okay and uh what else
 			
 			
 				are are you in that part are you in the south part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> now
 			
 			
 				yeah well i live actually in Hewett
 			
 			
 				oh yeah okay
 			
 			
 				yeah right outside so that is where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis Iron Works</ENAMEX> is
 			
 			
 				you know
 				you know uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parker Machine Tool</ENAMEX> down there
 			
 			
 				uh
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Parker</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				i don't think i have seen that one i am sure i pass by it or something but i am not sure
 			
 			
 				there is a place in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hewett</ENAMEX> called it is a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Air</ENAMEX>
 				that is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hewett</ENAMEX> just around the corner from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis Iron Works</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">huh Prime Air</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				yeah they make uh
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">humidifiers</ENAMEX> and uh filters for air filtration stuff for you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> homes something like that it's a new kind
 			
 			
 				oh okay
 				okay
 				have you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlin</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				uh yeah
 			
 			
 				i think it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlin</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mart</ENAMEX> they have uh
 				uh a place i guess that would be similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime Air</ENAMEX> it is called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H G H</ENAMEX> or something like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K G H</ENAMEX> or
 			
 			
 				oh really
 				huh
 			
 			
 				i can't think of i can't think of the name but
 			
 			
 				i will have to stop in there i went i have gone through there uh my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&M</ENAMEX> and
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 				oh yeah
 			
 			
 				he is working on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> sent him there for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s mostly in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engineering</ENAMEX> so once and a while we go up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> there rather than take <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty five</NUMEX>
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				that is about the last time i have been through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mart</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				uh-huh oh i don't like that drive i make that drive sometimes we have stories out there but
 			
 			
 				
 				there is always a state trooper down there you have got to drive careful
 			
 			
 				huh  oh really i know
 			
 			
 				between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlin</ENAMEX> they will nail you if you go <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over sixty miles an hour</NUMEX>
 			
 			
 				oh goodness they they are bad at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewett</ENAMEX> too on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> they are real bad that is where i got my last ticket
 			
 			
 				huh
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 				
 			
 			
 				so of course i couldn't pay that on a credit
 			
 		
 	