
 
     		
 	
 		yeah they they asked us um you know whether we felt the uh the war was was justified in dollars and lives and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean i i really can't uh see how it was i think the more interesting part of the question to me was the effect that it had on uh on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's what's called a moot question
 	
 	
 		you
 		yeah real good point but i was thinking you know i was while i was waiting for a connection i was just thinking about it i said you know the
 		i don't know if without the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> if we would have had you know all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hippie</ENAMEX> era the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protestors</ENAMEX> demonstrations um
 		you know and the the effect that it had on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Rock and Roll</ENAMEX> and you know all of the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomers</ENAMEX> i mean i i think it you know has a profound effect on all of us
 	
 	
 		yeah the the
 		i think that had we had the war or had we not had the war we'd a had a lot similar uh effect upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in terms of the the freedom era as it were
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think what we saw was a phenomenon of a large number of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time that were of the age of decision without the maturity to handle it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		me among them
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah likewise likewise
 	
 	
 		and uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> because he kept me out of that place
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and my number was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> i was going yeah and
 	
 	
 		wow
 		oh well see my my uh the the
 		i had uh i had forgot i hadn't even thought about that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long long time</TIMEX> i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> numbers the lowest one i had was like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a sixty eight</TIMEX> i think and then another one uh i had like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one thirty seven</TIMEX> i think you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah forget that you're not going
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh you know none the less uh i was busy going to college when that was happening you know
 	
 	
 		well i quit college when uh they when they moved out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		went into construction
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		took me seventeen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to finish my degree
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well um  i don't know it's uh
 	
 	
 		is it was it worth while from who's point of view
 	
 	
 		well i think that i think what it showed though was that uh you you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> was was is is not invincible and all powerful and uh you you know it it also shows that
 		even with the the kind of money that was thrown into it and the the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> armaments uh with the way it was waged which was not an all out war and i guess that's the other thing too it was never a declared war so you you know it never did really have the backing of the people
 	
 	
 		well i think one of the the major points that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> including myself missed until recently is the fact that
 		we could have annihilated
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north</ENAMEX> had we wanted to
 	
 	
 		oh and i agree with that but it was uh it was such a uh a a limited uh you know one hand tied behind your back uh
 	
 	
 		well even even at even at the not on the you know the gross tactical but on the on the very minute tactical arena
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they were sending out you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> to engage a company
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and they'd get wiped out you wonder why you know and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		at every turn the tacticians were denied access to information which is a biggie and uh components you know whatever it took to do the job by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		why why was that
 	
 	
 		why because somebody was getting rich i found that everywhere you look if you find the money you'll find out why
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah good point
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Chemical</ENAMEX> had a real good thing going you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Chemical</ENAMEX> had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> at every demonstration
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yes and if your picture was in that demonstration you didn't get hired by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Chemical</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really how interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX> was was uh doing a lot of that too
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DuPont</ENAMEX> is um  they're they're not high on my list of favorites they uh they fought uh the banning of ozone uh or rather um not ozone but uh freon just tooth and nail
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it's a big part of their market
 	
 	
 		oh right right but i mean you know they they took uh you know all the data that had been uh produced uh from back uh in the late uh eighties middle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid to late</TIMEX> eighties about uh
 	
 	
 		you know in the
 	
 	
 		uh how freon was uh shown to to damage the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ozone</ENAMEX> and uh they just you know were adamant that uh you know and and
 	
 	
 		they have no moral conscience
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		and that goes into and it and it's all tied together too i kind of believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam</ENAMEX> event i'm not gonna call it a war or a police action it was an event
 		that the main
 		push for that was outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> our involvement for one thing we were on the wrong side
 		you know we were on the side of the fascist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictator</ENAMEX> and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ho Chi Minh</ENAMEX> if you've read any of his writings he was a democrat
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know he wanted democracy
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		but he was forced to sleep with
 		
 		
 	