
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh
 	
 	
 		do you know you know what the topic is
 	
 	
 		music
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		what type do you like
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i like uh pretty much rock popular rock
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		what kind do you like
 	
 	
 		uh i like rock semi classical soft jazz not heavy rock
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um i can get into soft jazz too
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't like uh country particularly or rap or um what else
 	
 	
 		no
 		
 
 		country turns me off uh the my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> likes rap
 		i don't like
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah definitely strange but uh i i never got much i mean every so often there is like a song out that just sounds funny when you listen to it and those are probably the only kind i like but uh rap in general like i don't get into
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so who's your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> right now
 	
 	
 		um i i actually have a couple of favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> i i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> like you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX> uh who are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> song <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> you know i mean who are
 	
 	
 		great he's one of my favorites
 	
 	
 		yeah he's i i love him i i had his greatest hits uh and i had to have it on i have it on tape i have it on CD and i have it on record
 	
 	
 		what
 	
 	
 		
 
 		my tape went bad so i bought a record then my record went bad so i bought a CD
 	
 	
 		what is your very favorite song that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX> has done
 	
 	
 		
 
 		probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Piano Man</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh maybe maybe just because it is like on i think it is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the on the CD
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the tape too and i just listen to it a lot and i just i just love it
 	
 	
 		my very favorite is still rock and roll to me
 	
 	
 		hm that is a good one
 		you ever see the video uh by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Joel</ENAMEX> uh it's not  it's uh another one about uh he is in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> and he has you something like Keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> that's the name of the song and in the video he uh he's actually in court
 	
 	
 		yes i think so
 	
 	
 		and  and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christi Brinkley's</ENAMEX> in it yeah that's another reason i like him he's like married to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> i love you know
 	
 	
 		well then he has another video that she's been in uh he's like uh uh i think it is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Uptown Girl</ENAMEX> and that's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one that i had seen her in she is just so gorgeous
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i know i know no uh the the Keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> is great because uh you see you know all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> and they have these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> dancing  on the railings on the sides
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i just got a kick out of it it was just really funny
 	
 	
 		well the other one that he came out with and i loved the video for it too uh it was i think on his last CD uh
 		We Didn't Start the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh um-hum um-hum um-hum um-</ENAMEX>hum yeah he
 	
 	
 		oh i just love that song
 	
 	
 		he he just has the ability i mean every so often he'll just come out with uh you know a couple of the songs that are just great yeah
 	
 	
 		um-hum does he have anything new out do you know
 	
 	
 		no i haven't heard anything lately um but then again i haven't bought any CDs lately i had a CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> and i just moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX> and uh when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> i i gave my CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> because i was going to buy another one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and you never bought another one
 	
 	
 		and and well i have one now but i just got it it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX> so i i just uh recently have started going back into the CD market
 	
 	
 		yes
 		did you get one that loads <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> or did you get a single
 	
 	
 		yeah i got the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the five</TIMEX> disc carousel
 	
 	
 		that's what we have and i'll tell you it's a lot nicer because you can you know sometimes i get tired of listening to the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> over you know for the whole entire length of the CD and it's nice when you can randomly choose them too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		yeah i that's what i really like and i bought a little single disc for my car
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that's great i mean i every since i put that thing in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i haven't heard a tape since
 	
 	
 		yeah i'd like to have one of those next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i buy i don't know how expensive they are when you are putting them in
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i just i just got a little portable <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i bought a little they <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> makes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">base unit</ENAMEX> that you can just mount in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and so the whole package was under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah otherwise i mean if you buy them in a car now it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> bucks for a whole unit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		ooh that might be a little bit more than my budget
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's that's a little extravagant you know but if you can afford the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that it can come into you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's not that bad
 		but
 	
 	
 		do you go to any concerts or anything
 	
 	
 		i haven't been to any uh since i've been out of college um and it usually the concerts that have come up lately i have been out of town uh traveling so i just haven't had the chance to go to any
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and i work with a bunch of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> they're always going to concerts but whenever they tell me there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> coming up there's something going on and i can never go
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so i know i haven't been to any i've been missing out on life
 	
 	
 		well there is someone that i just discovered like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> and have you ever heard of Yanni
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		of who
 	
 	
 		Yanni
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> name the name sounds familiar
 	
 	
 		he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> he's dating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Evans</ENAMEX> right now and he does i first heard when uh i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years ago</TIMEX> there was uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> that played soft <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX> and light jazz
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i did not think i liked jazz at all until i started listening to this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yanni</ENAMEX> is one of these i guess he's kind of new wavish or something
 	
 	
 		hum
 		i think that's where i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yanni</ENAMEX> was there was something about him dating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Evans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that 's probably right exactly but his music is absolutely wonderful and i've kind of gotten into a little bit of this new age or new wave or whatever it may be and uh there's a lot of that that i like a
 	
 	
 		is it really hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 		
 		
 	