
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i uh spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> as a university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really i i've spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> um teaching in public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and elementary school
 	
 	
 		oh do you really that's great
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i taught in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 	
 	
 		did you teach in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what
 		i did i did um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you sound pretty young for a university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i was pretty young well i was uh i had never intended to do it and i was uh
 		uh given the opportunity after i'd started a management consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to teach in in uh uh one of the business <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California State University</ENAMEX> system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at any rate um the topic is fascinating because one of the things i've done for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> is um
 		research the problem from the point of view of uh uh what appears to be working best and how you can explain it theoretically you may be familiar with cooperative learning
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you ever
 	
 	
 		well you can you can tell me a little bit more about it because i don't think we did that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well the cooperative learning is a technique that was tried initially to integrate the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and uh what what it involves basically
 		is the use of peer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> becomes a uh a sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> resource person
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to the cooperative learning uh to the learning cooperatives i guess they're called and there are uh some fairly sophisticated approaches that are used in the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> with point systems and things like that so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh
 		gain a competence with respect to the material
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i think that the combination of uh technology and techniques like that together with marketplace forces will bring about a revolution
 		in the way we learn uh i think there is a direct threat to vested interest in the public school system
 		uh that will stand in the way of that progress being a little faster uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> are in too many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> uh complain about the uh uh the cost and ineffectiveness that results so my feeling is that um
 	
 	
 		true
 	
 	
 		the the problem is is
 		uh significant there are plenty of good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh available to
 		um offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> educational experience but that we just have to reallocate reallocate and reorganize the resources to do it and uh i think
 		certain techniques and technologies will influence all of that as well as research um
 		uh of the sort that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like me do looking at theories of behavior and how they can be used to improve performance particularly uh accelerate the the pace of learning
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my feeling is that uh those kinds of things will solve the problem eventually i don't know what form it'll ultimately take
 		um
 		uh but i think that
 		the future is pretty bright because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> recognize that we're paying an enormous price for
 		uh inferior quality when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> involved really aren't inferior so it must be the way we're managing the process that
 		uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i see what you're saying yeah i totally agree
 	
 	
 		i i don't
 		i don't think it's it's a matter of of uh talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do it as both as quote unquote <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>
 		but clearly what's happened in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is the school system's been asked to assume a great many responsibilities
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past thirty years</TIMEX> that weren't existent uh you must see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with real significant problems um in some cases
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh course <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa City</ENAMEX> i don't know how hard how hard is it uh in the public school system in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa City</ENAMEX> is it is it uh deteriorated a lot do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say or are they pretty happy with it or
 	
 	
 		well i've i haven't taught in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> but i've taught in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there were saying that
 		the way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were going a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were going away and going to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or else going to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> where they taught their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or you know anything but the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and the ones that did have you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> yeah well
 	
 	
 		even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s a place where you wouldn't think that problem would be very severe
 	
 	
 		well uh maybe it was the area i was in but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> had lot of transient um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who were on the poorer side and
 	
 	
 		yeah you see you saw a fair number of troubled kids
 	
 	
 		yeah and i mean like you said how they were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were doing more things for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		they thought than they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX> i mean they were the school i was teaching at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> i left they're considering providing hot lunch for or hot breakfast for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		as well as hot lunch and
 		
 		
 	