
 
     		
 	
 		and i have to admit that we just moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> recently and that i hadn't voted in an election yet and although i did go down and register and i that's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've ever done that has what's been your voting experience
 	
 	
 		
 
 		my voting experience
 	
 	
 		well do you feel like uh i mean i
 	
 	
 		i i well personally i've been very diligent until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when i felt my vote was absolutely
 		kind of washed down the drain
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		for the issues that you know that i felt really strong for um
 		i think apathy has set in to a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because of the way our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are and the way our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is being run
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		that's really true that's kind of the way that i have felt it i also feel guilty um not
 		knowing and not going the extra mile myself and studying out the issues and studying out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> course we only have mostly the representation given in the media
 		but um i have felt since i've been here that i haven't known
 		what the issues were and that i because it was a new community
 	
 	
 		you really do have to study to get yourself um up to par with
 		what is truly going on and that takes a lot of research and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> are very busy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it does
 	
 	
 		and uh and that is an excuse because we are we are always uh involved i know i'm heavenly involved in other things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and to take time out and uh study the issues in depth would take quite a bit of time and i don't have the time to devote to that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you hopefully will find
 		that
 		you want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> that are running to be honest and aboveboard and unfortunately they are not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no
 	
 	
 		and uh it's really a dilemma uh that we find ourselves in i believe um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i kind of just have taken a back step away and uh
 		hopefully that someone will clean up the mess that's there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		take it it because it is a task that is
 		to me kind of overwhelming
 	
 	
 		yes and uh
 		and uh i also feel especially in the presidential elections that uh since we're back on the old system of electoral votes and
 		or that and that you don't necessarily your vote doesn't necessarily
 		elect a president
 	
 	
 		right they just want to see how close the electoral votes are with the public votes
 	
 	
 		right and it's kind of it's awful and and it's hard to feel like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but i know that it's important
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i feel guilty that i haven't done that here haven't taken the time and i know that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can make a difference but it's hard to
 		to face the corruption like you say and uh and to know what you're up against
 		and it makes me feel bad that
 		i'm glad i mean i am thankful for the uh  nineteenth amendment that it gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> the right to vote and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm glad that that happened
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and everything and i hope that i will become
 		a better
 		make a better difference in
 		but i haven't done that so far
 	
 	
 		well i know that when you're in a smaller community i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mesquite</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when we have uh a local election say for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> and so forth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they really uh give a lot of information in the local newspaper not in the not in the bigger city <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> i mean they
 		they just give it a small portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> but the local newspaper really goes into uh quite a bit of history about the candidate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and then they have they raise a
 		they raise <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> and uh there's a pro and a con <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">side</ENAMEX> and uh you can really um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		feel comfortable in uh evaluating that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> by uh that method
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i feel pretty confident about
 		the way it's put forth now i wouldn't say that about the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> though and the and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> uh like the presidential
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i mean they've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are running that are admitted uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> and admitted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crooks</ENAMEX> you know i'm sorry but
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		i don't believe in them turning a good uh uh a new leaf
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		unless they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> that has done that to them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> they can't do it
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's not very likely i mean it seems like
 		their
 		
 		
 	