
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh what do you
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about it
 	
 	
 		well i don't know i would hate i would rather not have to have it all taken out but i kind of feel like
 		it's part of living in a free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>  but it seems like they take quite a bit out
 	
 	
 		uh i'm a tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>  and uh i uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but i agree with you i uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you probably know like i say you're a lot more knowledgeable about it than i am but do you do for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> or mainly
 	
 	
 		i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> i work for a bank
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh do you oh
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh
 		and
 	
 	
 		so what what do they think the corporation you work with
 	
 	
 		um
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks banks</ENAMEX> are regulated of course by the uh by the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> anyway so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we don't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> taxes
 		which are
 		are not federal taxes uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i think they i don't hear anything at work about them really
 	
 	
 		yeah well i tell you i i work for a credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> so that might be a whole another topic as far as well you know how do
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		what's the opinion around there about uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">credit unions</ENAMEX> not being taxed and stuff do they do have you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> had any i don't want to say battles but
 		do they uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and stuff they they claim the unfair unfair uh unfair playing field and whatnot and
 		whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">credit unions</ENAMEX> are getting you know being treated special and do they get
 	
 	
 		we've had that too because of the failures though
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh whether or not they should be assessed more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> has uh has uh is in the midst of a reform probably in that area
 	
 	
 		it's where they're going to tax credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> on a state level or or just assess their more for the insurance fund
 	
 	
 		or or higher assessment to yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		huh yeah it's uh i don't know i want i think i've always felt that if we <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">credit unions</ENAMEX> stick to their little niche they have that then it probably shouldn't be but it seems like more and more uh
 		we're getting out into a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> territories i do not know if it is too fair or not
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know that it is fair i think that it's you know the way banking is being uh compacted i work for at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nations Bank</ENAMEX> which has just merged with C and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S Sovran</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you know i think i think a little competition is good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		but down here a lot we saw  we say them doing things they shouldn't be doing
 	
 	
 		yeah they getting into business lending and things like that or yeah i the credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> i work for is one of the top the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> uh about the fifteenth largest and we are starting to get into that and that is where i really have my questions as to whether or not we're
 	
 	
 		yeah real estate
 	
 	
 		you know if they were able were playing on a level field whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are getting taxed and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	

 		and i don't know what the corporate taxes are as far as how much they get taxed but i mean i know it would have to it would definitely have to effect our bottom line if we got taxed there's no doubt about it
 	
 	
 		everybody's gone down i think the individual levels are fine
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i don't think they're perceived as uh
 		was i learned in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> if you taxed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent of the income of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that made over a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we wouldn't reduce the deficit by
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but but a drop in the bucket because there are such few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that do that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well what do you have have you ever studied i guess anything about a flat tax or anything like that i mean we've talked about it and how it kind be kind of a recessive tax for the poor or
 	
 	
 		well that's what sales tax are
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true but i mean on more of a national level i guess it seems like it might uh get rid of a lot of the problems as far as the loop holes and stuff but
 		maybe just have it based on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> different level and eliminate a lot of the exemptions and stuff is that
 	
 	
 		that uh flat taxes i think are a pretty good idea uh they're debating of course right now whether to bring in capital gains again uh to stimulate the economy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh find from what i from what i recall it doesn't stimulate the economy that much it just uh boots everybody's feeling about stimulating the economy
 	
 	
 		yeah that's more or less touchy-feely thing as opposed to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i just always heard that the poor would end end up taking the worst brunt of it because they're
 		you know their their income is less and yet they're being taxed at the same rate and therefore it hurts their spending power but you know i've heard different ideas to where they will make it so that uh you know depending on your income that it'll be maybe a different level of tax but
 		seems like then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would just do whatever they could to hide income so like you say it probably wouldn't do much anyway
 	
 	
 		the
 		i i what happens is i think it is a good idea but they chip away at it i mean the home mortgage deduction is like sacrosanct
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		you can't take away <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that said there you go you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> exception already and uh and uh it you know well if we didn't have this exception then we'll just add this one and it just gets it snowballs
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's true
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i think it is in theory probably a good idea
 	
 	
 		well uh
 		are the taxes in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are they are few state taxes very high or
 	
 	
 		we don't have state income tax
 	
 	
 		oh don't you oh that's sweet
 	
 	
 		none
 		but we've got an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">eight percent</NUMEX> state sales tax
 	
 	
 		oh that hurts
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh you know course that's
 		that's a regressive tax
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		and it's you know uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh it's not on grocery
 		
 		
 	