
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> what do you think um some of the changes in roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society in the past generation or two
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well of course working
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's definitely got to be the biggest thing is that everybody's out there working
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		including me  well what do you think it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um yeah i agree i also think that there are more um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> stay single longer it seems like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes they do yeah they do
 	
 	
 		yeah i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> were both married by the time they were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> and i waited until i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know um i know that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true it's a big change i'm an OB <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and so i really do see what you're saying there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it used to be that our list ran nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty one</TIMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>' ages
 		and now our care plans look more like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two thirty three</TIMEX> if we get somebody <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX> we go oh look how young so yeah you're right there's a big change and we have a lot of <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time moms in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their late thirties</TIMEX> and even forties
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that's true but again i guess it probably does go back to the same thing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> having careers
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they didn't have if they weren't out there working and having their careers
 		they probably would be married and having their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>  so  i guess it's a combination
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah seems like there uh-huh go ahead
 	
 	
 		no go on
 	
 	
 		oh it just seems like there are more single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> too i mean that's there're a lot of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		either divorced or um
 		you know never been married so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah there's a lot of mixed up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that's for sure yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree
 		well what do you think have been the most significant changes in the past generation or so
 	
 	
 		well just that i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 		the the role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> doesn't stay home and cook the dinner take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um we do it all  i really think that and i know that there's a lot more participation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> but i still think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have the major role i really do i think they're just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're not doing very much less i don't think as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and everything are concerned not from what i see and and they're contributing to the income besides
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that we're really really putting a lot of stress on ourselves
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and it really it's affecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> you know for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> not not to be home and yet you know um
 	
 	
 		oh it is
 	
 	
 		i mean i i don't blame anybody when they have to work  because um yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's it's difficult and i think that i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> actually so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's very wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and we're not part of that but i  it is you know and i think what i see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> working just for bigger and better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i really hate that you know i hate to see that and and i've been here for a very long time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		i don't know now i'm a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> and i don't have a choice anymore but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i used to just work occasionally for extra money but now i have to work all the time and that's really hard and and i don't know how a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> does just choose to go out to work and
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in a way it's good it's very good to get out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> and i think that's a good thing if you can do it part time but to just go out there forty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> at least and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and work and and leave your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> alone and that kind of thing i think that's
 		not very smart i think that's difficult on them so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well what do you think's gonna happen in the next generation you think it'll continue yeah
 	
 	
 		well it's gonna be interesting i yeah i think it will change but i'm not sure how it's going to because i see young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and wonder how in the world they'll ever afford
 		to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and and to raise a family i don't know how they're gonna do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i don't know how it can change to where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> can get back into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> again i don't think that ever will go backwards
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't know what effect it's gonna have on these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now when they grow up how they're gonna feel about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it you know it could lead to another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodstock</ENAMEX> type thing you know where where there's just too much material things and and maybe these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will really resent that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are out there working for things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they might wanna do without things rather than do that to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> it's hard to say
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it is i think some
 		i don't know how many you know what percentage but some are will move back toward more traditional lifestyle of staying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i guess i see that happening already
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some choosing it and and they get you know there're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> chide them for it you know why aren't you out
 		
 		
 	