
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i guess we start talking about the budget
 	
 	
 		very good sir
 	
 	
 		okay you you live near the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital what can we do about this mess
 	
 	
 		well uh living near the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s capital unfortunately doesn't do you any good uh all i all i uh find that i can do is read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and try to decide what's best for us
 		what we need to do and that's sort of a function of the economy
 		and our relationship with uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and so forth and right now we're in this big change since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has undergone such a uh big uh renegotiation within themselves
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i'm sure that we haven't quite decided where we stand in that yet
 	
 	
 		i see big opportunities in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> opening up uh it just it just seems to me like we ought to be able to go over there and help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> become a capitalistic society
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i think they're looking for that they just need guidance yes that would be very good for us to help
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		show them what it what it takes to have a a capitalistic society and one in which each of them has a a say and uh you know can express their thoughts safely
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		another thing i think the uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> could do right now on a short term basis to get things speeded up is
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		help out the working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> right now the middle income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh give them some tax credits i think they've done that i seems like i remember that happening once in my past i'm in my forties and i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		basically remember getting some sort of trax tax credit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and i think it helped i think we bought a car
 		uh at that time because we got some sort of a rebate
 	
 	
 		oh i don't recall ever getting a rebate but it does seem as though if if we are able to
 		reduce the our expenditures for defense course we've got to get get this big debt that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has under control
 		and if as we get that under control then i'd like to see the taxes that we pay reduced
 		a certain amount you know so that we're all comfortable but i do believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s gonna have to get itself straightened out debtwise before uh they could do too much that way
 		but i hate to see them raise the taxes if it's unnecessary
 	
 	
 		well i've always believed in paying my fair share of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of taxes oh and whatever my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> says is my fair share is what i think i should pay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		sure that makes sense
 	
 	
 		uh i don't necessarily agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who go out of their way to find loopholes and not paying their fair share
 	
 	
 		yes it it it seems as though a lot of the things that we see in the paper and in letters that you receive are showing you loopholes or how not to pay your share and that really is sort of against what the whole ball game's about isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> who does my taxes for me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> it seems like she's got a new suggestion
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and sometimes i go with them and sometimes i don't uh since i no longer work uh usually it's not very complicated anymore but uh
 	
 	
 		you no longer work
 	
 	
 		i no longer work uh  oh it's been almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> i had some uh strange heart problems occur
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		and uh so i'm more or less hang around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		well you have more experience at that than i i just retired from working myself on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December thirty first so</TIMEX> i haven't really had time to look at it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retiree</ENAMEX> point of view
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but it'll be an interesting uh concept i'm sure
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh
 		i know for the i thought maybe i would go back to work especially during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that first year</TIMEX> and then they finally decided that then maybe i'll never work again
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so it took some while to adjust to it and it and it took some adjusting financially and things like that i can no longer afford  things that maybe i used to take for granted
 	
 	
 		yes that
 	
 	
 		and i certainly can't invest money like i used to
 	
 	
 		i understand well it's unfortunate you had that problem and i do hope you will be able to work out your circumstances so that you can live comfortably and feel confident that you are doing your share of the taxes
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		and you know still there are certain things that you need to do in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and yourself
 		to enjoy life to its fullest
 	
 	
 		what kind of work did you do when you were working
 	
 	
 		i was working uh in doing research for the government
 		so i know what it's like i had worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> basically i'm actually i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penn State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh but my work has always been in research uh related uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> so i'm i'm aware of what it takes to perform the work that's needed
 		and
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has got to decide what it needs to know and then set up the criteria by which problems are solved and and uh the
 		
 		
 	