
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i was just wondering if you had had any experience with um
 		the care of the elderly
 	
 	
 		yes i have in fact uh just a little over just a little less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> went to be with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> and we cared for her the last uh oh seventeen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of her life here in the at home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		aside from uh
 		having to uh take her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 		and uh you know those times well she was there in the the regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then she was diagnosed having inoperable type of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> elected to have her uh finish out uh in the hospice program
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i as far as i'm concerned that is far and above any nursing home
 		because uh she's around her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> you know the the elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> in question is around their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> the uh hospice program provides a
 		hospital type bed well it is a hospital bed and all the oxygen stuff and a uh and a visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> at least <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every other day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">et cetera et cetera et</TIMEX> cetera
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's nice
 	
 	
 		and it's all taken care of by by uh Medicare uh
 		and uh it it's it's really neat uh and i you know i wouldn't i wouldn't banish uh my old loved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to a to a warehouse
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		and that's that's what i basically uh view a nursing home as a warehouse
 		so  that's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's really sad
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		it's really a sad situation
 	
 	
 		uh-huh no
 	
 	
 		and uh i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> struggle with
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh i guess the problem is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> of whoever you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		doesn't always want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">in-law</ENAMEX> living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is that right
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well that's really sad
 	
 	
 		yeah i know but uh in this case
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> and i uh
 		are uh we're are are are uh united in this area because i guess her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> both lived with uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		her parents
 		uh their their their golden <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		this isn't like uh uh
 		just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> uh instance in fact uh her uh
 		uh experiences were were invaluable to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh  in fact i don't know if i could have uh held up uh you know without my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> uh helping in this this this case
 	
 	
 		right
 		yes well i know when the
 		i remember being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> had had  several several strokes and things and that we had
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> tried to keep her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and they did for a long time i couldn't tell you how long until she got uh where she had to have complete care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just they couldn't you know keep her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> anymore and it was really hard on everyone that she had to have you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hour</TIMEX> a day care
 		and i don't remember much about it except that there was a nursing home at that time just a block or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> from our house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that um they put her there and we all went just constantly until she died
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but it was very hard on everyone to see
 		well you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> be like that
 		and i don't know that you know  i don't being so young i don't remember why
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know what was why she had to go there
 	
 	
 		well maybe uh uh well as as you say the the care
 		of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> or was was to such that such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> couldn't handle it
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i do remember that she was you know totally incapable of taking care of herself in any way and that that they couldn't they found that they could not you know give her
 	
 	
 		oh boy yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the hygienic care and everything that she needed
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well then then there's almost then there's
 		almost no no uh
 		uh choice left to her then
 	
 	
 		no but like you say there is a tendency for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be abandoned though you know in the nursing home i do remember the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> there um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		being real excited when we came to see our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> because they got some interaction with someone
 	
 	
 		right
 		in fact just to just to sit and chat with them for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes and</TIMEX> and be interested in what they have to say regardless of what it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right and i guess that's hard on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to give
 		give up their lives if they're busy they don't you know it's easy to abandon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because we do have the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		if you can afford them
 		but
 		anyway well i'm glad it worked out good for your family
 	
 	
 		and then and
 		oh yeah it did and i was just praised i just praised the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> that that we were able to uh
 		have uh
 		uh be
 		
 		
 	