
 
     		
 	
 		have a favorite for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> or i guess being as all the rest the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are eliminated that's about all we can talk about
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah right uh well i i think um uh oh
 		i probably um i don't know watching my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of uh of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so uh for  not not having any other real real preference i guess
 	
 	
 		yes go for that well that's who i kind of thought uh that's who i was gonna kind of cheer for i just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		think all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFC</ENAMEX> are more or less like the minor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX> for  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFC</ENAMEX> lately so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i just i hope they can give them a game i think it'll be a good game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> but
 		i don't know in the past they haven't been so hot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's kind of kind of bad when they get blown out like
 	
 	
 		do you uh
 		yeah gets you know you you watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> for the commercials and that's about it all the new ones that come out so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		just out of curiosity what uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um</ENAMEX> who who do who do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> generally cheer for who are who are the close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> out there the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i i think a lot of them uh uh kind of like me i i cheer i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> you know certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and so i root for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young University</ENAMEX> of course is pretty big up here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum sure
 	
 	
 		and so a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 49ers</TIMEX> because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Young</ENAMEX> plays for them uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McMahon</ENAMEX> plays for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bears</ENAMEX> so they cheered for him you know when he played for them but he kind of got to be a jerk so nobody liked him anyway but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh a lot of 49ers i think uh more than anything i guess but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 		yeah i mean in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> there's there's plenty you know there's a fair amount to choose from between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oilers</ENAMEX> and so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yep
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		yeah we i i've always been kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> i like them i'm glad to see they're doing a little bit better but i see i just usually root for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> that i know of i guess and whatever happens happens so
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		used to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> for for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> uh ended up
 		essentially dominating or  and and being so strong consistently and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX>  being being just walked all over  by everybody i mean they've they've lost a lot of fans
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh
 		oh yeah well i think i think you'll see i bet in the nineties they come out and i'll bet they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to beat is i mean they got so many <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> round picks again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that i think they're gonna be really tough and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i yeah yeah
 		sure
 		yeah they're they're obviously rebuilding quite pretty well and and stuff
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX> seems to know what he's doing too are you
 	
 	
 		yeah i i didn't know how he was gonna make the transition into professional ball um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's one thing to be a real successful college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> now i i at least i imagine it is um you know and and then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it seem like it would be quite different to to be coaching pros
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well you'd think that the just the personalities the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> it it it would seem a lot harder to get them motivated i mean it's a job then and you know you're not out for school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX> or whatever you know you're out for the fifty grand
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		course course also at that at that level i mean you're dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who who know you know who who are competitive obviously or they wouldn't be there and they're motivated obviously or they wouldn't be there you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		yeah that's true i guess
 	
 	
 		and so uh you know i don't know i mean but it seems like it would you know you can't treat them like they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and yet  in a lot of senses still a lot of them probably are
 	
 	
 		course i've always had a hard time screaming at somebody that was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about six five</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fifty anyway so i always thought that was kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stupid</ENAMEX>  wouldn't yell too loud at them because you never know what might come back at you
 	
 	
 		yeah you would've you would've been one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> with the soft styles  yeah
 	
 	
 		that's right  just sweet talk them as much as you can because
 	
 	
 		my yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was actually a football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> so yeah in the junior junior college yeah
 	
 	
 		oh was he on a college level or junior college oh so did you play at all yourself or
 	
 	
 		i played played high school but i didn't didn't go beyond that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i stopped growing i think about when i was twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and everybody else grew up so i quit after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little League</ENAMEX> because i realized it was
 	
 	
 		yeah huh
 	
 	
 		i was gonna get pounded on if i kept going so
 	
 	
 		uh  well i'm i didn't grow too big myself but
 	
 	
 		yep but do you follow college much at all either or
 	
 	
 		a little bit more so yeah because i i'm here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> and we have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT Austin</ENAMEX> it's here and and uh
 	
 	
 		do you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they they look like they were big you know they're kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> i mean  for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years years</TIMEX> had a dominating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> then they went through this big long  slump and and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> it looked like they were back and and there was predictions that they were gonna be a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it'll be real challenge in fact i think they started ranks like you know fifteenth in the polls or something and then you know then it was a long slide down it really was it a fairly disappointing year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 		yeah
 		well i you know what they're i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that's pretty uh it's uh like a rabid thing down there isn't it
 	
 	
 		it yeah it's it's pretty serious uh you know i i end up being so busy that i i don't watch much of it and and i don't follow it much but it's obvious that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around me do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and and i sometimes feel bad that i haven't you know i'm not up on it more
 	
 	
 		yeah in fact that's that was our whole reason for cheering <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> because that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ty Detmer</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> down there and that's that's who i follow quite a bit is BYU but
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we were kind of prejudiced towards him good or bad or whatever anybody thinks but yeah they seem that he just from what he was saying his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was into it i mean that just seemed like a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were involved kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and basketball or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		right and and supposedly uh uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> his younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is graduating supposedly his younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is supposed to be a lot better than he is yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really that'll be interesting see i know uh he's he been recruited pretty heavily he's not sure if he wants to f ollow in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s footsteps and go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y i</ENAMEX> wouldn't do it if i were him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no i don't know  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		boy if he doesn't live up to that at least his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s expectations
 		
 		
 	