
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		think of the job benefits you have
 	
 	
 		well i i think uh so far they've been pretty pretty good except the medical uh
 		not not the medical the dental insurance
 	
 	
 		the dental insurance
 	
 	
 		yeah i yeah i think um
 	
 	
 		um do you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 		okay hum
 	
 	
 		i know i went to have a tooth pulled
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cavity</ENAMEX> had gotten really bad and they they wouldn't uh cover it because they said it it was a pre existing  condition
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know how you wait you wait as long as you can
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		sometimes to to lose a tooth and then to for them to come up with something like that it i i just thought that was that was pretty bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		hm that does sound pretty bogus
 	
 	
 		and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i had a tooth capped you know one of my caps fell fell off and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they paid for the the cap but they wouldn't pay for the build up
 	
 	
 		hm
 		that sounds kind of strange
 	
 	
 		and i didn't understand that either
 	
 	
 		who's your who's your dental care through
 	
 	
 		uh well uh it's it's a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		ours is through uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cigna</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's not too bad i mean i haven't
 		i haven't been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> a whole lot except for like just regular visits
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh they haven't been bad they haven't uh they've been pretty good how about your uh do you have an HMO or
 	
 	
 		well i had an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to this year</TIMEX> i switched
 	
 	
 		you you went to like a regular plan
 	
 	
 		yeah i went to regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> uh i thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> was really great uh
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know because
 	
 	
 		did it get expensive or
 	
 	
 		yeah it's gotten expensive because right now i'm i'm only i only have myself so i don't have to pay anything for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser</ENAMEX> uh premium got a little higher than it you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i have i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX> right now and uh i think uh  i personally i i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>'s are scammy now  just because uh it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only five dollars</NUMEX> a visit every time i go that's not bad okay and it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> dollars prescription
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		every time i go and they give you the generic stuff anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh every time i go there you got to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three dollars</NUMEX> for parking
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know  and
 		so if i go to make a like i i called in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i wanted to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> about my backache i someone had just hit me and uh and i you know i had some muscle stiffness i wanted to go get some uh some some medication show my back to a doctor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they wouldn't let me see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> they said no you know uh just just uh take some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ibuprofen</ENAMEX> and put a pillow on your back you know and i'm
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that was a problem that i had with them toward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> i was i was really in a lot of pain and i went there and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they they gave me an appointment for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX> away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i went to the health food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and got some teas and stuff and started drinking them i got okay but uh and i didn't go back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i was just really annoyed with them because i uh i i tried profusely to get an appointment uh to see you know and i said i if you don't give me an appointment i'm just gonna go to an emergency visit to emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and and send you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> the bill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's what i thought about later i would've probably uh been better off if i just went to emergency and you just bill
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum and and that's that's the only way you're going to get any action out of them you know if you threaten them with that you know because i said i just had the accident and i don't wanna wait too long
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		before anything happens they're like well wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX> and call us back and i'm like i don't wanna wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX> i want an appointment now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah after i really thought about it some more the i i really could've done that but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was hospitalized uh
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> i had some surgery
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX> was really good for that because i didn't have to pay any of it at all
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's real handy once you're you know if you like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> broke his arm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> he went in to the emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and they took care of his arm and he every time he went to one he only had to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> and he probably went through you know quite a bit of care uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> was expensive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> was expensive the stitches were expensive and all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know it it was real cheap i mean once you have a condition and you go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> it probably works out real uh but for just like
 		i don't know i'm i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only twenty four years old</TIMEX> you know i don't really get sick a lot you know i in fact uh over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last two years</TIMEX> i've only gone to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> once and that was for a physical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you know for me
 		you know i don't i don't see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> a whole hell of a lot you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so but then again you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX> that i when i had the regular plan you know you have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollar</NUMEX> deductible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> once and it cost me ninety bucks so it was like oh well
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		i guess i could've done pretty good with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> dollar visit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX> premium
 		would cost me like forty something dollars <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow that's a lot
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> will cover uh whatever they would have covered for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> but the premium is still <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> more than that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaiser</ENAMEX>'s expensive i mean i think it's uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> it's like <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost four thousand eight hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so i went back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX> because i i won't hav e to pay anything
 	
 	
 		yeah that works that works out pretty handy
 	
 	
 		and uh although they do have a deductible that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> will add up to that pretty quick
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		it works out okay i think if you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> is probably the best
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	