
 
     		
 	
 		okay  okay well i think this is going to probably be the most difficult topic that i've discussed so far yes well have you returned anything lately
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really
 		you know i just did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> as a matter of fact um i'm wondering if their subject is more uh products by mail or things that you buy at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> but um
 		i bought something through the mail through a merchant through a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that's generally got pretty good products and
 		i was really impressed with the way they handled the return policy they sent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UPS</ENAMEX> to our door to pick it up free of charge  which is such a an unusual always have to go to the
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> or some place to return it usually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> was this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spiegel</ENAMEX> by any chance
 	
 	
 		it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Anderson</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s um clothing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		don't know  that one i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiegel</ENAMEX> does that and yes and uh to me that's very impressive to think that
 	
 	
 		do they
 		it really is
 	
 	
 		but well and did you have any problem obviously had no problem with returning it
 	
 	
 		it took a while because it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the holiday weeks</TIMEX> um
 	
 	
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		it was difficult to know when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was going to arrive we're we're fortunate in that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works most of the time out of our home so he was here but
 		it would've probably been an inconvenience if if it had been a home pickup and and we hadn't been here but they were also willing to pick up at work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		did
 		did you return it because it was defective or because you just didn't like it
 	
 	
 		it was defective we returned it for the same thing um in a little larger size but it seemed that it was stitched uh around the collar such that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time she wore it it uh it ripped
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and and i think that's unusual for that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> because they do usually have pretty good products but to to answer the question that we were posed about whether things tend to be poor quality i think definitely i think a lot of the things that um
 		are not necessarily low price tend to be manufactured in a lot of cases as if they were lower priced
 	
 	
 		well i know what you mean because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> i remember i was in one of the nicer department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and looking at it was one of the designer T-shirts or some sort of thing like that and the thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was very expensive you know as they always are and it was a piece of junk you know stitching was terrible i think that they were trying to just you know play on a name
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		exactly yeah and it it's unfortunate you really cannot depend on the the department store's name for that necessarily i don't know if you have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordstroms</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no we don't i've been to one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nordstroms</ENAMEX> in um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nice store
 	
 	
 		they are really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> and i think i assumed in the beginning that they would probably carry carry overall pretty good merchandise you you have to be just as careful there as you do at any other lower priced store
 	
 	
 		do you really
 	
 	
 		yeah surprisingly
 	
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		um uh we're originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis</ENAMEX> and we came down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylors</ENAMEX> here and i look at a lot of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> brands and i am very impressed with the quality of some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> brands in some of the stores
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nordstroms</ENAMEX> carry their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> brand
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um you know i don't know that i bet they probably do but i i'm not sure that i've
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> some of what i've seen as lines that they always carry as their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brand</ENAMEX> or just something that they've um gotten at a at a lower uh price because it's a large volume some of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s lines
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i tend to look there for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' things because they don't they they sometimes have things that you can't find elsewhere because they have a pretty large variety but not often for myself
 	
 	
 		do you shop by mail quite a bit
 	
 	
 		not that much actually i  used to i think before i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and because you end up paying for the shipping and handling and everything um
 	
 	
 		it's not as inexpensive
 	
 	
 		and you don't always have the convenience of returning it if it's not right uh i i tend less often to do that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> than i might've <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's the only problem that i see because uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> gets tons of catalogs and passes them on to me and i look at things and they have some gorgeous clothes but the problem is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you can't always go by sizes you know you'll go to a department store and try on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different sizes in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and they all fit you know differently but uh that's the main thing is that i can't tell
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whether the thing is going to fit or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i tend not to mail order
 	
 	
 		whereas you might take a chance in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and bring it home and consider it you
 	
 	
 		but
 		i
 	
 	
 		you find that it's a lot more inconvenient to have to have to arrange for returning it if it's by mail
 	
 	
 		well personally i always try on before i buy anyway i just it amazes me when i talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that they buy like they buy a bunch of clothes and they don't try anything on they take them home
 	
 	
 		oh really no i meant even if you've tried it on i i'm thinking about some clothes buying for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> or something it
 	
 	
 		oh okay well that's a different story right
 	
 	
 		yeah it is funny you know i'm also amazed at uh
 		that i read about those i don't know anybody who does this but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> buy clothes and wear them and then think that they can return them
 	
 	
 		i hear about that too and that just appalls me i mean that's stealing really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's what
 		
 		
 	