
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my name is Ferrell
 	
 	
 		are you ready
 	
 	
 		
  
 		where are you calling from
 	
 	
 		i'm calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> we've got a long distance connection tonight
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes it is definitely
 	
 	
 		you ready to start i am
 	
 	
 		sure go ahead
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well you know the first thing i thought about whenever uh i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but i um  have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who's a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she has told me some horror stories but uh other than that i was thinking about um the the fact that uh so many uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> nowadays can't even identify on the map on a globe where they are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's just astounding to me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i uh have a little bit of a background well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> taught <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six years</TIMEX>
 		and uh i'm almost convinced there's a lot of it has to do with environment uh
 		she taught in a poor area poor area here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and they recently did a big article in the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S A T</ENAMEX> scores
 		in all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> of the state
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		the district we're presently living in had like double the scores where she taught and it wasn't because she was a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> there were bad i think a lot of it has to do with the environment and the help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get from from home
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think you're right i think an awful lot of it has to do with uh  the kind of emphasis that uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> get uh at home on education because um uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who's a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> was telling me she said uh you know uh
 		that she has uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that uh are are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Oriental</ENAMEX> you know some of them who uh have only been uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> maybe for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> generations
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh she said their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> is excellent uh their their social social skills are good and uh you know why is it that uh that they can be such model <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and uh yet
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know other young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who have you know been uh born and uh bred here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> uh just don't seem to get it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well you know you see these documentaries on uh on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> for example and the uh rigors they put their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> through i mean their high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are going <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh to get into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> is uh no small feat there i mean just to be accepted i'm sure there are other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that put a little more pressure on their on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> than than we do
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm beginning to wonder if maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">um year</TIMEX> round <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> would not be a bad uh a bad thing
 	
 	
 		now we have that to a to a degree here that's only because we have a little bit of a of a problem that's i guess peculiar to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and we have a  a high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of young young people
 		young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the larger uh uh student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> ratios  you know average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> size is probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that poses another problem where the you know just the individual attention that's needed sometimes uh is lacking because of the you know the shear numbers of it  and what they've gone to is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> round program here where
 		uh in essence they have what they call tracks and you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round
 		but you have uh you go like for uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> and you're off for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> then you go <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> and so you have these these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> periods rather than than the classic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer vacation</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		these are just mostly the elementary grades however
 	
 	
 		yeah well  i don't know i uh i uh
 		i don't certainly don't have the answer to it i know that uh um in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> uh for example where i'm i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who uh uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		were telling me that they have the option there of selecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that uh uh they want their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to go to
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		regardless of where they live huh
 	
 	
 		yeah right and uh  the idea of running a a school
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		sort of like a business in a way such that if enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are interested in sending their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> there it it gets more funding and those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that are less successful uh uh uh less successful get less money uh
 	
 	
 		oh that's that's interesting it's kind of like uh turning it over to the private sector to some degree
 	
 	
 		yeah the
 	
 	
 		and the the supply and demand works  yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's an interesting concept
 	
 	
 		but i don't know if that's the answer but i do think that there needs to be some changes made somewhere along the way
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i i  the stories you read about the competency and the literacy of the high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> for example
 	
 	
 		oh it's a nightmare
 	
 	
 		i can't believe it you
 	
 	
 		well and the very idea that anyone could graduate from high school and not and not know how to read or write it's scary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's scary
 	
 	
 		yeah their their awareness of the of the uh current events and geography like you were mentioned early
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	