
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay what do you think
 	
 	
 		something wrong with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		
 
 		nobody wants to go to public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>  um
 	
 	
 		yeah the class sizes are too large and  they don't pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> enough
 		like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they have too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX> they're top-heavy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh they had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on the news they had some problems with the
 		the text
 		having um mistakes in them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh a lot of them aren't like the history books aren't historically correct they they covered up a lot of the bad things that have happened
 	
 	
 		just what do you think can be done about that
 	
 	
 		well i think they need to
 		do whatever they can like um i think
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">um Massachusetts</ENAMEX> put a priority on education and and um
 		bringing in industry and  recruiting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they made a lot of difference in that state and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i think we're like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty ninth</TIMEX> in spending
 		you know and they put through this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> bill but it doesn't change the amount of spending overall it just distributes the money more evenly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so that they need to do that they need to increase spending they need to um make it so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> want to stay in teaching because most of the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> spend
 		disciplining the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> instead of instead of teaching the subject now
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who's uh a very talented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and has given it up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carrollton</ENAMEX> uh just because it's not i mean she just can't stand the paper work um
 		you know it's uh
 		and she's not paid enough she gets more as a filing claims for an insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> which she's not even trained to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		i think it's real discouraging
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and uh i i think they changed the way the ladder is now that it takes  a longer time for for you to qualify for a higher salary and uh it's it's um
 		it's more subjective than it was before
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 		i don't know you know i don't know what incentive a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> has to stay in teaching
 	
 	
 		i don't either
 		well do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i just have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> now she's going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Public Schools</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas School District</ENAMEX>
 		basically
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't have any but if i did i don't know that i could i would want them to be in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas School District</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right but the worst school districts are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Garland</ENAMEX> Carrollton
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Coppell</ENAMEX> really doesn't matter much it's it's is not at the bottom and the best is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Highland Park Richardson</ENAMEX> and Plano
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		how old is your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		so she's just started this year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and you know and she's learning to read so and she can do a little bit of math now so
 	
 	
 		where are you speaking from i can hear a lot of background noise
 	
 	
 		oh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Valley View Mall</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah there's supposed to all all the calls are supposed to be from a different phone so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's where i am and they have a lot of pay phones here so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		wow that is funny
 	
 	
 		you know
 		and i and i don't know uh uh they cut back on the since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark White</ENAMEX> passed that bill about
 	
 	
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		cutting back on all the extracurricular activities that may have improved a little bit
 		because um
 		i was talking to a lady <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and that that's the first thing she said her her both her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and they'd quit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band teacher</ENAMEX> acted like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> was the only subject that he was taking and he was suppose to spend spend all of his time on band
 	
 	
 		and demanded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		right and he he was taking honors classes in all his other subjects he goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewisville School District</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know it's just ridiculous so he just quit simple as that
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		everything should be equal you know and there's no reason you already spend all that time in band there's no reason that he should practice <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">more than an hour a day</TIMEX> outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> if he if he even has the energy especially in marching season
 	
 	
 		well that goes along with football though too you know it uh
 	
 	
 		you know
 		right and and what do you do when you are taking calculus and uh chemistry and physics <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and
 		
 		
 	