
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well how do you feel about um putting an elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		i'm not too happy about the idea although
 		i do realize that sometimes it becomes necessary to do that or to have round the clock kind of health care available in the house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which often is is not that um easy to to do sometimes it really is easier to put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> right in the central place where the care can be given
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm very happy that in my life so far i have not had to do that kind of a thing um
 		my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lived with us for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some years</TIMEX> and uh just died peacefully within a short amount of time at the end of her life and uh i never had to face that personally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh what do you think you might do in such a situation
 	
 	
 		yeah oh i agree i it's it's a tough issue i feel like each case probably has to be evaluated individually i feel um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i feel like as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> you know we need to take care of the older ones in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and yet i understand um well we may be facing that with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> she lives is living near my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and they <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they moved her into a um retirement apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> so she's got part time care
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		but as soon as she needs round the clock care then she's not allowed to live there anymore and so we'll have to face the issue of whether she moves in with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> or they put her into a nursing home and
 	
 	
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's difficult because i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> feels really um torn about it she doesn't want to
 		to put her in a place where she's gonna be unhappy lonely or where there's bad care and sometimes you just don't know what the the place is like um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean you really need to get recommendations i guess from others and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and yet it's a real burden to her to have to to be there all the time or else you know or else like you said you have to hire someone to be in the home it's a tough issue
 	
 	
 		that's right um-hum
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just not as home as much as they used to be um sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> are still working and are not retired yet and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and therefore uh they have to leave the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> all the by themselves or with the care of somebody else and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> that uh older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have uh do require more intensive surveillance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh it it isn't easy i suppose one of the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh best things if you are considering a nursing home is to inquire among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and get personal recommendations i know i always trust the opinion of a
 		close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> uh above just what i might read about a place if somebody i knew and cared about liked a place and said no this was good and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we were happy about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> and the care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera and so forth i would it certainly would go up in my estimation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh sometimes we as you said don't know a lot about where we are putting somebody that we care about and it's hard to know what the best uh place is um-hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah  i uh i was thinking you know it might
 		i guess i would want to visit the place quite a bit before or something and and talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> see what their attitudes are talk to some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that live there and see how they feel about being there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um because i've been in different nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> where i've sensed different atmospheres you know often it's it's been negative where the
 		and i know that partly it can be the attitude of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> if they they feel neglected by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or whatever or they just feel ready to die and you know tired of feeling not feeling good all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then they're not gonna feel too good but then i've i've been to other places where you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have told me um this is a really good place the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here really care about us so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well there's hope i guess uh has uh your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> always lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well no um but all the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that i've been alive she has um for the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i see yeah
 		yeah what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is that
 	
 	
 		it's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see we used to live out there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Jose</ENAMEX> area so uh you know i'm kind of familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and like it very much yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fresno</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but um uh it's uh it's a difficult situation uh sometimes also when you get involved in the
 		in those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX> for the elderly the retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and and also uh maybe even the nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residence</ENAMEX> home
 		um it's tremendously expensive and sometimes they ask you to uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	