
 
     		
 	
 		have you gone to college yourself
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i have
 	
 	
 		did you where'd you go
 	
 	
 		i went to Western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gunnison Colorado</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		what about you
 	
 	
 		uh i went i graduated from ah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weaver State University</ENAMEX> here at in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ogden</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah so what did you uh or what would you recommend for a good college i guess
 	
 	
 		i personally would recommend the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> just because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you get a lot more
 		individual attention and and you can go speak talk to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's just
 		more i think it's more conducive to studying especially if you're like a freshman
 	
 	
 		yeah i agree with you a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> percent i <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weaver</ENAMEX>'s a pretty small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> we have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten thousand</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
 		i i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young University</ENAMEX> and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Utah</ENAMEX> that you know they got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know all they are is a number you go to a testing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for everything and you just check in by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> or you most all most of the time they said they actually even had uh
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> or not student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> but you know graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> teaching their classes
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		whereas you know all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> i knew they were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD's</ENAMEX> or whatever and that they were tenured and everything and felt like uh like like you say i got a lot more personal attention and
 	
 	
 		right is that uh is that in the mountains
 	
 	
 		uh yeah we are
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well that's the way that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western State</ENAMEX> was too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's beautiful i i'd
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i wouldn't trade it i wish i could move back
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm tired of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> that's for sure yeah
 	
 	
 		are you
 		are you close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah we're just uh uh out skirts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah uh we uh in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> was right on uh the benches of the mountains
 		so i was it was really pretty all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		sure enjoy i i don't know if i could ever move away
 	
 	
 		did you ski
 	
 	
 		of course yeah you i i haven't uh actually the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of years</TIMEX> i haven't been able to as much because
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh out of school but uh
 		i i did a lot when i was in high school and stuff when i didn't have to spend the time studying and working and supporting a family but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i love it you yourself
 	
 	
 		oh yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		yeah you don't get as much of a chance down there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> do you  i would think
 	
 	
 		no
 		
 
 		i regret it too i i really wanna
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'd like to go this year
 		we were supposed to go on a ski trip but that's one that's one thing i would recommend too because you know
 	
 	
 		go up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> or
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		most college you go to a college and you make what you what you uh what you can out of it you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when you get out then you know you're you basically promote yourself and you try and network into a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> or or get a job or start a business or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you just can't trade the
 		the the time you know that you spend in the mountains you know if you if you <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and hunt or whatever and ski
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know i i'd never give up that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they offer i mean anymore they offer cook there's a you know we have uh we had a mountain climbing class we had you know we had a ski class
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there was all kind of that stuff that was offered as you know electives and those were i mean those were the funniest ones i mean
 	
 	
 		right
 		sure
 	
 	
 		that made up for all the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> or you know the science classes you had to take but uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah that was what made it like i say made it worthwhile and
 		at least kept you going to school on a semi regular basis i know it was pretty tough come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> or in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> or especially when it was so cold <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> if you didn't have a reason like a ski class you never went
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it just wasn't worth it so
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but yeah i uh
 		i'm convinced that after getting me my undergraduate degree i would like to go to a big name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> degree but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they're so expensive i'm not anymore i i almost think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just require they require a graduate degree or an undergraduate degree they don't necessarily care where from and if you wanna set yourself apart you have to go get that big graduate degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> or some place like that
 	
 	
 		yeah they do
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		or else it you know you're just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Blow</ENAMEX> off the street nobody knows but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		what'd you get your degree in
 	
 	
 		uh business administration
 	
 	
 		oh did you did you have an emphasis in anything or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		emphasis in finance
 	
 	
 		oh did you that's what i got <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> in was in finance yeah so where you're working at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">now</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		really
 		i'm at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> by the name of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E Systems</ENAMEX> we're a defense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> down here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really are you  an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> for them or
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm a scheduling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really great
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm a little out of my field of what i wanna be i'm an  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> for a credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		it's not something i wanna do for very long
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		is there a lot of
 	
 	
 		we're kind of the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> it's kind of a negative type thing but
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> up there or
 	
 	
 		uh not not a lot of private
 		ah there i mean there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> but they're not really large enough they're mainly there's a lot of family type <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and just small <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten fifteen</NUMEX> people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we uh  pretty much are
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> plays a big part in our economy and
 	
 	
 		for what reason how do they do that
 	
 	
 		well we got we have uh
 		
 		
 	