
 
     		
 	
 		what kind of hobbies do you find yourself involved with
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i find myself involved in um singing with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> at the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> college
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and also embroidering and especially cooking i like to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and uh have been in charge of various events
 		and sometimes i embroider when i have really a bit of spare time
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		now it seems you're interested in woodworking
 		what kind of woodworking do you do
 	
 	
 		ah uh woodworking um very little actually uh
 	
 	
 		uh oh
 	
 	
 		no um
 	
 	
 		i thought that's what they said um-hum
 	
 	
 		oh no they they uh they they suggested a variety of possibilities and of whatever hobbies hobbies you can come up with uh no uh
 	
 	
 		oh i see um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my hobbies kind of vary from time to time depending on what kind of time i've got uh i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> as an auto mechanic
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and i enjoy working with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> uh i've built a couple of race <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh you have
 	
 	
 		uh yeah um
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		also i do enjoy woodworking uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> cabinet cabinetry type woodworking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		i've done some model <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		different things like that um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		right now hobbies pretty much tend to be on hold
 		with a twelve week old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh my uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full time</TIMEX> student hobbies are a extreme luxury
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you say you say you uh sing with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in a community college
 	
 	
 		uh yes um
 	
 	
 		what sort of music do you work with
 	
 	
 		well we we work with show music and with uh opera arias and actually we're very fortunate to have a um
 		former opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> who is relocated to
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and uh she has taken over the the vocal music <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and uh she both gives private lessons and has um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a variety of classes especially on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> that are interested and what i found i've been going over there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three or four years</TIMEX> now
 		and what we found is that there winds up being a core <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of us that um keep on coming back
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh we give performances at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and at the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Botanical Gardens</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> time and at various retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and things of that nature
 	
 	
 		that sounds like a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		and you can um select whatever things you want to work on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the semester</TIMEX> and she'll help you with them and give you um lots of good points and uh it it's a very
 		enjoyable group uh it's not um overly formal that you have to worry it's not professional but it's good and i enjoy it very much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		those are usually the best sorts
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i you you say show music like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> musical type show music
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh i've i've personally done some things from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX> and from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Fair Lady</ENAMEX> you know things like that um
 	
 	
 		okay
 		hum
 		those are wonderful shows
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and uh some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really are just very
 		fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> we kind of enjoy one another
 		so uh and and when we go out to those retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> or the nursing homes
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very very appreciative which also makes you very happy that you're able to kind of pick up somebody else's life also so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 		yeah well the the chances are these are all all things they're very familiar with and just the chance to have some entertainment and some some variety in their life
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 		yes
 	
 	
 		at at retirement homes i mean even still there are variety there there're a lot of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> that try to make it sound like it's a real you know luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominium</ENAMEX> setup but still the you know the bulk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living there tend to be living pretty restricted lives
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so something like that can be a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i really uh that's really what we have found and also um a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very knowledgeable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh in in the field of music they're just very knowledgeable about a lot of things and they'll come and talk to you afterwards and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you better know your onions  but uh it it is something i do enjoy very much so and the other thing i like to do is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		uh cook i have um uh
 		uh planned uh menus for various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i was asked to take care of uh several luncheons and dinners up at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s school
 		and the next thing that we're getting ready for is a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> luncheon and we're gonna give them <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds
 		
 		
 	