
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> okay so you were with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i've been with i was with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh TI</ENAMEX> for uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty four years</TIMEX> so obviously i found something worth worth doing there and have prejudices about uh what i want
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well any stay any place that long they got to be doing something right right
 	
 	
 		yeah uh where do you work
 	
 	
 		i uh work for myself i sell uh metal fabricating equipment and tooling and uh uh
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAD CAM</ENAMEX> systems and things like that and uh consequently i can't really discuss big time benefits at the moment although i had worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Univac</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitney Bowes</ENAMEX> and some big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> once upon a time
 		and uh i think most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't necessarily realize the cost of them and they're somewhat probably getting out of hand
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah they uh
 		i'm not sure what the category's supposed to be uh but it was what
 		something about what benefits would you consider something like that when you uh go to work for a large company
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i think uh
 		oh the way i got
 	
 	
 		other other than salary didn't it say yeah
 	
 	
 		right well no it didn't necessarily say other than salary but what would you consider to be kind of important i guess
 	
 	
 		well i'm i thought it said other than salary but yeah
 	
 	
 		such as
 		well i i imagine that's what they're referring to you know like uh your health insurance and pensions and all that kind of good stuff uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		well i uh personally i left my previous job which was with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chance-Vought</ENAMEX> before i joined uh
 		there and ironically i left Chance-Vought the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas County</ENAMEX> at that time with some
 		thirty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as i recall and uh joined a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> because i wanted to go with a small company
 	
 	
 		and they grew up around you didn't it
 	
 	
 		and uh that was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty five hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when i joined and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then it became <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas County</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> oh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh one reason i left where i was it definitely had to do with what i wanted uh  besides what i was getting and it had to do with uh
 		wanting to do research and in other words i wanted to enjoy the job and have the freedom to do the job
 	
 	
 		well i think that's one of the keys that most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh probably put above benefits that's why i work for myself basically too i want to do what i wanna do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i participated on many uh surveys and that sort of thing i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI fellow</ENAMEX> so i was down on you know on the technical ladder side rather than the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		heavy management although i was a branch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 		and  it's amazing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> in general just would not believe the survey results because to them
 		uh money is the motivation and uh benefits you know stock options uh perks that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and power and they they just couldn't understand why with the technical surveys that were done by the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of Electrical Engineers</ENAMEX> and uh others
 		uh including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>'s that in the technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> salary was never first  it was usually <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about third</NUMEX> and  yeah
 	
 	
 		well i think as long as it's comparable with you know the job or can
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that uh you aren't being  picked on in the sense of being the whipping boy dollar wise in the corporation you you know you know you got to i
 	
 	
 		right number one and number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> usually were uh number one was usually uh enjoyable work or work that i enjoy something of that sort
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> was freedom to do that work normally and uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> or even <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> sometimes  was the salary
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		and that was in virtually every technical uh ladder survey that was taken over the
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		oh fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">or so years</TIMEX> that i participated but invariably the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> would challenge this you know because because they just couldn't believe that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> weren't motivated by money
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		well i i wouldn't say they aren't motivated by money but i would say that there are other things that are
 		equal or greater important i i guess if you make enough money uh if the money were really big bucks i guess some of these other things you could uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'm sure you know if you were being paid a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> labor scale obviously money would be high up on the list but
 	
 	
 		live with for a while anyway until you had enough to do what you wanted to do but
 		yes
 	
 	
 		in a competitive uh market as it was most of the time when i was in where you could get you could get a job elsewhere anytime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day of the week</TIMEX> you wanted to go until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the last two years</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		in that case you felt more secure uh money wise so that you could seek uh enjoyable work or creative work that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	