
 
     		
 	
 		so i've been concerned about crime lately um it's really scary to listen to the news <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> and  to hear about all the problems i wondered if you were taking any special precautions in your neighborhood
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i i think we have a neighborhood watch i think i'm not real we don't get real involved we're never home so  um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh well i know they were gonna start one but uh i haven't heard any more since so i don't really know but as far as personally doing something no
 	
 	
 		no hm
 	
 	
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		well  we moved in when we moved in there there wasn't any outside lights and so we've been trying to install some
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um outside lights and  we put up a fence in the backyard mostly you know not so much thinking that we would deter someone to break in but that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> would be safe playing in the yard you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah huh
 	
 	
 		and i guess most of the crime that i'm concerned about generally is against my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it's scary to send them off down the street a few houses
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure it is
 	
 	
 		to let them go play with someone and because of what you hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting picked up and everything and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i have to spend a good deal of time watching them  walk down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and say call me before you leave and come back and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh i would too if i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we don't have any  we did install a um  a uh motion detector light back in our driveway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that was  mainly it was so when we pulled up the light would come on but also we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> back there  and we have neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that like to get into mischief so we thought with that light you know it would
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		maybe keep them from doing something to the boat  yeah so
 	
 	
 		then that's a good thought
 		well we've been real lucky that i don't believe there's been you know much trouble in our neighborhood but it but it does seem there that there is a lot more here in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> of um just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		bored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX>  vandalism
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's what it is we live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Coppell</ENAMEX> and and that's pretty much what it is is you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are bored like you say
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah and they don't uh i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> who lives in our neighborhood they've had their they've parked their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> before and it's been spray painted and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		a few things like that and course you know  i don't know  i'm getting scared for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to get older because you don't know if it's someone their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> know  who and or is it just random
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		crime but um we've been real lucky that no one in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> with the anywhere that they live has had been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of you know a serious crime
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh it's really scary to know that you you can live a normal life and try to be a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> but it doesn't mean you'll be safe and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh i know it hm
 	
 	
 		but i guess i take a lot of  um little bit of um
 		
 
 		safety in knowing that a lot of the crimes that they report are like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> related or  um things that places usually that i wouldn't be going  and things i usually wouldn't be involved in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah huh
 	
 	
 		and uh there's not so much of it completely innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> compared to but it is scary
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it is it really is
 	
 	
 		were you raised in this area
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> but i've been in this area in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> area for  uh let's see about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so has it been getting worse that you've noticed or about the same hm
 	
 	
 		oh definitely  in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> i think and uh
 		like i say now i don't think necessarily in this area here but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> in general i don't know i think back of when i was uh younger and in my party <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> some of those things
 		i did you know i wouldn't be caught dead like being out that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX>  in a dark parking lot  so
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		take a lot of chances well i noticed that um
 		that uh when we we moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> not too long ago and so of course we were interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> all have big tall fences around them and they're not really very safe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so it's been interesting to come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Plano</ENAMEX> area where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> don't have fences at all  around them and  it's just a whole different idea that that at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here feel that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are pretty safe at school
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> that there was the mentality that they weren't safe at school
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and so that's been something that's been good for the  you know in this area that you feel like um you know there's not going to be too many knifings or shootings at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">school</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>  and i guess i don't know how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live with that everyday
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		i don't either
 	
 	
 		pretty scary
 	
 	
 		yeah hm
 	
 	
 		but anyway well i guess i won't take up more of your time
 	
 	
 		hm
 		
 		
 	