
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh do you cook quite a bit
 	
 	
 		uh not really actually uh i live by myself and so most of my cooking is pretty basic you know just for myself but i cook when i go home my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> doesn't like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> so
 		i cook all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meals</ENAMEX> when i go home and that's about the only opportunity i like to but i just you know
 	
 	
 		that's good practice though
 	
 	
 		hard to get motivated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> for yourself
 	
 	
 		i know when i was single it was uh i wouldn't cook much of anything i think <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> i sauteed a pound of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mushrooms</ENAMEX> and that was dinner
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh well right now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i live in uh uh subdivision that we have a dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> thingy
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and what we do is once a month we'll meet at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> will prepare the entree and provide the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> and then every one else brings something
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and then it rotates from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month to month</TIMEX> you get together with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> so you only host <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		that's pretty nice
 	
 	
 		it is really nice but uh
 	
 	
 		well what kind of things do you usually have i mean do you do you usually have like
 		you know ethnic food do you try a different thing every time or
 	
 	
 		well
 		we haven't but i think that'd be great you know do <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> one time or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> the next time thinking the next one we get into that i'll do that
 		but basically the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> so far have just been picking you know what we have and then they'll let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know and they'll uh uh ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to bring something to compliment it but personally i like to prepare something that i could have done ahead of time
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		because i can't talk and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> at the same time uh if i tried you know i i leave ingredients out  but uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		we're suppose to be hosting next time i'm thinking of about having beef <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">stroganoff</ENAMEX> because i can do that ahead of time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> does that and freezes it a lot of times
 	
 	
 		and
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now now is this one of the dishes that you cook
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s bailiwick
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's really simple so don't don't let it uh
 	
 	
 		i was going to say i kind of i do not know i do
 		odd things i guess
 	
 	
 		what do you cook when you go home
 	
 	
 		um i guess last time i was home was at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and i cooked um
 		i bought some really good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> tenderloin at um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Snider Plaza</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i had i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have a deep freeze so i bought like oh God i want to say it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> pounds and put it in the deep freeze and so i cooked one of them you know and
 		basically have you ever used that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DV sauce</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no what is it
 	
 	
 		it's like um
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef enhancer</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean it might not i i haven't really looked at the ingredients and it may be one of those things where if if
 		it may have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSG</ENAMEX> in it i really haven't really looked i do not think it does but it might but
 	
 	
 		that doesn't bother me anyway so
 	
 	
 		uh you know i kind of like sprinkle some of that on it  and then take like
 		you know pieces of cloves of garlic and sort of push them down into the meat
 	
 	
 		oh you sound like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> he's a garlic freak too
 	
 	
 		and then yeah and then bake it you know and it it always turns out really good i mean course you know the better the the the quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> the better it turns out but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and if you can leave it out on the counter for a little bit and you know to soak in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the garlic</TIMEX> and everything you know that works pretty well but you know that's kind of that's kind of basic and i can do some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and junk like that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you uh stir fry
 	
 	
 		some sometimes um i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but i loaned it to somebody and they never gave it back
 	
 	
 		do you have a wok
 		well i'd call them up
 	
 	
 		so i kind of just use a skillet really
 	
 	
 		probably works just as well
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that's something you know we don't do all that often and every time we do it i think why don't we cook this way more often because it is healthy you get a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure</ENAMEX> and the easy see now that would be an easy thing to do for the dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> because you could do that in advance you know you i would just get like um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you could use do <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> either one and you know kind of chop it up into <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about inch</NUMEX> cubes you know and the marinade i think that is like um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh like a cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> tablespoons of
 	
 	
 		soy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">soy</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> tablespoon of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perrins</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Worcestershire Worcestershire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> or whatever <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> i can't pronounce it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i always call it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perrins</ENAMEX> because i can't say the name of it and uh garlic and chopped green onions and then you know chop up all of your meat like the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> before and stick it in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tupperware dish</ENAMEX> with the
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know with the stuff and let it marinade over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and then just strain out you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> and um
 		you know then then you know stir fry the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> and um you can get the cans of sliced water chestnuts and bamboo shoots and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you can put mushroom
 		
 		
 	