
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i suppose we both have credit cards
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah they seem to be a part of life
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah how do you use them
 	
 	
 		well i do use them um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have a few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> that i use more than others and uh i try to keep my balances fairly reasonable i i could probably pay them off any month if i wanted to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		but occasionally they can get out of hand and get higher when when you start using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a few</NUMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they all can build up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think they're handy i just get
 		uh i don't carry a lot of cash with me and uh i hate writing checks
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when you go shopping
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well do you use credit cards
 	
 	
 		yeah i use a few i um
 		i watched my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> go into debt  on them and so i've and then i guess my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> yeah so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> learned from that and i guess she taught me to be very very careful with them so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		basically um i just keep them i use them so that i build up a credit rating you know but otherwise um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i generally and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> it turns out i've just been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> but he has the same habit and we just keep a few you know few of the major ones and then use them once in a while for something but we always pay it off right that month
 	
 	
 		that's good
 		oh that's that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		so that way we keep any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> charge so that way we keep out of debt and we keep on top of what we're spending
 	
 	
 		well the interest rates in credit cards is so high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> compared to what you're savings is bringing it's really i guess ridiculous to let them keep building
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah that's what i feel
 	
 	
 		but i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can get get you know carried away with them and let them get out of hand
 	
 	
 		so
 		um-hum it's really easy just to forget you know that you you charged that or charged that i try to keep all my receipts and keep them in someplace where i know that the bill's going to come but sometimes i forget and
 		so you know  a bill will come in and i'll think oh no i didn't know it was going to be that high but so far i've been able to we've been able to pay it off every time so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um yeah
 		well that's good i'm looking right now i'm kind kind of looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> that has a lower interest rate it seems that some of them have gotten higher
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i saw on TV they had a program on uh credit cards and they're supposed to i don't know if it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> or some some other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> had a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> card that was the lowest one in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and i didn't write it down at the time and then i went and looked and to see what my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> was and i think it's eighteen percent or something so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		think i want to find something that has a lower rate
 	
 	
 		yeah have you ever used <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> card
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not even sure what their interest rate is since i pay it off but you know
 	
 	
 		is is that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> originally put it out but it's um it's pretty well taken all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> now i mean uh i've haven't found many places that don't take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and there's no annual service fee which is good you know and then um
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		they also give you they say cash back um like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end of the year</TIMEX> for the amount that i charge i get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dollars back or something but if you use credit cards a lot you probably get more back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh oh</ENAMEX>
 		oh they give you money back for using your credit card
 	
 	
 		yeah basically that's it yeah basically that's it and i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> charge is pretty low too but i'm not sure
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't know that
 		hum well you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> was one of the few department <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> that never would take any other credit cards
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i worked with at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> for over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and uh it was only a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> card that they would take
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		until i guess they decided to join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and come up with their own credit card another credit card that was accepted so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know now they'll take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> but i still don't know if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> will take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i never did apply for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> card i just figure with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Express</ENAMEX> i probably have an i can do enough damage with those two
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's best to keep the number down  that you have
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i've got some that i you know i haven't even used at all uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past few years</TIMEX> i probably wouldn't be able to use them
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh i i do like my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillard</ENAMEX>'s i have to admit that's one of my favorite places to shop
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i do do use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillard</ENAMEX>'s probably as more than any of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> stores
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well do you have anything else to say or
 	
 	
 		well yes no not too much more about credit cards
 	
 	
 		okay i don't think i do either so well it was good talking to you
 	
 	
 		okay well
 		good talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay have a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		good luck
 		you too bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	