
 
     		
 	
 		okay it's pressed are you still there okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm ready
 	
 	
 		so what's uh things that you look for when you go out to dinner
 	
 	
 		oh i just like a nice quiet nice atmosphere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that's always that's always a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> but just a nice quiet easy place maybe candlelight something
 	
 	
 		um
 		um that sounds pretty
 	
 	
 		just to relax you know because i don't really go out to dinner that much so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum well we don't go out to dinner that much either we try to get out maybe like once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> or something like that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i definitely want to go to a place that's nice and clean you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um i've been to some that's been terrible you know you see <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cockroaches crawling</ENAMEX> around and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		everything you know but i try to get one that's nice and clean and then i like to you know good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and good service
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah where you don't feel rushed you know and you can just relax and stay as long as you want and
 	
 	
 		yeah right right right
 		so is there some nice places to go to eat in Plano
 	
 	
 		well nearby we're almost in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> we're just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we have quite a bit between us and there it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> miles
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there is all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and
 		i had one that was a favorite for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and then it changed hands and doubled the prices and then it finally went out of business
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so but it was really nice it had a fireplace and
 	
 	
 		um that sounds beautiful
 	
 	
 		yeah it was really nice they had entertainment sometimes and you you could just really relax there and enjoy it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum um-hum well  this is only a little small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> um we have uh
 	
 	
 		but it's gone
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 		i didn't think my coughing would come back
 		anyhow we have only like one uh
 		restaurant that's kind of nice you know they have prime rib on uh weekends
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then then they have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about six miles</NUMEX> from here is called a little city called Wesley
 		and they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wesley Hotel</ENAMEX> there that they serve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and the atmosphere there is really really nice
 	
 	
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		so and then if we really want to you know something different then we go to Modesto which is like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes</TIMEX> away
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh we don't have any fast foods here in this small city
 	
 	
 		that's probably very fortunate for you do you have kids
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> well i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> but he's grown up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh because i have a twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> that would eat a happy <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">meal every night</TIMEX> you know and now she's graduated to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> cheeseburgers so something's happened here but but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> is definitely at the top of her list and i hate these places
 	
 	
 		yeah all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> seem to love <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> don't they you know
 	
 	
 		so uh-huh they do and i don't think there's an ounce of nutritional value in  anything they have so
 	
 	
 		no no i'm sure there isn't
 	
 	
 		so we have all kinds of fast foods everywhere around and it's really it's tempting when you come home from work and you're tired and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you just are tempted to give in to that and it costs a lot of money to do it too you know it adds up and it's not healthy and
 	
 	
 		i know it's
 	
 	
 		i i really got into that habit for a while but i got out of it again because i just felt like it was just too unhealthy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well let's see what else can we talk about
 	
 	
 		well how's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> today
 	
 	
 		oh it's foggy and cold here
 	
 	
 		is it that's what i've heard yeah
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum yeah it's
 	
 	
 		yeah have you always lived there
 	
 	
 		i came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> when i was sixteen
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i've lived out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> for a long long time yeah i like it real well
 	
 	
 		and you like it
 		yeah we've been
 	
 	
 		we used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> so we used to have a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> to go to there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but uh then i quit work and everything and i moved bought a house i had a condo in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> so right in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chinatown</ENAMEX> so we went to a lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that would be fun
 	
 	
 		and they were really good i really miss them
 	
 	
 		yeah do you miss living there
 	
 	
 		you know
 		uh no i really don't miss living there i just like to go in there and have a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> dinner once in a while you know
 	
 	
 		no
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um as far as missing living there no it's close enough if i wanted to go there to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> for dinner or something why you know
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and fifteen minutes</TIMEX> we could be there and you know have dinner and then come on back but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i go all the time
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah well i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in college there and she um is world champion twirler
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> so she went there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so i went out a lot with her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh yeah i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> pretty well and i love it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i guess
 	
 	
 		and we tug back and forth who's gonna move
 		but i think he's gonna move because i'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with more to lose here i have my twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> in school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she's happy she's always lived here in the south and i've had my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've too much to lose
 		
 		
 	