
 
     		
 	
 		what are your favorite TV shows
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um  i guess one of my favorite ones is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i always liked that one they're always so funny and i also like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cosby Show</ENAMEX>  those are probably my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> favorites
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah i i i rather enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby Show</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i both like Commish
 	
 	
 		you know i've watched that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and it was really good but now that's on what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> it's either <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> um around here at least
 	
 	
 		is it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
 		uh-huh i can't i can't remember
 	
 	
 		i guess it depends on what channel you're getting you know what system you're getting it through
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah  i yeah i saw it one time and i really liked it but i just haven't uh seen it you know watched it since
 	
 	
 		uh we we always enjoyed it it it seems to be kind of halfway between um
 		something like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All In The Family and uh Hill Street Blues</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it's it's it's it's a good show
 	
 	
 		yeah the episode that i watched um
 		i liked him because even though he's a law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> you know sometimes the laws are kind of ridiculous and you need to sometimes break them to get your point across and for a good reason
 	
 	
 		you tend
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and he seems to do that sometimes
 	
 	
 		he he tenderhearted fellow
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i i guess that's what <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> drew us to him the uh
 		the the relationship between he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> kind of looks a lot like ours
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought it was a pretty good show
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		i also like i i like to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">like Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twenty Twenty</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah um i don't know we uh
 		watch Commish any chance we get
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> used to be a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> but that's kind of they they it's gotten more and more to where they are so totally against um anything
 		spiritual
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		anyway
 	
 	
 		i've never  gotten into the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> era
 	
 	
 		yeah i i used to be a used to be a real big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		used to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trekkie</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		um pretty much yeah i always enjoyed the show anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek's</ENAMEX> in a set the uh Star Wars set
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the one of the first Star Wars movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think i watched it something like nineteen times
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness you must have some of the lines memorized
 	
 	
 		uh i did at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time  anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		wow
 	
 	
 		oh  a pretty big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of that sort of thing used to used to read a read a lot of science fiction work too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		no it
 		um
 		we don't do a whole lot of TV watching but that uh i don't know if you heard him or not they got a twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> twelve week old baby
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX> week oh i was gonna say i hear a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> in the background
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that between that and school it's not between him and school there's not much time left for watching much TV
 	
 	
 		i imagine that keeps you busy
 		yeah
 		well we're we're expecting our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three months</TIMEX> so i know we won't be watching as much as we do now
 	
 	
 		yeah this one here is our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and and we're both full time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that must be tough
 	
 	
 		what are you hoping for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> or a girl
 	
 	
 		it doesn't matter just a healthy baby
 	
 	
 		that that's that's the best way you you haven't found out yet or anything have you
 	
 	
 		well we had a sonogram but we told him not to tell us so it's gonna be a surprise
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's the best way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it's like finding out somewhere in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> what you're gonna get for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> i mean you know it's it's it's not as much fun oh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's not quite the same
 		yeah  i agree  i'm sure we'll be watching more uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> oriented television shows
 	
 	
 		anyway
 		yeah
 		oh i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> heart anyway
 	
 	
 		oh i am too i still watch cartoons sometimes every once in a while  when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> comes to visit so
 	
 	
 		i i
 		well
 		the new cartoons don't seem to be worth much but the uh well a couple of the uh ones <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s doing aren't too bad but
 	
 	
 		well you know it seems like a lot of them are a lot more violent than they used to be
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i remember like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flintstones</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jetsons</ENAMEX> and those were just kind of good old cartoons
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		the the the worst of the violence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flintstones</ENAMEX> was when somebody gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX> a poke in the snoot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but oh shoot i mean blowing up galaxies and and putting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> on the whole planet or or or you know or on all the you know everything of this species you know just all kinds of crud
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah and they wonder why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> turn out the way they do nowadays
 	
 	
 		yeah everything's mutations and and and killing and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		gone are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of those things they use what was it i uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNT</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner Broadcasting Network</ENAMEX> used to
 		used to uh do the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> cartoons <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old</TIMEX> cartoons they used to put between the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> feazure feature at the theatre
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		those old <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">little ten minute</TIMEX> jobs where the uh the real ballooned looking art work you know and and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	