
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> you live
 	
 	
 		uh it's near National it's near uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i was down that way once but i don't think i remember that is it on the coast
 	
 	
 		yeah it's just a little rinky-dink <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> but
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't go there it's really not a good neighborhood
 	
 	
 		i went all the way down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial Beach</ENAMEX> once that's far as i went
 	
 	
 		yeah it's nicer down there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		unfortunately i need to be near near the naval <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX> so
 		my choice of living <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> is limited  so um are you ready to begin
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i guess we're gonna talk about camping is that right
 	
 	
 		right
 		okay i'll push the button hang on
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all right there we go
 		so do you go camping at all
 	
 	
 		well yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i like to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp um</ENAMEX> usually just on short trips like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long</TIMEX> weekend
 		and we generally go to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> or National parks
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i like going for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the long weekends</TIMEX> we usually like going up to one of the camping grounds that have a lake near it
 		because we like to fish and camp
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah well we don't really care for fishing anything that that resembles work uh  so we just uh what we do is hike and take pictures that's about all
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i i like hiking unfortunately around here there's not too many spots to do stuff like that
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has a pretty nice system of state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> we've got um state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> just all over the place on different kinds of terrain and most of them
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> and they've got a lot of it there too
 		they've also got desert desert uh i don't know what you call it but
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		sites in the desert they have a special name for it
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has every thing from desert to uh swamp so i don't think they have too many
 	
 	
 		i don't think i'd like the swamp but mountains and deserts
 	
 	
 		they don't have too many swamps in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> i don't think  i don't think i've uh seen too many swamps in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		no it's pretty much dry
 	
 	
 		now we may do some camping camping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> though i've got uh my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> all live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sedonia</ENAMEX> now Sedonia yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really do you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayer</ENAMEX>'s at
 	
 	
 		what is it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayer</ENAMEX> outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prescott</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayer</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i think i remember going through there is that between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prescott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome</ENAMEX> or over the other way
 	
 	
 		over the other way it's actually if you blinked you'd miss it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well it be
 		yeah i think i do remember a little wide place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayer</ENAMEX> well anyway they uh everybody there says that you know there are places you can camp uh right around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sedonia</ENAMEX> there are
 	
 	
 		oh there's a lot of beautiful camping places around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sedonia</ENAMEX> and they're getting they're getting more of them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're just doing it slowly but surely
 		but um i like the rustic kind of camping
 	
 	
 		yeah well we we do we like actually we like to get off uh where there aren't too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we did find a nice uh prospect uh down on the gulf
 		um there's a uh national wildlife wildlife refuge called Urandus i don't know if you've heard of it that's where the whooping cranes go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> or at least where a lot of them go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh there's and island right off that called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Matagorda</ENAMEX> and uh you can take a ferry <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> out there and it's uh completely uh pretty much anyway complete wilderness island
 	
 	
 		oh that'd be neat
 	
 	
 		sort of like a big sand bar you know you wanna make sure there aren't any big storms coming
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		but uh then you can uh take a uh take a little bus across the island to the to the gulf side rather than the bay side and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's really nice out there lots of sea birds
 	
 	
 		that sounds like it'd be nice
 		yeah unfortunately my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i haven't been able to go camping because i just had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		all at once or all at once
 	
 	
 		huh
 		well no no i spaced them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX> a part
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but until they get a little bit older we really don't want to take them out camping with us
 	
 	
 		that could be difficult i've seen a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> camping but uh didn't look like any of them were really enjoying the experience very much
 	
 	
 		yeah  when i go camping i like to get out and hike and do things and when you have little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you really can't do that very much
 	
 	
 		yeah well i sort of like to feel less tied down rather than more tied down when i go camping and
 	
 	
 		right that's the object of it you know get out and feel free and do things you don't normally get to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um yeah we haven't got to go lately but when we go we we're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> so when we go back on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation next year</TIMEX> we'll get to go
 		which should be nice
 	
 	
 		well i really like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> i like uh uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last year</TIMEX> i've made it up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome</ENAMEX> just to enjoy the altitude and everything and it's really
 		neat up there somehow
 	
 	
 		it is actually
 	
 	
 		i met the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> historian
 		
 		
 	