
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay have you ever
 	
 	
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> have reunions on any regular basis
 	
 	
 		probably once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah um you have a pretty big family
 	
 	
 		yeah and the hardest part about getting the family the stuff together is everyone's spread out all over Timbuktu
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and you
 	
 	
 		yeah we've got a pretty big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but most of us live well i'm well i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is right in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> area uh what they call the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tristate</ENAMEX> area uh northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia Eastern Ohio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern Southwestern Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		most everybody is right in that area
 	
 	
 		that makes it a lot easier a lot more convenient that's why we only do it once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or ten years</TIMEX> because it's like that hard to get everyone together
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> together for our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> about once every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> it was on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s birthday but she's
 		she's gone now
 	
 	
 		yeah see that's kind of what happened with ours that's why we hadn't had one in a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		so so to make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> successful what i mean what do y'all do do y'all just start planning real far ahead of time
 	
 	
 		oh shoot
 		pardon
 	
 	
 		do you um do y'all start planning real far ahead of time
 	
 	
 		well no there's kind of a set pattern to it there's uh so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> it happens is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety eight percent</NUMEX> of the planning usually
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah oh the we get together at the the uh the park uh
 		the uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">park</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> area of the church i was raised in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		everybody brings lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and
 		we'll put up a volleyball net
 		just sit around and tell stories and catch up and
 		play volleyball <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and get really fat
 	
 	
 		eat a lot see it's a lot harder for us because we're like i say we're spread out so they have to plan anywhere from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> really probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> ahead of time so everyone can say um
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 		yeah
 		scheduled vacation time
 	
 	
 		their their vacation time
 	
 	
 		yeah we usually just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday Saturday</TIMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or maybe sometimes it's been like on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> usually it's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have more than you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple hours</TIMEX> drive tops to get there and back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		now is that where you're i mean is
 	
 	
 		well where i'm calling from is southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> so we got a ways uh uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i have a bit longer ways to go than most
 	
 	
 		but y'all still manage to make them
 	
 	
 		uh actually we've only made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them since we got married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years ago</TIMEX> one of the family reunions but we're both in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so it makes it kind of tough
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they usually they been happening um
 		just after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer semester</TIMEX> starts
 	
 	
 		you can't really get away
 	
 	
 		so usually not we managed to get to one that was before i started to school and she took that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> off
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well now that we've been talking about it i'm gonna i'm kind of getting home sick now  because it's been over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> since i've been home
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		yeah oh goodness
 	
 	
 		to see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> or well my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX>'s the only one that's still around
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was the one that used to plan the stuff basically
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so unless the aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> really get on the ball and put stuff together it's kind of like she was like the glue so
 	
 	
 		yeah i understand
 		where is home for you
 	
 	
 		originally um i was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so and you know we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> scattered out all over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana Mississippi</ENAMEX>
 		um here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so it's harder for everyone to get in get home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> you can find a more central location
 	
 	
 		now well but see the majority of them are in like just like how you said in close close <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">quarters</ENAMEX> so it's easier for us few stragglers to go home
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay the majority of them are still in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> right now or most there's there's there's only like few stragglers
 		uh if any with any distance yeah some of us there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and
 		uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>
 		uh i got a sister over in in uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		uh rest of them are within you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple hours</TIMEX> drive
 	
 	
 		well um how do y'all communicate like to plan it and everything do y'all just call each other up on the phone and say this is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> we're gonna do it or do y'all like mail out stuff
 	
 	
 		that's pretty much it yeah okay it's gonna be such and such a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> and uh y'all come  that's about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean you know this is the standard pattern is the
 		everybody brings their their favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> and
 		somebody brings the volleyball net somebody brings a whole lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> for the watermelon and
 	
 	
 		well um
 		i guess probably the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i went to i met so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i hadn't seen in probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> it was like don't you remember me and i'm like no
 	
 	
 		am i related to you yeah i married your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> uh something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i know
 		
 
 		do you i mean is that since you i mean do you have them every year
 	
 	
 		uh yeah they're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and and still you wind up meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you you you never knew you were related to let alone
 	
 	
 		well see it's probably not that
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i think that's probably why our's always so interesting is because we don't have them that often and then when we do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and everyone does finally get together it's like after the you know the just like
 	
 	
 		down right amazing isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	