
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> right yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> what
 	
 	
 		it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and you're Bob
 	
 	
 		i'm Bob
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i've been uh
 		thinking about the topic and i think it's uh
 		responds to the tremendous
 		i guess over load in
 		uh cases they say that these drug cases
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		alone are swamping the criminal justice system
 	
 	
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> world doesn't do a lot of the things i like but they don't have too many repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders offenders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and murder and a few other things
 		you steal they cut off the hand you steal again they cut off both hands it takes care of it quick
 	
 	
 		i've
 		i've heard that i've heard that uh
 	
 	
 		it takes care of it quick
 	
 	
 		yeah i've even heard that the other end of the continuum some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> who are arguing that uh because the system is so over loaded that
 		uh they recommend decriminalizing some of these things because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> can't possibly handle all the cases
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> wrongs don't make a right
 	
 	
 		i think its going to be very interesting because its uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's really become a major expense for us as a society
 	
 	
 		yeah in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh some private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprise</ENAMEX> built a few <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and with with the hope that the over flow from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> would kind of get to them
 		but uh see the evidently the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">counties</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are too scared to use them because of the expense but uh they're having trouble now paying their bills because they're not getting any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well you know the other
 	
 	
 		i don't understand that
 	
 	
 		the other thing that i think is interesting about this is that they've been experimenting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in the civil justice system with alternatives to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> where you can rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and i'm wondering whether we'll eventually go to renting a jury
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and finding ways uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The People's Court</ENAMEX> to try some of these cases
 		i think uh the expense is is enormous have you ever sat on a jury
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> i sat on a rape trial and we let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> off wasn't enough evidence although i'm sure he did it
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's uh
 		it's it's a major undertaking i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to give up their work and and a lot of their time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i i just think it can overwhelm us pretty easily uh when i hear what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are saying about just the sheer volume of the cases
 	
 	
 		i think you need to get tough with them and quit calling them i don't think they need air conditioned cells and color TV sets they need to be put on hard labor manual
 		and as tough as you can make it no coddling no kissing their and nothing nothing just say hey you committed a wrong and you're going to serve some hard hard time
 	
 	
 		well there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who think that that works pretty well and it'll be interesting to see what uh what we go to because it's uh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		it's push come to shove time as far as i can tell in terms of the sheer volume of this stuff
 	
 	
 		there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> you have a linteresting place called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Delancy Street House</ENAMEX> have you heard of it
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah it's well known and and it's consistent with what you're talking about in terms of the uh approach to uh the uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> once they get through the trials and i guess
 		you know we're going to see more and more of this kind of thing i think the jury trial system
 		um
 		it's gonna to be interesting to see whether or not it becomes more streamlined uh because of the cost involved in that the uh
 		the topic is an interesting one because of the um
 		uh the price you pay for freedom i guess
 		you know the the requirement that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> be given a trial and and
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and then then the issue becomes what do you do once somebody's found guilty i suppose
 	
 	
 		we was talking to somebody <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> over there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> uh
 		they have a very low crime problem
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things they do to them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is they publish the name and address
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> convicted of a crime and there is such embarrassment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that they have to move out of the neighborhood and move to another part of the country
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well well our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> sense of family has eroded i'm afraid in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but
 		i don't think it'll work here but over there the the way they're doing it it seems to be effective
 	
 	
 		yeah have you uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh seen the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> ever print the names of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were uh uh uh picked up as johns uh in under cover operations
 	
 	
 		i've heard that i've heard that no i haven't
 	
 	
 		they they they've done that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and uh you know it's gonna be interesting to see how all these things change as as we look at the cost of it because
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 	
 	
 		um that the well there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who won in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris Wafford</ENAMEX> who said you know and and in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> everybody's entitled to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> but not everybody's entitled to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and we must spend
 		i don't know what the figure is but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jury</ENAMEX> trials are are just so expensive very very expensive and time consuming and uh so i think that that all of the these things that we're talking about are going to contribute to change and i don't know uh
 	
 	
 		terribly expensive yeah
 		
 		
 	