
 
		
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				
 				uh do you have kids
 			
 			
 				oh yeah i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> how about yourself
 			
 			
 				um we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the way
 			
 			
 				oh you've got uh young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> then
 			
 			
 				well we have yeah we do we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our six a six year old</TIMEX> he's oldest and then um our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> will be a year on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
 			
 			
 				oh my goodness that's great
 			
 			
 				yeah yeah
 			
 			
 				what kind of mix do you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> or
 			
 			
 				<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> two <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> yeah
 			
 			
 				<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> boys
 				you know what's on the way yet are you
 			
 			
 				no i i'm just about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> and um i don't think we really even wanna find out we like surprises so we'll take either
 			
 			
 				i don't blame you well
 				well
 				well we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> also well we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> well uh
 			
 			
 				and and does does it are the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> first
 			
 			
 				yes yes so maybe maybe maybe you'll get lucky and get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> this time
 			
 			
 				oh
 				maybe huh we we kind of like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> though too so
 			
 			
 				
 				
 				well our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> one is uh
 				he's in graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&M</ENAMEX> uh he's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> he's a lieutenant in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>'s sending him for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master's</ENAMEX> in ocean engineering and
 			
 			
 				oh my goodness
 			
 			
 				we got another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's uh out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> he's a wildlife <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> uh
 			
 			
 				oh
 			
 			
 				and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is thirteen she's in uh
 				<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade so we got
 				still all sorts of good activities with with her
 			
 			
 				oh yeah you've kind of got uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">span</ENAMEX> there huh oh well what do you do with your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				
 				well she's into a little bit of everything she's uh
 				loves riding horses so she goes out riding as much as she can and
 			
 			
 				do do you have horses
 			
 			
 				no  no
 			
 			
 				she just she knows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that does huh
 			
 			
 				well uh yeah but mainly at a riding place that's north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that she goes uh she rides <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and does jumping takes lesson and all that kind of stuff yeah
 			
 			
 				oh does she oh she must really like them
 			
 			
 				and
 				yeah she's into
 				oh she plays the flute in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">piccolo</ENAMEX> and she's into this uh odyssey of the mind thing which is uh takes a lot of time for
 				it's uh for
 				what they call pace group i don't know if you've gotten into that with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but that's for the
 				kind of
 				well it's a program for
 			
 			
 				<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advanced</ENAMEX>
 			
 			
 				higher the advanced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> yeah yeah
 			
 			
 				yeah yeah i have heard of that our little little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s just in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade and and i i taught school
 			
 			
 				sure
 				oh okay
 			
 			
 				for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> so i i do know about  that program and and
 			
 			
 				okay you know what that is
 				well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is involve she kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> that up for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 				<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> they they got uh the state level they didn't win that but they got won uh local and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">region</ENAMEX> and they got a new mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> this time so
 			
 			
 				oh uh-huh
 			
 			
 				keeps them busy keeps
 			
 			
 				oh yeah i bet huh well so does she go actually out into a different <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> with
 			
 			
 				
 				okay
 			
 			
 				with um other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are involved in this
 			
 			
 				well uh yes but uh well they have what they well you probably know a pace <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that uh
 				they're advanced type the they're special
 				uh classes for pace classes i think uh this happens to be uh
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				uh history is what their peace <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> but uh so they they uh
 			
 			
 				oh uh-huh
 			
 			
 				she enjoys that kind of stuff and does well with it so yeah
 			
 			
 				oh that's neat
 				challenging huh oh
 			
 			
 				yeah yeah always something to do
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				well um as far as our activities we're kind of on a different level here but my
 			
 			
 				well you'll get to different levels i guarantee you that
 			
 			
 				yeah yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s gonna take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our six year old</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster</ENAMEX> truck show <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>
 			
 			
 				uh okay
 			
 			
 				they they like to  both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> things  yeah
 			
 			
 				that'd be fun
 				oh yeah yeah
 			
 			
 				but uh we we don't have any real um like we don't really ski we haven't taken our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> skiing or anything course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s young but
 			
 			
 				got to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX>  sledding that's what you got to do tobogganing
 			
 			
 				yeah yeah he's
 				the what
 			
 			
 				you got to go tobogganing and sledding with them
 			
 			
 				uh oh well yeah we we have done that he in fact he just goes right out here we've got quite a bit of snow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and last week</TIMEX> we got a lot
 			
 			
 				well you're welcome to keep that
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 			
 				
 			
 			
 				you don't like that huh
 			
 			
 				well i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> i i had plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> and when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and
 			
 			
 				oh
 			
 			
 				we've lived here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about seventeen years</TIMEX> but we used to take all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> tobogganing and ice skating and all that kind of stuff the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and it's a lot of fun really
 			
 			
 				yeah
 				it is fun
 			
 			
 				as long as you don't have to drive in it
 			
 			
 				yeah i no i don't like that i really i it makes me nervous yeah
 			
 			
 				
 				i had plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> to last me forever i i don't
 				care if i ever see any well i don't care if i see it but
 				just keep it off of here
 			
 			
 				yeah yeah oh i don't mind it but uh us um the winter gets long
 			
 			
 				
 				yes
 			
 			
 				you know i get ready if that come about this time of year i'm kind of ready for it to start getting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> and it's too early yet so
 			
 			
 				
 				well you got you got you got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX> before you'll see that
 			
 			
 				
 				yeah we do we do we've had a few early springs though the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX> they haven't been too bad come about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> it it gets you know a lot nicer and
 			
 			
 				
 				oh yeah our our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> when uh
 			
 			
 				yeah
 			
 		
 	