
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh so what do you like best about golf
 	
 	
 		i like to watch golf my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> plays golf and i've i've really become
 		fairly acquainted with the game it's pretty interesting to watch i think my favorite part of the game is the putting part
 	
 	
 		really
 		really
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you play
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i play uh i play probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> times a week my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		don't like it too much but
 	
 	
 		well i've already
 	
 	
 		it's such a great game i i i play <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX> you know thirty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> holes after work
 	
 	
 		good heavens
 	
 	
 		and then uh
 	
 	
 		it must stay light out there pretty well
 	
 	
 		yeah it does in the summertime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> it's too you know but uh you know i go to the indoor driving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">range</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all all winter</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> well yeah in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i practice putting and it's it's a fun game
 	
 	
 		there's a place here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buster</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and they have a laser well it's like lasers golf game
 		where there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> beams and you take your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and you hit the ball and they give you a screen of what you would be seeing from where you lie
 	
 	
 		that sounds great
 	
 	
 		it's really a lot of fun and it's it's fairly comparable to some of the nicer golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> around here the nicer public courses the price of it is
 		if you're ever in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> you'd have to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buster</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		well i have to do that because i love golf and
 	
 	
 		it is a very fine game i think it teaches a lot of good uh a lot of good uh
 		attributes
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		to people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cathy</ENAMEX> is that your name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cathy</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah you got it right
 	
 	
 		do you
 		do you uh
 		do you have a favorite golfer
 	
 	
 		do i have a favorite golfer
 	
 	
 		professional golfer excuse me my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is making fun of me
 	
 	
 		oh  talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T I</ENAMEX> thing
 	
 	
 		yeah she hates it when i you know she thinks it's funny that i got golf as a topic because you know she dislikes it so much so
 	
 	
 		uh when you start up on golf
 		well you probably picked it though on your list of of topics to speak about
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i would say that my favorite golfer is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Norman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Norman</ENAMEX> why
 	
 	
 		there's just something about the way he plays golf he just approaches the ball
 		so confidently
 		and the way he hits he's just really he's got kind of a funny swing but beyond that he's really he seems a very confident <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> and he does
 		he does play fairly well
 		what about yourself
 	
 	
 		are you sure you're not attracted to him or anything
 	
 	
 		well that may be too he's he's not the most attractive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> on the on the tour  i'll say that but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess after watching
 		for so long for so long i've been i've been watching and hearing about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> for
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years six and a half years</TIMEX> or a little more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and after a while you get to where yeah you start watching who plays well and who doesn't i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Kite</ENAMEX> is another good player
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> he's good
 	
 	
 		he's got a real ugly stance but
 	
 	
 		yeah i'll agree with you there Cathy
 	
 	
 		he does he he does play real well and he he seems to almost always win
 	
 	
 		yeah he does
 	
 	
 		so he's so that's got to say a lot for him right there that he just wins quite often
 		what about yourself who is your favorite player
 	
 	
 		uh  i'd have to say uh
 		i i still like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Bear</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		even on the even on the senior tour
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i like the senior tour i i think it's got more personality
 	
 	
 		well yeah well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have
 	
 	
 		you know and the names don't change <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every week</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		the there's one thing that's true yeah you can always count on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chichi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Don</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		so
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and uh oh yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Golden Bear</ENAMEX> out there hitting them up
 	
 	
 		sure
 		really
 	
 	
 		putting them in
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> Cathy
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i have a young boy
 	
 	
 		i'm starting them off young i'm gonna get them oh you got a boy good
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh he already plays golf he's not <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX> and he golfs around the house
 	
 	
 		he does has he got a pretty good stance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no he's horrible but  but he loves
 	
 	
 		
 
 		huh
 	
 	
 		to he's got a a set of three little plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and little plastic balls and he takes his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and he whacks the ball around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and he whacks the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> and then he'll get a big play ball and bounce it around with his club
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but he really enjoys taking them out and he likes to watch his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> practice swing and putt around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i'm already a golf <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> and i don't mind it i mean i know where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is when he's out
 	
 	
 		well that's true
 	
 	
 		and he's in a very wholesome environment while he's out there so
 	
 	
 		that's true he's out getting some sunshine anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's
 		
 		
 	