
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so national health care i don't know about you but for me i am voting for the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">democrat</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> that says he is going to do something about a national health care program
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i uh i basically agree uh i have
 		mixed feelings i guess there are some uh
 		somehow there needs to be some controls on the rising costs of of health care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i myself uh
 		i haven't worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> because of some medical problems and uh if i had not had insurance
 		with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i worked with at the time i believe i would have died and that worries me thinking cause i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't have any coverage at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah if you if you don't have a very good paying job or you are not with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that provides it it is uh pretty much unaffordable uh to pay for it on your own
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i i think that paying for it on your own it is like in my case i am up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about two hundred thousand dollars</NUMEX> worth of health care i don't think that would have been possible for  the majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in this world
 	
 	
 		yeah that is right
 	
 	
 		so but then again there is uh the high cost of medical care is out unreal
 	
 	
 		yeah i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who uh uh is from uh lived at lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> or lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and he lives here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> where they do have medical uh health care uh there and i guess
 		i guess there is some disadvantages too i guess uh uh because of that they there has been a great uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">migration</ENAMEX> of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> from there over to more lucrative practices and sometimes i guess it does effect the quality of health care somewhat so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i think somewhere along the line whatever plan they come up with it is going to have to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> in a high paying field
 	
 	
 		i
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i myself have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who hopes to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple three more years</TIMEX> and uh  he is doing it for the money
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they don't have i think they don't get into it for any other reason
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but he agrees with me though that there should be something worked out for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can't afford it
 	
 	
 		yes uh i uh agree too and also the uh the elderly a lot of times when they uh reach retirement uh
 		they can't afford any any supplemental insurance beyond what is provided through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> and sometimes that is not enough to to cover the costs
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		i found out yeah i uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare Medicaid</ENAMEX> whatever and uh i know it doesn't pay all of her medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> bills and so forth
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think it is kind of a shame that at this point in her life she still has to pay quite a bit whenever she is in the hospital <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several thousand</NUMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> stay if she ends up having to pay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah particularly for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are on uh on on just living mostly on social security or something like that they don't have enough extra money to pay for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i know one uh not this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> but the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> before she was out here and we were out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithville</ENAMEX> which is a little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> out east of here and
 		we had to take her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> for a back problem uh fairly minor she just strained it sprained it but
 		when the bills starting coming in she had already gone home so i got a chance to look at them and i was shocked i mean i have been through a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean with medical bills but when i saw what they did to her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> and it cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about three thousand dollars</NUMEX> just to uh get a prescription for some pain pills basically
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		uh in i guess in addition to uh uh national health care policy there uh there has to be some sort of
 		monitoring i guess too of the overall medical field and hospital costs and and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well that doesn't happen i
 		it is weird i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight days</TIMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> uh so many mistakes were made during my time there that i uh literally left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> in a taxi cab
 		just to get away from the place i was scared as to what they were going to do to me next
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and when i got the bill it was outrageous uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> that i had never heard of that i had taken which i know that i didn't i mean i wasn't ill i was just in for some routine stuff and  it goes on and on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i am afraid right now there is a lot of i guess you would have to call it just basic fraud in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">in</ENAMEX> in the business cause they know they can turn a lot of these things in and they are not questioned at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know which one of the uh democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> either either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerrey</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> i guess one of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i can't remember which is pretty much in favor of some sort of
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerrey</ENAMEX> is and i think also <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Brown</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> are interested uh actually the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has been going the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few weeks</TIMEX> i think he may be interested uh  he he seem to be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well he's he's probably campaigning i don't know how serious he is but
 	
 	
 		yeah  uh
 		yeah up until just recently i i would have thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> would uh you know i still he has done a pretty good job
 		
 		
 	