
 
     		
 	
 		the reason i was thinking about trials by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and um  i i guess i thought more highly of it until the uh recent  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Kennedy Smith</ENAMEX>  case where they uh were telling about how they used um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what they consider scientific methods to choose the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> to get the right results you know for their chance what do you think about that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well  um  you know it's it's like anything else i mean  i guess i probably should mention i am an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and i and i although i don't do trial work now i have done so in the past and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have to say that i've never been in the position to uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> make use of uh the types of techniques but for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> there have been  uh books written that everybody has access to about techniques in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> selection
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um you know uh i mean it kind of the way it kind of really actually works out in real life i don't think it's fair
 		um necessarily for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side  because they have a lot of money
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		to be able to uh
 		you you know it it kind of it strikes me as as unfair that if you have got enough money you can pick the jury you want and really the system doesn't  exactly allow that anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		the best the best you get on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> selection is is if you've got to pick a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you get a certain number of what they call preemptory strikes and a certain number of of
 		um  each side gets those and and then there are are strikes you know an unlimited number of strikes for what they call for cause
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		you you know  obviously
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose whose livelihood depends on um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury jury</ENAMEX> trials are going to use whatever they can use to try uh to improve their chances and and you know it's get it's
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the unfair part of it is that not everybody has access to the high powered technique but then then the the saving grace is that it can only get you so far
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean you know it it you may find that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> are ideal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> for you but the other side is probably going to even if i was sitting there with no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um  high-powered computer input and whatnot if i could just ask them questions i could tell that they're gonna be good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> for you and bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> for me i'm gonna strike them so you're not going to get them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean you can't really get what you want
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you can just improve your chances of guessing who you think you want
 	
 	
 		yes well i know um  fairly recently when that um one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> sessions for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wylie Price</ENAMEX>  i remember that um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and though i had agreed with some of the things he did i i disagreed with that particular case because he um
 		they made they got a lot of mileage out that they that that was not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> that um they said you know that he was found guilty and then
 		he uh then they made note that none of the  the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> were uh black or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African African American</ENAMEX> and
 		and it seemed to me that if he wanted  if they wanted that um i mean they chose them deliberately i mean because of all of the  publicity that it got from that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i really thought well  you know one of their points that they made on purpose was they chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who they felt were not their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> in order to make the case against him weaker
 		and it just seemed like it wasn't very fair that that you know that was  something that could have been said at the very beginning and not cost the tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">payers</ENAMEX> the money for that court
 	
 	
 		yeah well you know it's it's kind of been uh uh you see a lot in the death penalty cases
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that there a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> who strongly believe that the death penalty is not right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they um have pretty much dedicated themselves to doing everything they can to prevent uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sentenced to the death penalty from being executed
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they will go through endless appeals and one of the things that has been used and and it's been used most often um in in in the death penalty cases is the fact that
 		you know that the the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are convicted if they're black they may not have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> or they might have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> black on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> panel
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they have tried to statistically tie this to the likelihood of him getting the death penalty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but they've never really been successful in it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has has up to this point continued to reject those types of arguments
 		saying that that somebody didn't get a fair trial because there wasn't a certain  quota of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> on the jury panel
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i really do think that those arguments will continue to fail because
 		
 		
 	