
 
     		
 	
 		did you hear our topic and it's in regards to discussing homes
 	
 	
 		
 
 		homes yes sir um-hum
 		what are are you settled in a place
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm settled in a place i've been in it for twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> since nineteen uh actually thirteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> since nineteen seventy eight
 		in it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson Texas</ENAMEX> which is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Texas</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		and we've lived in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> we moved here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy four</TIMEX>  and uh changed locations in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seventy eight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		how about yourself
 	
 	
 		well we uh left here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy six</TIMEX> uh we were here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> then we uh have come back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just this summer</TIMEX> right now we're looking for housing
 		uh somewhere down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duncanville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cedar Hill</ENAMEX> area are you familiar that
 	
 	
 		yes nice area
 	
 	
 		yeah it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Duncanville</ENAMEX> we're in a temporary place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and uh so they've enjoyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so we're kind of trying to stay here but
 	
 	
 		are you finding it tough trying to find what you want or
 	
 	
 		well what the problem we got is that we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		and so uh we really want <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four or five</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom house</ENAMEX> and uh you know everybody says you know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> are on the market and all that kind of thing so we uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right right
 	
 	
 		we look at the paper we look at our talk to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">realtor</ENAMEX> and you can cut you know the listings uh in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a third</NUMEX> and when you go from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> bedrooms you know or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> are you looking or you settled i mean having having finished
 	
 	
 		sure
 		no we're settled and uh
 		we're uh
 		i'm probably older than you i'm fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> but anyway i my youngest is getting married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and graduating college so i can board up their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> and  look forward to retirement maybe
 	
 	
 		oh great
 		
 
 		that empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">nest</ENAMEX> syndrome is gonna set in i guess
 	
 	
 		oh gosh so we're looking forward to retiring in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years</TIMEX> and maybe relocating to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> or somewhere closer closer to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 		okay you are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> originally
 	
 	
 		no i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> but everyone's uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York New Jersey</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so but everyone seems uh has seemed to relocated down that area seems like a nice place to go
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah yeah we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and the oldest is uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> grade and the youngest is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade and i think they're gonna be uh with us forever
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know if that's true but it's sure you know we're we're not anywhere near looking to uh uh cut down in size we're we're trying to find the
 	
 	
 		oh i understand you need very minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah in fact <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> would be real good my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i can share a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>  and there
 	
 	
 		as far
 		right
 		it's tough to find a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room bedroom house</ENAMEX> isn't it
 	
 	
 		oh i don't think it's possible unless you you know multimillionaire something like that yeah
 	
 	
 		oh i know seems like when you get in that category you're in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three hundred thousand dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> or whatever and it's that's an awful lot you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah it is yeah we're um we're having actually
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if we find something for uh i'd say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than a hundred and</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thousand</TIMEX> we'll be doing all right you know that's uh but i think the thing's out there it's just a matter of uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know looking you know finding the right place uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		matter of looking right
 		lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will will buy a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> in your situation will buy a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom house</ENAMEX> and convert maybe the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> or something or do or do something i had a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> used to work for me at my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> from the high school and she had uh there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in her family
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and they converted the dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and and did this and that they always seemed to get along fine you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah yeah i think once we get into a place it'll be just fine but um you know it's until then it's uh
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		oh a little stressful you know just looking all the time and that sort of thing that's all
 	
 	
 		oh i know and it's  there's nothing harder than that i always just sort of a
 		assign my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> that chore then i would let her narrow it down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> then i'd go look because
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> seem to like to look a lot more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		oh yeah maybe that's the case at least she's got more opinions you know there's uh
 		seems like there's more constraints more things that she thinks about you know openness uh the size of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and all this kind of stuff that i would probably gloss over and maybe even ignore you know
 	
 	
 		yes
 		why certainly
 		i understand that
 	
 	
 		so what what kind of business are you in
 	
 	
 		i'm in the uh sporting goods business i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX>'s rep i represent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> different hunting and shooting type companies
 	
 	
 		oh yeah great
 	
 	
 		who who are you with
 	
 	
 		uh we're with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh Wycliffe Bible</ENAMEX> Translators it's a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions organization</ENAMEX> and uh doing uh translation linguistics that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well great
 	
 	
 		uh it's got an office down here in uh it near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Duncanville</ENAMEX> and we just moved down to be on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> down here so
 	
 	
 		how how was the uh you say you say you lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> area before how did that compare with this area as far as housing housing prices
 	
 	
 		it
 		right
 		uh we were uh
 		really surprised to find that they're higher here uh
 	
 	
 		no kidding
 	
 	
 		when we moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> it was astounding you know to find that prices were oh i guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost two or three</NUMEX> times as high as we'd expected and then uh to come down here we thought things would be lower and they're not
 		i guess um
 		really prices for housing are just
 		
 		
 	