
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all righty
 		so how what do you think of capital punishment
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> has capital punishment
 	
 	
 		oh does it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yep</ENAMEX> and uh
 		they go through a set of appeals that lasts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>
 		and uh
 		there are so many cases here like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sixty Minutes</ENAMEX> is on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> here there are so many cases here where they proved that they've convicted the wrong person
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that i'm against it they should just give them life in prison
 	
 	
 		well i feel that way the only exception i think is qualifies for capital punishment is repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offender</ENAMEX> actually murders <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> repeatedly
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		like serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> or someone who has been convicted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than three</NUMEX> times on a murder charge and then gotten out on parole i don't think they should be able to get out on parole and do it again
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that's the only time i think it's really
 	
 	
 		well like in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">state</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Manson</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who killed all those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think i think those types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> deserve capital punishment
 		but i think they should restrict it strictly for repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> or like i said serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> because i mean a lot of times not a lot of times but quite quite a few times they've convicted innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know if they've been convicted like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times you know there something's wrong
 	
 	
 		something's going on right
 	
 	
 		so i think that's the only time it's really a necessary
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so too after after it's gone that far then they pretty well have a
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		enough proof that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		the guilty party
 	
 	
 		they can't be rehabilitated rehabilitated either so yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 		but that's really the only time when i agree with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		most of the time i don't think it's a good idea because like you said there have been cases where they've convicted the wrong people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just because of circumstances
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> which is where i'm originally from
 		they had a big thing about capital punishment there because we had like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> caught
 		and they had a big thing about whether they should you know go for capital punishment or not but it's not used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they had a problem with it
 		unfortunately all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> got was sent to jail for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> until they get paroled
 	
 	
 		right i never heard about those
 	
 	
 		unfortunately one of them killed a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine so i was very much involved
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and when he got out on parole i was like
 		go ahead get out on parole
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		after that i had i had to tangle with him and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> caught him the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time and they still wouldn't do anything except send him to jail so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i definitely believe if they're repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> they should
 		be
 		something to be done with them other than just sitting there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and then getting out and doing it again
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have outlawed capital punishment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know which states in general
 	
 	
 		and that's that's the reason that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Bundy</ENAMEX> supposedly went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		that was his primary goal was to to have the death penalty
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		because he started out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> and traveled all the way across the country
 	
 	
 		huh i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		they had um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Harmon</ENAMEX> played him they had a movie about it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		and then of course there was a lot of publicity about it um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> before they killed him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		and he was really you know he was off the wall so
 	
 	
 		i don't know a lot of the crimes that are done nowadays it's like i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to be off the wall to do them but
 		i still don't believe capital punishment should be used unless they're repeat offenders
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but
 		i don't know i
 		once i finish law school i'll have
 		more probably more views on it
 		i'll be able to do something about it then
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah and some of the ways i think that um the way that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> um executes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> is probably the most humane way they use they do it by injection
 	
 	
 		oh do they
 	
 	
 		yeah instead of you know the electric chair the gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> that's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		that would be the more humane way of doing it
 	
 	
 		yeah well they you know they just go to sleep and and then eventually they die
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		instead of being you know fried or
 		or
 	
 	
 		or stuck in a gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> until they finally pass on
 	
 	
 		yeah fighting fighting for breath right um-hum
 	
 	
 		but i know a couple of states
 		still believe in the hanging but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't go for that either
 		
 		
 	