
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i guess you heard our conversation our topic for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was clothing
 	
 	
 		right yeah i certainly did
 	
 	
 		how you dress for work and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how do you dress for work
 	
 	
 		well uh uh about the same i dress for school i uh i i'm a graduate i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> so  i don't have to worry too much about uh what i wear too much of the time
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh which is nice uh  uh  i've uh although i do uh a lot of i'm a speech pathology major and so i do a lot of clinical work  and when i do clinic work then i have to uh uh look my best
 	
 	
 		you bet
 		look professional
 	
 	
 		yeah  unfortunately
 	
 	
 		yeah i understand i'm a i own my own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i'm in the i'm a manufactures rep sales <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and i'm very casual and wear slacks and sports shirt things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then when i travel it's a little different situation it's uh suit and sports coat tie and the whole bit because you go to meetings and you're required to look your best and look professional of course
 	
 	
 		yeah sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah uh do uh do you find that uh on the average do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> give uh more credibility or less credibility to a to a professional to professionally professionally dressed individual
 	
 	
 		yeah i think in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s society uh there's more credibility quite honest
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'll always remember i'll tell this real quick story when i graduated college my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago twenty twenty nine years ago</TIMEX> in fact was selling uh agricultural fertilizer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i worked for the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smith Douglas Division of Borden Chemical</ENAMEX> and i sold uh you know manure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i would go out and call on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>  and
 		i was always try to look my best wearing sport coats and things like that but i was calling on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that wore bib overalls and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		one day i got up and thought well i'll just go casual and do you know that i called on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> wearing exactly that bib overalls  and he sort of told me that he expected me to be professional
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he sort of expected me to dress as a professional so uh it was sort of was
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		even even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> oh wow
 	
 	
 		you bet even even back then so i've sort a uh
 		been aware of my dress ever since then and try to look my best but but here again i dress casual quite a bit so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah certainly
 	
 	
 		it depends on who you call on in my business if i call on the  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JC Penney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or say someone say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roebuck</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> then i wear coat and tie if i call on just uh  a normal little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> of mine i might be casual
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i call on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oshman</ENAMEX>'s sporting goods again it may be casual or it may be coat and tie so it just it it depends
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah it depends  sure uh so you don't you uh if you had the choice would you wear a tie or no
 	
 	
 		um
 		probably no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i believe you can get away with it but then it depends on who you're calling on who you're it'd be like your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> standing up in front of you with no tie you just uh he'd be missing something although he shouldn't be evaluated on that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		so it is it's it's just different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that uh
 		that's uh  if if you wanted to to uh really get into a hot issue uh  well at least in some in some beliefs uh uh how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> dress when they go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is uh is uh sometimes a pretty pretty hot topic
 	
 	
 		yes it is
 	
 	
 		uh unfortunately unfortunately unfortunately unfortunately
 	
 	
 		i'm uh  lightly a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh that go to my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> are you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> dress very casual you're liable to find
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in jeans and and and whatever but yet the way i was raised i'm a converted <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> the way i was raised i was raised a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baptist</ENAMEX> and
 		it seems like as a youngster i use to always dress up all the time but i guess that has changed also
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  uh yeah i'm i'm a  i i go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Church of Christ</ENAMEX> i've been raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Church of Christ</ENAMEX> and uh  i i uh
 		
 
 		too many times you you hear you hear a lot about what what you're uh supposed you're supposed to look your your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> best and uh  uh dress in proper attire and uh and sometimes that really disappoints me uh in
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		in uh
 		when i see in other economic areas uh like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just don't have that and they are afraid to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> or afraid to go simply because they don't have the clothes to wear
 	
 	
 		but at the very
 		that's a very good point i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> so i understand what you're saying there and there it's it's just a very good point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but uh you shouldn't what's the old saying you shouldn't judge a book by its cover
 	
 	
 		certainly
 	
 	
 		and uh evaluation of of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> of course i think it depends on the type of job responsibility you have i think you have to dress sort of accordingly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh you certainly should not judge a book by its cover and uh or evaluate a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> by that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but what about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> does i guess your dress changes
 	
 	
 		uh yeah a little bit uh  course in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> if i can get away with it i wear uh uh a pair of shorts and that's it run around barefoot no shirt or anything  uh but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	