
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well let's start with you
 	
 	
 		okay um the last movie i saw was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five Heartbeats</ENAMEX> and i liked it a lot because it had a lot of music in it
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heartbeats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's
 	
 	
 		who who was in that
 	
 	
 		it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Townsend</ENAMEX> movie
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um i i don't know all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> or anything but it was just it was a lot of music a lot of old songs things like that
 	
 	
 		when was it out
 	
 	
 		um it's still out now uh it came out i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month or about a month</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> ago something like that
 		it's about a black singing group
 		it and uh it was called the Dells
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it was kind of like just about their their life and their uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		history and things like that and the way they went from from how they went from stardom to non stardom
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh that was pretty good i enjoyed i saw Dances with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Wolves</ENAMEX> have you seen that yeah
 	
 	
 		that's
 		yeah i saw that one that was pretty good uh that won
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		best picture i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costner</ENAMEX> got best director
 	
 	
 		yeah right now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> i mean he's
 		starring in everything he's doing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> movie that's coming out
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and there's one yeah  yeah starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> movie huh
 	
 	
 		and let me see what else um he's doing some other movie i can't i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> that's it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> movie coming out and he's going to be in also
 		and let me see what else have i seen what have you seen
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> comes to mind here and i can't i'm not sure about the name has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX> and um
 		what was the name of that
 		anyway the basis the premise of the story is that uh uh
 		uh you go to a place after you die you go to a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judgment City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i know what you're talking about
 	
 	
 		and um anyway uh i can't remember the other the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		my
 		it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reviewing My Life</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		yeah and and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i didn't get to see that
 	
 	
 		Defending <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Your Life Defending Your Life</ENAMEX> and it's it's an excellent movie uh it's pretty entertaining uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's it okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		let's see what else have i seen lately
 		um
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my favorite movies it's not one that i've haven't seen i
 		well it's not a late movie it's uh
 	
 	
 		Home Alone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay yeah
 	
 	
 		it's probably my all time well not all time favorite but one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> that i can watch over and over
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah did well did you ever see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Alone</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i never did i i heard it was really good i've never just haven't gone out to see it was that pretty funny
 	
 	
 		that was a that was a that was a good one too
 		yeah it's pretty good and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		somehow just never made it to see that but i need to see it
 	
 	
 		i don't know i can't believe i'm just drawing a blank um because i've seen
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX> that i don't know why i like that movie so much i guess it was so much suspense
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i like suspense
 	
 	
 		that kinds of reminds me like uh did you ever see this is going way back uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jagged Edge</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh yeah on that order certainly is
 	
 	
 		that that was a good one too yeah
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		and i liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that played in that i forgot what her name is now
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Archer</ENAMEX>
 		she's the one she was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah and she played in uh Narrow Margin which was a little more recent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that was kind of another suspense type <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Hitchcock</ENAMEX> type
 		thriller that was good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		God i guess i haven't seen too many movies lately i need to
 	
 	
 		i haven't seen a whole lot either but  i know i'm drawing a blank on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what i've seen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just
 	
 	
 		somehow i mean i it's hard for me to get to the movies now because it's getting so expensive you know i'd i'd rather rent
 	
 	
 		i know it's  it's obnoxious because you go in there and you spend <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> bucks a ticket but then you end up spending another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">six dollars</NUMEX> on food
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and that's just for a bocket a bucket of popcorn you know yeah
 	
 	
 		and a pop you know so it's it gets pretty
 	
 	
 		yeah God forbid you should want something to drink with it
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah like if i so if i take a date it it it cost me you know twenty bucks easy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah easily
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		and usually going to do usually going to go to a dinner go to dinner or something  with that
 	
 	
 		i was going to say
 		you you know you can find certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that are nice and have good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		eat eat for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> dollars
 	
 	
 		it's almost more fun really yeah it's almost more fun really to rent movies you know just kind of stay at home maybe
 	
 	
 		yeah the problem is you always have to wait until they're out
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true too
 	
 	
 		so that's what you're
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you're uh dealing with
 	
 	
 		but then you can make your popcorn and you know
 		be comfortable
 	
 	
 		that's true that is true
 	
 	
 		so um-hum
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		well that's about all the movies i've seen recently
 	
 	
 		i ought to open the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> here because i know i've seen a few that have that played but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just can't come up with any names here haven't haven't been to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> for a little while
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		did you ever see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kindergarten Cop</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's
 		no i never did
 	
 	
 		that was pretty good
 	
 	
 		was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but um
 	
 	
 		there's a movie i do want to see uh  i haven't seen it
 		what is it oh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kiss Before Dying</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		it looks it looks pretty suspenseful
 	
 	
 		yeah whose in that
 		um-hum another one i saw is called the Object of Beauty
 		i don't remember recommend that as much as uh Defending Your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> but it was it was all right kind of funny
 		um
 		but um
 		what else has
 		been on and about
 	
 	
 		um-hum are you looking in the paper
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yep
 		i'm trying to i wanted to get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silence of the Lambs</ENAMEX> i hear that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that was great
 	
 	
 		pretty oh did you see that
 	
 	
 		yes that was that
 		that might be one of my all time favorites too that was an excellent movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was pretty scary because i was visiting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA Hospital</ENAMEX> uh near to where i live and they were saying that some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> there you can't leave by themselves because they'll make a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> out of anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know out of a piece of paper they can kill somebody you know and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in Silence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lambs Hannibal Lector</ENAMEX> he was he was that kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and you they couldn't leave him alone and that's that's what was so scary about the movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know since he was such an awesome character
 		you know i mean it was it was really fascinating he was very dangerous but you were kind of on his side because he was so fascinating
 	
 	
 		hm
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but but they couldn't leave him alone at all
 		and they found out what happened when they did leave him alone one time but i won't tell you that just in case you see the movie
 	
 	
 		yeah i'll probably try to go see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to see it in a little while here but it's been out for a while
 	
 	
 		oh very good
 		oh yeah oh yeah
 		i'm not sure when it'll be hitting video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> but it should be a while yet though
 	
 	
 		you heard anything on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">like Out for Justice</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh  i haven't heard anything about it
 		i but i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Seagal</ENAMEX> things uh they're just kind um
 	
 	
 		has he had very has has he had very many other movies out
 	
 	
 		he's had Out For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> and there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right before that with a similar title like
 		uh
 		i don't know some i don't know some macho title  that's why i i just don't like the
 	
 	
 		because it's a macho movie
 	
 	
 		yeah it is i i don't i don't like that a lot i don't watch a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> or anything like that either
 	
 	
 		speaking of that i think <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Terminator 2</ENAMEX> is supposed to be out
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that might be good though that might be good
 	
 	
 		i don't know i've enjoyed a lot of his movies uh they just uh they're action filled and they're a little bit of humor and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh the
 	
 	
 		i guess i i'm not fond of the action packed movie where they're always chasing or fighting or you know i like the more movies that make you think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		did you ever see um
 		um
 		Sleeping with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enemy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't seen that yet and that's something i really should have seen was that good did you see it
 	
 	
 		i haven't
 		i haven't heard much lately i just remember when it first came out that it had kind of mixed reviews
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine saw it and she said it was okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it wasn't anything spectacular
 	
 	
 		you expect more out of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		but the
 		yeah the previews looked so good
 		that i wanted to see it but i never did
 		uh
 	
 	
 		did you ever see the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FX</ENAMEX> movie
 	
 	
 		yeah well i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of it and i remember i was in school i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of it and i fell asleep and everyone else watched it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh okay because i was going to say i always enjoyed that i i uh i remember that movie and uh it was i mean i got into it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they have F <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FX</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know if
 	
 	
 		i really need to go see the original one i'm sure it was a good movie i just i probably had a test <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> or something i don't know
 	
 	
 		uh yeah it was one of those that has a lot of twists in it yeah it it's it's it's it's uh
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		i can't put it exactly on the lines of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jagged Edge</ENAMEX> but it you know it uh kind of on that end you know you get these twists and
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah and that um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's usually pretty good but uh
 	
 	
 		i think i think though that movies are losing their luster  kind of i think movies are losing their attractiveness just to a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just i think i don't know because of the cost and i think it it's just losing its originality
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		or something i don't i can't pinpoint pinpoint it but it doesn't seem like it's as big uh rage to get to the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> as it used to be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 
 		that's probably true i i i just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you see the same story lines different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't know it's it's it's it's it's it's hard to say and i know i don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i'm i don't keep up with it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know but uh
 		i don't try to just just just for that reason reason it is a cost it does cost a lot so why
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		go out and see something right away wait you know you kind of wait and if something gets really good reviews maybe you'd finally go spend the twelve bucks you know to go to it
 	
 	
 		right right um-hum
 	
 	
 		but um
 		you know i haven't been to a grand an opening for oh you know ages
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just because
 		
 		
 	