
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that i've heard uh many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> complain about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> was that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they didn't feel like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were dedicated to teaching their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or their heart really wasn't in it you know so what they went and got a degree and and everything but it wasn't
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		their not doing it just because they want to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		are you saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> or the parents
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know
 		well how do you feel about that
 	
 	
 		well i guess i
 		have mixed emotions on one hand
 		i think golly the pay isn't good enough if you didn't really want to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah you shouldn't be doing
 	
 	
 		it's probably something else out there
 		but on the other hand i think that maybe some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have thought that was kind of an easy way out
 		you can major in something basically useless to the world as a whole like say <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> or geography geography being one of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		nevertheless it's not exactly the thing that's going to make you bucks
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but you could then go ahead and get a
 		teaching certificate and perhaps
 		feed your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> a little
 	
 	
 		yeah what do you think about the the recent bill that was just passed you know where
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		they're taking the money from especially the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		you're calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		school
 		oh oh yeah i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm in Plano
 	
 	
 		okay yeah they're taking uh
 		the money from our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> here and distribute it some of the other outlying and and especially like west <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what do you think about that because it's it's you know the money's coming from us here that live here and work here and
 	
 	
 		well
 		i have always believed in sharing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> next door was hungry and they needed something to eat or something to wear i'd be glad to share and so i guess in the global sense you have to have that kind of feeling to a certain extent but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i also don't believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get funds or equipment  or anything without some of their own personal input
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		take care of it nicely or appreciate it or use it properly
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 		those things have to be taught
 	
 	
 		
 
 		excuse me yeah i agree you know
 	
 	
 		so
 		you know so there's that end of it too and and i think it's going to really
 		
 
 		you know so i don't
 		i don't say that in a selfish way because i think there that it's probably not totally equitable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and i don't know that there is a good situation entirely but golly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it sure going to make a big difference in our school system
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		you know it uh i was um-hum i was talking to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irving</ENAMEX> who sits on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">council</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irving Independent School District</ENAMEX> and she was saying they are number one
 	
 	
 		Plano yeah
 	
 	
 		they are adding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> they are adding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> to their school day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in order to accommodate the extra teaching that's going to be needed
 		because they're eliminating all aids
 		they're going to they all aids all paid aids everything is going to have to be volunteer through the parent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher organizations</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and frankly we're all ready maxed out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> you know uh volunteer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		work i work part-time out of my home and they did you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm always getting called and you know and used utilized you know what i'm willing to do it but i know during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when i was uh just not a working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> at all it was ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		they call you all the time
 	
 	
 		uh yeah yeah until i just finally had to say
 		i am so sorry that you know just cannot do everything for you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i agree
 	
 	
 		you know so there's and and the moms that work a lot of times just can't help at all and yeah
 	
 	
 		right well i i i believe that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> puts a big demand on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> for for the fact that they expect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to go out and
 		a lot of times chauffeur or lot of times you know buy a lot of things that might seem unnecessary but i it's unreal on the cost of sending a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> to school because of you know you spend your time voluntary and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		plus you buy a lot of extra arts crafts aids things like that notebooks for reports
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so many
 		yes
 		well and just you know the yearbook and the T-shirt and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> presents and the you know it really starts
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so i know that it really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>
 		oh my goodness so you really do yeah like uh all types of projects little bug things you know that
 	
 	
 		you know
 		um-hum i just helped a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> a teenager <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of ours she had to prepare something for to study <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they were i think she needed a recipe and the history of of the recipe or the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and also um
 		had to actually make it and bring it enough to serve you know fifteen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i found the cheapest thing i could find that i could help her with and even so figuring it up i think she spent close to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> dollars
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and it was say you know we did a couple of different ones and it was the least expensive and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and still be able to fix it at home and tote it up there and what not so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but that's
 	
 	
 		that's amazing because if if every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> does that what are they going to do with all that
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a lot of money
 		yeah and would they really eat it of course that's not really you know the quality of education
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		
 
 		you know i think that probably you know here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> we are
 		uh of course state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> you know added uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> next year
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh i think we're going to be seeing alternative calendar very soon i i'm still basically against it although i i do understand the positives
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that are you know touted but i think overall
 	
 	
 		how do you feel about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> school system you feel like it's pretty good compared to the others surround you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		there is a quality of excellence expected here it's very difficult
 		for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in this school district to
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excel</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> area
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because if you get into drama if you get into speech if you get into drill <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> or athletics or whatever it is i mean they want you night and day they want your time they want your blood
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah money and
 	
 	
 		you know so
 		and uh you know i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> who
 		been fortunate enough to be in in these extra curricular things but golly
 		you know it's just really you know it's like a smaller school system you know you could be in the drill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and you could be cheerleader too and you could be you know on the football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and still be on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and still try out for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		real demanding
 		
 
 		basketball
 		right
 		yeah that's amazing
 	
 	
 		so
 		you know that and you you can't do that in this school system so you know we've been working on college stuff for my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and shoot you know
 	
 	
 		that's a
 		that's a big difference
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh you know you kind of
 		you know you have to to look when we were writing things down i said you know you can't really talk about all your individual things but you know you've got to make sure that when you put down <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> here that it's not just any old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> that this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> that took
 		this honor and that honor and participated in this competition and participated in that competition so they understand really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 		that's wild
 		well it's been good talking to you
 	
 	
 		well yeah this is uh this is interesting interesting topic
 	
 	
 		
 
 		thank you uh good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		thank you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX> have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	