
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right uh
 		do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		and what do they say about finding adequate child care i think that may be the key word
 	
 	
 		they
 		i think that's correct there i relatively not existent from uh from what i hear from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> it seems like uh
 		even when they have consulted day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> that are quote unquote reputable that are sort of like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> if i can use that word uh still you have to deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you know happen to be operating it locally
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh it's just a matter of of trust you know i think they feel that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are um under qualified basically and underpaid
 		and i think that sort of goes hand in hand so it's it's difficult for them
 	
 	
 		well we've certainly found that to be true uh indeed we've
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and we moved away from institutionalized child care if we can call those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> kind of things like that uh by that name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and found that uh more creative <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> were the right answer for us uh at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point in time we've had au pairs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		by trading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> with them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then that worked for a while but they were really adequate ones were really tough to find it takes that
 	
 	
 		i'm sure that's true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that uh mixture of a very mature college student
 		who wants to do something and yet is willing to give the time
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the interest to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right i do have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that uh uh she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> became live in uh care givers and they they loved it they had stayed with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> from the time
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were small you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years old</TIMEX> up until they were well into grade school
 		and uh she was paid very well because they the parents trusted them and they you know had done such a good job
 		so um i can see where someone you know in a position like that in a live in capacity would definitely be the way to go if you're lucky enough to have the finances to be able to do that
 	
 	
 		well that's true and that's something that we're struggling with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> as
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think it's just a matter of priorities it's uh
 		you know a terrible thing to say when your speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in that way but you still have to be realistic as well i think
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know any you
 		much as uh
 		other cultures might disagree our lives don't revolve around our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah and that's that's that's sad to have to admit too but uh
 		you know it's just there's so much pressure when you're talking about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and and i think that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason why i continue to be without <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i
 		it's just such a such a responsibility and and when i've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have said
 		when you hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say it alters your life forever please take heed and realize that that's true so it's uh such a responsibility
 	
 	
 		well it certainly is uh
 		if i can gather the other side of the coin for a moment it is such an honor and a thrill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		to be a parent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that most of the time it's worth it
 	
 	
 		yeah most of the time
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know i i just have to be honest about it it's not always worth it
 	
 	
 		yeah oh sure sure
 	
 	
 		there are those times when i think jeez if i didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i could be out playing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> or golf
 	
 	
 		sure
 		right right right right
 		but you know it's it's funny i did i i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that said you know before we always said we don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because we can't go off on the spur of the moment or this or that and the other and she got older she said but you know we never do those things anyway so
 		why  why am i waiting you know it's just the it's just the way your attitude changes and you mature i suppose but
 		the thing about the child care i
 		you know i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that struggle financially and and they both do have to work it's a matter of not necessarily uh that she might want to stay home or he as well but you know that they need the money
 		and uh when i seen some of my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have taken that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six week</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> you know to someone else and
 		it's just i can imagine how emotional it must be and and you know multiplied by the fact that you don't really trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or you're uncomfortable with the situation you've been placed in as far as child care goes um it's it's just a scary thing
 	
 	
 		well we were lucky when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were that age and
 		living having lived in a community for a while and we knew the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to whom we were entrusting our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um um that's a big plus yes
 	
 	
 		and and felt that that bond of safety and feeling of safety
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and leaving them with them as small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we also learned something from that experience as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> got older in that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">givers</ENAMEX> are not
 		omniscious omniscipotent they're they are not all things to all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right right
 	
 	
 		the the ones that are good with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> tend not to be good with toddlers
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think it takes a lot i i don't know i think your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> level must needs to increase as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> gets older  i think that might be part of the problem with some people
 		you know taking care of a baby i know is not an easy thing but when you have them in their their little feet are moving and you have to chase them down constantly i'm sure that's a whole new ball game
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine year old</TIMEX> i'd trade happily for a babe in arms today
 	
 	
 		oh really  well you sound like your pretty well maybe passed the worst of it as far as worrying about since they're both in school you don't have to worry about a full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to take care of them
 	
 	
 		oh you don't know what happens after they get in school
 	
 	
 		
 
 		is that that's something all together different huh
 	
 	
 		oh yes now we have uh one takes piano lessons at at somewhere on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one afternoon</TIMEX> and the other one of course can't do the same thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh of course not
 	
 	
 		and it has to be somewhere else and no it's not adequate to sit and wait
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you can't do that no
 	
 	
 		no no no no that's just that will not do
 	
 	
 		no no no no
 		that's out of the question i'm sure
 	
 	
 		of course and but we are helping we are you know we are being cooperative what's wrong with you you don't understand this uh that's just the way their minds work and it's almost everyday
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right right um-hum um-hum
 		that's amazing it's amazing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually th e stamina that you must you know draw from yourself to deal with it it must be interesting i guess you find find out that you're a much stronger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> than you thought maybe
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i've been finding out that i really am a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but it's been hidden for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because i didn't need it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and now i need it
 	
 	
 		and now it's just uh it's just a reservoir that you tend to regularly i'm sure
 	
 	
 		yeah and and it stays low a lot
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well are your are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now do you feel comfortable um with them coming home after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> until you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		absolutely not
 	
 	
 		no yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean  one of them i would i would um leave unsupervised any time any place any where uh the other one i wouldn't leave <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">unsupervised two minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		that's just a difference in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i suppose
 	
 	
 		that's true what one leads the other you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and if you
 	
 	
 		and it's it's the one that's going they're going downhill is it is it the one that needs needs more supervision that has a bad influence on the older or on the more mature one
 	
 	
 		of course
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		how unfortunate
 	
 	
 		you you don't you don't think that good prevails
 	
 	
 		well i you know i'm living in a dream world what do i know as i said i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i'm an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> so i've never been around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh i'm sort of at a a loss where that's concerned but i do hear my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> talk about it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we're we're having such fun my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i were both only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we just couldn't wait to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so they would be such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> um-hum
 	
 	
 		wrong
 	
 	
 		that's like <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War Three</ENAMEX> every minute
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know i i i have to admit i was a selfish i was selfish as a child i didn't want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and now that i'm older of course it's different you know i think about uh wouldn't it be nice but uh anyway
 	
 	
 		just make good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah oh i have wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that's that's true my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 		so uh they just sort of you know adopted me as their eleventh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> so that worked out pretty well she never had to worry about uh taking anybody to child care because there was always somebody there older to deal with them so i guess that's that's an alternative you could just
 	
 	
 		have enough
 	
 	
 		um have have a whole bunch and by the time the little the youngest ones are are there you'll have old ones to take care of them
 		yeah yeah i don't know it just see when you see all these these uh horror stories on television about child care and
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		gosh i just i was seeing something on the television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> about a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that's been telling her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> these terrible stories and of course <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are denying it
 		and uh it's just frightening it really is
 	
 	
 		well what what's frightening is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> to see things that that you don't really understand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then you don't really know what happened we gave up on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> babysitter because we came home <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> and found
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		pieces of um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> ribbon you know hair ribbon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		tied in a chair
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		where obviously she had had
 		
 		
 	