
 
     		
 	
 		are you still there okay it worked that time okay
 	
 	
 		yes
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well we just ate out um had a big lunch actually because we both have been working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late</TIMEX> and we had <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um</ENAMEX> have you ever been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Olive Garden</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't is that good
 	
 	
 		it yeah well
 		do you really like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		it's it's not my favorite but i like it okay
 	
 	
 		then don't
 		then then this'll probably be i mean this isn't really excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that sounds terrible to tell you go go somewhere where it's not that great but it's um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're not going to believe this i have to tell you this if i don't because you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		that's okay
 	
 	
 		but my um  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> here  is acting like he's dying of tramane poison  it wasn't that bad  actually it's very good it's all the um for for run adult males
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which i'm not Italian no it's uh it's all the garlic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> and all the uh salads you can eat with uh an entree
 	
 	
 		oh oh oh that sounds really good
 	
 	
 		so it wasn't too bad it really wasn't but i was more in the mood for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> toast anyway so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but i really like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food though but do you have any favorite
 	
 	
 		well are there just the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of you
 	
 	
 		uh yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		okay well when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i go out we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so that makes a difference for us when we go out with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> obviously we want to go somewhere that we can the fast food ones are probably the ones they like the best
 	
 	
 		oh you're kidding
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		but we don't like to go there because that's the most expensive so we like to go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> place where you can buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> price and and feed the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> like that
 	
 	
 		yeah and you can usually get a variety of what you're looking for like at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gatti's</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		right
 		right but when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i go out we like to go somewhere with a little atmosphere and we usually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on down um oh what's the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX> down here
 	
 	
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six thirty five</TIMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah and there are um all along that that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeway</ENAMEX> there are are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> but one of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pappasito</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		oh yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pappasito</ENAMEX>'s we went there on my birthday in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> it's great
 	
 	
 		no we love to go there yeah
 		you know it always kills me because i don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">the decorations</ENAMEX> so much it's too
 	
 	
 		too much like a bar naturally and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> yeah i know i've seen it
 	
 	
 		yeah but i love the food i love the food they just are great
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is probably i'm not a i'm i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food gourmet by any means but it's probably the best tasting i i don't know if it would you classify that as Tex-Mex
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		um the shredded beef the the type of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spices</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauces</ENAMEX> they use
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh i like to get uh uh a shrimp uh it's a shrimp <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> and i don't remember the name of it but it's rolled up into into something and it oh it's really good that's good
 	
 	
 		every every
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i've never had anything there that wasn't delicious even
 	
 	
 		yeah they really good
 	
 	
 		even though you have to stand in line and all that that's the only thing i don't like about it too it's a little bit with the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> market atmosphere you know even though we don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we've been married long enough to um be around not to be around that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i'm trying to think of what else we like to eat the one thing i notice it's it's just um about dining out that you probably can relate to with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us getting ready to adopt i mean we find it prohibited just the cost anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		i mean lunch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was eighteen dollars
 	
 	
 		yeah it's very expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah and i don't know how you feel about that but i think some of it's over priced
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		i'm glad i'm talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> normally these conversations are
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sometimes it's hard isn't it to keep a
 	
 	
 		yeah it is i don't know um
 	
 	
 		no sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> and i that's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> uh go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Moon</ENAMEX> which is down there it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> in the front
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes that yeah off of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arapaho</ENAMEX> down there yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">August Moon</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh it's pretty good as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> goes but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> isn't my favorite so
 	
 	
 		i don't like it at all usually so
 	
 	
 		but he likes it kind of so he says that's a good place now me i'm i'm like i said seafood i'm i like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i love <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> and i i like a lot of different ethnic foods i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> food there's a place on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX> um called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sagar</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		uh
 		um
 	
 	
 		well we haven't been in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> down near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Presby</ENAMEX> and i had a meeting down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and i saw that and i i said gee i remember that they offer you um authentic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> feeding or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> or piano bar
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		and i remember when we went  we were married with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> that was just dating and um i had never had sake  it made all the raw fish taste great
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but if you're ever looking for a very uh it's very pretty inside and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> wear kimonos and you know if you're ever looking for that um but what other kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> gee i don't know um we went to a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grishman's</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenville</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is it oh how nice
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which was really over priced
 	
 	
 		i don't know that's
 		was it
 	
 	
 		um-hum but great desert bar
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um  that's what we need isn't it no there's lots of nice barbecue places here now i like barbecue okay <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> barbecue and that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i like barbecue have you ever been to the i think it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Spring Creek Barbecue</ENAMEX> yeah they have pretty good food yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah now they're real good yeah they're good
 	
 	
 		there had oh and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s going <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> and he said and free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX>  i didn't know they had that oh i can't talk i had chocolate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bavarian</ENAMEX> tort for desert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> which i never eat at lunch and it was wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah free <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> yeah
 		oh
 		is to die for i bet ooh
 	
 	
 		it was yeah in fact if i could pick my um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> on how their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> is and how their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> is and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> and the desert i would be
 	
 	
 		in heaven
 	
 	
 		yes i would be in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hog heaven</ENAMEX> and how are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> at an age where they can contribute to what they want or do you still order for them or
 	
 	
 		well my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> littlest i just had a baby and she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> and then my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> he he still but my other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> older <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> they can so they're they're they're
 	
 	
 		oh congratulations
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're kind of my my littlest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she's still like wants <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's McDonald's McDonald's</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah everybody every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that i even know that eats <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables um</ENAMEX>  below below <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX> still after a certain age realize that there is something called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i'm telling you
 	
 	
 		it's really sad isn't it because it's hard to get them away from junk then
 	
 	
 		well it's kind of funny is sometimes we're like we all want different things and so there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifteenth Avenue</ENAMEX> down here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i know where that yeah
 	
 	
 		and along that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> are all these fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> so we all get to go to our own little thing and drive through and get our own thing and then we go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> over there so we can all have our own that's on the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> we can't decide
 	
 	
 		right that's all
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well that's all right as long as that i was going to say because with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how do you um with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> we have a problem
 		i mean i can't even imagine you know trying to uh you sound like you're doing pretty well there with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i love them they're good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's the way to yeah well we're getting ready to i shouldn't say this on this conversation but it's just on my mind we're getting ready to go overseas to adopt
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh how nice
 	
 	
 		yeah we're excited
 	
 	
 		it'll be neat
 	
 	
 		i think it'll be worth it and somebody said to me in terms of  this is food so i can say this but they said you have to bring the formula and i said what's that
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they laughed and i said well you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>'s food
 	
 	
 		i'm thirty something and i and i said is that what makes them drool anyway you know i guess it are you is it a little bit constricted because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> don't take in terms of talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> i mean are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		how are they when you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> let alone <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you have to be careful if you go to a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> that that really is more adult you know with the atmosphere and everything they if you're like we could probably take our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and our oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they know how to act i don't i don't think i'd chance it with my younger ones because they're just too much of a distraction and some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> are really trying to go for that atmosphere kind of thing and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		the yuppie kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> yeah yeah i just i just i've been in some places where they say they take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and then i've just seen where the wait attendance the wait <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is rude you know and that always just bothered me um
 	
 	
 		what yeah
 		so
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		on the other hand sometimes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> are themselves  i don't know what other kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> really <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pappasito</ENAMEX>'s we love um we went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> back on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> we went to some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> across from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Collin Creek Mall</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it was absolutely putrid for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food i can't remember the name of it it's on um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tia</ENAMEX>'s not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tia</ENAMEX>'s um
 	
 	
 		i can't yeah no that's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> um it's right across from on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillard</ENAMEX>'s side there or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Folley</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		yeah i know which one it is and i can't think of it
 	
 	
 		i can't it's in the strip yeah and it it had white tablecloth i think it was like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> where you could write on them or something with crayons and it was just terrible
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh dear
 	
 	
 		i mean i was shocked i mean the dish was dirty um
 	
 	
 		it's one of those ones you have a bad experience and say i don't think i'll come back here
 	
 	
 		yeah where you felt like you were
 		right like you're in a bad part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy Italy</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah oh dear oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um boy</ENAMEX> but other than that i don't know we we do our share of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX> eating too
 		but it's more like uh go get it and carry it in because we're too cheap to pay the delivery  and i don't like strange <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming to my door um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah yeah yeah
 		well i i've about said what what what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> were and i can't really think of any other uh
 	
 	
 		me too
 		no except it just makes me fat no i'm just kidding but you can
 	
 	
 		places
 		uh yeah you have to watch it if you go out to eat that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true but you can always blame it on having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> no
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah there you go
 	
 	
 		well i enjoyed talking to you and i guess you know
 	
 	
 		well good luck
 	
 	
 		maybe we'll see you in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> somewhere okay uh-huh bye bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yeah maybe okay bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	