
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		what uh what baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> do you follow
 	
 	
 		i follow i've been a long time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cincinnati Reds</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> because when i was growing up and i was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX> i wanted to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> so i was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Bench</ENAMEX> fan
 		so i was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Johnny Bench</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> so i've been through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> since you know nineteen seventy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Seventy World Series</ENAMEX> like i said i was only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX> then but i had to give a report to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every</TIMEX> because that was when they played <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> games in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> sometimes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		i've kind of gotten away from them until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> because i didn't really know many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but i also being from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> area i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX>
 		so i kind of follow those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a little bit and you know since moving down here the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> you know i've been picking up on them a little bit
 		and uh
 		it looks like they could do all right <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and uh of course they're in there with the right <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX> i believe and they're in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX> headed for probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another good year</TIMEX> i hope what about yourself
 	
 	
 		oh i guess mainly the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> such as they are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they do seem to have a pretty tough division though with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX> all uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		jammed in there
 	
 	
 		yeah do you go to a lot of games
 	
 	
 		oh i get to i don't know quite a few in the summer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's i've been looking forward to it i've only been to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> game
 		and i just moved down here at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of last summer</TIMEX> so that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX> was winding down so i'm hopefully i'll uh get to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple this year</TIMEX> i want to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan</ENAMEX> pitch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time
 		that that's be that'd be really neat
 	
 	
 		yeah it looked like they're starting off kind of shaky but they they've gone i guess over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred</NUMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i was hoping that no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hitter</ENAMEX> that he threw would would get them fired up a little bit
 	
 	
 		it might
 	
 	
 		but it's hard hard to tell
 	
 	
 		did they uh play today
 	
 	
 		uh i was trying to think they were up in a stand at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if they're playing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> or not
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right that's right
 		yeah i watched a little bit of the i was flipping back and forth between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the Pacers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was on today
 		i i just like i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX> i've never really got into them and then this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine was just a hard core <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX> so he took me to a game and you know i think they're you know they're really neat because they're such a young team
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		actually the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and they got some
 		you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three or four years</TIMEX> their number one picks you know they're all suited up and playing for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and the draft and uh
 		you got to like that you know building the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> through draft picks and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah it says a lot for their future
 	
 	
 		yeah it does hopefully some of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> will come through and they got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Raines</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> and they got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlton Fisk</ENAMEX> he's you know still pretty solid a lot of experience
 		but uh
 		uh you like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Astros</ENAMEX> or anything like that
 	
 	
 		oh i don't really follow them a whole lot um i i hear about them occasionally i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> whose a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX> for one of their farm clubs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think so  we hear off and on about them they've never really done a whole lot i mean they're up and down kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> are  most of the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well when was the last time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> really did well
 	
 	
 		it's been probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four years</TIMEX> since they were i think they finished <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> i don't remember what they ended up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year third or fourth</TIMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three or fours years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah they have been off and on uh maybe maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> times since they've been here
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i never really followed them all i knew uh
 		kind of watched them a little bit in the seventies there again you know cause i was a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> in baseball i liked to watch a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sundberg</ENAMEX> and uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Burroughs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh forget who else used to play for them but uh yeah those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were were really tough
 	
 	
 		well they've been like a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and the minute they do real badly in the past they just got got rid of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX>'s the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> they've had in on you know any kind of length of time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so hopefully he'll eventually put something together
 	
 	
 		you think he's pretty good
 	
 	
 		i i can't  i don't know uh sometimes i think he is and sometimes i wonder
 	
 	
 		yeah i was watching the game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and they had had bases loaded
 		and they tried a uh a squeeze play
 		and uh i just couldn't understand that i forget whose who was batting and but uh
 		i don't know i just
 		i couldn't understand that move there was only one out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's like you know give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> a cut you know you got bases loaded you know one mistake cause a lot of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> aren't used to bunting that much and it's a easy double play
 	
 	
 		yeah true
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		i guess i was feeling pretty confident about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine this year</TIMEX> until uh he got mad at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Incaviglia</ENAMEX> and just cut him for because he was upset at him
 	
 	
 		you didn't like that move
 	
 	
 		well i i can understand his point i thought it was kind of childish to just cut him instead of trying to trade him because then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Detroit</ENAMEX> picks him up
 		and he started out real good for them and he he's gotten kind of shaky now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think they should have at least gotten something for him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's true
 		what about uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra</ENAMEX> you a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruben Sierra</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he's been around what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think so yeah
 	
 	
 		you think you can see him staying there for awhile or
 	
 	
 		yeah i think i think as long as he produces he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX> they they run kind of hot and cold too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX> hit a home run was it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to win the game
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i'd i turned the game on i don't know who won
 	
 	
 		i think they won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and i think that was on his he hit a home run at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> and broke the tie up
 	
 	
 		well good
 		yeah i'm kind of into <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> cards so uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i was buying a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Gonzalez</ENAMEX> cards
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so i'm hoping he's going to blossom and make me a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> someday
 	
 	
 		yeah  that'd be nice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> have the the pitching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> they need if they would just produce some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> they might do all right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i'm definitely looking forward to going to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few</NUMEX> games <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> that's good entertainment at a budget price
 	
 	
 		yeah you said you were a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> has uh all this brouhah a with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Rose</ENAMEX> over the years
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		caused caused you any distaste for them or
 	
 	
 		no you mean like
 		no
 		i mean
 		thing about rose i mean you know that he's got a problem in his personal life i just
 		you know he he messed up but i still think he's belongs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know he played for so many so well for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> that
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh it's just too bad it's you know like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> that do <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or do you know are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX> they just have a problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's too bad it carried over and has hurt his image and everything else
 	
 	
 		well but it didn't didn't seem to really hurt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in fact seemed to kind of fire them up and make them work harder
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		after he was gone
 	
 	
 		yeah i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Pinella</ENAMEX> is doing a good job too obviously
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he knows you know he's
 		you know he's been there he's played a lot of ball himself
 		so he's been in some <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX> and you know he's
 		a lot of experience as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> and it looks like he's doing all right as a manager
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		thanks for this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've ever been called so it's kind of interesting yeah i usually get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and pick up the phone and do some calling so uh
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		but i appreciate your calling
 	
 	
 		sure i enjoyed talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all right take care
 	
 	
 		you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	