
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well i heard <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is pretty bad with the crime
 	
 	
 		well you know you last night i was listening to the uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock</TIMEX> news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first five to seven</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> of a news broadcast all they were talking about was the number of shootings the number of drug deals that were going on and crime and and it's so depressing just to even listen to the news anymore
 	
 	
 		um-hum the same way here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dennison</ENAMEX> i mean uh back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks ago</TIMEX> they found uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i don't remember at some fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> they had been i can't remember if they been shot or if they just been thrown in the freezer but i'm pretty sure they'd been shot and put the freezer at the fast food restaurant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i've worked in fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> they don't have that much money on hand they really don't
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i did too i remember used i used to work at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Fried Chicken</ENAMEX> and uh and i just couldn't believe um you know that now i would hate to work at a fast food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> or even have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> work in one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh because of the the crime that they would uh just kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just for the few <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple hundred</NUMEX> dollars that they would have in there uh in their cash drawer
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		right my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> worked at a gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> when he was a teenager
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he well i don't know he decided not to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> or something and one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that
 		was working was shot and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenny</ENAMEX> quit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> he just he couldn't deal with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah oh i understand what your talking about
 		so yeah i have uh uh you know a real problem uh even though i live further out in the suburbs the crime follows you anywhere it it doesn't matter if you live in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or if you live in a large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> like this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		everywhere
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um so but i just think about all the different ways that we have to protect ourselves from
 	
 	
 		it just seems like a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are attracted to the bigger cities though the worst part of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville Kentucky</ENAMEX> for a while i i lived on the outskirts too but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> was pretty bad especially during like the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Derby</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of the year</TIMEX> it's horrible to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum um-hum yeah so i don't know um you know it's asking about what kind of steps we can take um
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		uh you know just as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> to try and um uh protect ourselves i know i have um you know a home security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> plus i have the uh the special lights uh on on the outside and i have this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the ones that blink off and on for the self i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah that uh
 		yeah yeah by themselves uh if you if there's some kind of movement then they'll automatically come on um but i mean it's just that i constantly think about keeping us safe and protected verses um
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two two</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of each um-hum yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh that's what i've got it is scary are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> are they babies or
 	
 	
 		no no they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		oh well good that they're a comfort to you i've still got babies i've got
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i've got a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four a four year old</TIMEX> he'll be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and a three month old</TIMEX> and it's scary  sometimes
 	
 	
 		oh wow yes that's a problem yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm used to living in uh which we don't live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> but we just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's still more crowded than what i'm used to i'm used to having you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and this one's got <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> on either side and you know real close together and just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's different yeah living down here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> now the nice thing uh i feel a little bit more comfort since we're so close together like this um
 		uh i feel like that there's going to be uh less crime or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> going to be watching out for you um because it's it's practically it's in their backyard too
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh oh well we think our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> are stealing from us actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 		they uh
 		well the one of them's a teenager lives next door and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are pretty wild
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they've stolen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> out of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and well he went and got a locking gas cap for his they weren't stealing it out of mine so much because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> the gas thing is kind of weird where it's hard to siphon <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so he went he went and got a locking gas cap and they cut tried to break that off he
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uba</ENAMEX> and noticed that it was hanging off where they had tried to break it off and they stole our tailgate off his truck
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh goodness
 	
 	
 		well we can't say they did but
 	
 	
 		someone did yeah
 	
 	
 		we're pretty yeah
 		it had to be somebody that you know could do it in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> and you know they'd seen it earlier
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum yeah i know that uh it's uh it's a real problem it doesn't matter really where you are anymore it's uh more of a matter of what you the steps that you do to keep yourself safe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um so that's that's what i try and uh do
 	
 	
 		well the only things that we can do as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> is you know like those uh watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that they'll have walking but they can be dangerous too and i've thought about it you know uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		really uh-huh
 	
 	
 		this isn't like walking around and looking for somebody you can get yourself into trouble
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you know i was uh going home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and i saw um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who who looked like he was breaking into a window and i thought gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> you know i don't know if he's really doing that or not or if he's the he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who lives there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know and and i was thinking well i need to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> when i get back home and because it was about oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four or five</NUMEX> blocks from where we live and uh and i thought no you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i wouldn't know if that was really a robber or not because it was in broad daylight but anymore you know the crime happens in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daylight</TIMEX> as it does in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i watched it on TV oh i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> sometime they'll break in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the day</TIMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i hear that you know it if if you lock yourself out of your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and you try to get in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> it'll you give that half the time it takes you to break in uh a professional could break in in in half that time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> that time wow and that's so scary so scary you you think you've got yourself all locked in and safe and and uh somebody could break in a nd uh well i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that's the one thing that i like is
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 		uh-huh i'm getting me uh i want a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> Shepherd um i don't want any of those ones that will  up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but i do want a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shepherd</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'ll leave every once in a while for he works on the railroad and i'm scared here by myself so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah oh yeah so that's another uh we just a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> now but he is just as vicious as if you know if you if somebody and loud
 	
 	
 		and loud
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know and i thought that uh you know we'd have to have a big dog but we don't need a big dog we got this little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bitty dog</ENAMEX> that uh part <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dachshunds</ENAMEX> and part uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cocker Spaniel</ENAMEX> and he um he's very protective
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cocker Spaniels</ENAMEX> are loud  well there
 	
 	
 		yeah very protective
 	
 	
 		now that's one of the best deterrents for a robber is a noisy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s got a noisy <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that's a deterrent because they know that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>'s going to bark
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		but it's easy to fool a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> too you know throw them <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it's a real intense burglar can just get another <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that's in heat
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		from what i've hear you know saw on TV
 	
 	
 		um-hum oh wow gosh well it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah it was
 	
 	
 		okay well
 	
 	
 		and uh maybe we'll meet up again alrighty bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	