
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you have any particular thoughts about the school system
 	
 	
 		well um i
 		i think that in in uh recently with the i'm not sure if it's more a problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> or a problem with the school system they seem to be burdening the school system more and more with
 		problems any problems that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> might have whether it's actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> related thing or not and i
 	
 	
 		i say agree with you a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> percent there
 	
 	
 		yeah and and well it's gotten to a point where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are expected to take care of everything
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		if uh you've some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who doesn't have uh
 		who's from a broken family the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are supposed to fill that void it's gotten way beyond teaching uh
 		you know teaching classes and uh maybe providing extracurricular sports activities or something like oh were kind of traditionally the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s roles
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's interesting because uh we're just having conversation on this uh with a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> and i was expressing my frustrations that uh
 		some of the so many problems i  i work in a high school are that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't have a a degree uh a of self-discipline which may be reflected
 		in society at large uh and you can't expect in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> for a particular course an hour a day to counteract uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen or seventeen years</TIMEX> of influence at home
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and it's seen more so because when you call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> up many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> won't even recognize
 		that there is a problem and  will say they'll say oh well our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i've never heard anything about this before this is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time there have been problems and
 		and you say don't these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> talk and you know we do check with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> find the same things for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and you know how do you tell your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX>'s the parent hey wake up and smell the coffee
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um it it is a problem and i'm not sure just uh how how the school system could operate in a vacuum on it whether maybe through a commitment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> being informed better that in fact that the problems that are nationwide
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		are are problems um of society and that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> can only do so much on it
 	
 	
 		well then then again when you have uh a society where a certain percentage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are uh doing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in the home uh either unemployed and don't care about a uh just a have their own problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		how how do you expect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to um or how do you expect the you can't really expect that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> who's quite frankly a loser in life as it is to to care about the the situation with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		that's right um-hum
 		
 
 		you know what scares me too is that we have yet to see uh the biggest effect of the crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh in the school system these are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are born with low deficit attention deficit and gosh what's going to happen when these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> start coming into the school system that that's really scary
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but there are i think there are a couple of areas where the school system can improve and this is something that i see too many times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> get
 		diagnosed as  slow learners and in fact they're not they're behavior problems
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so they get put in in in our school system in a class that's limited for skills <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that have really have to master skills and that's not their problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um at the same time i've seen we we have a
 		uh an international population there's no bridge area for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESOL</ENAMEX> which is <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Speakers of Other Languages</ENAMEX> program the once they're past ESOL they get out they got thrown right into the total mainstream
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh there really needs to be a bridge some sort of transition
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		for that so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> can improve both in standing up for splitting classes you know having learning disabled learning slow slow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in slow classes but not mixing them with behavior problems
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then you know the case where they put the behavior problems in the average classes you get these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> but highly motivated
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then you throw in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are not motivated maybe bright but they're discipline problems and you sometimes the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> really
 		are problems because you've got such a mixed bag there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know the gifted and talented are fast classes there's really not that much of a problem with but it's
 	
 	
 		well i i've seen more uh incredibly intelligent intelligent underachievers than than uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i personally i will i would take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's motivated and a little uh less intelligent than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who uh is one of these very intelligent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who just kind of
 	
 	
 		that's yeah
 	
 	
 		isn't motivated to do anything
 	
 	
 	
 	
 		yeah well i i not to toot my own horn here or anything but i i was graduated from my high school i was the valedictorian and i know that there were a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that were an awful lot smarter than me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they proved out like when it came time to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SATs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> were good but they weren't great and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when i got into college i struggled i struggled just to uh get my degree in the in the field that i was in whereas i knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> were kind of lazy and all but they got motivated in college and they did a lot better than i did and when it
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> do mature at different ages too that's and you know as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> you you try to make be understanding that you know there are different ages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are is
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that's just a question of maturity or is he problem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are asked to diagnose so much
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		um there i mean i mean we're have to be we're alerted there's all sorts of systems where suicide
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> predisposition i mean we're alerted to what the moment we see something if we see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that we have any reason that's on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> such as if he's got a beeper or
 		if they're if they're flashing lots of money around we've there are certain things to do i mean so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> the school system's asked to do so much but you can't operate in a vacuum
 	
 	
 		you actually have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with with beepers
 	
 	
 		this is a we're in a rather wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> with a beeper immediately gets sent down to the uh principal
 	
 	
 		i mean where what are the what could they possibly be thinking i mean how
 	
 	
 		it's for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use they can't imagine for anything else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you you know it's it's amazing but uh you get all sorts you get all all sorts of things uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> uh uh and it's
 		and you know as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> you're alert you're alert for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who's very drowsy you're alert to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who suddenly has a um behavioral change and you refer them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so i mean you have to find out whether there's a legitimate reason  or whether this is a warning signal
 	
 	
 		yeah can you how can you  how can you expect to
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> frequently resent when you ask them is there a problem that we should be aware of
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i i was uh sitting in the barber <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> i'm i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and i was having my hair cut
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the barber uh got a call while i was there uh from his son's school his son's in high school and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was failing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">gym</ENAMEX> and uh and having trouble with a few other things but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know it's like uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was like why now there's no problem with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and all this the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> had missed all these classes and basically he his answer was oh i gave him permission to to miss
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah the denial mechanism is really strong and so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are facilitators i mean they're manipulated by their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i've been fortunate i have uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who's a sophomore in college up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amherst</ENAMEX> and my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is a senior in high school and he's going on to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> and i mean they're really super they're both national level swimmers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and where we've been very fortunate but you know they had to be held accountable too i mean you know at some point a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> does help their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> but in in some ways but but you have to say at what point isn't the help becoming negative
 	
 	
 		right
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and i think this is where the school system uh is suffering and not through any fault of the effort of the school system
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but gee it was good talking with you
 	
 	
 		it was good talking to you too
 	
 	
 		yeah so there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that feel the same ways that you do and and are connected with the schools
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i've had interesting conversations on several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> not uh
 		not just this but different the different things it's amazing how the you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you talk to have some interesting conversations and uh it's too bad that all this stuff is just being thrown into a data base and that none of the ideas or thoughts are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		being used at all
 	
 	
 		well we are both  listen good luck take care bye-bye
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true all right yep bye-bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	