
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all right wasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> um arrested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> abuse or was it somebody else
 	
 	
 		
  
 		no that was <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> yeah it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC  i</ENAMEX> couldn't figure out if well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koch</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> isn't he okay
 	
 	
 		yes he is
 		but it was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berry</ENAMEX> uh yeah but my i i guess my feeling on drug testing in the work place i am <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent for it
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berry</ENAMEX>
 		oh i am too yeah so we got nothing to disagree about
 	
 	
 		you are um
 		yeah i know and um it it i a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know have a problem with the random testing like why should i be tested and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> not tested but the point is is that nobody should
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they can't test everybody
 	
 	
 		right and that you know it's it's
 		it's illegal i mean maybe if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> were legal then this would be all different but <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are illegal and therefore it shouldn't be it it should be the law that we're able to test for something that is illegal
 	
 	
 		right
 		well
 		right and most of your work places it can be dangerous if somebody's drugged using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's for sure
 	
 	
 		especially school i don't think there should be any kind of limits set on school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> being tested
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i agree
 	
 	
 		bus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> you know that commercial with the you know they show a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> doing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> or something and then you think it doesn't affect you and then you see her she's driving the school bus
 	
 	
 		right yes oh i love that commercial i know that one's really powerful
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it pulls at you
 	
 	
 		but you know it's true um not even the interaction with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like one on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but well i guess this relates to the school bus but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouses</ENAMEX> that are driving forklifts you know that um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there there could be some serious accidents
 	
 	
 		i know it just well and like at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> do you work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's really that's a shame
 		no i don't
 	
 	
 		okay well at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> you're messing with all of those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> and stuff and if you mix the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> or whatever it can put out toxic fumes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what is the policy at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> do you have to be drug tested or
 	
 	
 		well um i worked there for a while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manpower</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> and i was tested before i even started
 	
 	
 		oh that's where i work i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manpower</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		you do yeah where are you working at then
 	
 	
 		well i i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manpower</ENAMEX> i mean i'm a surv i supervise the office yeah huh so you were a  a  temporary working at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> oh neat
 	
 	
 		oh okay uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and i well i quit when i found out i was pregnant i was just really scared of messing with the chemicals
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah i don't blame you
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh TI</ENAMEX> is strict on their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> but they don't really
 		um
 		i don't know i just wasn't didn't feel safe messing around it
 	
 	
 		um-hum but you had to be drug tested before you could work the
 	
 	
 		oh yeah before yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manpower</ENAMEX> did it so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's interesting um here you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> is the the big name in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rochester Kodak</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what is that
 		what is that oh the film the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		what is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak Kodak</ENAMEX> yeah the film right no it's okay but um
 		i mean in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> everything is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> but you know but half the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> here works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> and um usually they set the trends and originally um it was only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were working in the industrial
 		type of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities facilities</ENAMEX> that needed to be drug tested because they felt that if they were using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they would be the most dangerous versus <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who probably
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know you know what they they never saw what sort of um
 		you know problem they could have if they were using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i guess i don't know but um just in nineteen i guess it was nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nine</NUMEX> they started testing everybody
 		so now anybody whether you want to go in and work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> or be
 	
 	
 		can they spot test you
 	
 	
 		yes they can but they can't do it more than once a year i think you you can't be tested more than once a year
 	
 	
 		okay
 		hum
 	
 	
 		would they spot test at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah they'll do it anytime i'm i'm not sure what limits they set on it but i know that you had like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> to go in and do it between the time you were told and the time you had to go be tested
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum oh well
 		um-hum that's good
 		well um the thing you know you brought up about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berry</ENAMEX> i uh you've probably seen the clip on the news the one where he's um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		going into that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and and making the deal with somebody did you see that well the you know he got
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		he got acquitted or whatever the term is but the yeah that he was um the charges were removed that to me is so
 	
 	
 		acquitted
 		it's political
 	
 	
 		oh i know and it's so absurd because now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are going to see that and say oh look he got off the hook i'll get off the hook too you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well in that uh book that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Kitty Kitty</ENAMEX> whatever wrote saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> can you see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> being tested  no he wouldn't be tested
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		oh i know
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		which i don't know how true that is but i thought that was kind of funny yeah but
 	
 	
 		really well i think everybody should i think it should become just a a standard law
 	
 	
 		but well even office workers i mean you could play with computers and lose what all kinds of information if you're just not careful  i'm not even uh
 	
 	
 		sure yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		all that great with computers but i know just one mistake you can lose the whole record or i can't even remember the word program yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		program yeah
 		but um i think that your point about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> is um probably the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place to start because they're the ones that are influencing
 		the new generation you know that are going to become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working in those companies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 		when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started looking for work there wasn't any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing and i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty six now</TIMEX> and it seems like they've always every every job you go for you have to be tested
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think i think that's good see i've never used <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> personally so
 	
 	
 		um-hum no me either
 	
 	
 		and i don't really want to be under the influence of somebody that is especially i could see a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> going nuts because well they do go freak out over anything you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh i know it's crazy it makes me so upset to hear about all these movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and you know TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> that have gone through some sort of rehabilitation and because um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess those those those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so glorified you know they're the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the sitcoms</TIMEX> on TV that's like perfection and then to find out that um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J Fox</ENAMEX> you know went through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> of using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> you
 	
 	
 		right
 		he did i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		yeah he did i just read an article about that um it it just shatters my whole feeling about him and and then i just think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that glorify him or the you know just idealize him or whoever
 	
 	
 		right
 		well most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> growing up in entertainment business do have troubles because they're in on the fast lane or whatever yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and they have the money you know they don't have to worry about where they're going to get the money to pay for it yeah
 	
 	
 		where they're going to get the money to do it
 		right but even if you don't have the money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that really want <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> will finds the money somehow
 	
 	
 		unfortunately yeah
 	
 	
 		while i was in college uh college i did a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> on that just how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people criminals</ENAMEX> has got drug problems you know it's just one of the major
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		reasons they're out to break into peoples <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and whatever yeah
 	
 	
 		um-hum right exactly exactly it takes over i even um i forget if it was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> or something where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> are even getting drugs
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but that's always been going on
 	
 	
 		i i know and isn't that insane i mean how does that happen it just doesn't make since to me
 	
 	
 		well from watching TV they'll put it in the the women'll put it in their bras or in their mouth and kiss the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> or whatever if they can get a touch visit or whatever it's called it's wild
 	
 	
 		uh
 		God
 		it really is crazy
 	
 	
 		i wonder if they get drug tested in uh uh prison
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		now i know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> for awhile well he's in it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> they had urine tests all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and but they get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to do it for them
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what do you mean they get people
 	
 	
 		all right say just per se my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that you know knew that a pee test was coming up he would ask my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to do it for him  i mean not that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> did it but oh yeah
 	
 	
 		oh my God yeah are you serious and and it would actually work like they could get away with it
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah because well because most of the time it was one of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> heading it up because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was like he was an E5 which is uh acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> and he would uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm not saying my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> did it but he's told me it's went on but his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> would be coming through the line hey <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX> i can't do this can you do it for me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and like i said it's all of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contemporaries</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s there so he just you know he was in command or whatever so you know that happens that happens a i'm sure that happens a lot
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh gosh that is really scary it's really scary to think that uh some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that were over
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's not a lot of them because not all of them have the nerve to do it so
 	
 	
 		right that's true but it could just take one that that's in charge of a gun a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cannon</ENAMEX> or a gun or something you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well yeah now most of the time if they're fire well no they can do fire on practice ranges but there's usually lots of room for it too but if you get caught you get busted out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and they can send you to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leavenworth</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		right
 		they can where
 	
 	
 		you know not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> Leavenworth isn't it Leavenworth that the
 	
 	
 		that is that a prison oh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah it's i think it's a government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> for um like treason and or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i see
 		wow
 	
 	
 		the base my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> was on had a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> of their own which they they they're pretty strict in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> i mean you get caught doing much of anything you get busted  so a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> won't do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well they need to be pretty
 		
 		
 	