
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh all right i had to register us in there
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh hopefully you're a basketball fan
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		hopefully you're a basketball fan
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		great i'm glad you are i'm not i i i could care about any of it you know  but go ahead i i would like to talk about uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		maybe college basketball i i like to see it
 		uh be more of an amateur sport i'd like to see it turn back to like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwest Conference</ENAMEX> down here i would like to see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> uh since we're supposed to talk about specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 		i would like to see them turn back to
 		where the college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> plays for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> and they're not they're not semi pro and just go on and are stolen by the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> the the League you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> plus i'd like to see them to be true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> where they're they're taking a regular
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		college course you know i'd like to see they didn't ask that but they're talking about college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> i you know since you're being you can talk for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> go ahead you you you if you like sports go right ahead with this one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		um well
 		i know like what you just said um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> had to had to uh
 		their best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">player</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this years</TIMEX> you know averaged <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> points a game they had to make him sit the bench and actually kicked him off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> because um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		his uh grades even though they passed Big Ten standings and they passed you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC</ENAMEX> double A they weren't they did not pass um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> requirements and so
 	
 	
 		now that's surprising that they uh that they have better requirements that's good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's what i like to see go ahead i'm all for that
 	
 	
 		and see so he was treated like all the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		and and so um you know their very best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> they probably lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> their games because
 		you know by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty</TIMEX> points was what he averaged um and so you know he had to sit
 		you know he was kicked off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and then they've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> top you know recruiting class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that are going to have to be
 		well the the prep school they go to before they can play because they aren't smart enough you know it's just sad because i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> even though they're one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that really uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		stress <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> they're really suffering you know and
 	
 	
 		oh i i agree i i think that that there's a lot of inconsistencies uh
 		uh when some conference uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> come from outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> you know and and play us here uh they're obviously plus practicing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty hours a week</TIMEX> you know and and there's no consistency seems to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> uh uh when they're trying a student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> is spending so many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> in class he only has <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty five whatever hours</TIMEX> he has
 		to spend on practice he should be playing they all should be playing another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that that has about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty hours</TIMEX> to practice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> but uh you there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that practices <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty hours a week</TIMEX> they're not going to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		like
 	
 	
 		i mean that's that's what i mean by semi pro there's too many semi <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> in college and and i think they ought to get rid of that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's what happened to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i mean he was uh
 		he didn't go to class and so they just said you know you can't make the grades you're going to have to see you later
 	
 	
 		well i'm all for i'm all for the oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> has a uh a uh minor league system and i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and basketball they asked us to talk about basketball
 		should you know let let them go have a semi <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro team</ENAMEX> but i think i'd like to see college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> let's talk about college basketball i like i like that if any basketball that i like i like that i i don't i don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't either it's
 	
 	
 		uh the high scoring there's no defense it seems like and they just kind of score <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and twenty five</NUMEX> points you know the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> scores <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty two</TIMEX> you know and i don't really
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh get much out of that
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 		yeah it is fun to watch some real disciplined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> play in a in college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> i think it was or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and they're they're like all white and their starting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh it did
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it was so funny to watch them play against the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> because it was like they played so much smarter and more disciplined i don't know if they won very many games but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know their style of play was so much different from some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that just run and gun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i like high school football which again again is is not the subject but that's so much fun to watch because they're they're the the pure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amateurs</ENAMEX> you know and there's no money involved you go to college you don't really know it it loses it somewhere
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh whatever sport it is if they're really putting putting a lot of money in these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> let's face it <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> are being paid
 		so i'd like to see college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and all the other sports go back to being <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amateurs</ENAMEX> i i don't care about seeing the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in the world play i like to see uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> just play and the ones that are in class and and like to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students students</ENAMEX> fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> like myself you know to to play the game i i in fact i like amateur sports i i don't i don't see it has to be i don't think that college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football football</ENAMEX> and or or basketball should have to be semi pro you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's
 	
 	
 		i wish it'd return to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the to good old days</TIMEX> of the amateur and everybody play that's what i like everybody should play you know
 	
 	
 		i'm kind of racist i guess when i say uh i like to see the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> do well you know  instead of the run and gun all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah well again i'd just like to see the the true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> the student true true true student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> you know i don't like to see the ones that aren't have no intention of going to class uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and again just picking a school uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh is
 		is usually not the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> you know because the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are i'm sure practice a lot more and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SMU</ENAMEX> down here
 	
 	
 		in fact
 	
 	
 		in in footballs been trying to get back uh to having true student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student student athletes</ENAMEX> and and that's what i think is a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		there's just so much pressure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i think to win though you know that
 	
 	
 		to win and get and money yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and you know if it's like if they don't win they don't get any money so it's and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> suffers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is kind of bad but that's just how it always is
 	
 	
 		yeah i always thought that college university
 		was to to for an education and then sports sports of course is part of the education i don't think that sports has to make a lot of money or you do away with it i don't know why they don't keep fencing and all that you know and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and they seem to be there's articles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> and all that about whether it be basketball or anything else if it's not making money then we'll do away with it well that's that's not i thought it was you know so that you give them an education of that particular discipline
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i and i i just think that amateur sports should stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> that's where it's at
 		and i i'm sure saddened to see i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> or somewhere they were getting rid of fencing and a couple of other things i don't know what it was and it just seems so sad to have to only rely on
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		you know college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> is that all they're going to have to make money you know plus i didn't think that was the objective was to make money but it seems like it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh it really is i know there's a lot of pressure on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to have a winning program
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to get the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> so they can keep their seats full
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana University University</ENAMEX> oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Purdue</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		well good uh you're you're a TIer up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> oh very good
 	
 	
 		so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> down here down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> is the big sport down here isn't it
 	
 	
 		uh certainly high school <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> but again high high school football uh is just so much fun to watch because uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		uh you know just not everybody plays of course but they're still uh it's good and it's still you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and there's absolutely no money involved whatsoever and you know they're going to class you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it's just real amateur sports
 	
 	
 		have you heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon Bailey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the IU uh white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> that plays well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when he was in high school uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they drew a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like forty one thousand</NUMEX> for the state finals when he played
 	
 	
 		is that right  that's uh i never has been in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball uh football game</ENAMEX> in high school that had that many
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah  so that's uh i mean that's pretty big like he's from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and he plays for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indiana State</ENAMEX>  seems to be a lot bigger than pro basketball up there the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pacers</ENAMEX> don't really draw that big of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> but you know the college the high school games i mean that seems seems to be the big attraction and college
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well my office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> here <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Earl</ENAMEX> he he goes to all the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Maverick games</ENAMEX> and he loves that he he would be this would be great question for him uh to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> like he's got i'm looking at his calendar he's got all over the place uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he goes to a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Maverick games</ENAMEX> and everything and but i i i can't get interested at all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> i i listen to him and occasionally i'll watch them on channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but uh gee i can't uh more than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> game just seems about that's it of uh uh pro anyway uh of
 	
 	
 		yeah seems like you could set the st the score at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and then give them <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> to play and then it'd be the same result you know because they they start they shoot so much and then the last
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> they decide who's going to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i'm surprised a little bit when you're talking about basketball how some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> work and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mavericks</ENAMEX> had
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that they got rid of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i'll think of them in a minute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perkins Sam Perkins</ENAMEX> can't think of the other one they're both
 	
 	
 		Tarpley
 		is he one Tarpley
 	
 	
 		pardon me yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarpley</ENAMEX> and they both left <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX> and both of them were on were on play-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> uh
 		so they they benefitted tremendously by by leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Perkins</ENAMEX> here uh
 		he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i did follow from think he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> i can't think of what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> he went to but from i guess he's been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five six seven years</TIMEX> in the pros
 		and he was he never quite achieved the you know the super stardom that he had in in in college but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		basketball they have a nice i don't know if you've been down to the sports for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Reunion Arena</ENAMEX> it's really a nice uh certainly the
 		
 		
 	