
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i have what uh about yourself
 	
 	
 		well uh a few i guess uh
 		i was trying to think  as i was asking you just exactly what movies i had seen recently i i took my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> to see one uh
 		oh my goodness i can't you tell me first because i can't think right now
 	
 	
 		yeah i i should because i've been waiting for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> to talk uh interesting interestingly enough
 		i had the same topic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> when i called so i've got my spiel down
 	
 	
 		you mean you had the same topic twice um
 	
 	
 		uh-huh twice in a row <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time it's happened to me but uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		let's see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i went to see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Kindergarten Cop</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh now that was great we saw that too
 	
 	
 		yeah that was it was it was pretty cool
 	
 	
 		it's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i've seen him do a uh a comedy almost type show
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		which is kind of a a change for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah now that was a good show my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i enjoyed that a lot i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> did too we didn't go together though
 	
 	
 		oh they went another time though
 	
 	
 		yeah they well i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> runs around i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> runs around with one his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> runs around with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> i think both of them separately saw it at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different times even with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and then mom and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> went to see it when it went to the dollar and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> movie house
 	
 	
 		yeah well fortunately we have a dollar movie here so i
 	
 	
 		they used to be a dollar here but it finally went up
 	
 	
 		oh i hope doesn't i think they're hedging to but uh i don't want them anyway it was worth uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bucks for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i to go
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah it was good show really was uh we went to see uh The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> i think it's The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Jo</ENAMEX> and i did
 	
 	
 		so
 		okay
 	
 	
 		that's the one that uh oh i forget the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s name that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> on TV
 		oh what's that yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodman</ENAMEX> and uh that was funny now that was really a good show
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodman</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i mean it wasn't a great show it's just a B movie but it was fun i think uh i think uh you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> would enjoy that it's pretty light hearted humor and and and it was uh it was kind of neat kind of cute
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> worth of laughs
 	
 	
 		oh it was definitely worth that it it was worth couple of bucks just to get out and watch that and it was upbeat movie and everything else
 		and uh you know uh eat the popcorn and all that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's where they make the money is on the popcorn anyway they charge ridiculous prices they charge more for the popcorn than they do for the movie
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King</ENAMEX> huh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's called The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> or something like that it's it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Goodman</ENAMEX> i think it's you know and he's the main star in the whole movie
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and it's got a  <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple</NUMEX> pretty good uh supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		and uh it's funny it it really is
 		uh you know we uh rather enjoyed trying to think of a couple of others that we went to see that we went to see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> movie i can't remember the name of it now though but it was uh
 		oh what was it i can't remember it's just terrible
 		anyway i i long time back uh uh for the benefit at least of the subject we're discussing i went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Hard Two i</ENAMEX> guess it was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Die Harder</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that was a scream and you know i thought that was pretty good and um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know i can't think of another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other than that at the moment how about you
 	
 	
 		well uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has a problem with uh
 		she can't suspend her disbelief of a movie like she'll sit there and say that won't happen that can't happen there's no way you know so it's kind of hard for me to pick like a uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		like if we would go see a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Von Dame</ENAMEX> movie and he runs around the screen for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and half</TIMEX> just kicking teeth you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he she'd be like no he he couldn't do that you can't beat up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> at once with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so she can't really enjoy it
 	
 	
 		yeah so she can't even enjoy it but i think we're working on her a little bit where she just sits back and takes the movie at what it is
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we've been working uh a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we've been you know we'll go to like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Segal</ENAMEX> or we haven't went to Segal yet we're going to and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Damme</ENAMEX> and like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		like like the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Blood</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> just did a comedy incidentally that uh i think's out now
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> told me <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> he's like a gangster or something
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so i'd like to see that
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm kind of looking forward that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> says there's one she wants me to take her to see this weekend
 		and uh i'm trying it's about a it it it's one that was done a long time ago i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Curtis</ENAMEX> uh uh uh
 		was uh the star in where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> dies falls overboard or something and comes back as a woman
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh there's uh uh a movie coming out uh gosh what's the name of that
 		it's already out matter of fact it's been advertised on TV um about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that falls over he he gets killed somehow or another and he comes back as a woman
 		and you talk about funny at least the little snapshot previews that they've shown on TV advertising it are hilarious i mean it is really funny
 		and uh so we're going to go see that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now we saw a movie called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sisters</ENAMEX>
 		what's uh that may have been almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> now i think about it
 		that was quite good
 		i don't know if you've
 	
 	
 		did that have that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX> in it
 	
 	
 		uh let's see i don't remember whether <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX> no i don't think so you mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no i don't think she was in this one i kind was trying to remember exactly who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> were
 		but uh it was a real touching show <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three sisters</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay this was a comedy so it probably wouldn't be the same one
 	
 	
 		no no this this was a real uh uh sort of serious piece it had some light moments but basically it was a serious piece
 		i thought it was just called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sisters</ENAMEX> or something like that or the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sisters or The Three Sisters</ENAMEX> or something
 		um uh i can't really quite remember and then we saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> uh some time back it's a shame i can't remember the titles of these for the benefit of this conversation although it may not be that the uh necessarily the uh
 		intent but nevertheless that that we saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here a while back that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolly Parton</ENAMEX> and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> starred in
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> together
 	
 	
 		with old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley MacLaine</ENAMEX> oh yeah i i don't know the name of it either
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and
 		yeah that was pretty good it was okay uh you know most of t his stuff is B movies anyway
 	
 	
 		have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Awakenings</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		i would suggest that it's
 	
 	
 		have you seen that
 	
 	
 		yes i have
 	
 	
 		was it really good i i have heard all kinds of mixed things about it
 	
 	
 		well i'm uh leaning toward medical professions myself so it had some uh
 	
 	
 		are you
 	
 	
 		you know  he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and it was in a clinical uh
 	
 	
 		psychologist something right um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah psychiatric uh clinical setting so it was interesting
 		to to say the least from that standpoint because it is a true story
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's right i think it was a take off from true story you're right
 	
 	
 		yeah so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah who was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> he rehabilitated he starred in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Taxi</ENAMEX> or not Taxi uh
 		yeah oh yeah it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert DeNiro</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		was it DeNiro
 		yeah that he just did an incredible job of acting
 	
 	
 		did he
 		well did you ever see speaking of uh of uh medical oriented movie or at least a movie about somebody got rehabilitated did you ever see the one uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX> starred in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rain Man</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah now wasn't that a good show
 	
 	
 		yeah now that see if you liked that you would
 	
 	
 		i really enjoyed it
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i enjoyed that show
 	
 	
 		okay if you liked that um you'd probably
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i both enjoyed that
 	
 	
 		yeah you would enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Awakenings Awakenings</ENAMEX> is as touching
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it doesn't have the the language and other things that might detract from the movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's really it's a movie that wouldn't mind taking my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		oh i see that's good
 	
 	
 		and i mean it's really clean and but it's it doesn't lose any quality i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think sometimes movies try to spice it up a little bit with things unnecessary uh language or nudity or whatever
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but this one here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Awakenings</ENAMEX> is very clean that was the only thing i didn't like about uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		rain man
 	
 	
 		it sure it makes it true to life and everything but uh you know about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rain Man</ENAMEX> it was language is harsh every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but yeah it was cool i'd probably seen it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> times
 	
 	
 		right yeah that that was uh one that we really enjoyed i was trying to think of uh
 		oh what was that one though
 		it slips me now unfortunately i should have done  thinking about this
 	
 	
 		well it's  you called on the spur of the moment you don't really know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah um
 		oh uh how about any older shows like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX> movies and things like you got any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> along those lines
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh
 		i like most of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX> westerns uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Dorado</ENAMEX> is that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah me too
 		oh yeah yeah
 		i like almost everything he yeah i really love rue Grit
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">True Grit Rooster</ENAMEX> Cogburn
 	
 	
 		and uh yeah oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they i thought they were really really fun they were interesting and the one he did with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jake Big Jake</ENAMEX>
 	

 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i've seen that on TV several times and that was a lot of fun movie you know i have kind of favorite because i like the uh the musical scores to it matter of fact i had to hunt for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to finally find a copy of the record
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> because they made so few of them it wasn't really wasn't all that popular and that was uh uh not was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">it Hogan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Heroes</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah that TV show or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heroes Kelly Heroes</ENAMEX> name of the show the one that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX> stars in and uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carroll O'Connor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kelly</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Heroes</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now that's one of my favorite shows i really enjoy i've been trying to tape that one for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and haven't succeeded in doing so yet
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		but i finally did find an album i had to look around several different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> here in the uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> area
 		and put the word out to find the album that had the uh movie score on it that you know they open the show with uh
 		uh a movie score with a score to that
 		and then they wind up at the end playing a tune that is just one of my favorites i've loved it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and i'm sitting here as i tell you this trying to think of the name of it
 		but uh  it's sung by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Alpert</ENAMEX> congregation
 		uh the uh the uh  the opening and the closing score of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Heroes</ENAMEX> the
 	
 	
 		do you remember much about that movie
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Heroes</ENAMEX> the movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i i remember that uh
 		uh their on there way into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> they make up their own little army you might say they start out small but they get bigger and bigger all the time they bribe this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> well little bribe he's willing to go in on it they've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanks</ENAMEX> that have these huge pipes he puts on the turrets to make
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	