
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as far as you know crime in the cities i'm sure it like in yours it's pretty pretty bad
 		uh probably the biggest thing we've got going now is the robberies and theft and probably murder are the two top ones that we have how about you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh well i don't actually live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> but uh i'd probably say that's roughly right i mean
 		crimes against property seem to outnumber crimes against life but i i think with the current war on drugs
 		and all this kind of stuff i'd say probably the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> would claim the number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> crimes crimes are probably solicitation of prostitution um and sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		probably probably right if you look at it from that stand point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what uh is there anything that uh that you particularly are concerned with in in your particular area
 		as far as security and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		uh where i live no it's it's not so bad i mean i can basically leave my front door unlocked and not have to worry about it um
 		but i do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and i think that they get a lot of fallout from this war on drug thing
 		um just because there are like crack <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> you know on their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and stuff like this
 	
 	
 		um-hum  do you live in a real small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or or out in the country
 	
 	
 		i live out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		how far out from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> i mean do you
 	
 	
 		i am <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about fifteen miles</NUMEX> out
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about fifteen miles</NUMEX> i live in a little suburb uh which is i guess from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve miles</NUMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it's pretty congested we are considered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but it doesn't really feel like you're in the country our major crimes in our immediate
 	
 	
 		hm
 		hm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> uh  is probably robberies <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> robberies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and very few instances of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol drug</ENAMEX> uh reported however i'm sure they're there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh right now our neighborhood is running about uh eighty percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowners</ENAMEX> have been robbed sometime during their their uh existence in that neighborhood
 	
 	
 		wow
 		that's huge
 	
 	
 		and since that time everybody's gotten some sort of burglar system or you know uh burglar alarms
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and including the out uh the outer perimeter type uh devices the sensors and things like that it's cut back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know considerably but it it just shifts it from our neighborhood to another neighborhood to another neighborhood so  it still uh remains city wide pretty pretty high
 	
 	
 		are they are there any theories on why this is happening
 	
 	
 		uh i would say the majority of it's happening during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> uh between probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in the afternoon
 	
 	
 		um-hum but why why is it happening
 	
 	
 		most well most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> they are young and both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are working so they're happening during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the hours</TIMEX> they're gone from work  uh so  uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i would say that's probably their prime motivation they'll stalk they'll stalk your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh look at your pattern and then go from there
 	
 	
 		so they're professionals
 	
 	
 		um they classify most of them as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> uh you get a few of them that are a little bit sloppier uh just taking  uh you know just junk items that they they can just get you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> bucks for real quick
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably the biggest items that uh that you get in our neighborhood or would be the high classed automobiles  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> Volvos things that they can get you know big dollars for uh jewelry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		are the major targets <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> that sort of stuff
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		very few you know penny penny ante stuff
 	
 	
 		well what do you think can be done to reduce that sort of crime
 	
 	
 		well uh the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> for one i think they could uh definitely add to the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and the type equipment that they use uh it's oh right now i think we're about
 		thirty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and there's only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> that patrol for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> for that amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> which is not very many and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right but that mean that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gonna</ENAMEX> tend to
 		i mean it seems to me that sort of approach will tend to simply make the cost of committing the crime slightly higher in other words you've increased the probability of somebody being caught a little bit the real question is how do you convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not to commit such crimes in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place
 	
 	
 		well the course in our particular <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> uh we have the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> overcrowding whatever so they're giving the early release uh
 	
 	
 		right they're doing that in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah and and it's i think what they need to do is stop building more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> and start giving stiffer sentences
 		uh but for the that would be certainly be a deterrent
 	
 	
 		so you think that would be a deterrent
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh not necessarily you know uh give in to their uh human rights desires you know if they're overcrowded just keep cramming them in there till they just suffocate uh
 	
 	
 		well what about an innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who happens to have been found guilty
 	
 	
 		uh i think they'd have to go to extra measures to make sure a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s guilty you know in a lot of cases course i i know you can't be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> percent foolproof uh
 	
 	
 		right so you'd you'd rather see it harder to convict somebody
 	
 	
 		i'd rather see it a little bit harder and have a little bit more evidence uh to convict somebody and then those convicted especially of you know murder and and uh you know major crimes uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to reach the life sentences and you know death penalties and follow-through with that uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		especially you you know in the case of murder uh i know in my case i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> were kidnapped during a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> robbery back in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> and we caught the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> got caught we uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh wow
 		
  
 		oh my goodness
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we went through the court system and all that sort of thing and uh you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> counts of kidnapping uh you know the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the forty five</NUMEX> to the head you know just the the mental anguish and the whole <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nine yards</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> only got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> and you know he was out within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> because of the parole system so what what
 	
 	
 		wow
 		did you did you sue him under the civil system
 	
 	
 		do what now
 	
 	
 		did you sue him under the civil system
 	
 	
 		no no i'm not real familiar with that
 	
 	
 		well you probably sue him for mental anguish or something right and try to get money from him and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and all that tried to tried to go after him and they said well you know he they're he has no job he has nothing there's nothing that he has that that you could go after
 	
 	
 		yeah makes you wish they had uh still had indentured servitude for this sort of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah uh very seldom
 	
 	
 		but they give give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> a job in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and make him pay his damn debt
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't do that here course they pay them but they don't you don't you or the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> never see any of that money
 	
 	
 		yeah that's too bad
 	
 	
 		and uh you know and they're right now they're reluctant to go after them because they're you know they're they're repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> they uh they've bee n in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> before they've been released you know several times which is another
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh deal i hate to see  but uh you know basically the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> commits you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> major crimes and uh and car theft on top of it and destroys my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> he we're out you know uh you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i think that's a  yeah
 		yeah
 		that's awful
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen thousand</NUMEX> dollars and you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> gets out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> and he goes out and commits it again fact he's back in jail now so what what uh
 	
 	
 		gives you sympathy for the vigilantes just
 	
 	
 		yeah what what deterrent does he really have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think in our in our particular neighborhood <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">vigilantism</ENAMEX> is becoming a real real possibility  uh we've had a couple instances where break-ins where the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have actually you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		shot the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and uh return <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> have
 	
 	
 		oh my God
 	
 	
 		and uh return <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> have they've actually waited for them where they've robbed you know particular neighborhood they'll rob <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> then other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will wait up you know and wait for somebody to do something else and try to take it in their own hands course it doesn't always work out in their favor
 	
 	
 		hm
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh nevertheless i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just getting fed up and saying you know you can't arrest all of us you can you know you can get some of us you can't get all of us
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and we're beginning to see more and more of that
 	
 	
 		i mean that sounds that's a deterrent too if you think the home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> might be armed right and awake hear you break in and you're gonna get shot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's i mean that's certainly a a possibility and and we have had a a few cases where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> has broken in you know during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> and gotten himself shot to death
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it helps for a while but then just another different set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are transients from out outside of the state
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hm
 	
 	
 		uh i would say probably eighty percent of them that are caught they're from places like up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana Arkansas</ENAMEX> you know across the the border
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't readily read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or whatever it's not many from the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>  but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a problem and i i just i think that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court systems</ENAMEX> need to be more accurate in in stiffer in their penalties would be a definite deterrent and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh giving the uh police uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> a little bit more jurisdiction over what they do when they when they catch these people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i mean i i tend to agree with you i think uh what i would like to see is number one completely getting rid of these victimless crimes um there's no reason to enforce those and spend time and money doing it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and worry about these things where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are getting hurt and i think one of the big things that you can do is to increase deterrence is um
 		if someone is found guilty of a uh felony  level offense they lose their citizenship and they lose their constitutional rights
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and just a lot of things that we're trying to worry about you know protecting these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from we just don't protect them
 	
 	
 		i know like in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s case they made her feel like the criminal they they went to all all
 	
 	
 		i know and i think i think that's ridiculous
 		
 		
 	