
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		yes yes i think we're terribly taxed i i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have taxed us just as much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and i don't think there's a change between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> than the other uh
 		i think we get get a lot back but not as much as we should
 	
 	
 		uh i guess what i feel about it is that it's so mismanaged that it there's got to be something when when we pay so much for the for the debt
 		instead of using the money for where it ought to go it it's just it's ridiculous What kills me is when they had a chance to to uh put into action action the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm the Gramm Rudman</ENAMEX> what is it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh the act where they had to cut everything across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> they kept doing they kept putting off doing that why did they do that that's exactly what they needed to do to get their act together
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gramm the Gramm Rudman</ENAMEX> Act yeah
 		yeah well i think they spend too much they they spend too much on themselves too the the
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i think so too
 	
 	
 		a lot of the the taxes gets back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and everything all running for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> rather than
 	
 	
 		yeah well things like mailings they don't use any kind of restraint on some of these things they just think once they get there that they can do just anything you know they don't they don't try to uh to conserve
 	
 	
 		no you're right
 	
 	
 		and of course here at home we end up conserving and conserving and i mean when i don't have money i don't buy something
 	
 	
 		yeah no i think uh it it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and them just don't have any interest in saving us money uh
 	
 	
 		they sure don't seem to
 	
 	
 		the national debt is terrible uh
 	
 	
 		there're a couple of things i think we need to really work for and i don't know quite how to do it but i think we need to have the one line uh uh veto
 		so that they don't have to spend so much time doing everything if it's a good idea it can be done again
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and if it's not so what at least you haven't thrown out all the work they've done for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and months
 	
 	
 		yeah i saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty Twenty</NUMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month ago</TIMEX> i guess whereas one i think that he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> or something like that maybe it was
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Connecticut</ENAMEX> i'm not sure one of the small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> up there
 		where he had a bill through for another um
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> that would be located there and he was the only one that wanted it
 		it was going to cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> didn't want it
 		and he was going to build it in his home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and they were going to hire a lot of people
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and it was ridiculous you know the whole thing and and you know they they asked him about it and
 	
 	
 		yeah this is that's right
 	
 	
 		do you really need this this is going to cost a lot of money oh yes we need it but do you know that the drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> doesn't want this
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they do things that are you know just like the uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah that's just an awful lot of that kind of thing going on and the trouble is you don't you have so little input about it you don't know enough
 	
 	
 		yeah that
 		right
 	
 	
 		to know what what to do about some of this stuff i
 	
 	
 		right yeah they're supposed to do what we say but they do what they they want to do really
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right the other thing about is i think uh limiting their time in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> would be good i i just can't believe there aren't other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that could do just as well as what we've got
 	
 	
 		absolutely absolutely
 		we need to get that through we we have said that i've said it several times on different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year two</TIMEX> terms is enough for all of them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh whether you're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> all the way up city council the works i think certainly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> that uh two terms is plenty
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's right
 	
 	
 		and then we get these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> out of there and they have to learn how to earn a living again themselves you know rather than living off of us
 	
 	
 		yeah wouldn't that be too bad
 		
 
 		well that's right i think i don't know i think uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in general the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX>
 		the idea of what you need to to exist is so outrageous that it's not hardly you know it starts at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> it starts everywhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		until we can't we've just lost control of of any kind of perspective about what is acceptable and what is not acceptable you know
 	
 	
 		well it's so much money and you can't even add it up you know that's why they think it's
 	
 	
 		no you can't even can't even conceive of what they're talking about
 	
 	
 		yeah when you talk about the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillions of dollars</NUMEX> on this and that our national debt in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">trillions of dollars</NUMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i mean it just and and you just
 		the other thing is it's it's all very well to give money to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i think we need to do that
 		but there are they need to put more limits on them they need to restrain about what they do
 	
 	
 		foreign aid yeah
 		foreign aid means to go down to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost zero</NUMEX> unless it's absolutely necessary they they've given that away for fifty years
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i you know i think that's probably unless unless we can afford it if we pay off the debts then we can give it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		i agree i agree
 	
 	
 		you know i don't really mind helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but you you need to get rid of this thing that's that's just uh eating us up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and get things on a on an even if it were if it were a family we'd be up before the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magistrate</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		for for doing all these wicked things you know but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> does it and it's all right
 	
 	
 		yeah i i know we're taxed to death on every every thing i don't know what's the best way to do it but uh
 		they don't even talk about that they just raise it they don't even consider it like you saying is to cut something back you know
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		well sounds like
 	
 	
 		they are at least doing something now with the uh the military you know they're cutting some of that but of course now you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> you know that's hurting us but although
 	
 	
 		yeah it's good to see them doing some things there anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has gotten a lot of good contracts from the war and everything else and if they'll get a lot of programs in the future because of their exotic uh weapon systems but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's the only good that i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> do you know and everybody and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressmen</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and everybody uh
 	
 	
 		well
 		i think we have to accept the fact that whatever happens we're going to have to bite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX> and we're all going to have to do it i it just isn't fair though that when this happens in some places it needs to all come off everywhere
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		that's why i thought well you know this is the time they need to put that into action into action and show they mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> that they've got to cut they've got to cut costs
 	
 	
 		yeah the only taxes i think that are well spent well not the only but uh
 		i think the now i i don't understand the present school thing but uh
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> one's in college already and one's about uh to be in high school but uh
 		i think that paying for school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> is the only answer really to get rid of crime and so i don't mind paying for school taxes even though my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will be out of it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's right
 		well i don't i don't really mind paying taxes for for positive things
 		that are helps like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and making sure that uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> is safe and some of these things but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it you just fe el like it's out of control you feel like they do not have control of it and that and so then it just aggravates you you know you think i could spend my money i could help the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> better by myself than they're doing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		the spending is out of control
 		yeah oh i agree with you
 	
 	
 		so it's
 	
 	
 		i i thin k that's a wide open subject what i think that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to take a stand i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will here shortly uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		well i think that's right if they don't do if they don't if they don't pull it in and start doing something i think they're really going to have to i think
 	
 	
 		i think the next time we have an election we need to try to get some of the ones that have been there forever out too that
 		what they did last election and uh ninety some odd percent of the same old boys got back in you know so
 		we need to try to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terms so they
 		respect our wishes you know they're supposed to represent us that's what they're called but they don't
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		maybe maybe maybe we can change and get us rid of some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that are in there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and gals whatever they are
 	
 	
 		yeah in some ways we're awful lucky i guess there a lot of lot of places where it's worse than it is here but
 	
 	
 		i know but it
 	
 	
 		still you don't want it to get that bad good heavens
 	
 	
 		no that's right you don't want to uh you want it to stay as good as it possibly can be
 	
 	
 		no we need to get try to get hold of it and and have it be things be honest and and i guess in the fact i don't really mind paying taxes
 		but i would just like to know that they're not being foolishly spent that they're doing something that's positive for for somebody
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't really feel like uh
 		i don't really feel like i use taxes very much i don't know maybe i do more than i i guess i do i use them in the in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> and lot of things but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that's you're right
 		well i think one of the good ones in the metroplex uh in the last say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> or so maybe longer
 		they've built all these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dams</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Engineers</ENAMEX> have uh soon as they finish a lake they'll go at get another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and that we haven't had we've had droughts here in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">long summers</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we've had good water supply and that's due to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Engineers</ENAMEX> building looking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> ahead and building all these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reservoirs</ENAMEX> for us you know
 	
 	
 		yeah they've done some good things the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> actually did some good good work on that in that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Sam Johnson</ENAMEX> came out and talked to us about that bout what they had done and they they really had done some good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some good work
 	
 	
 		yeah i think anything for water supply like  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> should do more of that too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah there are a lot of places places where they're in real trouble and and i think it would be easy enough to be in trouble here too if they don't take if they don't take that early stand
 	
 	
 		right
 		right they just finished <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Poole</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> over here and they need to start another one i think every time they finish one they ought to just have another one in line the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>'s critical
 	
 	
 		yeah that's probably right
 		the growth is fast enough so that they can't afford to just dawdle and wait until something until they need them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well it's good to talk to you
 	
 	
 		okay yeah how many calls have you made
 	
 	
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about nine</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to twenty</TIMEX> are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'er
 	
 	
 		no i just just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> i just heard about it and found it fun  guess i like to talk that's all
 	
 	
 		oh well great great okay
 		well it's been some interesting subjects yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		thanks for calling bye-bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> bye now
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	