
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrna</ENAMEX> how do you get your news news
 	
 	
 		uh most of it is from the radio uh and also from the news programs that we watch in the afternoon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we usually watch the local news and the the uh national news both
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i'm pretty much the same i uh i find that uh i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> and i i read a lot for school and i find i have no patience to really read a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> because i just i'm reading so much all the time
 		and i really enjoy just sitting down and watching a news broadcast
 	
 	
 		well you can always get up and leave that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that that yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		uh i do i just don't seem to have time to sit down and read the paper either by the time i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> from work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's already you know time for the news to come on
 	
 	
 		that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's so much easier to sit there and besides i can be doing other things and still listening to the news
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right i i agree that's a lot of times i eat while i'm uh watching the news
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah the same thing is there any uh what did you think about the coverage like over in the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think they did a great job
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought so too it was it you know for a while when we were really interested uh we saw it all the time some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> i guess carried it for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> there and then you know the special reports
 		and the extended news coverage i thought was really good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and you could always find some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> that had something on but you didn't necessarily have to watch the same thing all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah right yeah just news that's right yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i noticed that one thing that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> did you know they had uh uh they used to have we
 		well they do have television monitors stationed throughout our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and they used to have a program called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T News</ENAMEX> and just updates of of different things that were going on within <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> well when all the the mess with uh uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> came about they started carrying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		well now they have had so much good response from this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> now has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> on all the time
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		huh well that's great
 	
 	
 		so we can always run <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> and you know catch get a quickie update on what's going on if we really want to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah or if you you have a break in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the day</TIMEX> you take a coffee break you can always stay informed
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's really good
 		that's um i've found that when i i don't have cable television anymore uh when i moved went back to graduate school i just didn't have the money to buy get rent a cable TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> or whatever you know so i don't get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 		uh which was a big disappointment i used to watch that was my if i
 		wasn't home i'm a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and sometimes i teach in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> so i'll miss the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> news and uh you could always catch a good news program at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock or nine o'clock</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> i think that's
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		that really has changed the way um i look at the news
 	
 	
 		yeah we don't get it either we live out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and we just don't have it available out there where we are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but when we did have it uh we that's what we usually watched the weather stations
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's uh same yeah that's when i had it i i watched it you know religiously for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> and then you could go on you know to do what else you wanted to do yeah i find i read very little i don't even get a regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh because uh i i don't drive that much i only live <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a mile</NUMEX> from where i go to school and work i uh
 		i find i spend so little time in the radio in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that i don't really listen to the radio
 		you know i don't so so television is my main news source
 	
 	
 		oh i get that too because i i'm in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> pool and i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> you know uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> a day an yes yes and in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the in the morning</TIMEX> i try to sleep because it's it's dark thirty
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh really to commute to work oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but in but in the afternoon uh i try to read so i can can uh not pay attention to what our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> is doing
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i can the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> pools i know that and i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore Washington</ENAMEX> area and i know they do van pool a lot here from some of the outer areas but if you want a nicer home you know beyond the suburbs you know i that's necessary
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah are are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> itself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i am i am right outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> i am <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than a mile</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> and i go to a block a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Maryland</ENAMEX> that is just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than a mile</NUMEX> from my house
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so i i'm actually in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> yeah you could say i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> over there
 	
 	
 		oh really in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well no in in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> works for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> and uh uh the other one is uh
 		uh her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines Navy</ENAMEX> and he's stationed at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh that's
 		that's that's a really nice area <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda</ENAMEX> area uh-huh it's um it's funny there's a big difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> even though they're so close there's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only an hour</TIMEX> less than that between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> but there is a big difference in things like property values
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um the closer you get to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> the more expensive it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		an um
 		the the uh different slant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> it really is a uh
 		uh an international city
 		where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> you know it there's really uh most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have relocated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> area  you know
 	
 	
 		oh no i'd i'd rather have <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> with the home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> atmosphere
 	
 	
 		yeah that's i i like it i like it a little bit better too it's interesting though um to meet different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> i i'm just now being uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> originally i'm just now meeting different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and things
 		and i find that really interesting you know to imagine here is somebody that was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years ago</TIMEX> when all that was going on in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> you know that that's an interesting uh
 		interesting perspective but i i really much much like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> area yeah
 		and i think that also goes it's funny you you can watch different news i can watch <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> news or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> news and i really do watch <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> news
 		you know that really makes i don't really bother with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> because i just it's so far removed from what i'm interested in
 	
 	
 		well most of what they're talking about in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> is is the
 		crime problems that they're having there
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah they in fact they just it was just a big thing recently they've had some terrible problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> um they had to impose a curfew
 		that uh in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the areas in uh in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> suburbs the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> they've gotten rid of that
 		really bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> and then uh brought in yeah and then came a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that's um she's big in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> party
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i heard about that
 	
 	
 		so that's good so she has good national ties but she also was um
 		something like a  uh state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX> or something like that before this position she was a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditor</ENAMEX>
 		i guess she was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">auditor general</ENAMEX> or something like that for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">District of Columbia</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and then she left that to get a position with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and now she ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> so she's uh fiscally she's pretty tight
 		and uh she's cleaning <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> an and it looks like hopefully she'll do a nice job uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> you know which is you sort of feel sorry for a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there you know from what i pick up on the news uh
 		it's a difficult process you know to get rid of a a bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i know both of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> didn't want to live anywhere around the the downtown areas they both moved way out
 	
 	
 		
  
 		right uh-huh yeah
 	
 	
 		i think one of them lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germantown</ENAMEX> and i can't remember where the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> lives
 	
 	
 		yeah but those are nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Germantown</ENAMEX> is a nice area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a nice area
 	
 	
 		yeah it's means they have to drive a little bit but
 	
 	
 		yeah well they might be car pooling too do they car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX> in are they driven by themselves
 	
 	
 		uh well now i i think he carpools because he's got fairly <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">regular hours</TIMEX> since he came back but uh now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> has they have probably been carpooling together in fact because she had been called back up active duty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh oh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then she was supposed to have gotten out of active duty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as of last Friday</TIMEX>
 		so i haven't talked to them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> i don't know what the situation is but she was
 	
 	
 		um-hum they didn't call you for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s day
 	
 	
 		uh we were gone
 	
 	
 		you weren't home huh
 	
 	
 		no we weren't home but she had she had left called and left a message on our recorder but i had that from all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> except for one
 	
 	
 		yeah oh that's good
 		well i guess we should stop now
 	
 	
 		so
 		well i thank you for calling i have enjoyed it i really do like this program because i get to talk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh good
 		uh uh so do i i've become very aware of different political views because some of the things we have to discuss are very politically motivated or whatever i i really enjoyed it it's it's so funny when you live in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you only see that perspective
 		it's interesting to see the the wider world so i enjoy it hey thanks a lot and and bye
 	
 	
 		thank you bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	