
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more time your name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Tonya</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tonya hi Tonya Tonya</ENAMEX> listen uh there's only one show as far as i'm concerned <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek the Next Generation</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 		you sound like one of my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> hers hers her heart <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">throb</ENAMEX> is is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> and all those space movies
 	
 	
 		no i like your pessimism
 		yeah hey have have you watched the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the the the the Next Generation</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no i haven't i have i've was never really into <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Search</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well uh well <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Star Search</ENAMEX> who wants  really <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek well</ENAMEX> uh well this is this this cannot be compared to the old <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Search Star Trek</ENAMEX>
 		yeah uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		can't be compared at all it
 	
 	
 		is it better in your opinion
 	
 	
 		oh much better
 	
 	
 		um-hum what's better about it
 	
 	
 		uh well it's it's it's it's better put together better better dialogues the the the uh
 		the the stories are a little deeper and and and the the the technology of course that they use is much more believable from a from a scientific aspect also they're they're much more sound about what they say and do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		is it much more believable sounds like i would i would probably like that better then the the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh it's got got a lot more credibility than than the others also they they they they touch you know a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a a</NUMEX> a lot of issues that are are are quite relevant you know
 	
 	
 		okay
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh yeah yeah yeah i like it
 	
 	
 		maybe i ought to try it out sometimes  uh
 	
 	
 		hey try it out
 		and then then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> you can watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Married with Children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right you like that show
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i like that um i don't watch a whole lot of television but when i do i like just a lot of sitcoms because i look at television myself as
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		kind of a get away so i don't i don't like to watch a lot of serious movies uh not on television anyway uh when i watch TV i like to kind of getaway kind of laugh and that i like i even like to watch the sitcoms
 	
 	
 		yeah well that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well sure
 		it's a it's a good escape
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right now i'm watching uh
 		The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder Years</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder Years</ENAMEX> that's a good show
 	
 	
 		and yeah yeah and i like that because the
 		you kind of get to think along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> you know so that's why
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh you you you don't sound old enough
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		to to  to go back that far  uh i am unfortunately uh so  i was there during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> and i that that's what i love about the show it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 		oh
 	
 	
 		back a lot of memories and it's it's it it's amazingly accurate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum i was going to ask if it if it's accurate for you uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah it it it it really is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		because i really can't i guess i can't tell but i i enjoy watching it and i think we learned a lot from it
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		you know and how it was back back then and you know
 	
 	
 		yes yes well it it it is it it is accurate there's there there is um uh
 	
 	
 		because of you
 	
 	
 		the the latter part of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> was totally dominated by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		those issues and i mean you know it was it was everywhere and and that is the one thing that i notice they sort of shy away from a little bit
 	
 	
 		right
 		hum
 	
 	
 		i mean  they hit it a little it but they don't you know i mean it was in everything at the time i was in college and and it totally dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point uh before nineteen what was it i guess it was
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy</TIMEX>
 		you know uh when they enacted the the what they called the lottery
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		system of the draft in which um you know uh uh
 		everyone's everyone's birthday was chosen it was chosen at random and and only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first third</NUMEX> of those were taken and and and would be inducted into the you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> was the only one accepting toward the end
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so um
 		you know it it it it really was terrible because uh until until that it least every one was going crazy at least when they inducted uh they they did the lottery only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were going crazy because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		they were going to go have to go and it was a war that was really quite unpopular but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was kind of crazy
 	
 	
 		yeah unlike this war that we just got out of here
 	
 	
 		yeah anyway so so but but they they should uh uh you you you you know i think maybe maybe hit that a little heavier on that show what other shows you watch
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		um i like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> lineup on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby Show A Different World Cheers i really like Cheers</ENAMEX> and uh even
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX>  i i used to like the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby Show</ENAMEX> i've kind of gotten burned out on that though
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm kind of getting burned out but i still watch it i guess just for the heck of it because i've been watching it
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um i like Evening Shade</ENAMEX> a lot of the new
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that keeps threatening to kill me if i don't watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evening Shade</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a really good show that's a really good show
 	
 	
 		she says that it's it's a really good show so i'm going to have to check it out
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Designing</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Designing Women</ENAMEX> i like that a lot uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		so do i
 	
 	
 		yeah i like a lot of the newer a lot of the newer shows i like um there's
 	
 	
 		yeah i i i i i was really glad to hear that they were finally taking that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> off what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> did it's last show
 	
 	
 		oh yes that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in fact i went to a last episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> party
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and we just all got together and watched the last episode although although we didn't although we hadn't watched it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> you know yeah it really was everyone was pre tty disappointed in the ending
 	
 	
 		oh they
 		
 
 		yeah i hear it was the dog of a show
 		
 
 		oh well go out with a whimper
 	
 	
 		so yeah exactly uh
 	
 	
 		i guess that's the way to go
 	
 	
 		what else do you watch besides <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh do is there anything else on
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		no no i i uh i watch a lot of i've got cable here so i don't watch a lot of network stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i mean you know the typical <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> i um i do watch a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> stuff and and uh uh i'm home most of the time so
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah i find myself watching a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> i like they have a fashion show on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> that i like to watch
 	
 	
 		huh yeah i i got really uh i mean i i i watched it a lot before the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX> crisis but after that uh it just seemed like it it became apart of my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> viewing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right you feel like you really don't know what's going on unless you tune in at least for you know fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> or so and
 	
 	
 		yeah and and that's what i like about it i can tune in any time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right and get the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all all the days</TIMEX> events uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and get all the yeah i don't have to you know uh view it at at a certain time of day i can i can check it out anytime generally and uh and find out what's going on and i like that i
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i remember  i remember when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turner</ENAMEX> started that thing they said that it would never fly and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year or two</TIMEX> it really it really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sort of wallowed but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah and and if you know notice i mean it's gone so far in the with just with just with this
 	
 	
 		well the thing is is that that the world finds out most i mean like you know it was interesting uh like during the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX> crisis the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> here were finding out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> more what was happening by watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> than they were getting i mean the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> even
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> themselves were depending on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh exactly
 	
 	
 		for a lot of things you know they would make they would even mention <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> and have their footage on and everything
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		yeah
 		yeah so it it it it really has become sort of like the world's eye
 	
 	
 		so their going to become
 		right exactly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and i you know it was a it was an idea whose time had come that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner</ENAMEX>'s quite a character
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Turner</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		anyway i really enjoy i really enjoy having access to that all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i'll turn to it just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now and then</TIMEX> and you know yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah so you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are you you you evidently have access to the cable too
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah well good
 	
 	
 		i don't think i don't
 	
 	
 		didn't didn't know if they had cable in Waco
 	
 	
 		yeah we're we're up there  we're trying to become technologically sound here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so are you going to school there
 	
 	
 		no i work here i'm a news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> as a matter fact but yeah so speaking of news
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh really
 		oh well
 		well indeed well that's
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah i'm i'm not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> by choice i just i have to work here because it's my it's my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> job so  really uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor University</ENAMEX> is here so that's
 	
 	
 		i i'm sure no one is
 		
 
 		oh yeah yeah well now now now that that's a a very you know that that that's a good thing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX>'s favor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX> is is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		it's pretty much the outline i mean it's really a college town <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX>'s it for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waco Waco</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX>'s a well known university i mean it really is
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> which is not not far away
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		from here
 	
 	
 		well i hailed from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arizona State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i started to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or i i applied or something i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cal</ENAMEX>'s a great great great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> it really is
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i want to come visit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> at some point
 	
 	
 		you've never been
 	
 	
 		but no i never have uh i know i know i i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you must you must it's a it
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		so you know i just i i haven't got oh
 	
 	
 		well i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and it's a great used to be from
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> grew up in what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Raleigh okay my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> grew up in Whitefield
 	
 	
 		yeah well listen dear i guess we've strayed from the TV thing but pleasure talking to you
 	
 	
 		okay it was nice talking to you too have fun in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Berkeley</ENAMEX> okay okay okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right Tonya you take it yeah yeah do come check it out all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	