
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh do you want to start do you have any ideas
 	
 	
 		well the the the changes of course in the past past <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the work force
 	
 	
 		that's for sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and the while their positions salaries still aren't there yet the opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are at least driven uh do do tend to be a little bit more compatible with uh changes in life style
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i suspect that that may have had more to do with uh changes in society than anything else is the number of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the work force
 	
 	
 		um-hum yes and you know you said um along with salaries i also think that i think there's a little bit um that can be
 		i don't know a little more development in the area of respect as well i don't know if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in higher positions are necessarily given the same respect as men
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um i think it depends on which positions and perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> of the women
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		um let's face it there there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men executives</ENAMEX> who have um
 		uh gotten gotten there by uh rather um unsavory means uh you know  trapping everybody up along the way um when uh uh they may not be necessarily liked but if when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> does that she is ridiculed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">n-th</ENAMEX> degree where as it's almost expected of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> so some of that is stereotype i think
 	
 	
 		right it's true like the uh the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Working</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX> did you ever see that
 	
 	
 		um-hum i think i have although at the moment you i mean i know a little bit about it but
 	
 	
 		oh
 		um-hum well i think that sort of it was funny because it it sort of gave <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> very different types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that both had very strong potentials and one had extremely aggressive and step on whoever you can
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> of getting to the top and the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> just worked hard and did you know her job and did it well and all that but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-</ENAMEX>hum i think the educational opportunities have made some difference uh because at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother-in-law</ENAMEX> used uh talked about when she went to college
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		she really sort of had to to do her own way because although she was one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters um</ENAMEX> and while her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were um very supportive in many ways they didn't really seem to have the um the the uh
 		i don't know the understanding that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> should go on for a college degree uh had they been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> uh you know that would have been expected but for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> it wasn't as necessary um and see i don't think that's so true anymore i think
 	
 	
 		sure oh yeah
 		exactly
 		oh not at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> expect both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> to have whatever opportunities are available uh i know we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> but the differences
 	
 	
 		um-hum right and
 	
 	
 		are are negligent in that area and in fact they they were in my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> as well um it was never considered that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and i wouldn't go to college uh you and you know certainly my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> would but but we were included in that so i think those things do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are older because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> are all older i'm the youngest of older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">siblings</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> um was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		had the uh had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> um so she had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> in any case um
 		her she and her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> actually had to work and not go to school to put him through school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and that i when i mean she  she obviously at the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> didn't think twice about it you know that was just the way you did it but um and and and what was most important to them if they wanted to get a job was if they could type
 	
 	
 		right right
 		right right well you know that hasn't changed so much
 	
 	
 		you know um take shorthand and um-hum well that's true that's the
 	
 	
 		i know uh it's it it's always appalled me because i did not uh suffer that same problem fortunately uh because i went into biological research when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got out of college um and so you know i was not in a in a situation where i would
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		asked to do typing uh  but um i know that even now um many young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> getting out of college
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		tend to find themselves in that position of of having to be uh sort of part of the secretarial pool it might not be called that but that boils down to what it is
 	
 	
 		yes no it is it is
 	
 	
 		until they work their way up and i don't think very many young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are ask to do that although perhaps they are asked to do
 		somewhat uh less uh technical jobs or you you know too perhaps uh you know start working their way up but i don't think it's quite as um as low on the totem pole
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no exactly i know and you know just another whole thing i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manpower Temporary Services</ENAMEX> so i see i see the work force out there and i see a lot of um like what's just what's going on and i'm finding that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and maybe this is just the way it always was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the secretarial pool
 		um that really stand out are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that that end up being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> or whatever and so even though it might be belittled when they first go for the job
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it really is a stepping stone to something a lot greater
 	
 	
 		yeah i do know that uh there are plenty of uh executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX>
 		whose responsibilities are greater than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s uh  that and they may not make the money but they they have a lot of prestige many do make the money too actually but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure</ENAMEX> and they
 		i know well
 		but they keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> running you know they keep them oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um-hum and sometimes those are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> too sometimes those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretaries</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> which is good i'm glad to see that change um
 	
 	
 		that's true yep um-hum but you it's it's i've always heard i i don't know if you know this joke it's uh it talks about um this this
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and there was a car accident and you know that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right right
 	
 	
 		oh yeah and they go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and uh uh uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> what what i guess the the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was killed
 	
 	
 		uh yeah right
 	
 	
 		and they get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> comes in to uh work on the injured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and says oh i can't uh do that that's my child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right how does that happen
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean but see it's so obvious i guess the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i heard it i immediately thought of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> because that's what i originally wanted to do  so it's but it's amazing how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do you know for a minute stop and think
 	
 	
 		oh okay well you know i
 		well i think i even did seriously and i
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i'm yeah sure we're all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of this sure we've we've been brought up in the society that's perpetrated that problem
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right um oh what was oh you know one other place is um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> that i think that's really changed a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i i don't know if i necessarily agree with that but i  i don't think i agree with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> but that's a whole different topic
 	
 	
 		well i don't have yeah right right i i suppose my feeling is that it doesn't matter male or female uh
 		at least they if they're given the same opportunity then that's good although they can't always there there are certainly differences of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> the i guess the other thing that was asked in this to for us to discuss was um what kind of changes this has brought about or what do we see in the future
 		and uh just because this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday past Sunday</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX> of course there was some articles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> about the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> s in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">work force</ENAMEX> and that has that has certainly made a tremendous difference in society
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but what is interesting is at least in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> there was um a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a report of a study that suggested that there were more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> now
 		who regretted the necessity for having to work and and leave their young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and that more if given the opportunity if if financial if it were not financially necessary would stay home you know would have the choice would make take make the choice of staying home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yep yep
 	
 	
 		while their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were young <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um</ENAMEX> and it's interesting because i don't know if that's a switch if somehow maybe that's being revalued or reevaluated or not i was fortunate enough that um well it was a decision
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh when we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to make that decision and we determined that we would live on my salary on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s salary when we <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got married so that when we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we would not you you know fall into that necessity of having my having to work and so we made that choice we didn't live as well but we lived well enough
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right uh-huh
 		um-hum but you made sacrifices and you gained things you know but
 	
 	
 		uh uh sure but you see for me that was the more more important i know of plenty of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who did not were not able to make that choice
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that's difficult because i think in the long run uh part of the problem in society and maybe part of what happens to the bad the negative attitude of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working comes about because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		remember the the traumas of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> trying to work and run the household and some of those things that that has not changed and i think that's a serious issue
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right and and</TIMEX> and you know and then the marriage suffers because how much time can you physically spend with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> if your being torn in in all the direction
 	
 	
 		exactly yeah
 		right
 		oh yeah it it's very difficult so that needs to be done and education perhaps education will eventually do it but uh the idea that that all those uh things that were traditionally thought to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> when she was home as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewife</ENAMEX> are still hers even if she's out working
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		uh you know that's a serious problem uh
 	
 	
 		right uh one thing that i i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester</ENAMEX> is being a little proactive um several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are actually now providing some on site very reasonably uh reasonable cost day care
 	
 	
 		wow that's nice yeah
 	
 	
 		that is great because then at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is going with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> to you know right to the company
 	
 	
 		um-hum and can take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> if if if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is ill or something yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly and then the mother the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> or the father whoever can see them during their lunch or you know the um they're just a lot more available even though they're still at work they're not over at some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and actually i have a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who who uh have a a nontraditional a nontraditional uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is is home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is is out with the more uh uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> kind of job and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> case is a is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> so he does uh was uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		guitar lessons and does a lot of uh professional playing you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and so on but essentially it's his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> who uh is the primary uh uh money <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> there it's an interesting situation and they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		it is oh wow
 	
 	
 		uh so and it seems to have worked very well but um but those things are rare i i must say they're still not uh
 	
 	
 		that's great
 		um-hum society still isn't up to just being okay with that you know they're really not um because even the way you say it you you talk about it as the exception you know right and um
 	
 	
 		no no
 		it is the exception yeah
 		
 		
 	