
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and
 		how long have you lived there
 	
 	
 		i've lived in this area for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about twenty six years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well you're familiar then very well with what's going on there
 	
 	
 		yes i am
 	
 	
 		we just moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and i'm not yet familiar we're out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> a little bit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's a contract garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pickup</ENAMEX> and it's all thrown together in this area they don't have that
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well let me tell you what we have
 	
 	
 		good
 	
 	
 		i live in a very progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> and uh it has we have for the last
 		uh year i suppose had um newspaper pickup but there's always been you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout troops</ENAMEX> and that sort of thing interested in doing that because it they get earn a little money and also you know they were helping the environment but the um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> then got involved and decided to uh mandate newspaper collection and although they're still we still give ours to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl scout troop</ENAMEX> at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> uh they do have curbside pickup in over the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> for newspapers
 	
 	
 		good
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and then in addition to that they
 	
 	
 		excuse me do you have to bundle it or
 	
 	
 		uh we we can put it in paper bags that's that makes it okay that's that makes it okay um they used to only recycle let you do it uh tied with string
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		but now they do it in paper bags and they do say that it is paying for itself now in the actual <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">municipality</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockville we</ENAMEX> moved just outside of it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX> uh they've been doing newspaper recycling even longer and they were
 		they had their regular um garbage or you know
 		the the social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> pick it up on a separate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and they said that was paying for itself It was paying the extra salaries for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as well as paying you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for doing it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well good
 	
 	
 		but the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> now and it's a large county this is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montgomery County</ENAMEX> right outside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC um</ENAMEX> is has begun a program to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over a period of the next year</TIMEX> to um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have all well not all waste but <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um plastics um aluminum</ENAMEX> and other tin cans and uh glass of all colors
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and it's they they will you will they will also be picked up at the curb and it can be put together at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point and we've been doing it in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> for a while by at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> at first we were doing it um
 		separating it because most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> that would take it were uh
 	
 	
 		yes required it yes
 	
 	
 		required it's being separated but they've got this wonderful new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> now that separates it and they had a drawing of it a diagram of it in in one of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and it works um
 		it's like conveyor belts and some of it works by gravity and of course you can imagine the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> because it's very light weight
 		um you know falls in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> goes another place and other and tin that would be picked up by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">metal</ENAMEX> is just picked up you know some other way
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and then the plastic um you know go because it just kind of doesn't fall  i mean i guess it keeps going on the conveyor belt or something i can't remember the the design right now but it's wonderful because you don't have to separate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that is nice and i've read articles here uh about the confusion involved in what is to be put out and what isn't and the
 		problems that uh some of the recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> are having because of the slick <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> pages in with the newspaper which they say ruins the whole batch and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the unacceptable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> in with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> which ruins the whole batch and i just wondered
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well they do try to control that by giving a little instruction
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they do try to say you you know you should have it certain way but um on the the slick <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> print that comes in with like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and so on
 		they haven't really protested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> shouldn't be as a rule should not be put in but there are always a few of those pages and they must have a better way to do it now because they they haven't gotten too upset about that
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		in general as long as it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> because there's not you know volume wise maybe it does have to be
 		you know significant volume um percentage before it's a serious problem in the plastics
 		um the the county recycling where we take ours now because we don't yet have the curbside pickup um i
 		the the transfer the you know just solid waste transfer station they uh have indicated they only want the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> liter <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic soda</ENAMEX> bottles and or i guess any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soda</ENAMEX> bottles that are plastic uh caps removed and uh milk cartons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but in fact there is another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> that will take other items the the you know there are little codes on the bottoms of these things uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and they look it's a triangle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with arrows uh and that indicates it can be recycled but there are different grades of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and that's probably what you're talking about sometimes some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> cannot be reused in certain ways
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some can now even our grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> here we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> that of the plastic bags but you see i'm i have a problem with that i'll take them occasionally but i've decided
 	
 	
 		recollecting the the plastic bags yeah we
 	
 	
 		that i'll take them occasionally but i've decided that i will only take use paper which we are we do get a choice because i know that's biodegradable plastic isn't they can reuse it but it's really not biodegradable
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 		
  
 		right
 		right right
 		well we've had we've been collecting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> here and we uh as new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> we don't have affiliation with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout troops</ENAMEX> and and all that
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		we had a difficult time finding in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> uh a place to finally put them which surprised me and i thought they would be
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yes i am surprised yeah
 	
 	
 		uh located throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and we've
 		called and finally found one
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> miles away
 		
  
 	
 	
 		oh not very convenient then
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		well what part do you actually live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> proper
 	
 	
 		no right outside north of uh of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> near the university
 	
 	
 		because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matthews</ENAMEX> which i think is a little south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is south and and east yes right
 	
 	
 		yeah well actually it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> now they used to be called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> where she lives  they incorporated it but um i i was thinking that you know i i don't know what she does with hers either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well how active how active are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> there i'm i'm an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> grew up uh during <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War Two</ENAMEX> and we saved papers and tin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foil</ENAMEX> and string and everything else and uh did it through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> and i've wondered
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well it's it's not taken on there as well although the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i work in the school system so
 	
 	
 		if they're really active
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i teach in in the high school um the uh we have an environmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> which has just begun at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and i think maybe the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are becoming more conscious of the need
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um of course it's going to get down to if it's not made easy as i just described the way they're going to do it in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> uh they're making it so easy that you almost can't miss
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh doing it but because you don't have to separate and all that but that seems to be the only way that it'll ever really take off is if it's not too complicated because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in general are just lazy and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> they are trying to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> more conscious
 		and uh but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> are the ones that have to lead the way and they have required the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in the cafeterias to recycle but of course you know that
 		it doesn't go all the way they they make the effort they try but i think as the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> come on maybe they'll be a little more conscious of it and eventually
 	
 	
 		that that was sort of my point too in addition to being a a good focal or central collection point it does raise the awareness if you do it through the school system and
 	
 	
 		yes yes it does
 		uh we because they they recycle the styrofoam because that's what most of the uh you know the little trays that they have their dinner you know we used to use those heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">uh plastic</ENAMEX> or whatever they were metal even trays in in the cafeterias in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but but now they have these
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		plastic these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Styrofoam</ENAMEX> ones like they get at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> kind of and um and those are being
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		probably one of the worst things we ever done to ourselves
 	
 	
 		isn't it awful now but do you know that um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> is doing uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um McDonald's</ENAMEX> is phasing them out and uh they're supposedly going to try to recycle those that are still left we're talking about
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jillion i'm sure
 		so eventful it will take a time but um i i just worry about what's going to happen to the next generation um
 	
 	
 		uh no uh how do you feel about the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that you you teach do you feel that they have the right i i get mixed emotions when i see a bunch of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> throwing things out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> versus
 	
 	
 		well
 		many of them do
 	
 	
 		they they're talking about environment
 	
 	
 		i know oh but
 		yeah exactly  that does seem a little bizarre um i i find that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		there is a percentage of of uh the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> uh that is a a aware active and interested
 		there is uh a much larger percentage still that it hasn't quite you know taken yet
 		um but i think they're becoming more aware i think what will make the change is um enough of those who are aware and making an effort to do something about it those are going to have to  ridicule
 		those are going to have to  ridicule peer pressure or something
 	
 	
 		right peer pressure is a big one yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah to to kind of make the effort um
 	
 	
 		well i
 		yes i am too i am too well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> i enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		but i i'm hopeful
 		well i enjoyed talking to you and i wish i wish you luck there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		thank you uh bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	