
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Amy</ENAMEX> uh what do you think about taking care of the elderly
 	
 	
 		well i certainly um can
 		appreciate the patience and the you know energy and money and time and effort it require would require for someone to you know take care of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly parent</ENAMEX> or whatever in their home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i think that you know would definitely be preferable if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is
 		you know able able to do that i think sometimes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take on i know i have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who is taken on more than she can handle you know with her her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> just needing constant supervision and for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to be able to cope with that you know is really
 		difficult but i know it's hard not to feel guilty you know to put somebody in a nursing home i if i suppose if you could find a nursing home that you thought really comfortable you know that they were getting adequate care but i think that's probably pretty hard to do at times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i've not ever been put put in this position i personally would have a real hard time taking care of my father
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he's getting up there but he's very difficult to live with and i think that would be a real consideration in in um entering him into our family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> here you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so there's a lot of factors involved
 	
 	
 		what is the point at which you would go from home care to institutional care
 	
 	
 		well i think i would in some ways have to decide how much personally you know i was able and willing to handle and how much it would affect you know the rest of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um we don't have a real large <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> if you had a lot of money and you were able to
 		you know have like a little separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> or something where i wouldn't have to constantly be having my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know be quiet and go away and that kind of thing to accommodate an elderly person
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think you know just the medical aspects too would be a big question how much um it would require you know in terms of nursing care at home and i know that there is uh often times insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> won't even pay
 		you know and if they took <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> for doing things if if they were in a nursing home would cost you know a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> times more so that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's a consideration too but i don't know it it would be a really rough choice to make you depending on the parent their personality and your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and what's going on with
 		i'm home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> anyway with the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but if i was working you know full time and had to give up a career that would be another you know problem too but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've seen is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> has been in a nursing home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> i know that uh there's been a lot of questions from other family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> as to whether she's getting enough attention and
 		whether they just kind of let her sit there and roll her over once in a while it it's really tragic to go in those places
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what would you what would you look for in an institution
 	
 	
 		so  i don't know
 		um i think i would uh
 		look for a place that definitely had the physical attributes and it wasn't a sterile kind of environment but had a comfortable feeling to it that respected uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that you seem to see some respect for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peoples</ENAMEX> privacy and
 		the attitude that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> would have towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and i was visiting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> screaming at an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was there was a head injury <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> and he had apparently
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		wet his pants and they had a blanket draped over him and the blanket had either fallen to the floor or he had dropped it on the floor and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> was just screaming at him about how
 		obscene that was or something and i just thought gosh if i walked into a place and i saw a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> just berating or humiliating humiliating a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> i would definitely that would be something i'd really want to be on the look out for um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i would hope they would have uh some you consistent staff i know they don't pay that much in a lot of those places and so there's probably a lot of turnover that would be another thing that would be
 		you know something to be important because i think it's confusing particularly if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are in some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of you know mental confusion anyway to have constant new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and having to develop new relationships and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know what else other than that maybe some place
 		had activities you know that they could participate in instead of just kind of sitting there watching the wall or something you know talking to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> there see how responsive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> was to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		the things i brought up you know that i thought were important for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> member
 		it it would really be hard because when we go to visit i'm sure places have you know their best
 		foot forward kind of thing unless you drop in frequently and kind of get the since of what's going on behind the scenes it would really be hard to know it's kind of similar in away to some of the things you look for in going to try and find day care for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so uh i'm sure that if you have enough money you can find just super care but you know the cost of this probably just horrendous
 	
 	
 		right
 		would you consider a transitional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> such as one that allows the resident sort of like an apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that would be great i i had wished often um with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> that she had been in a place like that because she had lived alone in an upper story of an apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> away from even
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> not really close by her or a grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> or anything and i thought she could have lived a a lot longer if she had been
 		in a place where she didn't have to climb up and down the stairs haul <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> and then she would have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to check on her and didn't have to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> because she just got to a point where she wouldn't cook just for herself and then she fell down and nobody knew about it for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours and hours and hours</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i think that would be great if if you know if i had to choose a place for myself that's definitely why i think that kind of atmosphere would be wonderful even i recall where i was living in the college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dormitory</ENAMEX> as a graduate student
 		i thought how how neat you know that you can have a place where you can you know go down together and have dinner with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because if your living alone the isolation and the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX> and all those other factors should be taken into consideration too
 		so i thought you know they should have dorms for older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they had activities going on all the time and you know it was really a much more comfortable lifestyle i could imagine for an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> so yeah i think that would be great if they had places like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's uh you know i hope if my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> ever gets
 		to the point where she can't take care of the home herself that she would consider uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> type
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		setting you know from what i've seen with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother grandmother</ENAMEX> who passed i don't know maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> they had her in a setting like that where she was responsible to
 		go to they had dinner in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> and she had her own little room it wasn't like she didn't have a stove or anything in her own apartment
 	
 	
 		yeah they had their own privacy yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah but you know she could walk to walk to the dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> and had games and stuff so it was sort of like a step between a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and a uh you know just a retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">village</ENAMEX> or whatever they're called those so i guess there's different levels you just have to be sure and match your loved one with that
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah yeah i don't know you know how many of those there are but i definitely think it's a great idea to have that kind of thing
 		you know for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know that um in that way too that sometimes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> can be more involved with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> they can have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandkids</ENAMEX> and that kind of thing over to spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> or there's a lot more freedom i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		instead of just being kind of taken away from all of that and told where you're going to be and what you're going to do in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		yeah it's she'll become uh
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		you know a bigger issue as you know the medical profession continues to you know increase longevity
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		we're going to see you know geriatrics will be a a big part of the medical profession i think
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		let's hope it's true
 	
 	
 		it's a lot to consider
 	
 	
 		it is i've i've had had a lot of uh thought thought provoking conversations on  the topics  yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i i guess i'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">decreased morbidity</ENAMEX> which is where the elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> through i don't know a healthier lifestyle and exercise and eating right can
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know sustain them for longer periods of time
 	
 	
 		right right well as the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> get more into this preventative health care i think that will help it just seems very slow that that happening but uh yeah i definitely think that will help
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah hopefully uh yeah the insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will see the advantage of signing up a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty year old</TIMEX> for a uh you know exercise class or
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		well uh it's been fun talking with you
 	
 	
 		okay well take care thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	