
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um basically i'm at home and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s great
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh uh-huh yeah
 	
 	
 		it's wonderful you know and and uh so i'm <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about forty</NUMEX> and whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so yeah
 	
 	
 		around there huh well you're you're just a youngster then  i passed the fifty
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm just a
 		spring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		so i guess our topic's going to be changes in the women's roles so it should be real interesting
 	
 	
 		well
 		right oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so you think we're ready
 	
 	
 		i think i'm ready
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 		uh you want to start off
 	
 	
 		well let's see the changes i've seen in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s roles uh since i am in the forty age i'm a fifties baby um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> it's just a very very wide um it's been a big change
 	
 	
 		um very much yeah yeah yes
 	
 	
 		very much and i think you'll have to agree and since we were in uh sort of the ground level the bra burning of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> and and we didn't really know what the agenda was going to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i think you know it got off to a really radical it has a radical fringe to it that um i've sort of backed away from
 	
 	
 		i think all things get started sometimes in that manner
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they come in that way
 	
 	
 		and to make a change you know you have to make a splash but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to continue in that vein i think it got a little bit warped and off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>  in several areas but i really do think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have made a contribution
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um to human beings i mean to be human and what it's like and have feelings and emotions and it's okay and i think
 		um you know on the other hand i don't know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have changed that much so in in contrast to the women's changes um you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> stay steady and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> change around them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i hadn't thought much about that but that is true
 	
 	
 		um i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are trying
 	
 	
 		that's
 		uh-huh some of them
 	
 	
 		but they don't have a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to uh help them out and um what's changing them though is the economic situation where both
 	
 	
 		no
 		no
 		um
 		very much
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> it has to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team partnership</ENAMEX> now and they both have to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they both have to raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> if we're going to have any kind of future at all and and that i think has been the downfall of the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> you know the me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know the the yuppiedom the whatever it was the
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> didn't know how to go about doing the careers and they wanted to compete with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> they wanted to be like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and that's wrong i think they finally discovered that they don't want to be like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> men
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		not no they they hurt themselves a little bit in that way um
 	
 	
 		absolutely and so that's you know they sort of threw the thing back another
 		you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> that they've had to you know restructure but i saw the greatest T-shirt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> i got to get some for all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men friends</ENAMEX> it says let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> run the world <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have more important things to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 		there you go  there's a lot of truth in that yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		right but um i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> both have valuable valuable assets to offer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know we shouldn't we were made differently however you come to that conclusion we were
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		biologically physiologically made differently and there is great wonderment in that and uh you know we should respect that in each other so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes it shouldn't be destroyed yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		right and and you know just sort of all swooshed swooshed into one channel sort of thing it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's viva la difference someone said that and and i think that you can truly respect the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i mean you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> is just always saying what a mystery you are you know depends on
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah
 		well that's kind of makes it exciting  you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well see that depends on what day of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um i don't know i guess we've gotten more of a  in in terms of that i think we've got more of a sense of humor about each other and our roles and but it's still a challenge being in a marriage and trying to figure out those roles
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when both are working they have a more chance more of a chance of working together because they're starting out that way
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's that's a very different way to do things you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> doesn't start off at home raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and goes back into her career you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years later</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		because you get set in your ways and it's really hard to to really to get help
 	
 	
 		you do
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> did you know to get the work load shared
 	
 	
 		are are you married
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh our i we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> they're  they're all grown and on their own so
 	
 	
 		do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		oh my goodness
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		they're uh
 	
 	
 		how did you do
 	
 	
 		uh how do you mean that
 	
 	
 		well i mean okay well did you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys girls</ENAMEX> how did
 	
 	
 		uh we have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and our our baby girl just had a baby girl
 	
 	
 		how
 		oh my
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> was her first baby
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">o</ENAMEX> h how exciting
 	
 	
 		so it's been real exciting
 	
 	
 		i i tell you what i don't know what i would do without my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> having all their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i just love the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> and and since i'm sort of in a medical situation where i can't do that it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah have you been that way long
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just eight years</TIMEX> just the most important years of my life you know
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight just eight years</TIMEX> that's that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long eight years</TIMEX> though
 	
 	
 		yeah it has been and um so there have been major major adjustments but that's another story but you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has really really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		filled in the gaps i mean i
 	
 	
 		that makes a big difference
 	
 	
 		i couldn't ask for a better life i mean if this is the way it had to be this is the best way i could possibly do it and and that has a lot to do with his strength and his
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just pitching in and and his being able to you know all all ego aside do a lot of things that really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so when i say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> haven't changed i guess i should look at my own backyard sort of thing and
 	
 	
 		yeah well probably your role and and the way you are also has changed though you know compared to what it would have been like say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty fifty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah that's true i mean boy i mean i i would have had so i had so much guilt to begin with and the changes that had to take place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hm um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know where i couldn't do a lot of things and um just adjusting to that that um yeah that was a major change but so i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um  in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX> you know you each take your own situation and you and you deal with it the best you can but
 	
 	
 		the best you can yes
 	
 	
 		but but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> i think are a whole you know sort of riding the course they're they're got a little wobbly and a little shaky there i think
 		the future of this whole thing is going to be what happens with the day care situation
 	
 	
 		i yeah that's the only thing i worry about is the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s love and security that i think that's being damaged um
 	
 	
 		i think we're going to see a generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that you know are just going to be a little bit um  oh not very nurturing i think
 	
 	
 		a lot
 		um-hum i do too i i think uh now some some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can can do both they're very capable of working and and
 	
 	
 		yeah but i wish they weren't so many i i wish they weren't role models for everybody because it's so dangerous
 	
 	
 		a um-hum um-hum
 		it it really is yeah
 	
 	
 		it's dangerous for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> too to think that she can do that and then when she can't you know the failure of that is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know her life sort of falls apart and she doesn't know who she is and she's
 	
 	
 		so many have to work to make a go of it it seems or they say they do anyways and eh  but i think ones that don't have to the it's not as much of a stigma not
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 	
 	
 		to work as it was for a while there
 	
 	
 		well you know i think that's that's really i think it depends on what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you're in
 	
 	
 		well that could be
 	
 	
 		um i i would almost just say that because you know down here in the south  you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s role is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s role sort of thing and you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		yeah yeah you mean it's stronger there
 	
 	
 		um oh yeah yeah and and i think that um
 	
 	
 		much stronger yeah
 	
 	
 		you know career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> still have a lot of problems here with the good old boys here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> sort of thing making career moves but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah right right
 		right
 	
 	
 		um you know in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> staying home and being appreciated for their talents um it's just like the way it it has been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i mean you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneers</ENAMEX> around here that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s role and it and it's hard for her to um you know amongst her peers
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		be appreciated i think sometimes but then i'm not there so i don't know that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that do both and i see a little jealousy on the part of you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> what has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and and she has an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">au pair</ENAMEX> which is a live in college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> working for her and then she has her business in the back
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		and then my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> that has you know just runs the whole household herself and just has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and goes crazy all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i see i little bit of that and i always wish there was a balance you know with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and and wish she could spend more time with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the other gal i wish she could just get out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> for a while and get some peace and quiet
 	
 	
 		um
 		um
 		right
 		but but they're both
 		yeah they're both different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too that's
 	
 	
 		yeah definitely so you're right about that yeah
 	
 	
 		that's where the trouble lies some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can adjust and have both
 		do both well and others can't
 	
 	
 		and that's
 		that's true that's so true how how did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> do it
 	
 	
 		uh well uh i have one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> that works full-time she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little boys
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they seem to do fine she has been talking has talked about quitting you know and staying home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>
 		but then it's real hard because she's got an excellent job uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	