
 
     		
 	
 		the invasion of privacy is a topic that gets some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kind of mad i don't mind it too much uh it's more of a bother sometimes than it is uh a real invasion to me
 		in that uh some of the purchases that you make if you make them with a credit card in a given location for a given amount all that stuff goes into a
 		big computer data base and tends to go to the marketing schemes and then they will hound you forever for a particular purchase like that uh one of the the uh
 		cards little little card i answered in the mail that had a bunch of topics would you be interested in this be interested in that an it was kind of a little survey type deal and i checked off a few things and
 		just out of curiosity once i decided to see what would happen if i if i checked off uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about some</NUMEX> stock uh portfolio information as it were for the different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
 		and within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a month</TIMEX> i would say i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten fifteen</NUMEX> calls from different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> uh asking me questions all sorts of things about what i would be willing interested in investing in and how much i had to invest and
 		and i was kind of curious and i guess i got my answer but it was uh a bit much and to this day it has continued considerably it's i guess it's going to be hard to get off of that little list now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh  other little forms of of uh
 		not really an invasion it's public record it's it's not uh not even they never told you it would be considered private but whenever you buy a house uh the purchase price is there for everybody to see where it's located is there and
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that do this kind of research hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to sit there at the at the records <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and
 		take down all this this information and put it into their format so that they can put it on to their computer and and know that a given
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		neighborhood is at a given age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> they they know a lot about you for the on that one transaction and they know roughly what your income is if you're affording a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of that size so they want to send you literature for vacations to whatever because you're in that bracket
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and marketing is uh seems to be the driving factor for most of these invasions of privacy as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> call them so
 	
 	
 		right yeah i guess the telephone solicitation is the one that comes to my mind
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to me that's uh
 		it's inexcusable if you want to come and want my money come and convince me don't call me on the phone
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true i i guess that's uh where the old answering machine comes into play just screen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent of your calls and you don't have that that problem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i just keep my phone number listed under a separate name and when someone calls for that name i know that they're soliciting and i just tell them no they got the wrong number
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		that's the way to do it yeah
 	
 	
 		works pretty good
 	
 	
 		well the other some of the other problems of course are are uh invasions that are more along the lines of theft where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have allowed their carbon copies of their uh cards to get a way from them the credit cards purchases and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will uh take those and maybe steal some something off that number or just use that that information as uh you you purchased this then you know at that time
 		because that information is not always open to the public yeah you can't always get out and find every transaction that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> makes on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>
 		but uh a lot of of um
 		credit references uh when you dial that in to find out well what's their latest rating uh that kind of information you don't always want everybody to know but uh
 		it's going across uh computer lines and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can pick up what they want so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then there's the whole issue of of uh cellular telephones and and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> portable phones
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> consider that an invasion of privacy to have uh someone listening in on their their phones and ironically the laws have has classified one of them as illegal to listen to and the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> not
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so it's kind of a strange deal do you have a phone that uh
 	
 	
 		no i don't have a cordless
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> cordless that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can listen in on i don't either but uh i i happen to have a radio that will pick up that range  it it's very seldom that you can get
 		uh you just happen to be within a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and you have to listen at the exact right time and it's fairly staticky and on occasion you'll get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two to three</NUMEX> of them at once because the radios usually don't have the control that's needed to
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		screen them out and it's not the worlds most interesting thing to listen to but uh it it can be done relatively cheaply and i guess some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for lack of anything else to do do that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		i guess a lot of the data that's being taken with you know the advent of the computer
 		
 
 		a lot of the data that's being taken on everybody you know your social security number
 		is tied to just everything about you and i think that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		constitutes an invasion of privacy not so much the fact that the data is there but the way that it's being compiled and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> uses is quite a bit
 		you know if they they want to do a check background check on you they've got you everything on you from the time you got that social security card
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and to me that's an invasion of my privacy
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of sad when they
 	
 	
 		they know to where you've worked where you've been what you've done you know any any kind of
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh you know you name anything that's ever happened to you is going to be tied into either your social security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s license
 	
 	
 		it's kind of sad that they choose that number to identify you  with because there's very few you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use it just because it's easy and it's unique and then some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use it to yeah you can now identify that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> it's not quite so private anymore
 		and uh i don't know i very little of the information i give out really bothers me but as far as whether i care if anybody else had it
 		but uh i guess the idea that if you ever let it become a an all right thing to do for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX> then you'll never be able to get that privilege back  once gone it's going to be gone forever
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so
 		well i think we've
 		just about covered the topic i'm going to go ahead and let you go i got to get back to work here
 	
 	
 		okay all righty bye
 	
 	
 		talk to you later maybe bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	