
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what are some of the things that you do with them
 	
 	
 		well my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and he is really into sports and my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> just started sports
 		anyway my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he plays <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and he's doing really well and we go to all the ball games and everything
 		and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s a scoutmaster and so he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troop</ENAMEX> and they spend a lot of troop time together doing scouting things
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		uh my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and and just got through with <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> and so we would we'd have to split time and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> would go <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place and i'd go the other place but we one or the other would be at the games
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> and we spend time here at home i read to him and things like that
 		as a matter of fact one thing our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> does is we try to uh go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and everybody gets books and then i we get one book that we read together like story at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the end of the day</TIMEX> just before they go to bed
 		and then i have a brand new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		she takes a lot of time so i guess that's the time i spend with her feeding her diapering her you know  that kind of stuff rocking her
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		well you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> don't you
 	
 	
 		yeah came out even
 	
 	
 		well
 		yes oh well it sounds like really sounds like you do wonderful things uh in fact
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know uh enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> who do what you're doing now
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> don't have that option
 	
 	
 		well um i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> don't but i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> do and don't exercise it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		sometimes i feel that acquiring things becomes uh so important
 		and instead of uh just
 		putting in your time in those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i i've seen it quite a bit with uh as you can tell probably know i'm older than you i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> only they're both uh away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they
 		they engaged in the sports activities and it was interesting though our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> really never wanted us to go we wanted to go because we had moved around quite a bit and that's a wonderful way to meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> too other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he was a little shy about our going
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we did maybe every other game
 	
 	
 		well i get up there and yell and everything
 		i'm a yeller and my poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he says it's okay as long as i don't call him honey
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		as long as i don't say go honey
 	
 	
 		well when you said he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> i think oh gosh that is so hard on mothers
 	
 	
 		well it's it's um tense gets real tense sometimes
 	
 	
 		well being uh and i think other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh tend to not uh remember that that is a child
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it can be that way
 		that's really true and you have to try and remember that too especially when they're littler
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we're kind of on a winning team
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we we beat a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> rather profoundly and you can't help but feel bad but we had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">our years</TIMEX> when they were growing up that we were beaten real soundly too
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		so you know um i guess it's all in the age and as you grow up and you get better and
 	
 	
 		and they should they need to have that uh feeling of accomplishment also
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i think one thing like you were saying is we need to remember that it they're just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> though this is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> or any big time thing we need to remember they're children
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> whose uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> played basketball
 		and uh he was on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and
 		maybe got into uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> games both uh during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seasons</TIMEX> for a minute or two
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		and i just think that is so terrible
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		unbelievable i don't know how a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> could even do that
 	
 	
 		i know that here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> we have regular <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> plays during the basketball <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and then they have what they call classic
 		and the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> play and the ones that are just barely new sit on the bench most of the time they play a little bit just like what you just said
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and i we just don't want our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> to do that you know
 	
 	
 		no no well and i think after he gets older and if everybody knows that that uh
 		they're willing to
 		when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> gets very good and they want to get on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a little bit more high powered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> then he can excel
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or if he wants to
 		bid his buy his time a little bit sitting on the bench until he comes of age maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but i think they certainly have to know what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> they're getting on
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		well i love to hear about your reading too so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> don't uh
 		uh take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> i used to have a bookmobile that came by our house
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		it was wonderful and we could take as many books as we wanted to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they didn't come but about every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> and so you know you can go through a lot of books really
 	
 	
 		um
 		well that's a good amount of time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 		so it was just really wonderful so
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds great you know i used to read to them and now my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> oldest can read to me every so often and that's really been fun too that they read to me
 	
 	
 		yes
 		there was an experiment here well i don't guess it was an experiment it was just a project
 		in uh one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> one of the elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> uh where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh didn't watch television for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh there was a lot of cooperation i think uh among the parents and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with this and many that they interviewed
 		afterwards said no they really didn't didn't miss it they they got kind of used to it and it was okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah and they say when you don't watch TV as much you're more creative and and imaginative in your own mind of games to play and things to do
 	
 	
 		well of course
 	
 	
 		instead of just being entertained all the time
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i worry about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> potato uh
 	
 	
 		yeah syndrome
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well Clarisse it's been very enjoyable talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX> i just appreciate you too
 	
 	
 		oh thank you so much
 	
 	
 		thanks have a good day
 	
 	
 		you too bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	