
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay so um how do think how do you think we've changed in the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i'm at a little bit of a loss you know i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> see i'm what i'm about uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty eight now so</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when i was eighteen things haven't changed a whole lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are being a little more uh
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know a little less a little less bigoted in some ways i don't know seems to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess i'm like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> gets away with hell but uh
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well it seems to me that
 		civic freedoms are more restricted but that may just be because i've changed you know i used to live up north Down here <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> seems to me the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> are militant but uh
 	
 	
 		really
 		where'd you live up where'd you live at
 	
 	
 		i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akron Ohio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh did you i'm from  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>
 		so how long how long you been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		in fact in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> i've been here it seems to me it gets more and more gets to be more and more restrictive place to live
 	
 	
 		yeah uh you know uh as you're talking like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and stuff like that it's definitely a tough job to do
 	
 	
 		i think
 		yeah well i think it's crime has gone got a lot worse in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last ten fifteen years</TIMEX> and maybe that has a lot to do with it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i agree
 		yeah i i definitely think that has gotten a lot worse and you know i i think there's to me there seems to be a little bit of a decline in the family values
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i'd say my own personal lifestyle has improved but that's more a matter of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i'm no longer a teenager in high school got to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah think i think there's more pressure like on both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to work and things like that than there used to be and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 		somebody's at the door hang on just a second
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		go ahead i'm on the phone all right
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know that's just that's one thing i see i see a lot more you know double income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and a lot more
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitters</ENAMEX> raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and things like that i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true it's uh getting more and more expensive to live
 	
 	
 		yeah that's for sure
 	
 	
 		you know you can't you can't make it
 	
 	
 		yeah without it hardly that's right
 	
 	
 		i guess when i was growing up it was it was still the ideal to get a get a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and buy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and those good thing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> you see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		forever you know you just don't buy a house
 	
 	
 		yeah just because they can't get into one yeah that's right
 		yeah the ways our tax laws and stuff are structured you can't ever catch a break until you can get into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> in a lot of ways so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's good point so
 		i'm trying to think of anything else that's changed over the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i see for me it's kind of hard i don't know i think
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know i think the middle class is shrinking and the uh
 		lower class is expanding and sooner or later there's going to there's going to be a turn around
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i agree
 		well i hope so you know at some point but i don't know at what point
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but i think it's going to be at the expense of the middle class uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so usually is i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's uh
 	
 	
 		it's hard for me to say i hope it happens because i'd be one of those that gets caught but on the other hand there's a lot of injustice that needs to be be changed
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's right do you work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T I</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what what uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> do you work in
 	
 	
 		i'm in semiconductor
 	
 	
 		are you so i'm in semiconductor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so how long you been with them since you moved down here
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		um i'm over at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center One</ENAMEX> building
 	
 	
 		yeah so am i
 	
 	
 		are you really what floor
 	
 	
 		yep
 		two
 	
 	
 		i'm on the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> floor
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		how about that well it's a small world
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so so let's see <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> floor you work for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Linear</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		do you do you uh do you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alec Morton</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've probably seen him around
 	
 	
 		oh you do huh well he comes up and pushes us around so uh
 		so um so i'm pretty familiar with
 	
 	
 		are you D A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> or something up there are you D A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yep you must know him his reputation precedes him
 	
 	
 		yeah well <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> floor
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX> A D
 	
 	
 		well uh he uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> he comes up there and gives us all kinds of grief they they say it's what makes him happy is to give us DADers grief so i can believe it
 		but
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		yeah let's see if you've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> guess i guess that's about how long i've i've been in here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years</TIMEX> too i guess um been with T I like twelve but i started out in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX>
 		and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock Lubbock</ENAMEX> is i don't know i guess if this is the only place you've lived <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lubbock</ENAMEX> is a lot different than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah flat <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dry</ENAMEX> and dirty
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah yeah but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all seem to be a lot more laid back too i mean
 		here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> everything is just real rush rush
 	
 	
 		yeah i lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> and living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is a whole different uh social structure but uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well i got s ome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that uh  seems like he went to school at like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeVry</ENAMEX> is there a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeVry</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Akron</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't even know haven't been up there in years
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i see well he went to school somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and he's from that area
 		and uh he works over in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Park Park Central</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> i think
 		but uh  i haven't talked to him in a while but um
 		yeah he he misses it he used to go back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twice or three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> you know because he missed it sounds like you haven't been back there in a while
 	
 	
 		no i haven't been back in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen ten</NUMEX> fifteen years
 	
 	
 		you still have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> back there or
 	
 	
 		yeah i do i just haven't had a chance to get back
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um catch them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> probably
 	
 	
 		really
 		well let's see how how long are we supposed to talk here
 	
 	
 		i don't know i think we ran out of social social changes to talk about so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are probably needing me to go so
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right well it's nice talking to you talk to you later bye
 	
 	
 		yeah all righty bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	