
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		um
 		i think life uh now i grew up on a farm i don't what kind did you grow up in the farm
 	
 	
 		i grew up in um well at that time i was in a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trenton New Jersey</ENAMEX> so and it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trenton</ENAMEX> so i really had mixture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> and urban living
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i see i see well little little bit different i think though it was much slower and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		much much more self-contained
 	
 	
 		i think you're right it's interesting i'm um i work in a high school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh i'm comparing my life when i was in high school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX> to what i see these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> doing
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and the pressures on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh you know you hear this as an excuse but it's true they are so much greater
 	
 	
 		unreal unreal by comparison
 	
 	
 		oh i cannot believe uh what they're doing uh academically the demands on them
 		and uh and i can see why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do drop out
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's right i i can remember as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> you know nobody ever worried about me wondering out at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and going where i wanted to go
 	
 	
 		i can see i can see uh you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it wasn't it didn't occur to nobody to worry that anything would happen to me they were
 	
 	
 		and then you didn't you didn't have to lock your door
 	
 	
 		no no
 	
 	
 		and uh a live and some of these are urban worries but uh
 		it's uh it's a lot different all though i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> a go now in this area
 		things were um similar because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> let's see it was after
 	
 	
 		it's not all that long ago is it
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty twenty five years ago</TIMEX> is when we had the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> riots the first rights we've been having some problem now and it reminded me of that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah we were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		whereabouts
 	
 	
 		uh in uh Allendal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i use to have to go over to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Patterson</ENAMEX> when those riots were going on at sometimes um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know though it's it's kind of hard to really know because of though the news media had those riots
 		uh kind of blown up out of proportion
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> riots weren't because
 	
 	
 		because i went there many times and i never i never saw a riot
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> riots weren't because i lived right downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and uh and what you saw is was what you got i'm telling you
 	
 	
 		did you
 		that's what yeah well huh
 	
 	
 		yeah but you know it's it is interesting uh they're so many more they're different kind of dangers that face young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now
 		and social pressures uh the pressures of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> is so much the prevalence is so much greater the the kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> that you've got out the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i mean the consequences is so much what's going on is so much more serious
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's true i think that's true
 	
 	
 		then when we were younger
 	
 	
 		i think the other thing is that uh
 		we have taken some rather drastic turns in our in our education and the way we approach things as of
 		maybe starting back when when i'm number one you know and uh uh uh worrying about the self and not
 		uh seeing the consequences of the disintegration of the family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh and there have been many things that have happened that have not encouraged
 		uh closeness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and uh support
 		for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that the kind of support that they need to help them take care of the things if you don't have some kind of
 	
 	
 		yes and
 	
 	
 		of basic belief or something down inside of you then it's very difficult to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh to have anything to turn to when you got when you've got something facing you like that
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		i also being involved in the school system see so many of problem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> coming from their parents
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um children</ENAMEX> who will lie and cheat and you approach their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are constantly justify them rather than to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know they're constantly uh  uh excusing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and you can see exactly why the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is that way you can as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> can't hold a child accountable
 	
 	
 		like
 		right
 		now exactly
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you're not going to get reinforced by that at home
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		and you can't make up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one hour</TIMEX> a day what's not been done for fifteen or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen years</TIMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		no
 		that's right
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and you're get you get mixed signals so it's it's not always the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>'s systems
 		i think a lot of it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		no there's so much more then that it starts very much deeper then that i think that too i see some flickers of
 	
 	
 		the way you were mentioning yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of uh
 		of good directions turning
 		but whether they're soon enough and fast enough i don't know it's just
 	
 	
 		course life is a lot more complicated too in ways
 		um the kinds of jobs that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need to be trained for now
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know with farming being so mechanized uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> working on the family farm which was a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if that uh becomes less and less likely factory jobs are so much more um uh sophisticated
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		and the kinds of knowledge that uh you know it it's requiring an increasingly sophisticated labor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just don't have it it's uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		and there's so much so so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the lower end of those who who are going to be the the drop outs and the
 	
 	
 		and you worry with you know the effects of
 	
 	
 		and the poor and the homeless and whatnot
 	
 	
 		the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> on the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and the unborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh
 		in terms of  what it's going to mean to a society in the future it's a some ways it's rather frightening rather
 	
 	
 		yeah that's just another
 		yeah
 		it really is it's just it it just is almost overwhelming sometimes when you think of
 	
 	
 		it certainly is
 	
 	
 		of the jobs that is out there to be done
 	
 	
 		well it sure is
 	
 	
 		in order to flip things back around the way they needed to be
 	
 	
 		it sure is
 	
 	
 		uh not that i really think that they were perfect <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty or thirty years ago</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		it was a little easier though wasn't it
 	
 	
 		uh yeah just the volume makes a big difference i
 	
 	
 		that's
 		yes
 	
 	
 		as uh as uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> you know i use to think sometimes it's not so much
 		uh it's not so much the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> it's just the volume of it to try to keep all wash done and all the things done and you know and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and they all the things demanded of the mother too i mean uh i look at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s life uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean she she didn't work um um for a long time uh when i was very young she didn't drive
 		uh she learned to drive i think when i was um a teenager and her life was a lot simpler and i
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right and and</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s lives were simpler because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was there somebody was there
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		and and when there's nobody there i always thought too that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> worrying about going to work when their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> when their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are little
 		and i and i think that's sad if they have to because they miss so much
 		but i i believed after having a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> that the worst time you could go to go work was when they were teenagers
 	
 	
 		they need you more as a teenager
 		isn't that true that's why i'm working in a school system so that i'm home when they're home um
 	
 	
 		right it's not so much that they come to you every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minute</TIMEX> but it's that you are there when they need you
 	
 	
 		that's exactly isn't that that's so true uh uh i find working in a high school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's very helpful because it let's me be a little more tolerant and understanding of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it keeps me from being the old foggy but at the same time it also it prevents <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> from try to go pull the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wool</ENAMEX> over your eyes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes i think that's true
 	
 	
 		as to what's come but that's the same i'm home at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX> i'm home with the holidays
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		i'm home at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three o'clock</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are at home or where home one is now a senior in high school and the other's in college
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		and uh it's uh it does it
 	
 	
 		but that helps a lot i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who just uh had a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> job she needed need to work and she
 		opted to go into a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> where she could take her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		and looked a long time before she found one that was laid back enough so they she would be able to interact with them and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and felt like they were getting  you know uh a good kind of experience as well
 	
 	
 		well i'm
 	
 	
 		but uh i think that's really important i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> realize how important it is
 	
 	
 		that's that is that is so true and it's not that always that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> always say something but every once in awhile they'll come up and make a comment
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah you
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you realize uh it's important that
 		and and yet you know we have to make that choice i think um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty years ago</TIMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>  didn't have to make that choice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i think that's right what was what is your name again
 	
 	
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Lee</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and your name was
 	
 	
 		well i think probably that we've just about
 		i don't haven't change the world but
 	
 	
 		well i enjoyed talking with you
 		well i enjoyed talking with you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes it's nice talking to you too bye now
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	