
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right well uh quite a few and they're varied they don't uh uh encompass uh many handcrafts like knitting and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i do uh quite a bit of wreath making and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> are my hobbies i do a lot of gardening i go to estate sales which takes up a lot of time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now what do you mostly do
 	
 	
 		well mostly right now i'm a  i do a lot of sports and stuff like that is my hobbies and do a lot of things with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> as much as possible
 		we're uh we're about to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to go roller skating and a birthday <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and stuff so
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>  that should be fun
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah fun for them
 	
 	
 		yeah how old are they
 	
 	
 		uh i've got a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> who's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that's three
 	
 	
 		well i think that's better than having that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> at home
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and they they rented or you know they the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> they uh just rent skates and stuff for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so uh they're they're looking forward to it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and the
 		the the skating <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rink</ENAMEX> does the rest practically i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> what a help that is
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah uh-huh
 		yeah so uh how long have you lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what kind of
 		well not that long uh just since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> we moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Enid Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so uh we are we're originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> this part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but we did spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enid</ENAMEX> and loved it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we needed to get back uh to our older parents
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i am loving it the weather is divine
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		was uh did you like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> while you were there
 	
 	
 		oh yes very much yeah
 	
 	
 		um what did you all do
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Oklahoma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillips University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enid</ENAMEX> and then he went with uh a family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> that had uh has oil and ranching
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and varied enterprises
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he just quit a perfectly good job and came we came East  yes
 	
 	
 		really
 		so is uh is he working there then or
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh he's doing uh quite a bit of consulting work and has been offered a permanent position and he's contemplating he he's liking this free time actually
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just wonderful after all these years of working
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well how did how did you get uh hooked up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> switchboard thing
 	
 	
 		um  a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gal</ENAMEX> who works uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> on this project i think she's a temporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i see i see
 	
 	
 		we have spread the word a little bit in this part of the country
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> has talked more than i have uh she's talked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four five</NUMEX> different people it seems like she hasn't talked to anybody from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> in fact she's talked to a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> i think yeah
 	
 	
 		really uh what is her name
 	
 	
 		her name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i haven't talked to her i haven't i haven't talked to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh well uh the the call was probably for her they wouldn't accept my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T I N</ENAMEX> number so we put hers in but uh uh like i said we're getting getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> ready to go to the birthday party so but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		some what yeah i i've only talked to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> and they've they've all been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but she hasn't talked to anybody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> yet so that's interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well you haven't told me uh what sports that you are active in
 	
 	
 		well the sport i like best probably is basketball but uh i guess i'm probably better at softball and so i'd like during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer months</TIMEX> it's occupies quite a bit of my time but
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i play in a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX> and and occasionally in a tournament or something on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> usually goes with me we try to do everything we can together
 	
 	
 		well i think that's uh easy entertainment for a family too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well they
 		uh a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine that plays on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> we uh that's usually the team i play on with the tournaments and stuff and they have a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are almost my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> age so they play together pretty well and
 	
 	
 		under the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bleachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah pretty much and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX> enjoys uh the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> real well so they you know that's kind of nice it's like getting together with them so to speak
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes well it's getting a little hot isn't it it
 	
 	
 		yeah well it's been raining a lot here so far so we haven't really had any kind of real heat i think it's going to be warm enough <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> we were noticing a while ago it's already eighty in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so it looks like an air conditioner day but
 	
 	
 		yeah it sure does or maybe this evening anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah it yeah but you know i'm sure you're familiar with that living here we go we go through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enid</ENAMEX> you know quite a bit we go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulsa</ENAMEX> from time to time and my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> live in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> so we drive up there and
 	
 	
 		very much so
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well lots lot of times we take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy five</TIMEX> and uh it seems like
 		seems like that goes through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enid</ENAMEX> i know i've either seen the signs or
 	
 	
 		no no it doesn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enid</ENAMEX> is uh it's in the northwest it's uh directly across the straight uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tulsa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i know i've seen the sign somewhere yeah
 	
 	
 		uh sure you have yes well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enid</ENAMEX> is not uh an unknown little city it uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		an awful lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know where it is or have been there and it was uh a very uh self-sufficient uh wealthy uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know until uh everything happened the bottom fell out
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but it's beginning to do well but there's a lot of uh old time wealth there that has helped to stabilize things
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so uh how long you said you've just lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> just like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> then is
 	
 	
 		since yes something like that oh
 	
 	
 		and you really like it there huh i've heard so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about that area i've never been there but they sure say it's pretty
 	
 	
 		well it's it's pretty the weather is wonderful uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX> we it was just we had so many wonderful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i if it got to be forty degrees i decided it was too cold to to walk the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>  isn't funny how  how your standards change
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah it really does my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> uh doing church work up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> right on the coast
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and it rains you know a lot there but you get used to it i mean it's like a fine mist all the time and it doesn't really it gets to where it doesn't bother you
 	
 	
 		sure
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> this part is very much like that too very foggy and misty the moss grows on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> in the woods up  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight ten</NUMEX> feet
 	
 	
 		rea lly it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 		yeah that's the way it is was there too
 	
 	
 		yeah i think however that's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> uh i know it did it all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said to me well that's our wintertime
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh but
 	
 	
 		well i know you need to go and i've enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		well i have enjoyed talking to you too it was nice to talk to you
 	
 	
 		thanks so much have a
 	
 	
 		i hope you enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh thank you and i hope you enjoy and get through that birthday party
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah  well i hope i live through it that's what i hope okay thanks a lot good-bye
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	