
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it seems to me that one of the biggest differences is the computer revolution
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i can very clearly remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> i was just beginning to explore computerizing my office
 		and and exploring trying to find out what kinds of computers might be useful and we did end up with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> PCs which i now would not have chosen but that was before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macintosh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> i was uh in graduate school pecking out a dissertation on on a manual typewriter
 	
 	
 		oh i know it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so i would say that's one of the largest changes in at least in my life
 	
 	
 		yeah i've i've seen that just in the last um even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> how much they've increased uh increased in use or probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> in college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my degree was in computer
 		uh technology originally and it seemed like it would they were just getting out with the you know the disks and all that getting away with the cards
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know doing away with the the programming cards and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX> i i had a college job uh working as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX>
 		and we had to write code in binary and uh  have it punched in on those little cardboard cards which i don't think exist anymore you never see one of those punch cards anymore
 	
 	
 		i know
 		no
 		um i think TV has a lot to do with the changes too don't you in like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s attitudes
 	
 	
 		well very possibly uh i'm not sure in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> it's been very different from before uh
 		certainly in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> i would say there have been significant changes even even the change from black and white to color television <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX> i guess there were color TVs but i sure didn't have access to one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> practically everybody had a color TV and now i think they're as almost as many well there are more TVs than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">households</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's close to getting uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> TV per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> they say
 	
 	
 		and now everybody uh has VCRs and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> VCRs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah certainly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> uh VCRs were just coming on the market so that's made a significant difference in the way i watch television for instance because uh now
 		i almost never watch a TV program when it's on
 	
 	
 		yeah i know
 	
 	
 		i tape it and then watch it when it's convenient and that way i don't have to worry about being interrupted i can just put it on pause
 	
 	
 		yeah and you can you can flip through the commercials so you don't have to watch the commercials
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		that's always hassle convenient
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes you can watch a program in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty five minutes</TIMEX> instead of an hour
 		you skip the commercials
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so what was their question about decline in sociological
 	
 	
 		wasn't the decline so much i think they just said the changes in uh social social changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how was life different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten twenty or thirty years ago</TIMEX>
 		so
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		it
 	
 	
 		i can't really remember back that far but  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>
 		um
 		i don't know
 		i'd say like in the nineteen seventies you remember how
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would walk around with AM
 		what do you call those little AM radios and now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have jam box with CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> in them you know
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes that's certainly a difference
 	
 	
 		and
 		hand held <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TVs</ENAMEX> and car phones
 	
 	
 		yeah that's another one yeah car phones is a good point and uh cellular phones of all types and beepers uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> i was working in a job at a medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and i had to carry a beeper around and they were
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		kind of bulky and all they did was just uh make a beep noise and then you had to go find a telephone and call in to find out what they wanted you for and who you were supposed to call
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> they have these tiny little things that are only about the size of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> pencils
 		and they fit in your shirt pocket and they have a little display screen that shows you a message and either tells you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a phone number to respond to and
 	
 	
 		those are cool
 	
 	
 		yeah those are pretty neat and they have the kind that just vibrates so you can shut them off in a theatre or something and you can still get your messages
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but let's see social changes uh
 	
 	
 		where do you think it's where do you think it's going to go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i haven't the slightest idea i was just thinking though about a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a huge social change in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was just beginning to be recognized and noticed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> i i know that because i was writing a a paper about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was writing a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> article
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and they still didn't even know what caused it or anything uh there was a suspicion that it was a virus but nobody had identified it and they were really just going on epidemiological uh
 	
 	
 		wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh guesswork uh because the way it was transmitted made it look an awful lot like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">uh hepatitis</ENAMEX> and then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		from from the spread pattern of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hepatitis</ENAMEX> they could work backwards to the transmission by uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and semen and then i
 	
 	
 		i'm curious what was your uh graduate study in
 	
 	
 		well i was i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> as a matter of fact and medieval studies
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but i went to work as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and writer
 		so uh uh uh uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> i was working in the medical center uh publishing a journal
 		and writing about medical topics
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and let's see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> i guess we're were just beginning to get into what they were calling the uh
 		the sex revolution where uh after the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> and uh uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		freed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up from worries about uh illegitimate pregnancy and
 		i guess in the seventies is the the time when that was supposed to have exploded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years ago</TIMEX> there was no pill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		do you think that's caused a lot of pressure on like younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> today to make choices that they probably shouldn't have to make
 	
 	
 		yep
 		i do i really do i have uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in college right now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepchildren</ENAMEX>
 		and i know that the expectation for them was uh to have sex and uh much earlier than the expectation when i was in college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in my day we talked quietly behind our hands about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we suspected might be sleeping with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but they certainly didn't expect everybody to and it was really only uh acceptable if you were engaged and planning to get married in in the relatively near future
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i certainly know from talking to my stepdaughter that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in high school were under a whole lot more pressure
 		nowadays
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		it's kind of scary when i think of what will happen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> you know when i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they're grown and
 		um just kind of some of the changes that will happen even more so seems like it can't get much worse
 	
 	
 		and i guess the answer is is stay flexible because nobody can predict what's going to happen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 		i certainly wouldn't have been able to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> tell you what uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were likely to be like course one of them was just a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a an</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a brand new baby <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> so i sure wouldn't have been able to predict
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for him
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and some of the other ones weren't born
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so
 		sounds like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s going to become even more communication society with faxes and cellular phones and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		worldwide communication and
 	
 	
 		electronic mail
 		i just got on that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past about a year ago</TIMEX> and that's made a difference in the way i do my job because it's so much easier to get hold of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and get quick answers to things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		even when they're another on another continent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		it's pretty wild
 	
 	
 		yeah and even you know that reminds me <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Express</ENAMEX> was around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> but it was used as kind of an extreme emergency
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and nowadays <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> use <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed Ex</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure do
 		huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do seem to travel more it's much more common for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> to be going to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i was
 		almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> before i got off this continent
 		and uh both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> had been abroad when they were still in high school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know that's what uh what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was talking when i picked up and moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> and they were like well you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thirty years ago</TIMEX> we wouldn't have done that you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh especially come home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every couple months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 		and
 		
 		
 	