
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay what do you think are some current trends in uh the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> spend time together
 		based on what you've seen
 	
 	
 		um i i think that it's getting to where they're not spending time together
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um i think uh like in my situation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> are supposed to spend time together my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s been off doing his thing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day today</TIMEX> and i've been off doing my thing all day
 		and i haven't seen him since <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock this morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		are you newly married or
 	
 	
 		um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah same same situation here i've been married about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten months</TIMEX>
 		so
 		yeah i can i can i know what you mean
 	
 	
 		it's it's really hard hard to find time to spend together when you both work full time and
 		uh you both have hobbies that are different you know if you have hobbies that are the same then you know you can enjoy your hobby together but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i have different hobbies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		is he a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunter</ENAMEX> and a fisher and all that
 	
 	
 		no no he's a record <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collector</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hot Wheels</ENAMEX> collector
 	
 	
 		that's wild that's wild
 	
 	
 		um so he was off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> uh looking at at records
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh and i was off you know doing you know house household type things you know laundry and um did some shopping and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 		um from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i've talked to i don't know if i should bring this into it but um a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dads</ENAMEX> said that they would probably choose careers that are more um where they could manage their own schedule
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they could spend more time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because they look back and you know they're all like
 		um kind of regretful i think
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think i think that would be the ideal situation i think that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like in my case i i do shift work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't have that choice
 	
 	
 		yeah same here
 	
 	
 		um i have to be at work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at X hour</TIMEX> you know at this at at a certain hour and i can't it's not flexible
 		um it it would be nice to be able to have flexible <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and and maybe after we decide to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i i might find a job that has flexible hours i would i hope so anyway um but i would i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah that
 		at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> is that where you work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's really kind of sad some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i work with
 		they like when i worked on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> shift um their parent their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go to school during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and then they wouldn't see them at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> because they would be in you know at work and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are going to be in bed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so it was kind of like they see their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen minutes</TIMEX> and the same with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relative</ENAMEX> may work even a weirder shift like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> or something you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it was really sad just you know that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		have to well you know have to have dual income a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> choose to which is fine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come to suffer
 	
 	
 		yeah i ideally it would it would be nice to be able to just have like back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> you know back like when when i grew up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> stayed home you know and raised the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> didn't go back to work until i was in junior high school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um so she was there pretty much all my you know formative years
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that was nice and i liked that and i would hope that i would be able to give that to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but i think with the way the future is um economy wise i don't think it's going to be realistic
 	
 	
 		i know unfortunately that's probably true
 		um
 		do you think some the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> spend quality time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are do you think it's more like watching TV and stuff like that
 		not really uh
 	
 	
 		i yeah i i think that i think very few spend quality time i think most of the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are usually off watching cartoons or playing video games or stuff stuff like that i think that um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um uh most most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that i see don't really they don't really value quality time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's always that way until
 	
 	
 		until until they're older and then they look back
 	
 	
 		until it's too late yeah it's true
 		um what's what are some other questions they have i'm not sure
 		i know  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are growing up i guess they never spent much time watching TV in fact i've never seen my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> turn on the TV we didn't really have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very often
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and and they spent a lot of time like outside with us and stuff but you know
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> had his own business and it was easier for them to do that but i i don't know it was  i guess i didn't realize what a luxury it was at the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now a days are raised on TV i mean that's that's almost like a surrogate TV is a surrogate parent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		that's a good way to put it
 	
 	
 		and not a and not a very good one at that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		pretty good way to put it
 		
 
 		if i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> well if you had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> what kind of things do you hope to do
 	
 	
 		um i i hope to
 		of course be able to teach them right from wrong i hope i hope to be able to spend um their growing up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> being in the home you know not having to work
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and being able to do i i i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who who um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i work part-time also and i a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i work for are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> that stay home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and they they do a lot of volunteer work and they're real active in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and um they do a lot of things with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		that they wouldn't ordinarily be able to do if they were working
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'd i'd like to be able to do that i'd like to be able to stay home and be able to spend time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		do volunteer work and be in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> and stuff yeah i agree i hope that happens in my case
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but i think that's for the the few and far between i think that uh
 		probably ninety percent of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um parents</ENAMEX> out there are are probably working parents
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and i i don't i don't really see that that trend changing much if anything i think there's going to be fewer and fewer uh single income families
 	
 	
 		i know
 		yeah and what's sad about that is day cares end up instilling values in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that may not necessarily be consistent with yours
 	
 	
 		exactly see i i never
 		i don't even know what day care is really all about because i i never went to a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> i never i never had that kind of experience
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh i well i don't even think we had i don't even remember them being around when we were little
 	
 	
 		yeah i i see it seems like that's that's a big trend you know in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years day</TIMEX> cares have have have popped up and become a lot more um
 		a lot bigger part of of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> lives
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's like a home away from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> for a lot of them
 	
 	
 		sure is um
 		well
 		
 
 		i guess we could ring this off since we we've exhausted all of our ideas we seem to agree
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think yeah i think this is a good closing point
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so
 	
 	
 		well it was really nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah you too i wish you the best
 	
 	
 		thanks you too um bye bye-bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> thanks bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	