
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah the changing roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> how roles changed and what do you see coming in the future
 	
 	
 		oh okay that's not a broad enough topic
 	
 	
 		okay yeah  sounds good
 	
 	
 		i'm ready when you are
 	
 	
 		okay hold on
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		are you there oh my goodness i can't believe i did that okay hold on
 	
 	
 		yep i'm here
 		uh that's okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 		um
 	
 	
 		okay um i don't know are you in your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> or do you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay well then i can tell you that roles have changed i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty eight</TIMEX>  and they've changed quite a bit um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i this was my twentieth high school reunion in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and basically um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the choices i mean you know you probably heard that in the fifties <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> liked to stay home and all that that's kind of um the opposite of what it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> and early seventies it was sort of just to um go protest and uh
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 		right
 	
 	
 		just everybody be damned and live with someone and you know social social morals were a little bit lacking
 	
 	
 		oh i know that uh
 		um-hum i know that uh in in the early seventies uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> were the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to to make a move as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um uh before that a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that wanted to protest were large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> like uh Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or you know just large large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but but the
 	
 	
 		right it was more it was more civil rights oriented or race oriented rather than gender based yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 		and i think i think the women's movement kind of brought in individual lives where you had women's movements and you had gay movements and just the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i think since then is is when a lot of the women's roles were started to change
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		it did
 		it did and some of the other stuff that um i think that changed it you uh when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got out of college fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> they were always saying well if you if you were assertive you were a libber or you were aggressive not assertive and independent and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in terms of the corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> i've seen a big change in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> finally being quote unquote used to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are in uh controlling positions as higher you know corporate in the corporate hierarchy so i think that's good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think that uh you know you can just look at home life and see i've been talking a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about education and things and and what what what affects the school system and i think that a big thing that affects it is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is not home anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		um like she used to be she used to be kind of kind of a a rock you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> yeah and uh since since everyone
 	
 	
 		the mainstay yeah
 	
 	
 		going out and working now whether it be because of finances or just the economy uh the mother's not there anymore and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are i think i think a lot of society is suffering not to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> shouldn't
 	
 	
 		and restructuring stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		you know go out and do what they want to do but i think that um society's going to really have to get used to it and they're not quite used to it yet and that's i
 	
 	
 		right
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or the moms the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> or the parents yeah
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		um i'm trying to think of what else i have a lot of opinions on this except all of a sudden i went blank
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a lot of the things um the demographics too i mean there's more i don't have the numbers in my head <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> but a lot of the things that brought feminism i mean there are just more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in in in the demographics just generally in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> in terms of being
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		i mean i'm the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boomer</ENAMEX> i hate that term but in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women  women</ENAMEX> going out i mean <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX> i remember that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh  yeah</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what's it like to be <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> today i mean when i was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX> the issues were either go to graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or get married um those were the general issues
 	
 	
 		speaking of getting married i was talking to someone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> on this on the project and uh uh we were talking about child care and he asked me if i had any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> he was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about forty</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years old</TIMEX> and i said no i'm just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> and i said no i'm just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		he was ancient yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know because i don't think of myself as needing to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but the the first thing he says is well don't you miss that part of your life
 		and i just i my my mind just went i went what you know because it didn't it really didn't doesn't even occur to me right now to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because
 	
 	
 		you didn't know what was there to be missing
 		
 
 		i don't have any either and i've been a married for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> so huh
 	
 	
 		yeah and it it just you know i think that i'll probably have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> when i'm about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty thirty five</TIMEX> something like just because i'm not sure if it's just if it's just me or or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in general that are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty three right now</TIMEX> because um
 	
 	
 		yeah when it's time um-hum
 	
 	
 		i'm really into my career i'm trying to go somewhere
 	
 	
 		yeah you want to establish
 	
 	
 		and and get there quick and then worry about you know because right now in my career i'm i'm really starting out and it's going to take me a while to move up and i don't need anything kind of holding me back um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and and you'll find that that's the other big thing that has changed in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um women</ENAMEX> don't feel like they need to get married anymore i was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty seven</TIMEX> when i got married and i just at the time um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> actually even jokes about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX> when we met and i was at a point where it was like i didn't date i mean i just i went out to have a good time but i didn't have to have male companionship um and a lot of the um
 	
 	
 		right
 		right right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that i had in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> at that point who had gone back and gone to law school or MBA programs um which i also had done had just you know they were very sad but then by the time i got married um it seemed like they were on their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> around the marriage track
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so i guess that's a big change in terms of just um the attachments that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> feel like they need to have the dependency their self-identity is stronger yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah it's it's just really not there anymore and that that has to do with you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> getting out and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> seeing other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> you know out in the corporate world that's like oh i can do that you know maybe i don't need to get married
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and i i i mean i don't know how how old your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is she's probably let's see my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early sixties</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		she's about <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">forty um</ENAMEX>-hum
 	
 	
 		okay  i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty eight</TIMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s forty  i just turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty eight</TIMEX> um  yes i'm laughing oh my God it does start to creep up no um but it's okay don't ever let age i mean i don't think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		nobody talks about it for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> except other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and other men
 	
 	
 		i i just turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty three uh April</TIMEX> twentieth and i'm still going you know oh my God i'm getting so old i just because me myself i just like to move really really quickly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and
 	
 	
 		i like to anything i do i got out of school quick i'm you know i'm working quick i want to move up quick i want to make money quick i want to retire quick and so anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		when when the age creeps up where i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three and twenty four</TIMEX> i'm thinking my time is running out you know but i'm actually very very young
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah you are because what i was going to say is what you'll find is my background is in journalism and corporate communications and what you'll find is i mean i'm just now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		finally to a point where i mean i don't know why i didn't didn't do it sooner but this is probably typical of the women's movement too the idea that you're going to be forty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> anyway if you want to go back to school i'm seriously considering going back to school for law
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		um which is a complete i wouldn't say career change it's it's a  but it's still is a different application and i mean if you think about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		you know i can i still can have another career i mean i've worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">over fifteen years</TIMEX> in what i've done and i mean so when you're saying quick um i think that's probably one thing that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> coming up after mine is thinking that um
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		they have to do everything you know sort of i call kind of i call it a chewing syndrome they have to eat real fast they have they have to rapidity of speech they have to just go through everything
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and you'll find that probably by the time you're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty eight thirty</TIMEX> if you haven't slowed down something will slow you down do you know what i'm saying um because it's just you find out that you're really not um smelling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">roses</ENAMEX> and i know that sounds trite and all that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah i think i think a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> probably feeling that way i know i'm probably feeling that way because it's everything's geared towards young
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and whether i want to realize it or not everything on television is young young young young you can't be a model after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> you can't do this after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> you know and every everybody that's in the music business is starting out at fifteen
 	
 	
 		oh it is
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and so i feel like i'm old it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">i sing i sing</ENAMEX> and i would really love to become
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> but i think i'm too old now and i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX> because everyone i've seen coming up they're fifteen
 	
 	
 		oh you're not no
 		no
 		it's true i mean it's it's
 	
 	
 		you know and so i'm going i'm so old and i'm i i really have to always tell myself no you're not you're very young and you know so it's
 	
 	
 		no you're extremely yeah it's it's just well it's like us we're getting ready to do if possible for an adoption and i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that say well why would you do that if you know you haven't been able to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> which we do know why would you do that now at this part point and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's just individual choices i stopped comparing myself <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX> to somebody who had um in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i mean he just turned forty his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will be out of high school before he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty five</NUMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 	
 	
 		um i mean that's like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> look how young she is compared to where you are out of school and everything it's just it but what you find is you don't compare the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> because you just get into trouble it's all independent and choices
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		right
 		um-hum yeah very true
 	
 	
 		um but what i was going to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> is uh your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> probably just won't say it but i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> are always saying uh to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and i my female cousins
 		you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are so lucky because quote unquote you have all these choices you know you went to school you can do this you can do that we couldn't do that then and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and i go well why couldn't you  and they
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 		yeah that's that's why i say i feel i feel really lucky right now because because i'm not married and because i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i'm out of school i'm <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty three</NUMEX> i can do
 		anything i want to do anything and so i mean even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> i'm looking for another job now but and i get so depressed because not because i can't find a job but because i can't figure out what i want to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		and that's normal i mean i think that's the world today
 	
 	
 		and yeah and i feel
 		and i'm lucky though because not a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can sit there and go gee i don't know what to do i have so much you know not a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but it's depressing too what do you what do you do that you're uh-huh
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's exactly yeah
 		that's how i mean
 		what i'm right now i'm i'm a freelance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> right now and then um what i'm doing is
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		working at um a electronics an electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company newspaper</ENAMEX> right now on the side and then i'm also actually i'm excited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> i have a um
 	
 	
 		hum
 		oh
 	
 	
 		luncheon appointment with a prospective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">client</ENAMEX> to do um marketing communications for them
 	
 	
 		hum
 		hum okay i'm a i'm a news <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> now and what i'm looking for is something in i really don't want to stay in news but i would like to stay in journalism and i've been looking for something exactly like that just um-hum
 	
 	
 		so we
 		oh you are
 		what
 		here's what you should do this is off the topic and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> probably won't  did you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX> by any chance
 	
 	
 		okay
 		
 
 		no i don't i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> and i i just happen to work at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> because you know
 	
 	
 		oh okay that's even better
 		i went to are you in radio or television or news
 	
 	
 		broadcast broadcast news uh-huh TV
 	
 	
 		uh my journalism degree is in
 		
 		
 	