
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um
 		about crime um
 		what are your concerns
 	
 	
 		well my uh uh basic concern is that
 		overall we have uh such a overcrowding in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> now that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> are actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh  basing their decisions on what they do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> once they are caught
 	
 	
 		right i agree
 	
 	
 		that uh probation and stuff like that is uh becoming more and more prevalent uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prevalent</ENAMEX> and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are getting out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year earlier</TIMEX> and so there's less you know motivation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to you know deterrent i guess the deterrent value has gone down
 	
 	
 		i know it
 		i agree
 		right
 		yeah i know it they've taken the deterrent out of crime anymore it seems like and
 		just i don't know i'd never i don't think the punishment fits the crime on most of these things anyway uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just get a slap on the wrist for murder it seems like and then others
 		get you know a a horrible sentence for
 		practically nothing i just can't understand you know what they're of course i know i think dope has a lot to do with a lot of the crimes we have and dope and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all that sort of stuff but  and i think they've tied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX>'s hands a lot too on some you know some laws out there tied their hands where they you know
 		can't arrest them or can't shoot or anything  like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i know it's a
 	
 	
 		you can't shoot a fleeing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">felon</ENAMEX> or something oh you know just ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah it gets sort of hard and then uh they get information from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> isn't present and they can't use it you know because they just assumed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was you know tortured or beaten into uh giving his confession
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		absolutely absolutely and and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> i get so made at them because they or defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> any way they just seem like they
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		get these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> out on the flimsiest excuses you know and uh i don't know really makes me mad some of these things that they come up with
 		that i just can just boggles my mind that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> is even i remember reading in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> where a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was
 		suing uh let's see who was he suing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> he had murdered because he said if they had been stricter parents
 		she wouldn't have been out and he wouldn't have murdered raped and murdered her and so he was suing them and i thought that shouldn't have even come to court you know
 		that should have been laughed out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> isn't that pitiful i
 	
 	
 		yeah that i don't what ever happened but that is amazing
 		oh brother
 	
 	
 		i hear your little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> crying
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah he's a little upset he doesn't see me
 	
 	
 		is he bless his heart
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so he's like oh where'd you go you disappeared
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		down here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		how old is he
 	
 	
 		he's uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten months</TIMEX> my goodness
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah he's getting to be a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> really
 	
 	
 		is that your only child
 	
 	
 		uh no i have another one that's two
 	
 	
 		oh oh my goodness you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have your hands full don't you
 	
 	
 		well  yeah both of them in diapers
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a that's a little of a work load
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> boys
 		yeah i guess that's uh oh my
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so she uh she does has most of the fun time
 	
 	
 		that helps
 		yeah yeah you get to come home and really enjoy them probably
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		back to crime
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		we're supposed to find out what let's see what are our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> or what do we think
 		did she say what what do do do we can solve it or something i think
 	
 	
 		yeah right um-hum
 	
 	
 		i'm like you i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> need to
 		or i don't know build more <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> i don't care you know or and execute some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that are on death row you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's probably the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that</TIMEX> that seems to be the guiding factor with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> they say hey we'd like to convict more of them but you know we don't have a place to put them so what are we supposed to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		and if they would you know when they send these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> to the death penalty kill them you know quit wasting our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>' money by having appeals appeals appeals appeals just get them on and kill them and go on with it you know and
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		
 
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		empty there's there's a bunch on death row we'd empty a lot bunch of beds if we'd uh uh you know do what we're supposed to do and get on with it but and to me that that's a
 	
 	
 		yeah right if you don't want to have the death penalty take it away but you know make up your mind hum
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		and if you know
 		if uh uh i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is one of the leading ones that we we've probably executed probably more than i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> yeah and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah the southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are are more into that and
 	
 	
 		yeah i know they have it up here but it takes  you know
 	
 	
 		they just keep appealing it appealing it appealing it yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and then they just get out for
 	
 	
 		and it's going to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> for it to kick in
 	
 	
 		yeah and then they get out for good behavior you know and that makes but see i don't care what they say i think the death penalty is a deterrent to some to to to some extent and you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> did did you watch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes the other night</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> being given a free education from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University</ENAMEX> and i thought and i thought  golly and this  uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> said you know if they want to give out a free education there is a lot of poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that'll like to have a uh degree from B <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U</ENAMEX> you know why give it to these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> who aren't going to be able to use it anyway you know and i just
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		makes me sick that they could they're mollycoddle i remember down here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one time</TIMEX> the judge ordered the uh
 		i think the  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> complained that didn't have color TV so they had to give them colored TV as a cruel and unusual punishment because they didn't have colored TV they had to watch black and white  oh God
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		
 
 		oh my word yeah i i think the deterrent would uh really make a difference tha t and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know uh paying cops a little bit more you know because the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> we have they're either you know there are some that have that are actually going corrupt because they don't get any money and there are some that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		sure
 	
 	
 		the best quality <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not going into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> because they say hey you know there's better things i can do you know
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> in law is a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> here and um
 		he makes he makes pitiful i his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> makes more than he does and i think that's a shame that that happens
 	
 	
 		um-hum there's yeah there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are dedicated and will do it anyway and then there's some that you know the police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> would say well it actually would like to turn this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> down but  we need them you know
 	
 	
 		yea h that's the way he
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah right right
 	
 	
 		and um i'm sure you
 	
 	
 		or they're forced into you know having so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> and whether they're qualified or not they hire them because they have to have that ratio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Whites</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> so they uh
 		that's uh what's happening to a lot of them i think they're getting and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> probably aren't good cops anyway but they were in the right place at the right time and the right minority so they they're getting on i'm i'm sure i know there's some good minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh they're not applying for the job i mean it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> but they're not applying for the jobs especially
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think quotas like and they do have quotas i guarantee you they've got quotas they have to have so many
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		like i say whether and that's the same with the fire department anything else and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if they're not qualified they shouldn't have it you know i don't think they should lower the standards just so they can pass the test or anything and that's what they do a lot they just lower the standards a little bit and that way more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> qualify and i think that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		i think that that is true well i better get going see what he's doing
 	
 	
 		okay we've had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our five minutes</TIMEX> haven't we
 	
 	
 		okay  thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		thank you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	