
 
     		
 	
 		okay there's there's one  um i'm at living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> where you at
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome New York Rome New York</ENAMEX> okay well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> let me look at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and ask him  does <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> have state capital punishment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome New York</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yes they do
 		he's reminding me of where i live yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		i new <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> does not but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're they're trying to reinstate it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>'s opposed to it being that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> that he is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Cuomo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		but the state legislatures are more and more coming to supporting it
 	
 	
 		yeah i um i ethically don't like the idea but or i should say morally i don't like the idea but um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> ethics ethics and ethics socially and ethically i think it's a good idea
 	
 	
 		i'd i would agree with that they almost even more
 	
 	
 		in certain crimes
 	
 	
 		i don't know if this is cold and too pragmatically but i'm really offended by the thought that i have to support uh just the existence of you know murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX> whatever  you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right and any demand on the street no i know
 	
 	
 		right that that uh after they've gone and done horrible things molested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and kill them and whatever that society has to pay uh upwards uh thirty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to incarcerate them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is having a problem right now and it's the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the the</TIMEX> the repeatable crime i think that's the the  repeat crimes and the repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> is happening down here where they're they're patrol the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">patrol board</ENAMEX> is letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> walk that have done
 		oh heinous things from calling from uh killing police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> to i mean just multiple you know molestations molestations to murders of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> just you know really bad things
 		and they're get these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are getting out like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three to five years</TIMEX> before they're even suppose to be considered
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and now they can't find them and they're finding bodies in ditches you know i mean you think think why they say it's because you're over crowded it's over crowded then you think how can every is everybody that stupid or is the world really that rotten
 	
 	
 		i
 		i don't know it's a hard question you look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> we have the largest murder rate of any developed uh or uh
 	
 	
 		right i know
 		and then and i don't know how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are about handguns but uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> i work with just told me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that uh in the state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">capitol</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin Texas</ENAMEX>
 		they had been uh looking at a bill uh making it easier to accept the bill to access to access handguns and they passed it
 		which basically means without an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> check any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> one can get a gun
 		
 
 	
 	
 		here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> it's a lot harder than that uh it takes uh it takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost six months</TIMEX> to get uh handgun permit in this state
 	
 	
 		is it that's good
 		say that good i think that's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> yeah that's great
 	
 	
 		now the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">the</ENAMEX> and that's with uh you have to have uh
 		oh a police investigation you have to have references and i know because a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine wanted to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and listed me as a reference um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i know it there is it's very easy to get uh
 		uh you know there's no no restrictions whatsoever on hunting <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX> and shotguns and things like that which aren't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the i i don't consider to be the kind of a a crime uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> you know uh so
 	
 	
 		right they're not the cattiness behind right yeah i mean i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> in general but when i think about uh this topic like capital punishment i look at somebody
 		i mean i just remember when i was in college in a dorm and i think if he'd been around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of my family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> probably would have killed him but in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> when they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Bundy</ENAMEX> case
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and how they just executed well it hasn't been just but it was in the i think the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">third quarter of last year</TIMEX> nineteen ninety
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i had you know i knew some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that said why are you glad you did you know this had nothing and i said just maybe because he got a lot of media hype and all that but i actually i mean there should be more cases like that where they
 		flip a switch i have and i might be too cold too but they flip a switch i don't know i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah i well
 		and and the thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bundy</ENAMEX> was though he escaped and then
 	
 	
 		so many times
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh did it again and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i mean and that's just maybe because of the little more that they said celebrated that uh he's not the only one you know you you see somebody's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini</ENAMEX> series and you hear about somebody's crime there was something on and this gets back to capital punishment
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had stolen uh not stolen but kidnapped uh some wealthy ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> somewhere in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and they changed all the facts that they said it was true and they buried her alive
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh God
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Strauss</ENAMEX> had played the lead role and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and and the at the end of you know how they have these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mini dramas</ENAMEX> at the end they said this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">set person</ENAMEX> was paroled like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months ago</TIMEX> and you're thinking oh
 		that's nice
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean you know i'm not sure that capital punishment serves as a deterrence
 		but it does serve as a punishment uh definite punishment you know lasting punishment
 	
 	
 		that sure there's an end to the the situation
 	
 	
 		right in that particular instance um
 		but i but i don't but i know it's not a end all and be all that's the problem i have with it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> they think it's an end all and be all they think that if they electrocute or slip or do something else gas somebody
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um that they're not going to have the crimes that they do have and we happen to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> which is extremely crime ridden and we just moved here uh we've been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">before</TIMEX> lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis Saint Paul</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh which has an exceedingly low crime rate and then we were transferred back here and when you're gone from some place like it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six years</TIMEX> as we were you really begin to see uh just how problematic
 		just living is even suburban no matter where you are and how you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome New York</ENAMEX> is that and and is that like near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Syracuse</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome New York</ENAMEX> it's up state it
 		it's uh near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syracuse</ENAMEX> it's about uh well i i actually live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Village of Sylvan Beach</ENAMEX> i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		what what type of area is that is that uh in term
 	
 	
 		it's more rural uh it use to be use to be a uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh have a lot of heavy industry but it's kind of uh all the industry has gone south and uh now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> is the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> in the uh area and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh so it's
 	
 	
 		how would how is the situation in there in terms of crime and things that would not too bad
 	
 	
 		not too bad it you know you the still have the um
 		more drug problems and typical uh small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> type problems but i don't know that there's a real
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no there isn't the harsh  crime and all
 	
 	
 		not the harsh criminality
 		that you find in yeah now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is a
 		i'm being very sarcastic it's just a great place um on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's um
 		i don't know the good ole boy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> here is uh very strange like i said they believe that if they kill somebody you know
 		tit for tat and deed for deed that that does something uh but yet they want spend the money to build the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> that i mean they really are over crowded i mean that's that's just not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i just you know i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> which i think is basically like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> i'm not sure if they i don't think they have capital punishment there
 	
 	
 		think
 		think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> may have just reenacted it because i'm from uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just uh just outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not trying
 		yeah and i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> so oh well we'll forgive each other
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um because they use to be very very conservative when i was growing up i and i can't i haven't lived there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> but um
 	
 	
 		right
 		the west part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is and then the east part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is got all the bleeding hearts and all the welfare cases so
 	
 	
 		there you go
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know that's a different topic subject altogether but uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know i think everybody would feel it is same way if they were touched by crime i think everyone would you and i think are probably honest and candid because we could do it on in this vehicle um but i think everybody if they were touched by it would say
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if they had any sense of rage that could be brought out which i think every human does i think they'd say yeah do it if somebody in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or if it happened it me you know um
 	
 	
 		sure
 		yeah if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> or family get uh had that happen to them i think everyone would uh i they'd probably
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		pull the trigger themselves or flip the switch themselves and with a smile on their face as they did it
 	
 	
 		yeah i just don't think that uh you can rehabilitate i mean i just don't uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh i did a paper back in college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time ago</TIMEX> for criminal justice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and i just the subject i remember we drew things out of a hat and it was something uh just it was basically the essence was does the crime fit the punishment and
 		when you see how many repeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> there are uh check check fraud cases where they go to jail for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five to ten years</TIMEX> and um rape <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX> getting their hand just slapped
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and how it is based on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> and if the time of day that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is in session you know all these uh intangible intangible intangible things and you're thinking
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you would not only would you not want to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> you wouldn't want to be a criminal either
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because you wouldn't know what you're getting um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i don't know methods of capital punishment i have no opinions on that either i just
 	
 	
 		well uh i uh yeah i don't know i think the old gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chamber</ENAMEX> seems to be about the most painless because i guess it's a pretty pretty rough thing to be uh electrocuted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		is it uh how about the injection is that suppose to be
 	
 	
 		oh yeah an injection yeah that would be even yeah i didn't even think about that
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not even sure in the split among the fifty states do you know which way it is the ratio it's more than aren't uh that it's more that don't have it isn't that correct
 	
 	
 		i think yeah there's more that don't have it but amazingly it's like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> went back and reinstated capital punishment oh maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six or seven years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if they've used it since then since they've reinstated it but uh it's on the books which
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and always say do something about i'm not sure if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Minnesota</ENAMEX> i
 		they didn't they didn't they were against well did they have it they were against it um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> as i said has it but i haven't been back here long enough to to realize whether or not if they've done it in the last
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	