
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay i think we're supposed to discuss the changes in the roles of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the last generation or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and my opinion is that uh the  biggest changes uh probably are about two
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of course is obvious and that's the working woman
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one which i don't know if you'd go along with or not is that maybe a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are not as uh likely to want to be dominated as past times
 	
 	
 		well that's i would say that's probably true uh i know in in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s case she is a very independent sort uh you know she she has a lot of say about uh you know just about everything that uh happens in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> life
 	
 	
 		and you're proud of that
 	
 	
 		and yes i am i i you know i i feel very confident that if you know something were to happen to me or to us either one that uh you know she would be
 		capable of taking care of her own you know what ever her own needs are right and and i think that's very important
 	
 	
 		of course
 		well uh another uh thing that i want to talk about is which of the the changes that you can think of are the most significant
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i i really think that that that independence of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is uh probably more important an and i guess that uh really came about because of the change or a lot of it anyway because of the change in the work force
 		uh with more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working and having uh more uh important or or uh
 		what's the right term anyway their jobs is being you know more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> depending on them and more management decisions made
 		i think that uh lends to being you know more independent and
 		stepping out and saying what you want to say and what needs to be said
 	
 	
 		well and don't you think that you do see more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who are um becoming part of middle management
 	
 	
 		yes i i i that's even even uh upper management is is uh i think is going to be a a coming thing for for women too uh
 		and in the professions also not just uh not just within company <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> but you know professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh
 		are going out on their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> a CPA
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i know quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> CPA's you know that are out working on their own running their own accounting practice and doing quite well
 	
 	
 		uh-huh let me ask you a question uh while we're talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> women uh in uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> say do you think uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> CPA gets paid equally to a man
 	
 	
 		uh i would i'm not sure but i would think so within uh within a public accounting firm
 		uh if they're on the same level of responsibility now i would say that there's you know some
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or i would even say a probability
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> still have it a little more difficult to achieve the same level that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> does uh there's you know there's still some stereotypes uh within even within the the accounting practice
 	
 	
 		what and even within women
 		that they perhaps some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do not expect uh
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		
 
 		um but um within <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> within public accounting
 		within the what is now the big <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> in particular the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that's starting off in accounting uh have an awful lot
 		of uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> to work and and there's a lot of stress put on them uh a lot of requirements for
 		uh you know traveling and being available <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all uh hours</TIMEX> and and that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		going away on those audits
 	
 	
 		right and and i think that uh that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> may you know they may tend still tend to to not want to do that  to the point that they would restrict their own possibility for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh for promotion to achieve that but you know the ones that the ones that really want to uh certainly can go ahead and achieve that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well what what future do you see for us in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next twenty years</TIMEX> say
 	
 	
 		um i i would say that uh
 		there will be you know in the business world there will be more uh opportunities more expansion of the women's role in business
 		and i see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s roles expanding in the political area uh quite a bit uh of course you know we in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we've got uh uh a uh woman <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yes
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and we've had the all let's see what have we got uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> that have all had women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> i think uh recently uh three
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> of them have women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX> also has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman mayor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know i see i see uh
 		you know the movement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> into into the political arena as being very important uh
 	
 	
 		well i'll tell you what worries me a little bit about uh the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> and i'm hoping that that's going to be a change and i don't know if you see it or not my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> doesn't always uh
 		see it or understand it uh and that is the uh the trial of trying to be the superwoman the supermom the
 	
 	
 		yeah the supermom yes
 	
 	
 		yes and uh i have gone through that uh myself and it is hell it really is is tough and to be able to excuse myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from doing that was a wonderful liberation
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i guess i had i think the woman pretty much has to do it themselves but i believe that in the future that they're going to stop trying to be all things
 	
 	
 		right
 		right i i think they'll be uh  you know in in the political area i suppose uh
 		for for the most part <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> have gone through their a a good bit of their business life before they get into politics
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and and i think that that if that's the the situation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> they will have had their family life and their business life you know may be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> and then move into politics
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that's uh you know that's the way that uh that you can have you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can have all things you you just can't have them all at once  and uh i think that's you know that's the case for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>  you know for the most part too
 	
 	
 		yes and
 		a very i will say this very quickly i had an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney friend</ENAMEX> who said and he'd been practicing probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years</TIMEX> and he said i wish there were more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in politics
 		they are not quite as crooked
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 		well i i think that's uh that's the truth and and i i think that there's i think and this is uh may be a bad thing for me to say but i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have a higher moral uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> for the most part
 		than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> do and it you know the  along the sexual type you know the
 	
 	
 		the acceptable
 	
 	
 		the the the little things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that get involved in
 	
 	
 		morals that we uh-huh yes
 	
 	
 		right that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> just don't tend to do that of of course it takes you know it takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> both but i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have
 		or or a little more uh discreet or at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least</NUMEX> a little more careful about what they do and are and you know
 	
 	
 		are reticent about it anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman congressman</ENAMEX>'s not going to have her picture taken on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> somewhere out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> with you know with some young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you know for the most part yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		however i being uh uh former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> myself
 		i did change from being someone who i who felt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> could uh share out share it one job and things like that and i became
 		more understanding of how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> often are  are for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> have thought about uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the working world and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> couldn't believe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he started teasing me and calling me a male chauvinist or a female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chauvinist</ENAMEX> but but i do i think there certainly some pluses uh on both sides we just need to get them all put together
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		well it's been so nice talking to you and good luck to you good luck to you and have a nice day bye
 	
 	
 		right and uh
 		yeah it's been nice talking to you too
 		okay thank you you too um-hum you too bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	