
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well
 		did you get a chance to watch any of the games
 	
 	
 		uh no i i just kind of i
 		i kind of watch them on the news and that's about it
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		uh uh
 		um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> isn't he
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		what did he get hurt <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no i don't think so because uh i saw just a little bit of the game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and he was out there playing
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		although uh i what i saw was at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the first quarter</TIMEX> i think he only had like eightch <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> points
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the first quarter</TIMEX> they thought that was big news
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know but i don't know who won and uh i don't know who do you normally pull for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Mavericks</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		no i i kind of feel like the about the Mavericks the way i do about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah uh just all this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Tarpley</ENAMEX> stuff and
 		and uh what is it their you know he got he's in trouble again down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and and uh they said the other night his contract is so big
 		that if anything happens to him you know if they don't trade him they'll have to pay him off
 		you know so they're rather have him
 		except that he gets in trouble all the time and falls off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX> and and and have some chance of him playing you know earning his money
 	
 	
 		oh jeez yeah because that's just dollars right out of the franchise
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure is
 	
 	
 		oh man
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now i uh i i've always been pulling for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> for a long time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh not just not just because they always win but uh when they had uh Akeem
 	
 	
 		they're consistent
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		anybody who was old as that playing that well
 		you know i just kind of had to go with them then i kind of got caught up with a lot of the other players
 		and uh course uh all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that follow the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> and everything out there in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> um and it also helps when they were winning
 	
 	
 		yeah well they play better as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> than anybody else seems like
 	
 	
 		i was i always wondered that you know i i will take a look at the individual score you know in the individual stance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know they they have in the paper you know like fifteen different categories
 		and they'll have like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> uh they'll have the the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scorer</ENAMEX> the top rebounders uh assists foul shooting percentages and all that
 		and you go thown through and virtually every one of the categories there isn't uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Laker</ENAMEX> in the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> usually hardly any uh anybody anybody in the top <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> except for like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> continue to win so you're right i think they do really play much better as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> than they do uh uh each one you know individually at their spot
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah and year in and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> out it's not like they have you know
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> will will will win the play-offs and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> they'll be all they'll be too busy doing their endorsements and stuff to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to concentrate on the game
 	
 	
 		i understand that um i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>'s really uh giving uh aren't aren't they playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>'s playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> and i think they're really giving them a run for their money
 	
 	
 		yeah except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX>'s hurt
 	
 	
 		did he get hurt again
 	
 	
 		his his back is bad all the time now i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		i tell you what i guess it's tough to play that many games and still stay healthy
 	
 	
 		yeah they play <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times a week
 		like you know and then they go on road trips and they do the same thing and and then they and then they stay out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three weeks</TIMEX> at a time
 		so
 		it really gets you know the i mean they're sleeping in different bed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i imagine that really helps his back
 	
 	
 		he ought to have his own bed come along with him you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah he said he said <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> on the news that he hadn't done any extra shooting for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks</TIMEX> so you know and he's the one that's always winning the um
 		the
 		the outside the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> point shot and the
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		he does that every year
 	
 	
 		yeah matter of fact i watched him uh on TV you know sink i don't know a jeez it was like uh uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> baskets in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> or something like that from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> point range
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		unbelievable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh i don't know did you ever play much basketball
 	
 	
 		not much just uh
 		just just playing <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah because it's it kind of a violent game
 	
 	
 		it really is for a non contact sport quote unquote
 	
 	
 		and
 		and they don't
 		yeah and they don't wear any pads so i
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		i figured
 	
 	
 		
 
 		some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> got pretty funny funny looking uh eye wear
 	
 	
 		yeah they have to wear goggles because they get hit in the in the face with elbows all the time
 	
 	
 		man
 	
 	
 		well it's his it's i was looking in the paper for something on it and here's the the top <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> draft prospects
 		and uh
 		i mean they're all the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> you know
 		except they're just taller
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> when i was up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cleveland</ENAMEX> i was staying at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marriott</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cavaliers</ENAMEX> were playing somebody i think it was like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> or somebody like that and uh i was down by the pool
 		and there was all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> standing around about chest deep in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> now i wear uh contacts and i i had my glasses on and i went down there and and just jumped into the water where they were
 		and it went right up over my head and i came up spittering and sputtering for air and they were all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> there to play the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cavaliers</ENAMEX> they were all like uh like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six eight</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six ten</NUMEX> and they were standing in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> that was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> foot
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> foot yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and it was uh it was funny i tell you i saw i saw a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i don't remember what his name was but he got on the elevator and he had his swimsuit on
 		and uh he was just skin and bones you know it looked like something out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh  i made some comment and uh he says yeah he says i weigh about uh uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred and forty</NUMEX> pounds
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but he says it's not much when you stretch it over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> foot one
 	
 	
 		yeah really
 	
 	
 		so you're right those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> really you know the the big ones i don't even know how much <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewing</ENAMEX> weighs
 		but uh he's got to be way up there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		well here's a here's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSU Stanley Roberts</ENAMEX> he's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seven feet</NUMEX> tall and he weighs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two hundred and eighty pounds</NUMEX>
 		so
 	
 	
 		God
 		that's a that's a lot that's a lot of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> coming down on you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		jeez
 		i didn't even see who's who's supposed to have the the uh the best uh draft picks
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it doesn't even say it doesn't say here it says uh
 		it says the underclassmen this is for underclassmen for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i guess i guess they don't they have they they uh have a lottery on it
 		they pick numbers
 		and that's how they take them in order
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		it must not be according to their how they did during the year
 	
 	
 		i i used to go down to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Reunion Arena uh</ENAMEX> went down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of the draft
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that was really pretty interesting they usually have uh uh you know a video uh highlights of the season
 		you know and basically kind of walks you through what happened to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavs</ENAMEX> and who they traded for and how they did and a lot of good footage both the good and the bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i don't know i haven't i didn't go down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> but uh it it was only like a couple dollars to get in and it was really kind of interesting
 		but uh so who do you thinks going to win the play-offs
 	
 	
 		i i don't know who's  is it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and
 		and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> uh and let's see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">uh Golden State</ENAMEX> and the Lakers
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 		think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> and then the uh
 		shoot
 		i can't remember them all now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah Portland Boston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> play-offs
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> was uh favored by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and the Lakers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Golden State</ENAMEX>
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> over uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
 		jeez
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Boston</ENAMEX> will win
 	
 	
 		think so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i tell you what those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> really hang tough
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i i'd like to see them back up there again
 		they really uh they really gave some some really good years of uh uh
 		of enjoyment and fun and everything have you ever been up there to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston Garden</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh no uh
 	
 	
 		well i don't know is that in i i haven't really gone to a lot of games live but boy i'd sure like to
 		basketball's gotten to be a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	