
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right uh you have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> i understand a couple of them what are they
 	
 	
 		i i well i have uh these well i don't know if they consider themselves <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> anymore they actually you know sort of take over the place and and we're kind of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> get like that don't they they think they own you
 	
 	
 		they don't they really they own the place and naturally these are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay these are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> i remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time uh i used to get a chuckle out of out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pogo</ENAMEX> that dates me quite a bit you probably don't know Pogo
 	
 	
 		oh Pogo sure
 	
 	
 		yeah he when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beauregard</ENAMEX> was talking he was the dog remember and he used to say <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> can be most as much trouble as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> if they work at it a little bit may and even more when they work at it a little bit  and i think that's true actually
 	
 	
 		i agree
 		i don't know i i i think that um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are in such a situation that uh um i'm kind of um not able to do a lot i'm i'm kind of in a wheelchair and i mean i kind of am but um
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah i've got these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> that hang around with me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> and i don't what i'd do without them
 	
 	
 		they
 		just good company huh
 		that's neat
 	
 	
 		it is and
 	
 	
 		you know it's funny how <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pets</ENAMEX> get to be so
 		they really you you really do mourn them after when things happen now we don't actually have a pet right now
 	
 	
 		the okay
 	
 	
 		but uh but we have had some and and i can't it's it's always hard for me to believe how close i've gotten to them we had a little uh um
 		oh dog it was a little uh i got it so it wouldn't wouldn't shed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> poodle a little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> poodle
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh he used to i used to come down stairs in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> to feed him you know and i'd let him up out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basement</ENAMEX> where he was sleeping and he would just dance around the floor and i just got
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and we only had him about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four weeks</TIMEX> before he was hit by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but i cannot believe the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> just
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		he just got in to to us so quickly i could not believe it
 	
 	
 		that yeah that's
 	
 	
 		i i have to tell you about our most interesting pet though
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		uh we had an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">iguana</ENAMEX> living with us for about uh oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh by choice
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two and a half years</TIMEX> i guess it was about uh oh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three feet long about three feet</NUMEX> long it was a beautiful animal name was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		Clyde the Iguana
 	
 	
 		Clyde the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iguana</ENAMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> went to uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and when he came home uh he didn't bring the iguana with him but for some reason or other he had a thing for them i don't know whether he'd i think there was one in the school uh zoology department you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or biology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> one or the other anyway uh and anyway he just he went and found this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> somewhere who had picked up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in
 		i guess in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> i don't know where but anyway he brought this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and i looked at him and i said you've got to be kidding i'm not going to live with a lizard  but you know i visualize that animal racing about
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you know like you think of lizards doing but they don't do that they're very much like uh well the thing about them is that they hold so still you don't notice that they're there and then they move and about scares you to death sometimes
 	
 	
 		did you have him in a cage
 	
 	
 		no he had full run of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>  he just loved to sit on the back of my dryer where the hair the heat came up out of the dryer you know it was he was really a neat pet and though i
 	
 	
 		oh no
 		oh no
 		oh no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know he'd ride when we'd have family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> and everybody would sit in the living room and the fire would be burning he'd walk across my feet sometimes  and it it was a long time before i could really pet him and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but i fed him and he he knew how to get me to feed him he'd come out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> just kind of look at me till i went and got him something out of the refrigerator
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh no i mean you don't argue with an iguana do you
 	
 	
 		but he was really a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">neat animal</ENAMEX> he he'd lay in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>'s lap you know and just uh when he'd pet him he'd just stretch and you know you could see him just enjoying it like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> does
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		it was kind of interesting but he did a lot of interesting things and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> carried him around and he liked to ride on the back of his up on his head you know with his tail wrapped around his arm so he wouldn't fall off and
 		and scare everybody to death and
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness goodness
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> loved him
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just loved him <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just came from all over to come and see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX> and visit with him and and he tolerated them you know he'd even tolerate him petting though he didn't like them too well at first but
 		he he got tame you know so that uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could go in there and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drummer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he didn't he the only thing he didn't like very well was the drumming when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> would drum he'd sit there and scrunch up you know like he was trying to hi protect himself and then he'd leave the room
 	
 	
 		was the drumming
 		and cover his ears
 		isn't that funny the way we put you know um human characteristics on an animal like that and and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they really are they're interesting well they take on human characteristics like
 	
 	
 		as a it's
 		i guess they do
 	
 	
 		uh our other animal the next year our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and well while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX> decided he wanted a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> and he and he looked around a long while and he found a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norwegian</ENAMEX> elkhound
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and he just brought this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Norwegian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elkhound</ENAMEX> and home and he was so funny uh
 		for a while they built a a run for him out to the side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you know he'd been on the patio but they put the run out there and he didn't like this run because there were no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that came by
 		and sometimes he would just make a racket until you came and got him and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> we'd forgotten to put <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> out for him and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hal</ENAMEX> and i were in bed and all of a sudden there was all this noise out to the side the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and and he'd pick up his dish and throw it in the air
 	
 	
 		huh he used a classic illusion
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and then bark and march around you know and then he'd pick up his dish again and throw it in the air  until we came out and gave him some water
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i forgot to ask you did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">iguana</ENAMEX> catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flies</ENAMEX> for you
 	
 	
 		did what
 	
 	
 		did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">iguana</ENAMEX> catch <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">flies</ENAMEX> for you
 	
 	
 		no he didn't eat flies no they eat uh they greens uh we fed him the outside leaves of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lettuce</ENAMEX> you know i'd get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lettuce</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and he'd eat the outside leaves
 	
 	
 		he didn't eat flies
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and then in the summertime you could put him out and he'd eat outside oh except you had to keep him away from the garden because he liked to eat the little <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peas</ENAMEX> as fast as they came up you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i bet
 	
 	
 		it was really  it was really a glamor and of things that were fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sprigs</ENAMEX> you know he liked that
 	
 	
 		well can we ask you whatever happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		well yeah when uh when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> went to college up at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ricksun Idaho</ENAMEX> he took him with him
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh everybody was used to him and they just loved him and what not and this his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> put him out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> didn't know it and it got dark and he didn't get him in again and they searched and searched and searched for him but uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh it got too cold up there and he he died in a tree that they found him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> in a tree he was dead
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		so you can't you have to be pretty tender with them we had a he had his own heat lamp and uh and uh hot pad he laid on you know
 		that was another funny thing he had a hot pad and it it burned up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> it was that was funny too watching him kind of burned up but anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and we got him a new one he had a blue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before and when we got him a new one it was brown and he wouldn't lay on it till we changed the covers
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		no he wouldn't lay on it
 	
 	
 		because that was like what he was used to
 	
 	
 		but
 		so they really are they really pick up things he was he was a clean animal uh we had he went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> in the bathroom
 	
 	
 		how did he do that
 	
 	
 		put well we put some papers on the floor underneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">john</ENAMEX> and he went there to go to the bathroom
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you had to be sure you left the doors open you know he didn't like to go anywhere else he'd he'd scratch and do all kinds of things to get you to open the door if you happened to close it on him or something you know but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		but even when he went when he had an accident or something uh if you just let it dry it dries kind of like uh especially when he was inside and eating just <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lettuce</ENAMEX> it dried up a little bit like ashes and you could just vacuum it up
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter time</TIMEX> there was no smell at all no odor at all to it in the summertime when he was outside and eating outside the smell was a little bit like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		but that that's incredible it's a different little things to
 	
 	
 		yeah he's a he was a really interesting animal
 	
 	
 		oh that's
 	
 	
 		i i just uh we just really and you know to this day i still miss him and that's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well see i guess it's because you lived with you know him an and overcame some fears to get used to him and
 	
 	
 		yeah he was just
 		yeah yeah i think i guess so but it it it was interesting well
 	
 	
 		yeah definitely
 	
 	
 		what do your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> do besides sitting and purring and letting you pet them
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> they well actually they're my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s pets
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		oh and you just kind of took them over huh
 	
 	
 		well
 		well actually it's like he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you know and i have i was always kind of nondescript in that category because i always liked dogs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they've kind of taken over and and uh you know they
 	
 	
 		a little bit easier to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> in this kind of country though isn't it uh
 	
 	
 		maybe it is i they're so independent well i'm glad we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them otherwise i think they get neurotic if there just one of them
 	
 	
 		well i think
 		yeah that could be could be
 	
 	
 		they get real crazy but there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> from the same litter they look totally different they are they well they are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Siamese cats</ENAMEX> but one is
 	
 	
 		oh pretty ones
 	
 	
 		one is uh um they're both registered you know one's a seal point she's the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and then uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhart Newhart</ENAMEX> is the uh the
 	
 	
 		Newhart
 	
 	
 		the
 		he is something he's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> he really he just flops for you he just wants his belly scratched and that's it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he's just the warmest thing in the wintertime he just sits on your lap sits on your lap but they're like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 		
 		
 	