
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff Penn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi well what's your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bears</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i uh don't have uh much much of a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> haven't done much so i guess i'll just have to say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> well they haven't done much for they never did much  even when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staubach</ENAMEX> were playing i'm being real sarcastic  did you like them back then
 	
 	
 		
  
 		um
 		
  
 		oh yeah in fact most of the world liked them back then whether you did or not
 	
 	
 		touch yes well when i moved here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">uh mid seventies um</ENAMEX> are you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> yes so am i uh i just use to laugh because back then i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steelers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> i'm from originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that was not the thing to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> when they their preseason games at the stadium you know where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> versus what do you think they're going to do this year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh they may be a little better but uh they got a long way to go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landry</ENAMEX> got the shaft
 	
 	
 		he sure did that i agree with you on yeah what do you think of uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who's coaching them now from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> i can't remember his name off the top of my head i can picture his gray hair but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they all start with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">J</ENAMEX> so yeah he's <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Johnson</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		well he's he's learned a little bit but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> he was here he was playing college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and it was pretty simple stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		are you a football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>  uh by nature or is this something you grew into
 	
 	
 		yeah i i in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>'s the game instead of baseball
 	
 	
 		that's true i agree with you there though at least it has a little more action than baseball
 	
 	
 		yep um-hum
 		yep
 	
 	
 		well i don't know why i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX> but i do i just think they have some good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		well they've had some very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and fact uh the best tight end in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> is now their coach
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty nine</NUMEX> yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Ditka</ENAMEX> well you can't say too much bad about him i mean he did learn his hone his trade under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landry</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well actually he was uh as as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> he learned his trade under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landry</ENAMEX> but as uh as a player i remember seeing him as a young man
 	
 	
 		that's what i meant
 	
 	
 		fighting everybody off while he caught a pass on a tight end
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> well i was probably a little bit too young for that but um i know we just laugh now in terms of not specific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> but um
 		we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> got bored <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> and he turned on the television and one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> said what's
 		you know what's the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX>  and i wasn't even aware i mean i knew it but i just i guess i kind of shut it out like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>   yeah something
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Football League</ENAMEX> is playing uh Frank uh playing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> i think i've forgotten where they are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and somebody that
 	
 	
 		oh funny
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landry</ENAMEX> is down there over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> now yeah
 	
 	
 		oh you're kidding oh goodness are you that avid a fan that you would watch it regular uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round
 	
 	
 		no no i uh actually i haven't uh watched it as much since uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>' demise as i used to i used to watch it every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> but irregardless of who was playing whether it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes it it seemed like it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to about ten</NUMEX> to twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> i mean all the sports including football it used to seem uh before the higher ticket prices in terms of just not for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> but i mean what what the salaries some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> were getting
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah now that it's uh well i think a lot went out of it when they had the strike too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i mean i um i mean like i was just reading something in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s paper about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herschel Walker</ENAMEX> and i had to chuckle you know i mean you wonder what he really is  i mean i really don't care but what happens to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> when they're sitting in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and they fall asleep because um
 		they're so tired and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon</ENAMEX> they're overcome by  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carbon monoxide</ENAMEX> fumes
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's hard to believe all right
 	
 	
 		you know um  but i think it's still healthy i mean i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> that plays <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and if that's what he wanted to do i certainly wouldn't tell his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to encourage it but i think it's still an honorable sport
 	
 	
 		yeah who do you think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> will have quarterbacking now
 	
 	
 		i have no idea who is he who um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State</ENAMEX> i think he's already over the hill isn't he oh i can't remember
 	
 	
 		hum
 		it
 		seems like it
 	
 	
 		i can't even remember his my mind went blank <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it must be the heat um
 		i don't know i just uh i actually like you know i was probably was like you were when the when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payton</ENAMEX> was big you know this is probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years</TIMEX> after when everything was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but um  i actually once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payton</ENAMEX> left i kind of just lost you know
 	
 	
 		yeah he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> all right
 	
 	
 		yeah i kind of just lost um and i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditka</ENAMEX>'s going to stay around much longer i don't know if he renewed a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> or not i think he's either in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of that</TIMEX> or just did that
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems seems like the spice has gone out of it for him
 	
 	
 		yeah it's kind of you know i mean uh it's it's kind of like when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steelers</ENAMEX> went you know like i said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> it seemed like <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> was really interesting the and it didn't matter who was playing it just it was worth watching
 	
 	
 		yeah there
 		yeah there were several really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in that time frame yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah and it was competitive and it seemed a little cleaner i don't know um
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it probably was the uh now then there's a lot of dirty stuff going on on the line that the  that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referees</ENAMEX> don't call things get out of hand
 	
 	
 		yeah and there's some technical stuff you know this Minicam stuff these instant replay things that uh i'm not sure that i would agree with some of it but i still think it's a good sport
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well actually i think if they'd a had that technical replay technical uh bit where they replayed it at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> would've won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowls</ENAMEX> that they didn't win because of bad calls hum yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		some of those calls well i have to agree with you because i can remember um when they played the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolphins</ENAMEX> and i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditka</ENAMEX> take the touchdown and i remember there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> calls in that game i think it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy</TIMEX> was that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy three or seventy two</TIMEX> i can't i can't even go back that far anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah there was one that uh supposedly uh uh
 		fumble after a touchdown and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> theoretically lost it but uh  they didn't really  in fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> uh who had recovered who was supposed to have recovered it later admitted that he had uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so now i know
 	
 	
 		after it had already crossed the the goal line in the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s hand he jerked it out of his hand so it was he admitted that he had done that after the fact but you could see it on camera when it happened but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> couldn't see it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah usually usually when that happens and i mean it always seems to go the way of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ref</ENAMEX>'s call though it never seems to go the way of you know either the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> or somebody protesting um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but that's really i guess what i know about football
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the where do you work where do you work
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 		right now i'm not i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homemaker</ENAMEX> yeah yeah true
 	
 	
 		you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homemaker</ENAMEX> well that's work enough
 		
 
 		my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> says that is plenty work enough
 	
 	
 		domestic engineering domestic engineering there you go yeah it's um
 	
 	
 		pardon
 		domestic engineering right right
 	
 	
 		i don't know i just really had to laugh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i mean the what the subject was when i placed this call when the subject was football because uh we had just
 		had that on that that was uh you know wear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round and i said oh they've got to be kidding i just don't think financially they'll make a go of it and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> said to me well it was somebody from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Lynn</ENAMEX> or somebody who um was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> of that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		i said uh you know wouldn't they be defeating their purpose to go away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think they would
 	
 	
 		but nobody seemed to uh you know nobody just thought that it so the motive was just another way to make a profit
 	
 	
 		yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> to me will always be Fran Tarkenton though
 	
 	
 		yeah actually you know i mean that's just um that's the era i'm talking about i mean i remember when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gale Sayers</ENAMEX> played i i mean i can remember that's kind of when it seems like it was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> could beat any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in that time frame and that's what made it so good yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		right any probability could happen i mean now it's just it's and usually it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that's great over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire season</TIMEX> and then it's kind of flat watching some of it i mean it's um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and it's whoever has got the most money that gets the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and so forth
 	
 	
 		right exactly i mean i can remember when drafts and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heisman</ENAMEX> i mean i could remember i mean i just i mean i used to think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorsett</ENAMEX> was good now i look at him and i think well why did i ever think that
 	
 	
 		well he was good in his younger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> he really yeah he really was
 	
 	
 		in his younger yeah and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walker</ENAMEX> now i mean i don't know if he's dried up or not the way they're talking that uh
 	
 	
 		well he's he's getting old enough to be uh his legs wearing out but the last time i saw him play when he was healthy he looked mighty good
 	
 	
 		did he and who's going to quarterback the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i don't even is it still the blonde headed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aikman</ENAMEX> it what do you think of him
 	
 	
 		it'll be it'll be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aikman</ENAMEX> yeah
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aikman</ENAMEX> himself if he had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> around i think they'd be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super team</ENAMEX> but he can't do it by himself he's got to have a line in front of him that knows how to block
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so you think it's the defensive element that's really lacking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well no i think it's mainly the offense the defense is better than the offense really the the the uh offensive line is is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		in terms of running yeah
 	
 	
 		just hasn't been able to keep down the pass <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">rush</TIMEX> at all so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aikman</ENAMEX>'s had time to get rid of the ball
 		and he's been and the main reason he's been hurt on occasion it's like most of them the offensive line didn't do it's job he got blindsided or something so
 	
 	
 		protecting him yeah didn't he just go through through some rough elbow surgery or something about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five months</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they found a whole bunch of chips in there that they though though they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chip and they uh
 	
 	
 		ooh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they uh got i've forgotten my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> keeps up with this more than i in fact he should be on this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> he's the one that knows all about sports  yeah
 	
 	
 		sure
 		probably my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> should be too i just you know you just go through and you check those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> and you go well  there's not too much well listen i won't keep you on a nice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		well i appreciate the call
 	
 	
 		okay no problem and you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		same to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	