
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well what books do you like
 	
 	
 		um a broad spectrum  my tastes seem to change over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> um
 		i like uh uh  mysteries adventure some science fiction
 		i like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sagan</ENAMEX> i read i read just about everything that he puts out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um Robert  Ludlum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i've just started uh i got a whole set
 		of books on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherlock Holmes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i'm just getting into that uh that's kind of uh interesting it's unique
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how about yourself
 	
 	
 		yeah those are great uh i've been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherlock Holmes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and i think i've read most of his stuff multiple numbers of times
 	
 	
 		oh you have
 	
 	
 		uh i just find it very relaxing and very enjoyable and i always hope for my memory to to fail me so after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> i can pick up a story and read it again
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh okay uh i got a whole set i got a set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		so i've just started into some in to him i haven't uh i've uh i think uh they had uh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherlock Holmes</ENAMEX> uh miniseries on uh  on educational TV
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh channel <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> up here i'm not sure what it is down there and they had uh uh some of his i i started watching that and i got interested in it so that's why i got the gift
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so you've been doing it for a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah i started reading them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and i it's and i i'm not really much of a mystery
 		reader although i've always liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherlock Holmes</ENAMEX> and then somebody turned me on to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Frances</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and he's uh a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jockey</ENAMEX> and he writes mystery stories and they always involve horse racing in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> form or another he's very very good if uh you've never read him
 		that would be a great opportunity
 	
 	
 		no i mean is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Frances</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		his name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Frances</ENAMEX> and any book <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">store owner</ENAMEX> will know who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Frances</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		and you can pick up any of his stuff and you can just sort of try it and if you like his style well he's written i'd say <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty or twenty five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah um
 	
 	
 		novels you know he's quite quite clever
 	
 	
 		my taste runs runs to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ludlum</ENAMEX>
 		you know that type of
 	
 	
 		uh the adventure stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah adventure yeah uh some of that gets i don't know i think they've got ghost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> now on a lot of them and uh they just put their name to it because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> either that or my tastes are changing um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they just don't have the same depth that they seem to have before
 	
 	
 		huh yeah you know i always suspected uh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Michener</ENAMEX> of doing that you know i read some of his early stuff and then it seemed like his later stuff they would be these long long long passages that were just of inferior quality it
 	
 	
 		it was yeah it was uh just to fill a page
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean i just got the feeling that he sort of has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coterie</ENAMEX> of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and he says okay go write <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX> on this and he and he kind of he might write some stuff i don't think he writes all his stuff every word i may be wrong
 	
 	
 		yeah you're probably right um
 		uh
 		i'm trying to think of that uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have you read any of his
 	
 	
 		i've read a couple of his things i i just wasn't that crazy about him
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		which really puts me in the i know in the vast minority
 	
 	
 		no no no no i've i've read a couple of them that weren't too bad um
 		my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is into him so he's oh you've got to read this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> you've got to read that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> but i'm not that's not really not my uh cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		except the
 		the latest one he's got out uh it's uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen hundred or fifteen hundred</NUMEX> page he had he had published it about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and he's got it out now with the with the the full text no cuts and no
 		he he explains that when he did it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time because of publishing costs they asked they asked him to cut it back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that's what he did now he's got it out and
 		i can't even think of the name of it
 		but it's starting out pretty good um it's something that's not
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		like his present style
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		but other than that um
 		i've read Dune i don't know if you've read Dune
 	
 	
 		i read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dune</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and i again you you i uh i just did not care for Dune i read through it all it was laborious i i
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		felt i had to get through it and when i put it down i never wanted to read another thing by that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		to read it again yeah i've read uh i like the original
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dune</ENAMEX> and then they had
 		he's had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> others after that which i didn't care for at all so i kind of fell off
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but again i realize i mean i all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were saying how great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dune</ENAMEX> was and i just could not
 		could not get into it i read the whole thing but i didn't enjoy didn't enjoy it that much
 	
 	
 		have you read any science fiction at all
 	
 	
 		i really read a lot of science fiction and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asimov</ENAMEX> is one of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think his stuff is is great just going back to his very early works and almost anything he writes i try to read
 	
 	
 		uh
 		even i haven't read any of his recent but i've read some of his old uh uh  things and in yeah i i like him he's he's not too bad some of it's
 		uh not him but some of the other science fiction i mean it's just so uh uh
 		like uh Tolkien
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i never could get into him
 	
 	
 		interesting and i was just crazy about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tolkien i</ENAMEX> read his stuff and i reread it and i read the whole twelve <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> pages aloud to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> when he was uh a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> when he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight or nine</TIMEX>
 		we would just read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> pages <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> and i just did that you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half a year</TIMEX> until i'd read the whole thing out loud
 	
 	
 		huh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah my
 		um both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> are into him but i don't know it's just something i
 		i don't know if i had the time or put myself in the frame of mind for it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		what do you do what do you do for um
 		educational
 		anything
 	
 	
 		well uh uh being a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> there's just a certain amount of academic reading i do as a matter of course
 	
 	
 		oh so you have to you're forced into it no matter what
 	
 	
 		well well well yeah forced is probably not too strong a word but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		to keep up in your field you usually have to do some uh some technical reading but uh i actually like um
 		for technical reading i like to read what i call uh soft core science like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Discovery</ENAMEX> Magazine
 	
 	
 		that's i get that
 	
 	
 		which i like very much and uh
 		and then uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science Foundation</ENAMEX> puts out an excellent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> called Mosaic
 		with uh the and they get some of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars scholars</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> to write articles that can be understood
 		they're not highly technical but they're not probably not as simplified as in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but they're very good except i couldn't i just got on their list somehow because at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i did some research for them and i'm not really sure how one would go about getting this but it's it's excellent
 		uh
 		for finding out what's going on in fields other than your own
 	
 	
 		yeah have have you ever heard of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Source Book Project</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't believe so
 		Source <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Book Project</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it deals with anomalies um
 		whether it's uh animal vegetable or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">mineral</ENAMEX> or or geologic anomalies
 	
 	
 		oh no no
 	
 	
 		you know like uh  uh rain fish
 		you know that type of thing
 	
 	
 		oh that would be fascinating
 	
 	
 		or the uh
 		the uh is it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mima</ENAMEX> mounds in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um Kentucky</ENAMEX> i think
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		what what about them
 	
 	
 		well it's just the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Source Book Project</ENAMEX>  um
 		it gives you a short
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> synopsis of of whatever they're talking about and then it gives you all the sources
 		that you can look up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you're interested in it
 	
 	
 		i see okay that would be a very interesting thing
 	
 	
 		and they they tried to uh
 		uh throw out the uh sensationalism you know like flying saucers and all that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the things that they that they publish are documented sightings you know and an or
 		digs or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i'm kind of in to that i'm uh uh i belong to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Narragansett Archeology Society</ENAMEX> so i like going back and you know
 		digging up things it gives me you know uh it's kind of a a thrill to see something that nobody's looked at for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three thousand years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah do you have any interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stonehenge</ENAMEX> or did you ever have any
 	
 	
 		uh
 		as far as being uh yes that type of thing yeah that's what these Mima mounds were supposedly like early <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stonehenge in America</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		yeah i'm fascinated with that kind of stuff in fact just recently uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> ago
 		they discovered a cave
 		
 		
 	