
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right Clarice uh what's your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX> probably the one that plays here
 	
 	
 		the Mavericks yeah
 	
 	
 		the Mavericks uh they're not doing the greatest that i've seen them play before but uh well they're doing okay
 	
 	
 		yeah they didn't quite make the play-offs though
 	
 	
 		but but
 		no no i i think without uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Tarpley</ENAMEX> they're he he added something to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but uh i think they need to let him go maybe
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he doesn't seem to course i have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> that i think are really super i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaiah Thomas</ENAMEX> is just great and uh i think uh he
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he does really well i like to watch him play he just has a really good moves and uh  i don't know i i guess uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i guess i like to watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mailman</ENAMEX> play for the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> uh when he delivers he does okay and uh uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i can't think of the name of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX> on it oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics i</ENAMEX> like to watch them play the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i like their whole team
 	
 	
 		oh the Celtics
 		the they are a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> is what's really good about them
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		they just uh work the ball and uh pass around and make each other look good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum i you know like i said i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaiah Thomas</ENAMEX> but i think sometimes that uh
 		that uh he he sometimes ends up being a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man team</ENAMEX> uh whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics</ENAMEX> like you said they play more as a team um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		makes it little more fun to watch at times
 	
 	
 		yeah i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> a lot too he's really good uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Ainge</ENAMEX> he plays i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Ainge</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Ainge</ENAMEX>
 		why do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Ainge</ENAMEX> that that's i mean you've named like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of the top names in the game and then you come up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Ainge</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i
 		well i guess because he played at at my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX>  so i i kind of watch him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every now</TIMEX> and again
 	
 	
 		did he play BYU oh you went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> huh okay
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah yeah and he played really well when he was there so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh it's it's hard to uh name him with some of the very top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> i think sometimes but i'm glad he's playing in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> yeah he's a
 	
 	
 		yeah he's uh well i have nothing against him i just uh
 	
 	
 		you just wondered why i named him huh
 	
 	
 		i wondered yeah i wondered everybody has their their favorite you know maybe not the the big name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> but uh
 		yeah he's playing a vital role he he's playing for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> he's playing for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> he's i mean he's coming in and doing a good job he's it was a great trade how they got him
 	
 	
 		Portland um-hum right now
 		yeah they yeah i i liked when he uh he was playing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Celtics</ENAMEX> and then he traded to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it was a good trade so
 	
 	
 		seems like uh
 		i don't know if it's mainly because of him but it seems that he plays for top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 		and uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contenders</ENAMEX> uh he might have uh did he go straight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> or did he hit another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> on the way
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't remember i really don't it seems like he went straight there you know because i don't remember him playing for another another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> other than straight through
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah he's uh i i like to watch him play because he's a yeah he's pretty tough you know he's he's a scrappy guy
 	
 	
 		so what's your favorite team
 	
 	
 		he's a competitor
 	
 	
 		do you have a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh do i have a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> uh well i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX> so i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacers</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX> because he's from the home <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i just likewatch him play anyway uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		let's see i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> because they're from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> area and uh they've uh suffered through many a hard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> before they got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh even then once they got him they didn't make the play-offs for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years</TIMEX> they had to gradually build up a supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> because you can't just win with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> you have to have a a you know a good solid team
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> can carry a bulk of the of the scoring load you know you have to have the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> there to complement him and finally with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pippen</ENAMEX> and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horace Grant</ENAMEX> some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are coming right along
 	
 	
 		i watched uh well i didn't watch them but i i saw in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and in on the news the play-off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and
 		and without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Bird</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> when they got injured you know it was interesting i think then how their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> did um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how it it it brought the scoring down a little bit but their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> stayed relatively together you know and so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i think sometimes it's interesting we we really watch the big name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and but they have to have a solid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> underneath or else they really don't don't go anywhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i i think that's kind of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mavericks</ENAMEX> problem they have okay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> but sometimes the strongness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> isn't together
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know every once in a while they click during a a game and then it works for them but then it's just not always there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i i guess that's
 	
 	
 		well they made a couple trades this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that uh well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fat Lever</ENAMEX> was hurt most of the year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that so they didn't get to reap any benefits from that and uh i don't know how well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex English</ENAMEX> did but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">English</ENAMEX> did okay he did okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		see see we don't have a TV so i didn't get to watch any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks i</ENAMEX> think i got to watch probably one game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adubato</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> uh has done a lot a lot for them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think he he's uh brought some strength to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> um
 		um he he's really trying hard he's a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i like him as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX> so
 		i don't i don't know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		well they move around so much
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		can't hardly keep a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> where he's at for very long enough to get know who he is
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true  that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah i think uh like you said i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarpley</ENAMEX> if he was had his life straightened up he could really help a ball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> but you know the way well he's operating now he's more of a detriment than anything else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think they're i think they'll let him go
 	
 	
 		they should
 	
 	
 		anyway i i uh i like basketball it's a fun sport i i like to watch it i like to um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess i like it because of of the quickness of it um and and i like it because it takes the players
 		have to be
 		you know it's not a game where you can just not practice i mean they have to be on the top of their game to be i n the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah or else
 	
 	
 		top physical condition too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so do you like college basketball high school ball anything like that
 	
 	
 		i don't watch much of that i watch our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> Plano uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano East</ENAMEX> is where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> will go i have an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and he plays <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband coaches</ENAMEX> his team
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh they uh i think they were one off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> loss to the play-off
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh i like to watch our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano East Senior High</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> play they are they did really well so yeah
 	
 	
 		good
 	
 	
 		i like yeah i do like um the the games not only basketball but the other ones too that the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> play i keep up with that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah i i it's fun watching basketball at all different levels i mean there are benefits and and
 		bad points of watching it each each different one i mean you may not see a spectacular <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordanish</ENAMEX> move from a high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> but you know it's more of an accomplishment if if they hit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pointers or something the game is you know it's just a different game pretty much but that's sort of what makes it fun
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well you know what i think is you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spud Webb</ENAMEX> i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you can really even if you're short like that you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> they get these huge tall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that just are you know if you want to do it bad enough i think it's a possibility in anybody's life
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he's he really goes for it and he's a good little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> you know so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah he's
 	
 	
 		i think if if any of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> want to do it they really can if that's really their dream
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so  takes work though that's the big yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		takes a lot of working
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spud</ENAMEX> was just gifted with a exceptional vertical leap and that's what helps him out more than anything else
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		plus you know he's like you said he's worked hard at it i'm sure
 	
 	
 		well
 		i just think that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>'s a fun game and and i guess i still have to stick with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mavericks</ENAMEX> i guess as far as
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	