
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and what movies have you seen recently
 	
 	
 		well  we aren't just real big go to the you know <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time it comes out kind of thing we neither one like to stand in line
 		so we uh a lot of times will just kind of hold on until it comes to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a dollar</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		i don't blame you we're the same
 	
 	
 		something or maybe rent the video although i prefer the dollar theater because it is kind of fun and
 		i say dollar theater i think they're actually two dollars these days
 	
 	
 		right  there's been inflation all the way along
 	
 	
 		it's like saying go to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and dime you know it's not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and dime anymore but the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a analogy is there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um uh we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> and we have we have a guideline i shan't say rule  that uh you know we like to see the movies that they want to see first
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		um
 	
 	
 		so that we can kind of talk about it and decide whether it's really appropriate or
 		you know or not and uh  we're probably stricter than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i know we are because i know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> even the youngest ones routinely see things that
 	
 	
 		well i know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have gone to things that i would never set foot in but they haven't gone with me and i haven't paid the bill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there's are there are an awful lot of movies that i just think are uh unconscionable to be shown on
 		especially to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i have had to hope that they would enforce the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> ratings and not let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> under eighteen in
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum and i don't really think they do i mean uh
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 		
 
 		we're having an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pollen</ENAMEX> attack here and i'm having <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">hay fever</ENAMEX> excuse me
 	
 	
 		oh bless your heart i've i've have a throat that is so sore i know exactly what you mean just from that
 	
 	
 		oh
 		but anyway anyway um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty one and twenty four</TIMEX> so i don't have to
 	
 	
 		with absolutely no you know
 	
 	
 		do anything now
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but once in a while what i try to do is try to entice them into something that i think is going to be
 		useful or educational or something so the two
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		recent recent films that we have seen where i've been able to drag them along um are the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Bronoff</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		version and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rosencranz and Gilgenstern are Dead</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		which were wonderful
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		both of them were just outstandingly good
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		excellent acting wonderful sets costumes and really worthwhile
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum we uh
 		i guess probably the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that we really paid full price for was um
 		oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> one that they made the book
 	
 	
 		hum
 		i'm a bad one to ask because i don't
 	
 	
 		i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX> the uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> there we go
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes i know the one you're talking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		there we go which i was so glad that uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had read the book before we went because otherwise he you know he had to kind of sit and explain it along the way to me that uh you know that uh i thought it was very well done though uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh yes
 		well uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> went and took his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and he enjoyed it a lot but i've never cared much for war and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> movies so they let me stay home and work in the garden
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		that was  a a nice trade
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but they thought it was a good movie and uh i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> so i said if it comes out on video i'll be willing to pay the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> dollars to rent it and then if i'm bored i don't feel like i've lost a lot and i can turn it off
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 		that's right we uh have have have thoroughly enjoyed the uh
 		Dancing with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolves</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that was uh
 		i guess we paid full price for that one too
 	
 	
 		well i
 	
 	
 		that one was very unnerving for me i uh i have an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> uh native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> heritage and
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i knew going into it that it
 		was probably affect me deeply
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was right  it definitely did definitely did it definitely did
 	
 	
 		well uh i have to tell you a comment that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> is next door to mine goes to a lot of movies and uh he will come back with his capsule review and he said
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it has absolutely beautiful scenery but you wouldn't like it because of the cruelty to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and any movie i have to say i where i notice the scenery means i didn't like the plot
 		so
 	
 	
 		well i have to agree with you it that that part of it was somewhat unnerving although
 		it was cruelty to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> yes but not
 		kinds of things
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know it was
 		very much in the natural
 		you know the way it really probably was not some sadistic
 		crazed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you know who's going around pulling the wings off flies and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>  you know swinging <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> by their tail not not that kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> torturistic type thing you know it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it it was awfully graphic
 		that way but
 	
 	
 		well i keep telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i don't go to movies where there's lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and uh shootings and i certainly don't go to horror films
 	
 	
 		oh yes i agree
 	
 	
 		oh i
 		if they are are trying on purpose to scare me then i don't want to go
 	
 	
 		i'm certainly not going to give them money to do it
 	
 	
 		absolutely not oh i'll tell you one though that i heard such good things about um
 		oh let's see what was it um
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Lynch</ENAMEX>
 		movie and it's about
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sailor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lula</ENAMEX> they're the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> i can't remember the name of the film now
 	
 	
 		well i'll
 	
 	
 		but anyway got lots of just wonderful reviews and i had heard that it had violence in it but i thought well i'll go give it a try
 		and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first five minutes</TIMEX> of that movie were so disgusting that i went and got my money back
 	
 	
 		said i'm leaving
 	
 	
 		i did i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> i've got a book in the car give me the car keys you can stay and watch this if you want to but i don't need this
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i just got up and left and in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about two more minutes</TIMEX> he joined me and we asked for ou r money back i said you know i i realize that this is advertised as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> movie
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and i had heard that it contained violence but i had no idea
 	
 	
 		that this was what i was getting myself into
 	
 	
 		how disgusting this was going to be and in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> i watched there was no let up it was it was just filthy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and there's
 	
 	
 		and now i don't mind uh nudity and i don't mind
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suggestiveness</ENAMEX> if it's appropriate to the story i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prude</ENAMEX> and i'm not a prig but i do not see any reason why
 		you should have one string of filthy language with no intermission in it and uh graphic violence and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and uh it total disregard for human beings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the i read something here just a while back about it was a newspaper thing just about the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">moguls</ENAMEX> and the
 		television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> and what not that basically
 		they individually personally are not even close to living the lives that the normal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> does that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		we uh
 		excuse me
 	
 	
 		and i think that's got to be true if you look at what they produce  that they think is the ideal normal person
 	
 	
 		so how could they possibly you know so when they do find something that relates to
 		some of us you know it's just kind on the seedy
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		side of our lives you know it's not the uplifting
 	
 	
 		yeah and most of us aren't that seedy
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly  we're a lot more mundane and humdrum and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		at least the ones with the money to go to the movie
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know we uh we saw that little Home Alone with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		you know thoroughly enjoyed that but it was uh you know
 	
 	
 		i heard that was real cute
 	
 	
 		totally different you know kind of thing and even in that there were a few things that had i been making it i wouldn't have put in you know so  but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you know we uh we
 		try to you know catch things when they come back on the television and they're redone
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so that the bad language is out and the heavier scenes are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		removed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we rent a lot of the old musicals and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> type things you know for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to watch here at home and try to
 	
 	
 		there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that has uh been renovated by a foundation to its heyday of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenties</TIMEX> and it has the big old organ and everything and the big screen and they show only movies made before nineteen fifty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh how fun
 		oh how fun
 	
 	
 		and it is just great we go to that probably once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or more
 		uh at the very beginning when they were having film festivals like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Hepburn</ENAMEX> festival and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Astaire</ENAMEX> festival and so on we were going a couple of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> a week
 		and it's great for one thing it's not
 	
 	
 		i wish they'd do something like that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it's not full of rowdy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> who are uh spilling their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cokes</ENAMEX> and throwing their popcorn and talking all the time mostly middle age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> who are pretty decorous and sit still and listen to the film
 	
 	
 		that's true but
 		
 
 		that's cute
 	
 	
 		and they get these absolutely terrific prints that are from the uh film archives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> that have just been specially restored and sometimes they are made from the original negatives so they're really crisp and good
 		so they're really crisp and good like they were when they first came out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's neat though that's you know that's good i wish more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> would take up some of those that they realize that they can be entertained and
 		and enjoy a
 	
 	
 		and you can go to a movie like that and you know that it's going to be entertaining and it's going to have some wit in the dialogue
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evening</ENAMEX>'s activity
 		
 		
 	