
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh
 		have you did you have you grown up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanie</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no i've only been here for the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		oh where are you from
 	
 	
 		i grew up most of my childhood in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and we we took a lot of vacations while we were there because everything was within driving distance
 	
 	
 		well
 		now there's a place i'd like to visit
 	
 	
 		so we we traveled all over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's neat
 	
 	
 		when i was when i was very young unfortunately a a little bit too young to really appreciate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i was grade school age uh
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had a bicycle tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> or took a bicycle tour <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five months</TIMEX> right after the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">world war</ENAMEX> and so we've seen lots of pictures of the of the beautiful spots and areas yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		uh that
 		that would be a to me a really nice vacation because i'm i'm not in physical shape for something like that but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i sure would work on it  if i had an opportunity like that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's neat neat  what kind of vacations do you like
 	
 	
 		uh well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are scuba divers
 	
 	
 		oh huh
 	
 	
 		so we both like to go to dive resorts uh we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> on our honeymoon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we dove there uh
 		but we we did <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about six dives</TIMEX> while we were there and uh we were originally planning on going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cayman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		uh last year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but we weren't able to get enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> together for the trip we had to have like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for this package uh deal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh uh-huh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and we couldn't get enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> together
 		uh to go so it ended up falling uh falling through we were going to get a really good price
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		when when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were younger we enjoyed we lived up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and and used to like uh traveling into upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and camping
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we had a little collapsible sailboat and liked to sail and
 		that sort of thing but we've never really uh did any diving or anything little bit of sailing of uh uh  oh
 	
 	
 		snorkeling
 	
 	
 		water skiing
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but not much of uh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		of anything else
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i both like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> so any any vacation that we go on is usually involves close to the ocean or or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it's got to be the water
 		when when we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jersey</ENAMEX> we used to go down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jersey</ENAMEX> beach a lot and really enjoyed that a lot it's really they had
 	
 	
 		yeah we
 	
 	
 		a really nice beach areas there
 	
 	
 		after we moved away from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i lived there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i really enjoyed that because you know the mountains were real close we like the we like the white mountains and
 	
 	
 		that's a really pretty area too
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no
 	
 	
 		uh unfortunately i didn't really get to go skiing much while i was there i went skiing once
 	
 	
 		yeah we loved the we loved the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> area too because the  the lakes were really pretty close you know you could
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you could drive within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty minutes to an hour</TIMEX> and just be at a real nice vacation spot where you could sail and and just really and then we weren't too for from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Appalachian Trail</ENAMEX> we did quite a bit of hiking
 		which is kind of fun
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		are you a you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hiker</ENAMEX> or not
 		not so much huh
 	
 	
 		not not really so much if if if there was some place that that we went to where there was hiking involved i i would be
 		you know happy to go hiking but we we never have really planned a vacation around uh places to go hiking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		so your your next your plans are try to find someplace to scuba scuba dive
 	
 	
 		yeah our next vacation will will be scuba diving i'm sure
 	
 	
 		you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no not yet
 	
 	
 		okay then that's probably one of the reasons our
 		we had little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> all the time so some of the things are not as quite as uh adaptable yeah it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it's a it's a little more difficult planning a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">vacation</TIMEX> when you have have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you have to try to figure out kinds of things that you can do that they will enjoy too and so i think what
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and diving is something that especially for small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh i think the the minimum age for diving is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is probably legal anyway would be probably about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> or twelve i would think probably but maybe fifteen even i know that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing that happens to us to vacation trips now is that usually that try to involve some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the family you know we go wherever somebody is that we haven't seen for a while  so that that's kind of uh we just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		came back from uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Rapids</ENAMEX> where we saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> graduate
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		from uh with his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s degree in social work and so that was fun and and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> we have a we have a
 		a reunion in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> area up by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Cities</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where we're going to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> with
 		as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of of a rather large reunion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that uh as we can get together so
 	
 	
 		that that sounds like a lot of fun our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> had a reunion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> that was kind of like that too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and they all kind of met at a central place i i didn't go
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh but it would have been nice it would have been a nice vacation
 	
 	
 		we we've traveled we've moved around enough so that we now have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in different parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i guess my favorite vacation idea would be to somehow figure out something kind of mobile where you could
 		stop and sleep maybe you know like a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a small camper we've we've traveled in a big one i hate them  because they're hard to jockey around you know but maybe a pickup with the back on
 	
 	
 		something or something like uh what's the like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volkswagen Vanagon</ENAMEX> i've heard is really nice
 	
 	
 		yeah so you could kind of sleep in it
 		sometimes but you wouldn't want to do it all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh we have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> here and there i would just love to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just</NUMEX> drive
 		through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and stop and see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know and visit for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> and then go on and you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> has been talking for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> about uh getting a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> wheel
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just picking up he's retired uh he's in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his sixties</TIMEX> and he uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would like to just get a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> wheel and just travel across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> here or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks</TIMEX> there and just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know not be settled anywhere just see see the rest of the country
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it is
 		i think that would real and i would like to maybe not take great long trips but but have your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home base</ENAMEX> where your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then just travel out for like maybe oh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> maybe go
 	
 	
 		he he does that quite a bit he he hasn't lately though uh because he's been ill
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but he's been known to be gone for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> at a time and you know he'll say this is my itinerary i'm going here here and here and i'll be back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah there are a lot of neat neat places to visit in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> that's for sure we've i haven't been much to the south i haven't been in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> i guess that's those are the only <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> i have not visited but uh
 		up the coast uh at uh uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and around there where the where the early history is there's some
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Johnstown</ENAMEX> and uh in some in that area is just really neat interesting things to so you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> have you been a to a lot of the different historical sites
 	
 	
 		yeah we took a trip uh around to the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>
 		battle grounds and things back in nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> when it was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centennial</TIMEX> or something i believe it was uh had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> then i think but that was a really fun interesting trip i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we we read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> book before we went you know and so we were ready to look up the places we read about it was really interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 		i think right right now while my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we'll probably take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as many</TIMEX> vacations as we can
 		doing things like scuba diving and and adventurous types of things and then when we eventually when we have kids
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now his his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> did a lot of traveling across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you know they went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX> and did things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well now camping is fun with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		if you're you know once they get a little bigger not teeny tiny ones but even even some little ones do pretty good but but when they get a little bigger so they can help that that's a fun way to  to uh cut costs and it's enjoyable too very restful
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah i i do enjoy camping
 	
 	
 		i mean i find
 		yeah i find the outdoors very relaxing and you know kind of
 		a change
 	
 	
 		as long as i have a shower nearby i'm fine  and electricity
 	
 	
 		yeah  well i'm with you i need my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> comforts too well it was great to talk to you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it was nice talking to you too <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay see you later bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	