
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		are you satisfied with the public school system in your area
 	
 	
 		uh well we don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but um from what our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> tell us um most of them do are not in favor of the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> public well i shouldn't get specific the way the public education system is run here
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um they just don't feel that um the quality of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and the quality of the uh curriculum and they actually send them to uh the suburban areas i i guess it's okay if i say the area Plano
 	
 	
 		sure uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and i think one thing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s doing right now about the refunding i think is completely unfair it's not that i
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't agree with that either the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> approach where the rich give to the poor
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah is is that the basic reason you don't agree with it
 	
 	
 		no i don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> move to the suburbs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> uh uh mostly because of the school district because of the level of education that's offered
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and they're already paying for it i mean i you know um i know we used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> and a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there sent their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because um they just didn't like what was going on
 	
 	
 		yeah well it costs uh so much in taxes here and uh even if they do give money to the poorer school districts i don't think it's going to lower my taxes at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i know it i mean i look at high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> like um what was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson J J Pearce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">High School</ENAMEX> that just won the national academic some kind of um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh</ENAMEX> championship or tournament that they had for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> is one of the school districts that would be hit by taking away from them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure
 	
 	
 		that's a good way to say it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> um approach
 	
 	
 		well that's that's exactly what what their doing um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't think that's going to improve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> as far as the school teaching uh goes
 	
 	
 		you know i used to work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EDS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX> you know the big joke sometimes um about him but the one thing he did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX> in testing the competency of the uh faculty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i still think that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		well i think it is too uh every
 	
 	
 		because i don't i don't know where did you go to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i went to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i went to school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> so i can tell you it's probably the same type of thing that um i had a really good education but it wasn't where i went to high school it was an inner city but it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> was very good
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh-huh well we need qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> no matter whether they're teaching in the inner city or the suburbs
 	
 	
 		and i don't know what you
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh the trouble is that uh the suburbs are able to pay more that's going to attract the the better uh teachers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		which is understandable i mean i'd go where i would be compensated the most
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure</ENAMEX> and uh it cost more in tax money too so
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it's yeah in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i don't know i don't if it's because of um the influx of minority uh in terms of that they're trying to please all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and their not pleasing anybody you know i don't know if that's what it is
 	
 	
 		well it could very well be uh there is a definite racial split here
 	
 	
 		i don't know i'm not really
 		yeah i mean i don't know if that's exactly it or not but it seems to be a little bit more um
 		well i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> i'm trying to think of some of the things i know about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> up north compared to down here
 		it just seems like down here that unless you're in a suburban entity their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SAT</ENAMEX> scores their reading comprehension levels they're just not as high
 	
 	
 		well i was in a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and uh we had a good public school system but i don't think it was great i think the curriculum was very deficient to prepare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to go to college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh the the racial mix of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um students</ENAMEX> in my area was entirely white we had uh no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minorities</ENAMEX> at all
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> was uh mine was completely um <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caucasian</ENAMEX> and eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">European</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well that's interesting
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it was very eclectic um but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> were what did curriculum i mean they had things like philosophy and journalism i mean
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but there wasn't a uh real for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> such as myself that knew they wanted to go to school and knew they wanted to um go to a fairly competitive undergraduate program it wasn't what i would call a uh a career a academic
 		path preparatory path for college prep um as opposed to suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Evanston Illinois</ENAMEX> which has one of the largest  you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and the and the money base to go with it um
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		i don't know i just look at high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano East</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX> and the ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> and i think well you know i would send a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		well the good school districts here do have honors programs uh they do encourage that among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who are uh prepared to go to college but uh that brings up a whole uh bunch of other problems um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> did have honors programs and i was in it but it really you know in terms of i'm wondering how much different it was compared to in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> now there is a high school um
 		is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTT White</ENAMEX> or is it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jefferson</ENAMEX> i don't know that much about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> high school system um but i have heard that the of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> that are very good but out of how many you know fifty to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> high schools
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		it's just um and then i read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX> was going to be the site for a possibly new um parochial or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> high school
 	
 	
 		all right i haven't heard that yet
 	
 	
 		something like to be one of the largest ones in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest</ENAMEX> or something yeah
 	
 	
 		that's interesting i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at work who uh have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in high school and they're not satisfied with the school district at all and they do send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> private schools
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do they see and are they in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> or are they in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they send them to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Marks</ENAMEX> i think where ever that's located
 	
 	
 		okay yeah yeah that's one of the more um yeah i have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that uh have younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they send them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montessori</ENAMEX> system
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and when you hear what they're paying you just
 	
 	
 		well he he said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six hundred a month</TIMEX> and that doesn't include their personal expense
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		so you're you're talking about uh college uh level fees here
 	
 	
 		yeah twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and you add <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to that and you say oh my goodness yeah i
 	
 	
 		sure but i think i think the honors programs are good in the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but uh some of the problems you get are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are in those programs get harassed by their peers
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		for doing too well
 	
 	
 		this is true yes i can personally relate to that yes
 	
 	
 		and that discourages them from doing well
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i don't know i think one thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> does um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepfather</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and one thing they do their at least in in the section of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> where he was from that they um
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		they actually they call them externships but they actually the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s um uh they go by forms they don't go by grades and i guess i guess
 		what would be the equivalent of our early high school <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine tenth</NUMEX> grade they call it the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> of eleventh form um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they actually are forced to take time off and pick an area of study it's proctored it's you know regulated and all that sort of thing um but they actually are supposed to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and do their own thing on a particul ar subject and it doesn't matter what it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it has to be academic but they it's free of their choosing
 	
 	
 		well their allowed to progress at their own pace then
 	
 	
 		right in that one just for that one particular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semester quarter</TIMEX> or what ever you know that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one quarter</NUMEX> uh a study <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> would be and
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		i don't know i don't think we do enough of that here in terms of getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to think independently
 	
 	
 		no
 		i can relate to part of that uh in in my high school uh say just for for example in my math courses uh i i was not to brag about this at all i was so far ahead of everybody else that i didn't have to go to class
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		and i got to sit by myself in an empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> while everybody else was in class taking algebra and work at my own pace
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		see yeah
 		that's kind of what i'm talking about i mean um uh i mean we can only speak from personal experience and i'm not bragging either but it's the same thing i mean i took <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> or advanced placement classes
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and it there were things that i probably knew about in other segments but they just didn't offer them i mean they offered them in things like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> and chemistry
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things that were obscure to what i was interested in in terms of um a career um
 		i think part of the thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> today is too is the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have gone down the tubes the structure that now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> play police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> you know their parenting their disciplinarians
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm sure that has a definite effect
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and i'm doing this all this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> hand we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> or anything so i can't
 	
 	
 		well i i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> either but uh from i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who had been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX> once upon a time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and whenever the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was traveling away on business or they they had financial problems their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh their it was definitely noticed at their performance in school
 	
 	
 		isn't that something i mean are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>  i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> were divorced too but i can't remember ever i mean it was sort of just like uh you knew you had to study or you just didn't
 	
 	
 		yeah it got so bad with with this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that uh the the school uh called their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> up to ask if there were any problems going on
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 	
 	
 		because his performance at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> had degraded so much
 	
 	
 		i mean i wouldn't want to be growing up now a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> that's one thing um but i don't know how you solve that you know those are social problems the academic problem i don't know i think of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> things in my mind i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> should be tested
 	
 	
 		i i believe in that
 	
 	
 		and they probably would shoot me if they heard that and i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> i think that they should leave the funding or the money where the proven programs are
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> i do think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> need to be more involved i don't know i just it's probably easy to say because none of us have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but um i just
 	
 	
 		right well i remember as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> uh they had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTA Parent Teacher Association</ENAMEX> meetings all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">association</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> always went to those uh
 	
 	
 		yeah mine too i mean and do they have those anymore i mean i don't even
 	
 	
 		i i don't know
 	
 	
 		i don't have any uh but you know just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> we were somewhere actually on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> we were in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park Cities</ENAMEX> ordering in a we were in a specialty uh food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> ordering something to send out of state and
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> we were all upon the topic of adoption which may be in our future um if we're real lucky at any rate he was saying how he was glad that his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> biological <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> natural um this had to do with the adopted the adopted one which
 		biological i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> adopted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um</ENAMEX> that's irrelevant but he was saying that uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> said and what does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is very good looking what is he well he's nineteen he graduated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> um but he's interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> and he's just going to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland</ENAMEX> and
 		he said you know he said i'm not calling him stupid or slow he just he said he did really didn't want to study and he goes and you know he leaned over to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and he said well you know so and so he said when you have them if you get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> what you'll understand is you'll just be glad if they don't you don't get a call from the police
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and he said our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> you know blah blah blah um he may be have only been a C <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> but we've never had trouble with him he said and when you raise a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s society he you're just glad they make it through school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well the the dropout rate is so high in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> uh yes it is i i think it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty eight</TIMEX> percent
 	
 	
 		
 
 		is it see i don't even know that
 		
 		
 	