
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we're just starting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> through adoption so i don't really have a lot of um concrete um
 		opinions just what i know out of my peer group uh has gone through and none of it's been good
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh the ones that can afford to have live in nannies they seem to be having an okay time
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but a lot of the other ones that have are professional um i'd say fifty percent of you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> that i'm in my circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 		have tried it and then stopped working until they're you know going to get their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in kindergarten or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but i there must be some good service out there if you really look and pay for it
 	
 	
 		right
 		what what age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> are you thinking in in terms of
 	
 	
 		in terms of what they're talking about
 	
 	
 		no for for yourselves
 	
 	
 		oh infant um
 	
 	
 		oh okay so you're starting from the baseline  from the baseline
 	
 	
 		infant
 		yeah after <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of marriage yeah we are we're actually it's happening now so we're just going through the process
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so and and actually the question is uh very appropriate because i'm not sure whether um
 		how strong the maternal instinct's going to be they tell me it's going to be strong do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		i have one son
 	
 	
 		and did you put him in day care or is he older <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> or younger or
 	
 	
 		well he's now he's now eighteen and in in you know has completed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> of university
 	
 	
 		sure so he's out of day care
 	
 	
 		i right and and so that but i was working full-time uh when he was born but i was very lucky because i was a a college professor
 	
 	
 		you uh-huh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so i was able to you know and i it was walking distance from my from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> so i went up there and i sort of left him with with a neighbor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">flex</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i left him in a carry cot when he was very little and i said you know he doesn't need anything except you know
 		look look at him if he cries but you know don't pick him up and and this sort of stuff because i was gone <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only an hour</TIMEX> at a stretch or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and a half</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		and i was able to you know get his his schedule just uh cooperated and
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's wonderful yeah and and i guess um that uh because of your um your uh profession i mean i um i'm in corporate communications but i've done freelance writing in the past
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so what we're hoping is that um i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> thinks i can do it i've just never worked out of a domestic base you know i've always been in a corporate uh environment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but i'm hoping that possibly i can do something where i can go flextime or part-time or if they don't have that um
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> i'm very lucky though again too my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> is very akin to family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> so i think that's something that something that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> need in going into this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		um i don't know i do think there's good day care out there what part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> are you in
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> but but i was out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> when um my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was little but but the thing is if you have this flextime and that you might be able to do something similar to what i did which is
 	
 	
 		you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 		right that's what i'm hoping
 	
 	
 		you know be there short times and then later on when he was you know i mean this we're talking about uh i went back to work and or taught some some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> after he was born
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh my goodness you were fortunate yeah
 	
 	
 		and so
 		yeah and so that's when i was saying you know don't don't pick him up and stuff but then later what i did was i brought a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> into the house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum sure
 	
 	
 		and she was she was supposed to help me a little bit with cooking and doing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>'s laundry and this sort of stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then i also came home and sort of was
 		was able to see from a distance what she was doing and you know in a sense she she carried him around a lot too much uh you know for for my taste it was constantly no i don't want him to explore anything he might
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh he might hurt himself
 	
 	
 		so do you think that i mean do you think that that was in a way though good objectivity good objectivity that now that's doesn't really that's not a correct <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> but um you know in a sense you see what i'm saying though from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s standpoint i mean in a way it it was quote unquote good objectivity objectivity
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think it worked out very well a very well because what he learned to do by the time he was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or so he would sit next to the desk where i was grading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> or writing lesson plans and he had asked for a paper and you know sort of scribble and then he realized that there were quiet times and there were active times
 	
 	
 		see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right and then he learned he he also learned that um there were times that you had to be gone so you probably minimized well we're actually um we're getting ready i mean you're far enough away now i can tell you this just locally i make sure we're going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romania</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and that's um just
 	
 	
 		did you say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romania</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armenia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Romania Romania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		as in like what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> and um but we we're real excited because we've just developed a contact
 	
 	
 		oh good
 	
 	
 		through professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and it's private and it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> it's we're just very excited um
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		and well
 		it it what's the word i'm looking for when you deal with issues like that um in terms of family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> through adoption um and then you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> responding to you well if you go through that why would you put them in day care
 	
 	
 		oh that's silly
 	
 	
 		um issues are being raised prematurely in my mind but i guess they're not because
 		it's something i'll have to deal with sooner than later um and i what i've learned to do is just tune out everybody's opinion i feel that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s healthy um you know as long as we make it feel secure i'd love to do something like with what you did
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i don't think i could be a dumper where i could take it from you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight in the morning till nine at night</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and leave it there
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		uh maybe after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two or three or  years old</TIMEX> i don't know um
 	
 	
 		oh i  in my opinion it's even then i mean uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> need you
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah i just
 		well they need a schedule i think i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> were you um in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> when you were uh uh
 	
 	
 		no i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um oh that's sort of well that's the same thing i mean i don't know how they are there but uh
 		in eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">my stepfather</TIMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> it just seems the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> does not provide for either child care or geriatrics or elder care as i call it
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and we're just not set up for that um with the
 	
 	
 		i yeah
 	
 	
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		no i was just going to say i guess uh my sensitivities are are much more with the
 		you know to be at home because actually i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> with me fro m the time she was from the time she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> until she died at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		see i think that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		and i mean that was recently after my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son son</ENAMEX> was going off and i mean yes in a sense i went to work and she was at home alone some of the time but but still you know it was much better than being shipped
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		to a
 	
 	
 		to a day care center
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know which is much my feelings on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the elderly i think we're too we're too too much towards it's somebody else's problem you know i want to work shove them in in some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twelve hours a day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		we cast off right right that i'm that way yeah
 		right it's easier and i agree with that that's why i you you know what is amazing to me is now your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is already grown but you can probably empathize with this
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's amazing to me how forthcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are with their opinions and thoughts
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		in terms of what to do um
 		and i just don't think there is a day <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> care system um my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> i'm particularly fortunate that they have they're in tune with that
 		but i've been at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> where um you know the decision the the trend is or the definite mood is well we made conscious decisions not to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's sad
 	
 	
 		you know and in and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> like us building through adoption there it's almost radical to some people
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and what you just learn to do is tune everybody else out and um and i respect there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that i know that are divorced or on their own or
 		in single parenting and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> that they you know they may have the need for child care like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i agree with you that it's just i call it dumping  i mean i
 	
 	
 		yeah no i i think that certainly there is a role uh for this type of help and and as long as one can can supervise it and and you know make it work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		into into one's own schedule without it seeming like dumping or or uh giving it you know the whole job to somebody else to take care of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		then yeah it's are it's in tandem then
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i just um and there are trade-offs too i think one of the things that is a problem is that um in terms of compensation to some of the child care providers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um it's just
 		you know it's so low but yet the overall cost for somebody doing it on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> or even a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> basis it's prohibitive and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are not making more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thousand a year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		actually there seems to be an alternative in my neighborhood is there seem there are several uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers mothers</ENAMEX> who stay home
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they take you know it's probably not completely legal uh i maybe it's legal up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but and they they take care of another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and i i can actually name could name <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around my neighborhood that really do a good job on this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and they yeah
 	
 	
 		and i mean that's another possibility and you know you might want to stay home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> and some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> might want to stay home for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i haven't thought about that yeah and actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> has an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen month old</TIMEX> and
 		she's an at home part-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paralegal</ENAMEX> so i'm thinking hm  and we get along fantastically so i'm thinking you know and that's the way you have to um how was i'm just real curious how was the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> in terms of that with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		is that is child care or that type of idea completely foreign to them
 	
 	
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> actually there was a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center um</ENAMEX> where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> did go for a year i think from when he was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two to three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but then he actually started kindergarten at age three
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so and it you know it wasn't like pre kindergarten it was real kindergarten
 	
 	
 		oh really he must be smart yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah so he was he was ready to to go to school at that point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but yeah they're they do have such facilities but for the most part uh the with the extended family
 		you know you can usually find somebody which is much like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> you know to sharing responsibility and i'm and also there aren't that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who who do who work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		the professional yeah i was wondering about that um there i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and there was just a very big um series about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Moslem</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there were enlightening things that broke some of my stereotypical thoughts i'm digressing here but uh i was just real curious when you said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> if you didn't mind me asking
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no no and i didn't mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> so you you assumed right
 	
 	
 		oh no that's okay  well even if you did that's okay actually i think
 	
 	
 		well no because at first thought uh when i said uh you know i said that not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> work i'm i'm thinking oh well she's going to you know because certainly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> do work
 	
 	
 		right right they fight they work
 		
 		
 	