
 
     		
 	
 		okay do you vote regular
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i do i try and vote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single</TIMEX> election
 	
 	
 		every one
 	
 	
 		but uh  that's just since in the past say about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> before that i really didn't pay any attention at all
 	
 	
 		well see that's me i've never paid any attention to voting
 	
 	
 		oh you haven't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i didn't use to but now i really because i get so angry about what goes on and then i feel like i can't really complain too much unless
 	
 	
 		unless you have something to do with it  right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but the problem is that i am very liberal politically and so i hardly ever have anybody that wins that i vote for
 	
 	
 		oh liberal by what do you mean by liberal um
 	
 	
 		liberal politically i'm you know like pretty left wing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat Democrat</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well see i don't know anything about politics
 	
 	
 		oh you don't
 	
 	
 		uh what's the main what's the main difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay well  there's a lot of them um depends on what issue you're talking about but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are on a lot of issues are more liberal than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and
 		well it used to be it's kind of hard to say now especially after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Storm</ENAMEX> but um i think back in the eighties times when uh my political opinions were being formed like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam war</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were more
 		you know what they called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawks</ENAMEX> which is more like aggressive in war and more pro-war and pro-aggression and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> were the doves they were more for peace and i'm not sure how much that holds true anymore i think you know the issues are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and you vote for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> usually are supportive more supportive of public assistance programs and and programs to
 	
 	
 		usually okay
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		the the big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> thing is that they don't they vote for less government they want less government involvement in society and so they're more less apt to vote in you know more aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		more uh they're less apt to vote in programs that involve the government
 		running things
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so so have you ever voted at all
 	
 	
 		okay
 		no i never have
 	
 	
 		you haven't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how old are you
 	
 	
 		i'm <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty six</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		i know i should i
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		well
 		i don't know much that much about it i don't keep up on it and i don't feel like i have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have enough knowledge on it to even you know to pick the right person
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		so that's what they need well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it uh they said something to improve voting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if they could
 		make it more oh easier to find out you know what's going on do you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		like uh
 		like to me i don't i didn't know what would have been wrong with i can't even remember who ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> i think it was uh
 		that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> wasn't it a woman
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dukakis</ENAMEX>
 		no it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dukakis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> didn't he have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> or wasn't or was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
 		there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that was running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">vice president</ENAMEX> for a while Ferraro
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that was yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ferraro</ENAMEX> that was a while ago that was a couple elections ago yeah
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		yeah  that's okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well well that's what i mean like i didn't know what the difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i didn't know anything about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so what do you think about
 		uh what do you think about what you see on TV about them like in the news or on the ads do you kind of just
 	
 	
 		okay i don't remember anything about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dukakis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you don't
 	
 	
 		but
 		well they're all saying that they're going to do you know whatever is best for their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's what i mean if they had some kind of public programs where you can just go out and
 		i don't know like you know in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they didn't teach you about <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> not really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		you didn't get any government classes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really hard too because before they used to have um
 		a lot of
 		it seems like the stuff that they put out now it i mean i doesn't just seem like it i know for a fact that the any kind of stuff that if you wrote and asked for material well what do you believe in what do you believe in they don't take any stands on anything they kind of say well what do you want me to believe
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or they word it so that it's really hard to tell where they're standing on certain issues
 	
 	
 		well i'm not sure they're yeah i know how they do it it like it with the abortion issues and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah they have to kind of take a stand on some things like abortion and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		things like that so that's kind of how i judge there's a few things where they have to say yes or no like abortion or gun control or let me see i try to look at
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		what  if some of the newspaper articles or the i don't trust TV as much but newspaper articles can show whether how they voted in the past
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and but you get you know it all depends again on whose writing it and who they're for because they can slant that too
 	
 	
 		right and like i said most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> i'm the
 		also the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> put out what makes them look good anyway
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and everybody's got you know stuff they don't want known
 	
 	
 		right  everybody's got a secret
 	
 	
 		well anyway i'm sorry i didn't i didn't have
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		
 
 		so
 	
 	
 		much knowledge i don't even remember this being on there
 	
 	
 		well that's okay
 		do you think
 		do you think um i mean what would it take like that this is really good actually that for to talk to somebody who hasn't voted i mean what kind of
 		how would it how what kind of stuff would they would you like them to do so that that you would know more about it like send stuff in the mail or have it at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		incentive
 		you i guess that would be good now i'm sure they've got it at the library
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean if i get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> so i don't
 	
 	
 		oh do you yeah that'll tie you down a little bit
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but i
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		or do you just not do you feel like it's not really going to make that much difference if you don't vote or
 	
 	
 		oh i know if enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think like that it you know would make a difference if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> stopped thinking like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		well a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they'll vote the way their family votes you know if since you're what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then then like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or whatever will follow you and just vote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		um-hum well  not in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we're kind of  really independent
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		no
 		all split
 	
 	
 		but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> do that i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> feel like they have to vote the way that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> vote
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and that kind of keeps from getting a lot of issues resolved  golly
 	
 	
 		i lie
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but
 		well
 	
 	
 		i don't know if i did understand politics i probably would vote more but like i said if i voted  for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> or like when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gary</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hart</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hart</ENAMEX> was running
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would have voted for him just because he was nicer looking not that i think he was good looking but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he was young
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then
 		i didn't think that was right because he may have been a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but because it was he had an affair
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it just threw him out of the whole running
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go by their uh
 		personal life when they vote
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and
 		which i guess if you got turmoil in your personal life you're going to let it come into work but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm sure there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have had
 	
 	
 		i think everybody does it just depends on how well you can hide it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and i that's very true i i think that doesn't really have that much to do with um unless they've done something really horrible you know or something real abnormal
 	
 	
 		well criminal or something like that's different but
 	
 	
 		yeah right but otherwise
 	
 	
 		if him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> weren't getting along i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what is what effect does that have on him running for president
 		do you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it's all so secretive see we really don't see the
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		i think that's that's having a big effect on how poorly that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s being run is that um the the election
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that want to get elected are turning it into a popularity contest by advertising the things that  you know that really don't have anything to do with how well they do the job but see they're trying to find an excuse not to deal with what
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know the issues that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really want to know about because on those issues you have to say yes or no and if they don't say yes or no then
 		maybe somebody'll vote for them that wouldn't have if they had come down on the wrong side do you know what i'm saying so they just try and make it a personal thing i mean if you remember
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		any of the TV commercials from the last presidential campaign they all had uh pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> walking around with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> and
 		even from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> it was all just like looks like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> commercial you know
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  well what did you think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> as a president
 	
 	
 		that's about what it looked like
 		i just thought he was really inept i don't think he did anything at all he they just kind of sat him up there like a puppet and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were
 	
 	
 		do you think he won from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>  because of the um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> that were held at that time
 	
 	
 		well i think that was part of it i think there's a lot of the the economic problems that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was having at the time and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the recession</TIMEX> and stuff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just had a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> as not being real capable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but he actually all right this
 		i thought he was great
 	
 	
 		i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> was good too and that was yeah
 	
 	
 		did you i always liked him i thought he was great at the time and i i just couldn't get over the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> beat him i you know that i just couldn't believe that he got voted out
 	
 	
 		but i think i wasn't well let's see that's been about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> right
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		okay so i was only fifteen or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> but i remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> and i liked him yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you did have you heard stuff about him lately do you know what he's doing
 	
 	
 		no i sure don't
 	
 	
 		well he is just he is really active still politically he's been overseas you remember when he was in office he did a lot of stuff for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> for people
 		
 		
 	