
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX> what do you think about uh
 		choosing choosing a college
 	
 	
 		yeah what should i tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> but being a student uh i guess i'd say there's there's a lot of things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i think
 		they need to provide a lot of guidance during high school
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		preparing them for the college they want to go to and then it's a trade-off between what you know what you got to find out what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> wants out of college you know is it uh
 		a a social thing or is he looking to make big bucks later with a with a name brand college so to speak
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		things like you know do you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S M U</ENAMEX> you want to spend all that money and get that name or do you
 		you know you you just kind of wasting your time to spend all that money if you're not going to use the degree for something
 	
 	
 		yeah do you think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in high school could know what they want in a college
 	
 	
 		i don't think in high school you know but i think that's when you should start being exposed to the ideas and start asking some questions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		having the having you know somebody that's been to college needs to sit down and explain these things to you you know i went in not knowing anything and if i'd a had a little better idea what was going on i'd a probably
 		made a lot of decisions differently
 	
 	
 		in what way
 	
 	
 		oh i'd probably started sooner and
 		taken courses in high school that would have prepared me better for for what i was going to see
 	
 	
 		yeah would you have uh went to the name college or
 	
 	
 		probably not in my situation i don't have the money for it but uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then again
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		it's kind of hard to say where i would have gone had i
 		been thinking about it back in high school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i think
 		i don't know to me college was a was a
 		i knew nothing about what it was going to be like it's it's a whole different thing than high school you know just go up and show up and stay up all day
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and you know they tell you what to do and you do it it's kind of a you drop in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and it's up to you to to learn it and get it done
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i think those are the kinds of things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> should should let their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> know if they know themselves
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> is a whole different ball game
 	
 	
 		yeah did either of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> go to college
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		yeah neither did mine so i wasn't really didn't know what to expect so uh
 	
 	
 		so yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it sounds like uh
 		like you said sometimes the the name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> the the large major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> carry the big name and uh
 		if they're private you know like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> or something they're big bucks sometimes fortunately though uh some of the big name <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> are in state
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they're state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX> or you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Purdue</ENAMEX> or something like that and you can get uh a good education at a good cost you know if if you're in state
 	
 	
 		decent price yeah
 	
 	
 		but if you know if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are out uh uh they want to go to college out of state you know you have to look like you said is the
 		are you are they going to get the education that's going to balance out like here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sherman</ENAMEX> there's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin College</ENAMEX> and i'm from up north i never heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin College</ENAMEX>
 		but it's well respected in this area it's private it's very expensive and just talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that go there it is uh
 		you know you you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professors</ENAMEX> on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name basis you go over their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> quite often and eat and spend time with them and at the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> you just don't do that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		you know there's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">couple hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in each of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and
 		and i remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> wanted to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> over but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were you know just kind of scared to go over and are they going to be called brownnoser when uh so it's just sort of unaccepted you just kind
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		go to class and you don't usually use the office hours i mean there's not the
 		the relationship you get the degree with the big name on it but you know you don't build that there's a lot of learning that you don't get
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		as opposed to that's what i like about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin College</ENAMEX> i didn't know that because i'd never been around any small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> but uh
 		but there again like you said the big name the big bucks you know you can go anywhere with a
 	
 	
 		that
 	
 	
 		a degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> turn heads but you know a degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin College</ENAMEX> or something you know where's that well you know it's not really well known and unfortunately sometimes that has to do with their sports program you know
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		if uh you know well some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> maybe not like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U N L</ENAMEX> V you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> kind of think that's a joke you know and you know it's big name and everybody knows about it and everybody wears <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U N L</ENAMEX> V shirts but you know what kind of education are these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting but
 		you know some of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> like uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Duke</ENAMEX> you know while they're successful in like basketball i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know that they're really good in academics
 	
 	
 		right a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i think i think i don't know for sure but i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> up in the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are generally provide a better  education
 		i could be wrong about that but my experience with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> has not been all that great
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i've never been to school down here so i really don't know uh i guess there again i mean there's the good and the bad like um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there seem to be a lot of junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and community <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> down here and up north there aren't
 		i mean pretty much you either go to a technical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> out of if you go to further schooling you go to like a technical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeVry</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		or you go to a university or a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> there are no  there as far as i know there are very few
 		
 		
 	