
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> you you maybe this is a fantasy we can to talk about any kind of car we want here
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rolls Royce</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX> that sounds like a great deal to me  you have great aspirations  well let's see i we just bought uh a seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> that we have restored
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's great your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> uh i'm i'm a hobbyist too i like to work on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		and it
 		yeah it has really been a lot of fun uh we found some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that actually you know worked for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> and uh they also repair them for other the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on their off time
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		so have we we have redone that thing from stem to stern i mean inside outside you know we've redone the body repainted it detailed it so you know i really haven't thought
 		much past that it seems like you know i don't know if i'll ever want another new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> again you know
 	
 	
 		was you why they they didn't say buy it they didn't necessarily say buy it new they just said what would you buy you know
 	
 	
 		maybe not
 		yeah that's true i i don't know it just seems like uh you know for what we've put into it i feel like that's something that might retain it's value a little bit more than you know yeah yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh sure a restored <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX> is is great i think certainly if it's an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> will be good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right we the one thing that uh we did decide as it's it's we wanted it to be as authentic as possible but
 		we did break down and put a CD <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in it  that's not quite authentic but at any rate that that was one thing that i one of the features that i did want
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		i'd passed up on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and put a sunroof in it i had to stop there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you all you all done a lot more when i talk about working on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i sure don't do that
 	
 	
 		yeah well of course we do it ourselves but like i said we were just lucky to find these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that do it you know they're they just weren't really expensive and
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay
 		oh that is good to have uh knowledgeable people
 	
 	
 		and uh yeah you know right and they work on it so the things that can be done here they just come here to our home and and work on it or work on it so
 	
 	
 		that's amazing
 	
 	
 		yeah it's you know it's really it's really been nice we uh
 	
 	
 		i i do all my own work uh so i i have Chevies mostly well that's all i've got right now i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V Eights</ENAMEX> i'm uh i'm uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but i do like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		you're an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> yeah yeah i i have always had an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and uh i had a real real bad experience with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cougar</ENAMEX> that i had it was an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cougar</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't know i think it just soured me on it for some reason because i had trouble with it starting the engine blew up  in it i had to replace the engine when it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two years old</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i i thought what the heck you know we'll try something different so
 	
 	
 		well i'm not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and never have been as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and uh i do like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">V Eight</ENAMEX> engines and i think the the
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i went to the auto show with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> hear recently down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and i to me the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are far superior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> in styling engines right now i mean i'm not saying that they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really
 		yeah right yeah yeah i would that that there's i see a marked improvement you know you know as far as uh what i've heard about performance and such
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know so uh uh hopefully it'll stay that way i mean you know i'd i'd i would hate to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> car industry suffering more than it already has
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know even though right now i'm not driving an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but uh i think
 	
 	
 		i uh you know they said they said what do we want to buy i i'm uh seriously not seriously thinking but i i would like to put it in that category uh buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> but i wouldn't buy a new one and you know of course if i had the money i'd be happy to by a new one but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i do look for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year old</TIMEX> vehicle you know with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty some odd</TIMEX> miles or whatever twenty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">thousand miles</NUMEX> whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty thousand</TIMEX> yeah yeah well that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are avid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX> they had uh and i think my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> drives the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SeVille</ENAMEX> now that's uh i guess it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years old</TIMEX>
 		and uh she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">SeVille</ENAMEX> before that that had the odd backs that was sort of
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i remember those yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and she it final just wore out they had they had purchased it i don't can't remember how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> they had that car but she loved the styling of it
 	
 	
 		that she may want to save if she she doesn't have it anymore
 	
 	
 		no she sold it and she
 	
 	
 		that since they don't make them anymore she that could be turned into a classic in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten fifteen years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know
 		yeah she kept telling herself that and it's sort of a bone of contention between she and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> because
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> said well just let me take it down there and find out what's wrong with it i mean he came back with a new car  yeah i think he had an ulterior motive he could just see you know dollar signs starting to flip by as far as repairs went but uh
 	
 	
 		no he wanted new one yeah right yeah
 	
 	
 		they they really are nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> there there
 	
 	
 		i i'm still a full size <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and i like a full size <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> i i want one of those i think they are i don't know a classic but they're certainly not they haven't changed in about uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and they'll eventually phase them out uh and i sure would like one ever those uh
 		uh within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next five years</TIMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems funny you how within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> have gotten bigger again you know they had
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they've scaled everything down so much and uh i have i don't i've never owned a really large <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i don't know i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cougar</ENAMEX> was the biggest thing i ever had and
 	
 	
 		well even the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are bigger too but uh i've never had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lexus</ENAMEX> are very nice looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		i've never had a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> car i i've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who had them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think they're a lot over rate and their's no styling to them that you can't tell <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> from the other they all look alike you know i don't mean that as a joke i mean they really all look alike and the adds i don't have any idea what which <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> it is
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		what is what yeah uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		until i look at it to see what it is and i think they have not uh lead the field in styling they do have nice sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but the price is way more you can get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> for the same price as you can get a small <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> it's ridiculous now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah i know that uh i've i've sort of always felt like with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buicks</ENAMEX> it seems like all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buicks</ENAMEX> to me look alike  you know i guess it just uh there seems to me they're all the same shape i have a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Regal</ENAMEX> and she she's had she's got way offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred thousand</NUMEX> miles on it and that's what she's going to buy again and i'm like oh please it looks exactly the same as this old one that you've got and so i guess it's in the eyes of the beholder i suppose
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah yeah well if if you're interested you  to go to the next auto show i i look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillacs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> there were some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillacs</ENAMEX> that i didn't even realize they made but they were just styled so differently
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they were standard <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cadillacs</ENAMEX> but they really looked beautiful
 	
 	
 		are they still are what they're what they have out for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year</TIMEX> is everything still pretty square it seems like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillacs</ENAMEX> is one of the few <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> that are still making really i i can't think of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that they make are the than maybe the
 	
 	
 		oh no they have they have convertibles now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> field and they have that new uh it's not the big uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fleetwood</ENAMEX> the one i want which is the same in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's another one that has came out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few year</TIMEX> it's not the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX> is totally different no the auto show they had fantastic looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> so uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when when was this when this was this recently
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month or so ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay because i have a
 	
 	
 		well they have it every year
 	
 	
 		yeah usually when i see the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> it's during the fair when i go to the auto <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Fair</ENAMEX> and that's usually when i see anything you know
 	
 	
 		right now this was uh in it was downtown
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">uh Convention Center</ENAMEX> they had all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> they had certainly had <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> they had the full range and they had some they had some new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> that weren't even out they had a uh
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">new Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Suburban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> you know that big big one that was uh they didn't have a price on it nor did they know had a it would cost it had a microwave in it and everything it was they had several futuristic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh my word
 		that's wild you know you you hear about things like that and you think that can't possibly be done i mean it just that's just too weird
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know
 		and i like engines they had a lot of broken down engine not broken down i mean you know cut uh displayed engines you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right uh-huh so you could tell the what see the inside of them or whatever yeah
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but uh that that sold me in buying a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> you know i mean certainly interested in buying a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but again the yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were for superior in styling and new engines
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah hum well maybe somebody's finally woken up you know
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i think so because they've been making these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cylinder and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> cylinder engines for a while and i think that i i would definitely buy again there's the question are we in the market uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i could buy anything you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you know i could fine i i was really crazy about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jags</ENAMEX> for a while and the convertible what is it XJS or something like that
 		and i you know thought that's a dream <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and and you really would have to be a dream <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because the repair bills are supposedly just constant you know i
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well i work on them myself so i don't that you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> don't go to the shop you know so uh i am a mechanical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and i've always done it myself and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well that's good that you can
 	
 	
 		i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them and uh i can't remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i think i had one someone welded a muffler on for me in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a years time</TIMEX> i think that's the only thing of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> that i've in it just the welding on like i said i don't do that you know
 	
 	
 		oh really that oh gosh that's great
 		i think it takes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> to do that you know my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> but he cannot i mean i or maybe he's just doesn't want to mess with it that's might be part of it but uh
 		you know we just i just say forget it we'll just take it in and have it taken care of he drives drives a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i noticed that when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> uh i was wasn't a mechanical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> but i worked my way through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> as a mechanic so i learned early from fifteen on
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and dropped it for a long time when after i got out of college and then picked it up again later on and now again i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicles</ENAMEX> and i i don't i never  and they just don't go to the shop at all you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well that's to  that's one thing that when you would consider see when i go out to think about a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or buy another car i don't think about well is this engine that i can work on or that you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> can work on or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so you're you're pretty lucky in that respect that
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm keeping V <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> V <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> engines because that's what i know and in fact i stock the same part i'm like a little stock if you brought your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> to me i could i'd probably have some parts for it right now you knows
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's what you know yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's pretty good it's really been funny because we have like been you are own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> kind of with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and when i say we have redone everything i mean we have redone everything and it's
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh that's great i've always wanted to that too
 	
 	
 		it's really been so interesting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you meet because uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX> has called all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you know he's gotten these catalogs trying it's really more difficult to find these vintage parts than you might think this is for a seventy three
 	
 	
 		oh i can imagine
 		
 		
 	