
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		here we go
 	
 	
 		okay where are you from
 	
 	
 		i'm from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attleboro Massachusetts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh is that where you're talking from
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		oh well yeah can tell from your accent
 	
 	
 		how
 		how about you
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville Kentucky</ENAMEX> but i'm here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you're down there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> oh okay um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we're supposed to be talking about why <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> vote in national elections
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		do you vote regular
 	
 	
 		i vote regularly yes i do
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		in the national elections um some of the local um
 		i don't tend to
 		unless there's a referendums
 		something that's going to affect the town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh then i uh
 	
 	
 		well i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		then i put my <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two cents</NUMEX> in
 	
 	
 		uh i need to get into voting i've never voted
 	
 	
 		you never ever voted
 	
 	
 		no i've never voted i've never felt comfortable enough with it i don't know enough about politics to know what the right choice is anyway
 	
 	
 		as far as uh
 	
 	
 		even local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> it just  i talked about this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> on the telephone with it's uh
 		so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> you know
 		they put up a front to me you know they're not showing you the real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> anyway they're just show showing what the public wants to see
 	
 	
 		uh that's true unless you unless you come from i come i come from a fairly small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> so i i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rhode Island</ENAMEX> but i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's fairly small and you and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you tend to know at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or you know uh
 	
 	
 		well that would be nice yeah
 	
 	
 		it's uh
 		it's getting away from that now i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>'s growing bigger as as all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> are
 		and you're right they're uh uh i think uh
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> when they first get into politics they want to do a good job
 		and then after they're they're in there a while you have to play the good old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> network
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it's uh
 		uh um they have their own special interests and watch out for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are going to do the most for them too to get them reelected i think
 	
 	
 		right
 		well that's what i mean it's just
 		you don't know
 		what's real i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah how about uh bond issues or referendum that they they put on
 		you don't
 	
 	
 		i don't know much about that at all
 		what do you mean like when you vote for a certain thing not a person
 	
 	
 		right yeah whether they they want to build a new school whether they want to put in a new reservoir or or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay no i've never voted on anything like that either
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but yet they're taking your tax money or they would if if some of these bond issues passed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		you still didn't have any feelings one way or the other about whether they they should do it or shouldn't
 	
 	
 		well see i've never how do you do the do you do that like you're voting just like if you're taking a a presidential election do you just go somewhere and place your ballot or
 	
 	
 		yeah yes
 	
 	
 		huh well see i've never heard of that well i know that sounds stupid but i really haven't i've never heard of that
 	
 	
 		um
 		how how long have you lived in in
 		where are you now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm no i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denison Texas</ENAMEX> up north in on in the north part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		okay but you haven't lived your your whole life you came from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> did you say
 	
 	
 		right i moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> when i was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay but you grew up in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		right i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> okay that's and but that's and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>'s a a large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a fairly big city
 	
 	
 		yeah you didn't have local real local politics like you know like a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> would how about where you are now is that a fairly large
 	
 	
 		Denison it's uh
 		i wouldn't say it's large but it is one of the bigger
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in this part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah so you're in the same boat there
 	
 	
 		right it's about the same
 	
 	
 		and you don't really know who's who are what's going on or yeah
 	
 	
 		no i remember once when i was working in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX> one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor candidates</ENAMEX> come up to the uh
 		uh place where i was working and he had asked me i don't know i guess it had been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years</TIMEX> since i'd been eligible to vote and i haven't hadn't been voting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> he had uh
 		this is one of the things that you know formed my opinion on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician politicians</ENAMEX> he sat there and promised you know the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX> we're going to take you up and get you registered to vote and you're going to vote for me and blah blah blah but then he never showed up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ha</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it was one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> or whatever but still i thought you know they say what they want to for the time being what sounds good
 	
 	
 		just just so they can get in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's all and it's uh they probably should limit the the terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> to no more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> i mean <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> terms
 		that way they don't get in there because some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have been in there like for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> and they they kind of run things the way they want to run them whether whether it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for the good of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> or not
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well that's i think they need to have a a better
 		oh
 		i need to know a lot more about politics and they need to have something in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> well like in high school they should teach politics or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> i mean i think so
 	
 	
 		yeah um some of them do now um social social sciences and i'm not sure how far they get into politics and that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i want to know about politics in particular you know just you know what the workings of it is
 	
 	
 		oh the  like uh uh
 		parliamentary procedure and and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		everything right in order for me to be able to form a a good opinion opinion on who to vote for or whatever i i need to know about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and if i could keep a follow-up on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> running like right now you know i know whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president vice president</ENAMEX> and i know a couple of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koch</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 		i don't even know who's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> down here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> off hand
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		um i don't it it's they've got they've got rules and regulations they have to follow for for government procedures but there's too many special interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> now that are in there that that can sway an election one way or another
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i don't even think running to to the running of
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> now is done by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">the president</ENAMEX> they say yo u know he's i think he's only really a figurehead he only can do certain amount of things because he's got so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> after him you know an he's he's got to look out
 	
 	
 		so much
 		well what do you think about i think just you know anybody should be allowed to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> just even an ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> if he knows the politics
 	
 	
 		well you can except it costs so much money now that the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can't do that
 	
 	
 		right it's it's that's what i mean it's all money and
 	
 	
 		um plus they're all you you have to play the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have been in power now  uh most of them are i think are are crooks
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you have to play their ball game they've been in there so long and if you don't then they'll you know they'll find ways to get rid of you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no one's held accountable anymore for things that happen well
 	
 	
 		what did you think of that whole mess with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ollie North</ENAMEX> and all that
 	
 	
 		oh i think that they should have crucified him
 		that's what i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> too <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> he knew about it
 	
 	
 		oh of course he did
 	
 	
 		and if he didn't know the whole scope of it whoever whoever was directly under him
 	
 	
 		he should have looked into it
 		right or it should have been looked into more
 	
 	
 		yeah an now it's coming out where there was there was holding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> now they're saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX> were being made political pawns when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> were running i mean you know
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's the way i felt when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was running i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> as a president
 	
 	
 		he was a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i'm not sure uh he was too probably too moral
 	
 	
 		yeah but he was a i don't know he was a good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and everything though well from what i've seen i was only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen then</TIMEX> but i
 		when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> came in i figured i thought it ran through my head that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> lost because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hostages</ENAMEX>
 		you know that whole mess
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		wasn't it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was elected that they were brought home
 	
 	
 		well shortly there after yeah
 	
 	
 		or yeah shortly after
 	
 	
 		yeah so there was some collusion in there i guess
 	
 	
 		i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were disappointed because they had been held hostage for so long
 	
 	
 		and i think that's part of the problem why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't vote anymore because of of it's just out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s hands and they say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote means a lot but
 	
 	
 		but is a lot enough people
 	
 	
 		it used to i don't think it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote means means diddly anymore
 	
 	
 		no but if enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think like that then it does
 		you know
 	
 	
 		yeah but but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get disillusioned too
 	
 	
 		well well if i knew more about it like i said if they would get some kind of educational program out there where just anybody can learn
 	
 	
 		um probably one of the local do they have adult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ed classes</ENAMEX> at some of the local schools
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure they do
 	
 	
 		where they teach uh you know like political science or something
 	
 	
 		i don't know i could check into that
 	
 	
 		yeah because you because it might give you uh an insight you know uh you have to vote i've always i've always voted i even though sometimes it's hard to choose between whose running
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right well wasn't it i know i can't remember i think i guess it was when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferraro Ferraro</ENAMEX> is that her name when her and uh i can't remember who was running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> with her i just remember she was going to be vice
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh uh Ferraro yeah Geraldine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		who was running with her who was her running mate
 	
 	
 		uh i don't remember
 		
 		
 	