
 
     		
 	
 		gun control seems to be a rather um timely topic with all that's going on legislation wise
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh the the interesting scale that they assigned it uh  the one being a banned and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> being no regulations or totally free
 		i'd have to put myself pretty much in the middle i guess i i don't mind regulating all of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and i
 		would certainly call for a ban on certain types now the the wisdom as to which types that's gonna be a debate forever i would assume
 		uh the method of of controlling it well that's all into how much money you wanna put into the the controls um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point that was made in the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> hearings or the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> who stood up and said that uh you know we can check a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s credit card instantly
 		but uh we don't wanna check his background and of course those are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different issues as far as privacy goes uh but there's still the the technology exists to to check it if they want
 	
 	
 		hm right
 	
 	
 		so it's it's it's kind of a
 		uh i guess you got to put a dollar figure on it if you really wanna make that kind of an effort and regulate it like that and then you've got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that decide that there's
 		there's no particular reason to have them at all and you got to balance those against the ones that say there is some sport to it
 		and i guess i would fall more in the the realm that i like the sport issue of it but i i could give it up
 		without too much trouble it's not the world's most pleasurable thing and it costs a bit to do it uh finding ranges and things like that um i have shot a variety of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> but it's just it's not
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right
 	
 	
 		like golf or whatever i mean there are other things that you could go do  so uh i i don't see the the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">joy</ENAMEX> of shooting is is that much of a driving factor i think uh society could easily swing the scales the other direction just for the sake of safety
 		so the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that tend to get hurt i don't even keep the gun in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so uh we don't have that problem but uh  it's it's a hard hard topic i guess for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a lot of hard issue a lot of hard feelings about it
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right
 		they do and you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> you can get them  on either side  and just like you say uh well i think i i guess i'd have to  place myself uh
 		uh probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>  because or not wait wait onto no control i'm sorry uh excuse me that uh uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i was going the wrong direction  um because of we had a neighbor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that was killed by another child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they had a gun in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullets</ENAMEX> in a separate place but the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years old</TIMEX> and was so
 		intelligent enough to  uh he knew where <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">booth</ENAMEX> both places were loaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and they were playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> and he shot the other little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> right between the eyes
 	
 	
 		boy
 	
 	
 		so uh i mean it it destroyed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> uh in just that instant and and i a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say that they need it for protection uh having
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		worked at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> or i don't know if you're in a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> are you <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> yeah that's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>  um then you know that uh uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		if you live anywhere real close that uh the safety is uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> argue that they need a gun to make sure that they aren't going to get shot because of the incidences of break-ins and you know but uh uh we have never
 		had a gun in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> growing up uh i um uh once uh uh knew a fellow that had had been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> and he said that if you pull a gun on a robber
 		he's going to assume that you know how to use it well and he's going to you know try to shoot <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> uh so you know if he's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> um and if not um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		then usually they uh if he's got a knife or whatever they could throw it at you  i mean you know they he he said that it it's better not to have especially myself now i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> and uh i so i'm
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">handicapped son</ENAMEX> is is not at home i'm by myself but uh there's i still won't have a gun in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> because he said it's it's really  um playing <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian Roulette</ENAMEX> if you do  uh
 	
 	
 		yeah about the only circumstances that they'd be of any value is when you happen to already know that the the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> was coming your way if once you're surprised it's too late and and the rare circumstances you know the very few of those burglaries actually occur in such a way that you knew the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was coming and had time to do anything about it
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 		right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and i don't have that problem is i don't use that argument as saying it's worth keeping <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>'s um
 		claim that the uh the constitutional and the right to bear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> and that whole statement uh it's hard to know the original intent but i i don't see it as that
 		that difficult of a story to believe when the opposition says that uh yeah its the right to to arm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX> and as opposed to just the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> and you have a
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you have a earn a right not just a privilege as it were if you were gonna serve in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">militia</ENAMEX> then you have a right to have that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> but uh or you know there's all sorts of arguments there but i don't even worry about
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		i know
 	
 	
 		the what the original intent was they didn't have this problem back then  so we we change our rights with our social status they're man given rights and they can be taken away by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		no
 		no that's true that that's that's right that's right
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that hide behind that i don't worry about they can go live in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> if they want
 	
 	
 		well the yeah that's how i feel too i know well even even here where i work uh we have uh a gun <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> and of course those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are very avid
 		they you know they say there should be no ban that it's not but i can't see why any uh on on the street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> should be able allowed to be allowed to have a machine gun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know when you were talking about maybe what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> it would be hard to decide but there are a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> that uh just are not uh sport or
 		i mean i don't know too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that use a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">machine gun</ENAMEX> to go sport hunting either  so um uh i i think they should have at least some control over over those things um when and when you were speaking about  they can check up
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know on credit cards well i i understand about the privacy act and everything  but why can't they check to see if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who is applying for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> has had a record or not that to me would not be an unreasonable thing and if they do course
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the argument with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the gun club um is that uh well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are going to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> are the ones who are going to steal them anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and so it's not gonna be that they're buying them course some of them do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it it it is a hard question
 	
 	
 		tends to tends to strap only the legitimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> most regulation does most it's very difficult to uh legislate uh
 	
 	
 		right oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crooks</ENAMEX> or whatever you wanna however you wanna word it so it's well this may be a never ending topic i got a couple of calls  waiting on me so i better let you go
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		okay well thanks for talking  bye-bye now
 	
 	
 		okay bye
 		
 		
 	