
 
     		
 	
 		all right um
 		what kind of recent camping experience do you have
 	
 	
 		well there are several things that we've done as a family um
 		as far as uh when we go on vacation we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>  and so it's difficult sometimes for us to afford the hotel all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we take our tent and we pitch it and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are just great at camping my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> are scouts
 		and are very adept at that kind of thing and so it makes it a successful thing you know we just pitch the tent and we find the campgrounds that have facilities which is really nice because there are a lot of them across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um
 		and uh uh like i said our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are just really good and we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> and even he's not any big problem with it
 	
 	
 		oh that's good yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i think it's uh it's a lot of fun uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camping</ENAMEX> experiences have been mostly with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who was in the scouts he's he's huh he thinks he's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> now but uh we started camping with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cub scouts</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh camped uh you know for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> with the with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> and and went to some of the scout uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp sites</ENAMEX> around
 		and we've had really had a good time uh
 	
 	
 		they're nice too
 	
 	
 		with that
 	
 	
 		yeah um and i was a den <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> for a while too and uh like they have a thing called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mom and Me</ENAMEX> and that's right you'd go out with them even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> do and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> over night
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		but uh
 		our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first uh first</NUMEX> camping experience was uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> took the the uh Webelows i guess it was camping uh and we went over to uh a lake over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Texas</ENAMEX>
 		and we my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and i borrowed a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these pop up trailer tents
 	
 	
 		oh how fun
 	
 	
 		and it rained it started raining about the time we left home and it rained
 		uh like that was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and it rained <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day Saturday</TIMEX> and it was still raining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> we went over and set up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and you know stayed there over night
 		we couldn't do anything so as soon as we woke up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> we you know we had breakfast and then we all came back home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think he and i were the only ones that stayed high and dry so to speak
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		most of the most of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camping</ENAMEX> experiences have been you know pup tent type of you know little <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> tents on the ground and sleeping in a bed roll you know and that kind of thing so it's uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		we did have a really bad experience uh we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> and um
 		while we were there we  uh had camped on kind of a sandy ground area instead of uh the hard firm uh dirt ground
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> there came a very um windy type weather and it blew our stakes out and and the the tent fell
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that that that's always bad when the tent falls on you in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so that wasn't too exciting but good experience for us to know that we definitely didn't needed to do the stakes into a firm ground
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right yeah you need to be on higher ground sometime you don't want the if there if it's going to rain you don't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to run down into your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		but uh yeah we had we've had some really good experiences it it's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> since i've been camping but uh as a matter of fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> uh is camping now he camps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> he
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh how fun
 	
 	
 		he's uh involved with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scarborough Fair</ENAMEX> down at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waxahachie</ENAMEX> and he goes down there on uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> on uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> and stays uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and then comes back home after it closes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		and stays so
 	
 	
 		so he has a tent that's i guess he's got a permanent tent site for his tent stays down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all week</TIMEX> you know and he just goes down and spends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> down there
 	
 	
 		well that sounds great
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so he's really having a good time camping and and you know his experiences that he got from scouting have really you know been good for him uh from that he he lost interest in scouts but he still uses what he learned so
 	
 	
 		see that's that's very nice
 		the only thing i think about camping is when you have to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook outdoors</ENAMEX> and you don't always have to do that but um we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dutch oven</ENAMEX> and and we found some really fun recipes that we can do in that that are quite tasteful
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		you know you uh do you do the cooking in the coals where you wrap everything in foil and
 	
 	
 		we've done that before uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but yeah that's we uh my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i took the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scout leadership</ENAMEX> training program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we really had a good time with that we did have a uh
 		i guess it was a raccoon that came into our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campsite</ENAMEX> and stole some of the food you know that we didn't have set up i think it actually went into the tent with uh with a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> that were in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> you know went in an and got stuff out of their tent
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		oh jeepers
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but they uh you know it was uh it was a fun time and we we've enjoyed camping what you know what little we've done uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're not
 	
 	
 		well i think camping is one of those things that you can make memories with so  i think it's a wonderful activity and it's just
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		we uh
 		we went uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time with a uh another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> or with the the scouting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> but it was the parents uh you know it was a family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things was that uh the uh we had uh uh a couple that were uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and they demonstrated cooking some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> out you know on a on a little gas burner type thing out there you know it was part of our our entertainment you know for the thing they cooked some kind of uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an Indian</TIMEX> uh pastry type thing on a in a skillet skillet you know so it was really it was really interesting we went to uh
 		down to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen Rose</ENAMEX> to the uh where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> tracks are and there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campsite</ENAMEX> you know down there in that area that we uh that we went to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		well i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and before we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i see the different kinds of camping there are you know like the mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">camping</ENAMEX> and then here it's mostly flat land
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i'm not sure which i like better it's kind of nice to be on flat land but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah right
 		well yes
 	
 	
 		but i think you get a more scenic type thing in there so
 	
 	
 		right yeah so if you haven't camped down around at that place down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">around</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen Rose</ENAMEX> you might enjoy that uh it's you know it's got some it's got some hills and stuff down there so
 	
 	
 		no i don't think we've ever gone there
 		oh that sounds nice
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh yeah you know well i've enjoyed i t and uh make you make me want to go camping again you know okay thanks
 	
 	
 		well thank you
 		i've enjoyed talking to you
 		well go go go  have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> um bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you too bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	