
 
     		
 	
 		okay what kind of vacations do you
 		participate in
 	
 	
 		well well when we were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we went to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> a couple of times
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carlsbad Caverns</ENAMEX> and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alamo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and since then i've gone to uh well i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> trip
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> Caddo
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		have you ever been on a cruise before
 	
 	
 		uh no
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		nothing like that no
 	
 	
 		uh
 		would would you like to go on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> do you think
 	
 	
 		no i don't think so because
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because uh i like to fish
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i camp out and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		well they sure are a lot of fun they sure do a lot uh good eating
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you like to eat that's the place to go
 		that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> to go on i i it's the best eating in the world
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		oh i mean it's nonstop <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the minute</TIMEX> you get on the ship until you get off
 		you can start eating and you can eat <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> long if you want
 		fantastic
 		i'm going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">in the Fall</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm really looking forward to that i've always wanted to go and
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that's a uh flight attendant for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and her route is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so
 		she wants to go see <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
 		just because she just flies in and flies out so she  she knows <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> but she doesn't know the rest  so we're going to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wales</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
 		i think that'll be fun
 	
 	
 		is that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spring</ENAMEX> that this Summer
 	
 	
 		uh we're going in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Fall September October</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i think that'd be great
 		plus like i say i like i like cruises i'm going with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> i'm going on a cruise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summer</TIMEX>
 		uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about seven days</TIMEX> and uh i'd i haven't decided i've been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bahamas</ENAMEX> but i think i'd like to try the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cozumel</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto Vallarta</ENAMEX> and that that route around like that i believe this next time
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bahama</ENAMEX> one was nice and if that's one of the cruise we can get on i i'll take it again because it was really a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>'s real clear down there
 	
 	
 		oh just crystal absolutely crystal clear the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> are just beautiful and if you like snorkeling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh just you just can't beat it i i love to snorkel
 		and the the beaches are just snow white
 		absolutely snow white have you ever been to the west coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um no just to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well the west coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> all all those beaches are snow white like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the east coast you have to get down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> before they're any you know before they're snow white but the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">west coast</ENAMEX> is just beautiful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i go i moved here from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> back from i was living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and came back and uh
 		oh i'm going to retire down there one of these <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and it's going to be in on the west coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> because it's so gorgeous
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand sand</ENAMEX> is just out of this and it's just like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> powdered sugar
 		around uh
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice Beach</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Clearwater</ENAMEX> especially has beautiful beautiful snow white sand
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's really nice
 		but i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> so i don't care for the mountains too much
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> i'm a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Californian</ENAMEX> and they have mountains there my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lives up in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 		they're nice to visit and i didn't enjoy growing up in the mountains and
 		i'd rather go to the sun than i would to the to the mountains i mean they're all right
 		i don't like it because i have to go now see to see me mother i have to go to the the the mountains
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but if i didn't have to
 		if i didn't have to go i would never go
 	
 	
 		did you ever go to Yosemite
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		that's pretty isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah it is and i've been to uh of course i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> where it was really mountainous and beautiful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh when i go back and visit it i'm really disappointed it it it doesn't uh i remember it as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and it's nothing like what i remembered as a child it's so commercialized and i it really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		made me
 		got kind of turn my stomach when i went back and saw how commercialized it had gotten but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'm not a camper outer so i you know i if you like to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out so that's fine but i i don't want to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out
 		i like the luxuries too much  i guess i'm spoiled i am spoiled
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i spoil myself i guess so i
 	
 	
 		and then in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> it's mostly streams and they've dammed up some of them now so yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it just so you don't
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> just doesn't really show me anything anymore so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now my where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lives in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is absolutely gorgeous i mean just
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		picture postcard gorgeous and it it you know it just out of sight but uh it's too uh i've got to be by a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> i i can't stand living that far away i fly up into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> and drive down to her house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so she's really way up there and it it i just it's just too far away from a a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> for me i got to have a shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> and  what have you
 	
 	
 		and northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> really is out in the boondocks isn't it
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> she is in  it's it's a good <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve hour hour</NUMEX> drive just from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> on winding winding winding river roads
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's way on up past the wine <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and everything is like i say it's really gorgeous but
 	
 	
 		but
 		you fly in through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medford Oregon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> there uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah and then drive down it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an oh an hour hour and a half</TIMEX>'s drive from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medford Oregon</ENAMEX>
 		but it's all mountain driving
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and fortunately my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> picks me up i don't have to drive it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		tried driving it once from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> and that was a that was very dumb i'll never try that again
 	
 	
 		they have a they they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> there don't they or
 	
 	
 		well this uh where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> lives is uh it kind of in the middle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> up north so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're about uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two</NUMEX> drive from the ocean for the coast
 		so you could go up that way but it would be out it would be out of your way better from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">from</NUMEX> to go to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at like up through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redding</ENAMEX> and
 		on up that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		how far is it from Tahoe
 	
 	
 		oh gosh i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> i think <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> no
 		i can't remember i seem like it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> somebody somebody told me it may be
 		it may be twelve so i can't remember mine i know my son
 		went from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tahoe</ENAMEX> to over to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so and he knows that i i never have gone there so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		master the mountains too
 	
 	
 		yeah it really like i say it really is gorgeous
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i uh i like the sunshine better i mean i'd rather go out where there's beaches and
 		i don't i like to sun bathe and uh you know it's getting so dangerous now the sun bathe or the sun burns and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> skin <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> and everything so i load up you know on
 		the sunscreens and so i because the ocean to me is real soothing and comforting comforting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so that's why i like to to go there but and of course i don't like uh i like uh i like to snorkel so i have to go where there's real clear water to do that
 	
 	
 		yeah and around here the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Possum Kingdom</ENAMEX> is about the
 		the closest place
 	
 	
 		is it really uh
 	
 	
 		yeah they have real clear water and plants
 	
 	
 		oh i've never been now where is that near
 	
 	
 		it's uh near um
 		well it's it's kind of near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abilene</ENAMEX> but it's it's uh about halfway in between here and and Abilene
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		it's uh you if you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albany</ENAMEX> is then uh it's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about maybe an hour</NUMEX> west of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weatherford</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		out there west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a big it's on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brazos River</ENAMEX> they dammed up the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazos River</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and it's beautiful
 	
 	
 		is it
 		no i i guess i've never been up there my my
 		when i moved up here uh uh uh from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> i i misplaced my snorkeling i think they what they did they didn't unpack it it must have been in a box or something they didn't unpack because i ended up without my snorkeling equipment and and a few other things and they must have
 		been in a box that i had in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> and they just didn't get them to me so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm going to have to start from scratch i guess and buy all new snorkeling equipment
 		but i had some really good snorkeling equipment i really hate to start over again but there's no other choice choice but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		anyway have we talked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">our five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so
 	
 	
 		okay well it's been nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah nice talking to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh bye-bye</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	