
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		there we are
 	
 	
 		yes
 		tell me what are some of the things that you did with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> when they were growing up
 	
 	
 		oh well uh when they were little we did lots of reading and playing and going to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and things of that sort and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boy i</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> they were both interested in things like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model rockets</ENAMEX> so we would go to the football <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> and set off <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model rockets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> also
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are um are swimmers and so as they were growing up much of uh our um normal life outside of school and everything around and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolved</ENAMEX> around their swimming so in order to have a reason for being there especially as they got older i became involved in it too so we were always together at their meets
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh well that's good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">um mine</ENAMEX> were not terribly sporting uh they both did <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T-</ENAMEX>ball and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> in grade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but neither one of them carried on uh the sports after that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> tried those but they really they did go in they started swimming when they were oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and they really loved it and they're swimming both
 		they'll be one is in college also swims in college and the other will continue to swim in college and they're fortunate they may even made nationals
 	
 	
 		oh wonderful oh that's great
 	
 	
 		and so we would drive up to see that when we whenever it was reasonably close but we did a lot of things um and we tried to do things both together and individually with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah i
 	
 	
 		we live near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> so we we would always go in for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sure
 	
 	
 		that's always a big uh thing and one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is uh also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> so um one of the things that we did with him a lot was to go  either my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> or i or both of us would to concerts with him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> um uh is in big into tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> so our whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we take family trips to different places to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> or go to fish shows so
 	
 	
 		ah
 		my goodness uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well we didn't have any uh avid uh activities like that they they were interested in a lot of things but nothing to quite that depth i guess but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i don't think we've we've missed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> on the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">east northeast</ENAMEX> coast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we would
 		oh my goodness well we did go to things like aquariums and uh uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		natural history <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museums</ENAMEX> and zoos and all of those things that one does with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yes in fact it's funny our vacations have always been um uh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as as they've gotten older when they were younger we would go to the beach but as they got older we tried to pattern our vacations where we would travel and do things and that there would be a a feature each day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		ah yes
 	
 	
 		whether it would be going to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> we uh we went up to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> and we went to the marble quarries up there and uh uh to see that and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX> we fish <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hatchery</ENAMEX> and so we did
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know we did try and of course we learned too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but um and uh i don't know i uh when they were very young i did not work
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i started working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half</TIMEX> time when uh they were at the nursery school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and i i started working part-time when they were in um junior high school and high school and now and i worked in the school system and now i work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full school day</TIMEX> but that leaves me off on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">holidays</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summers</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i was still home yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it was a it was a you know i think they need me more when they were older than they do when they're
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think it uh they need you in different ways
 	
 	
 		that's true yes
 	
 	
 		you want to be around for the crisis and things like that and
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		but it's not quite so much the hand holding and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter</ENAMEX> and jelly making
 	
 	
 		um yeah that's that's for sure that's for sure what do you do you have any feelings as to the trends that you see
 	
 	
 		well it look well the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> trend i would say is that
 		with so many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> choosing professional careers there are fewer of them <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> and i don't think it needs to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> but i think it would be nice if some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> would be around for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few more hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah when they  you know it was funny i can remember and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and i have talked about it how important it was when i came home from school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it wasn't really conversation but there were always things that just tumbled out
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh a
 		granted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> doesn't always think that they're sharing it but it when they when it's not there they miss it
 	
 	
 		i think that's true but i don't i also think that's at least in my experience truer of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> even when i was there my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> didn't share all that much with me and certainly not to the extent i did with my mother
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah no i i i realize that but it's funny they don't always do it but occasionally they do and you want
 		and when they do there's a reason for it that they're sharing it and you want to be available at least i've wanted to be available when they for some reason they had they were bouncing something off of me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		because it was something that was bothering them or they were concerned about and it was uh you just felt gee if i weren't here
 	
 	
 		um-hum who would they ask or what would they do
 	
 	
 		how or or if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 		that's right
 		yes that's exactly right uh but it has been um it's been interesting and particularly i i think because the society in which we live <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are separated you don't have grandparents near by or aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i mean i grew up in a situation where on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> we were always visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i did too we were close to my uh maternal grandparents i mean just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a few miles</NUMEX> and uh close enough to visit my paternal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> know quite often they were fifty <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles</NUMEX> away but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		see and we're uh that we i i grew up with you know every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> there was some visiting somewhere um and it was sort of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> um but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we although we have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> in the area that we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		we see we they don't have it's not that constant
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		thing where you are on intimate terms with cousins
 	
 	
 		well when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were quite small uh we lived close to both sets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and they saw them a lot but they don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins uh</ENAMEX> or they didn't their uh their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> are about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> younger
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh they never played together or anything and there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> of them and they didn't live in the same town
 	
 	
 		yeah and i i just sort of think
 		yeah that the trend of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and time where where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are spending less time you don't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> too to take up the gap
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in some ways are are are suffering a little bit in that uh the model the role models that get the the the family issues that get discussed and all these i think are very important parts of them growing up so we
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we try to to do it as well as we can we keep in close contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandparents</ENAMEX> and talk over the phone and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and aunts and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> and we do but it's although it's not the same we are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's part of i think teachin g too is what a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is like because then how how do they pattern their own
 	
 	
 		well everyone makes it's own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> but uh it it seems that there should be some continuity and it's helpful to have uh things that
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		become family traditions and that sort of thing
 	
 	
 		that's yeah well we've always we have had this tradition um that we always go out before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and cut our own tree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's always been a little bit of a tradition that we've had now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> it's been was hard with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> now being in college so this was one thing that we um weren't able to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> but we did that for ever
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		from the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were young enough to realize what it was until uh our older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> went away to college
 	
 	
 		oh well that's the kind of thing that they will remember though
 	
 	
 		and we have advent calendars still from the time that they came you know to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		ours finally disintegrated we had a felt one that was like it was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> that had uh a little trinket for each day
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		that was pinned on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the date</TIMEX> and then you took it off and put it on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> so at the end you had a decorated tree
 	
 	
 		that's uh-huh
 		well
 		ours ours is uh a friend
 	
 	
 		and it finally got moth eaten we threw it way last year
 	
 	
 		uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand</ENAMEX> appliqued one for each child
 	
 	
 		how nice
 	
 	
 		and i mean they look <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as new as they did when they gave them to she gave them to us and there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> and you buy a present
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and you wrap the present up and i mean the presents have gone from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> when they were very young to a little box of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Band-Aid</ENAMEX> and an eraser and things
 	
 	
 		how cute
 	
 	
 		to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> where um sometimes i put a little gift if i see something that's uh occasionally a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX> decoration which they will save for their
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		their future to sometimes just money um pieces of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">candy</ENAMEX> so i think as they're getting in college i i just my for my older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that was in college i put a dollar bill for each day
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh i'm sure he appreciated that
 	
 	
 		which was the equivalent um well it was the equivalent of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> present
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it was uh and it was and you know it was fun but that's a tradition and they will those will be passed on to them when they
 		when they get married and leave
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well you were saying what other trends are there and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> just occurred to me because i was editing a book about it recently
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that is the trend in a lot of uh lower class areas for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmothers</ENAMEX> to be raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		and that's a lot of it is due to the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are on drugs
 	
 	
 		the broken yes and the broken <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> we um as i said living in an area of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we definitely see this uh and um it's that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> figure not only raising her own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but raising um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> too frequently
 	
 	
 		right well we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sociologist</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> where i work who was writing a book on uh multigeneration
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">matriarchies</ENAMEX> in a way uh where the tradition in the family has been for a teenaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to have a baby while she's still living at home with the mother
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes well this is a this is a sign uh this is in fact uh we've been studying this in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that um this is one of the symptoms or not the symptoms it's one of the ways that young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> feel that they are maturing it's a rite of passage
 	
 	
 		and
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it they uh the the fact that they're unmarried has nothing to do with
 		
 		
 	