
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yes i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum i don't any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so i'm gonna have difficulty with this topic but uh what kind of things do you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> do
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		um well we go out and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fly kites</ENAMEX> and we go fishing and we go to movies
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and we go out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> and and uh she likes to pick <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and look at birds
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hm</ENAMEX> then your kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is probably pretty rare now a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> i don't see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> fishing and doing things like that that's great
 	
 	
 		well
 		well i'm divorced but that's what when she's with me that's what we do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we color a lot and i read her stories and
 	
 	
 		um-hum that's great
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i think uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> now for they probably don't spend enough time together you know whether they're
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are together or divorced they don't spend enough time together and and i think that contributes to a lot of why society is going downhill right now is because the basic family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> is uh being destroyed
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		just simply because that time isn't spent just doing things like fishing and because that i think that when you spend a lot of time with each other you communicate a lot and the communication helps you build on your uh
 		helps just just build your family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah and even even when i was when i was uh living with her and we did stuff then too so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's pretty to me that's pretty rare
 	
 	
 		yeah i know
 	
 	
 		i think that whenever i do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i'll i'm gonna try as hard as i can
 		to see see that we spend a lot of time together you know maybe just even if we just rent a movie and watch it together just to make sure that everybody's not going out and doing and their own thing all the time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know that's good sometimes because you need to you know get away but uh i don't think you you should spend too much time outside at the detriment of of losing your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> unit
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 		because then you never get to know them either they're all grown up and their you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah and as i understand it i don't know i haven't experienced it but you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> these days are growing up so much faster
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know once they hit like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> or twelve you know you've pretty much lost them
 	
 	
 		yeah they're out doing stuff by that time
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah so
 		um
 		do you think that you do you think that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s pretty rare in that you do a lot of things or just the relationship between you and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i really do because because i don't see many other this and when whenever we go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> or something sometimes on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekdays</TIMEX> we'll see other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but not usually on the on the uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> we don't see very many in comparison
 	
 	
 		what do you think is the key to just bringing the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> back together what what kinds of things do you think can
 	
 	
 		well i think they ought to turn off the TV for one thing
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that's
 	
 	
 		and and go out and do stuff you know because she always likes to do things whenever the TV's off you know she'll forget about the TV completely
 	
 	
 		hm
 		right
 		i think that's the first thing a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do and i know i'm guilty of it like i came in from work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> first thing i did was turn the TV on because i taped the stories from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i like to watch them but i think that's that is a big problem television it's it's it's too static you know it's something that you can do but you there's no thinking involved no motion
 		you know and i think i think that's another reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
 		uh so health conscious now is because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s becoming really a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch</ENAMEX> potato society
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> aren't doing anything just sitting around you know no thinking involved and now i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are trying to get out of that at least and that um you know there's a lot of
 		um it's it's becoming really health conscious
 		and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are you know starting to look out for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> and things like that trying to get out and workout more often and jog and walk and different things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's probably good you know if you get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> involved in exercising and maybe playing <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX> or something like that that also helps that's also something you know family oriented that everyone can do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		yeah but when was uh when she was here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> we played tennis but  she hasn't brought her tennis racket over lately
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we
 	
 	
 		how how old is she
 	
 	
 		she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		um well she has
 	
 	
 		we we just been hitting the ball on the ground
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		she can't hit it in the air yet and then we kick the ball we play like soccer
 	
 	
 		we'll you still have a lot of time before she gets
 		up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>  that's good that's good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		hm
 		okay well it was very nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	