
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um i think that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and age everyone needs to have some sort of exposure to community service
 		because it it seems like and i'm i'm thinking of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in jail now i think that maybe if if
 		if some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had gotten exposed to the community gotten exposed to working with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that some of the things that they did they would not have done because they would they understand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more they understand helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more they understand the plight of people
 	
 	
 		that's true um-hum i agree with you in the sense that uh i think that it's important for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to uh also share give something of themselves
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh i think that there's too much
 		in the in uh a way of like self-gratification today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's not enough sharing
 	
 	
 		um-hum i would think that for like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are just filthy filthy rich
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that they would benefit also in doing community service so that they
 		can see and i'm i'm speaking about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are like born rich
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and that's all they know and i'm thinking that community service would help them uh just get a feel of what else is out there how other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are living you know if they were to work in in uh uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know in a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> or something they would understand how other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh you know on the same note if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> if
 		poorer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  uh were working to to serve the community
 		i don't know they probably have a better perspective of of i don't know just life itself
 	
 	
 		yeah and i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> is great too because uh it you go to different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and you see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you know in fact i saw an interview on TV <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Swayze</ENAMEX> and he's making a movie in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think it's uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calcutta</ENAMEX> or either <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> somewhere where it's a it's a very poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poor</ENAMEX> country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the West
 		he said since being there and i guess he's been there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six months</TIMEX> he said that his whole idea of what's important has changed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		and he said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have no idea he said of of what human sacrifice is you know since being there he's he's learned to what it is to be poor and have nothing and yet those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have
 		uh such uh a happy
 	
 	
 		um-hum demeanor yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		uh yeah in in other words they don't dwell on on what they don't have they dwell on what they do have and they're happy with each other type of thing
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		and he said that out here he said that when he comes back he knows that it it's just completely changed his life
 	
 	
 		um-hum and i i think that that you know this on the same note
 		being he was exposed to that and maybe he wasn't before and now he sees and i think that anybody that works
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		in the in some kind of service or for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> or something they can see you know you don't see what you don't you can't know what you don't see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		exactly right
 	
 	
 		you know so and you have to experience some things you know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are poor
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you they don't know what poor is
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		unless they actually see it and you know help or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i i know that it that must be true especially if you do something along the lines of uh you know helping them learn how to survive how to plant how to find water and i've seen so many uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		extraordinary things on TV that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have done
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		working in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> and how you know uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> they worked in is so much better
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can make a difference
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i i really believe that they can in something like that
 	
 	
 		there's something i i've really been skeptical of you know when you watch television you'll see the service announcement for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in other countries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if you want to send like you know fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">cents</NUMEX> a day
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		or something like that and you can help a child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's
 		i don't know i guess it's just me but i don't know whether to trust that or not
 		i mean there are so many scams and things going on you know i would love to help somebody
 	
 	
 		i know
 		and how do you
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but i just i can't bring myself to
 		trust
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		this this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> who's trying to do this or whatever it is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know just because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are so i don't know just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just so money hungry that i think they would do anything
 	
 	
 		i know
 		it's true it really is it's the sad life i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's um
 	
 	
 		and so i mean you don't know what they
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it it's not like it used to be even in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> of my growing up i mean i'm fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years old</TIMEX> and i have seen a town change from a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to a city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know grow from a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> to a large town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you would think that more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be better you know share more do more you know be more community oriented and all but if they just get more uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		unto themselves kind of
 	
 	
 		yeah more self-centered um
 	
 	
 		right and and it's not the sharing of uh a neighbor to a neighbor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and  we would go out and not even lock our doors
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and not even worry about it
 	
 	
 		but you can't do that today
 	
 	
 		but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i mean you know it's like you wouldn't even think of doing that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if you don't have bars on the window you're not even safe you know
 	
 	
 		yeah even when when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> it seemed like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> was so open you know everybody left their doors open you just run in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> you leave your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> running
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and this was only uh well i guess it has been awhile it's been almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> since i moved here and it's amazing now now how much it's changed i mean i don't go out i don't go outsid e at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> they
 		i was going to say because i i heard uh in fact i was talking to someone from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> they was saying that uh in fact it was this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> particularly that worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and she had gone over seas to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she asked them there if there was some anywhere that she shouldn't go because she was alone you know being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> from another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and she said they thought for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few seconds</TIMEX> and they said uh no there's nowhere that you can go that you would have to be afraid
 		they said to her that even if she left her purse
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		on the subway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay that she would have that purse returned to her
 		this is how confident they were okay with nothing missing
 	
 	
 		wow
 		wow
 	
 	
 		okay this is a foreign country
 	
 	
 		better
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you would think you know uh being uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> or whatever you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigner</ENAMEX> there that that would be all the more reason that they'd take advantage of you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		oh
 		God that would be the exact opposite here i mean if you leave something anywhere you might as well forget it
 	
 	
 		okay
 		and she told me she said she could tell them for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">fifteen minutes</TIMEX> places not to go in in and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's where she was from
 	
 	
 		um-hum that is sad
 	
 	
 		she said even choosing her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> she had to be so careful because of being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> alone
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that that's a big that's a big thing with me i live in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> i'm single
 	
 	
 		you know she had there are certain
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i've i could live in an apartment i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waco</ENAMEX> okay and you either live in really low priced housing or you live on the other side of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in the high price apartments
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i live i don't make a lot of money but i live in the high price <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> simply because i feel safe here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i pay i'm paying probably the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollars more
 		than i would be paying somewhere else but i wouldn't be able to sleep at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and that to me is worth the extra money for me to be you know i feel very safe where i am
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know instead of
 	
 	
 		and that that's why i think if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were more exposed to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh especially uh young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> getting out of high school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time they would go into the service to have the same exposure and you know uh to further their worldliness so to speak
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and go to see uh foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that they would not necessarily be able to afford to see it was like they said join the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> to see the world type of thing you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but nowadays they don't do that anymore it's not uh a thing uh a lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> don't even uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have the desire to go into the service
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't even consider it
 	
 	
 		or to uh you know do something for someone else
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah and it
 	
 	
 		and i don't know i i attributed i think a lot of that to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> working
 	
 	
 		to
 	
 	
 		you know to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> not being at home
 	
 	
 		yes yes i was talking to someone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> about that and we were saying that the basic uh the the basic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is is disrupted these days
 	
 	
 		the bonding process yep
 		it very definitely is
 	
 	
 		and so i think you know before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> would work and the mother you know would stay home and having that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> there that base i think was a big part of of family big part of
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		of what you know your your uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> thought about what they did you know
 	
 	
 		yep
 		and the thing is like i think a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> can afford to support a woman
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> affords the luxuries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in in other words like anyone can live on a certain income no matter what it is you have to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		so to speak okay it it's what's important to you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now a family i i think that like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six weeks later</TIMEX> they're back to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		they don't even have a bonding with that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> they don't ever ever see the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's the most beautiful thing that happens between a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and a child the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> like say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> of life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so much happens in that period of time
 	
 	
 		when i called
 	
 	
 		and i mean once the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> if you had a job from say <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine to three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		big deal i mean they're they're in school you're at work that's great but it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that come home and don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> there or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are at home in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and the
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		
 		
 	