
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you have any special menus that you like to use when you're entertaining
 	
 	
 		well i don't entertain that much anymore unfortunately but uh
 	
 	
 		yes but we dream
 	
 	
 		if hum
 	
 	
 		we dream though
 	
 	
 		oh yes well i mean you know like for holidays the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> gets together so uh i guess you'd call that about the same i mean i don't have dinner <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> but uh uh i have family get-togethers
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i i guess it's about the same thing so uh
 	
 	
 		are you a traditional cook
 	
 	
 		well no no i in fact i love to find different things uh i'm always searching for recipes that are different uh some things are traditional
 		okay uh we always have <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> but uh uh there but i always try to add <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> new dish
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i find it uh
 		interesting to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		vary it
 	
 	
 		i do to
 	
 	
 		so that uh uh
 		but uh uh well i you know it you can do a lot of things the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> is is pretty standard usually i mean you pick a different kind of you pick whatever kind of meat you're going to have and um
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		you uh can do a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a few things with it you know but uh but i mean as far as salads or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX> there are so many things that you can do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> that uh
 	
 	
 		then you can
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		it makes it quite a challenge and it depends on whose coming too
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh for a holiday family get-together i don't
 		make any you know i'm not real picky about exactly what it is but if we're just getting together uh you know for a family uh dinner then i try to keep it as uh fat free and as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX> free and you know all that other stuff as i can
 	
 	
 		yeah i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son-in-law</ENAMEX> who is a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> reads cookbooks and he cooks but uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> i have uh
 		had something different for him every holiday
 		uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX> whichever one they're with us and uh i think the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>  that have been the biggest hits
 		uh i think one of them came out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> cookbook
 		you're familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> her all of her culinary delights and it was it wasn't all that you know yummy and it it wasn't a lot to eat but it was interesting caramelized caramelized onions
 	
 	
 		right oh yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh interesting
 	
 	
 		and uh you cut them in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> and turn them over with the cut you know don't peel them or anything and turn them over with the cut side down and you bake them like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours and a half</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two seventy five</TIMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then when you know until they're kind of well not really burned they call them caramelized and then
 		you uh you mix up this little uh mixture of cranberries and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sugar</ENAMEX> and a few nuts and
 		uh a little bit of liquid and then you bake that for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about thirty minutes</TIMEX> and then you it's just a really pretty condiment really actually
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so then you just eat the insides you know the few layers of onions that didn't get hard or anything and then uh then that filling but that was interesting and another interesting one that he liked so well was
 		turnips i've always had a neighbor or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that had wanted to bring me turnips well who not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like turnips
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i did
 		a casserole using <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> turnips half <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Swiss cheese milk</ENAMEX> and butter
 		and just baked them and it is absolutely wonderful
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		if and the secret is using half <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i could see that would be then it wouldn't be such a an overpowering flavor you know it would be uh just just a flavor but not you know the real strong that's the only thing turnips have such a strong
 		flavor to them now i love them raw but
 	
 	
 		and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss</ENAMEX>
 		oh i do too oh especially so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like them to dip in vegetable dip too i think
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 		now you know speaking of vegetable dip i was introduced to uh to to something by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> of mine recently that i never would have dreamed of because of you know usually when you think of a vegetable
 		uh tray you think of uh uh broccoli or cauliflower and and celery and the the you know standard things have you ever tried using raw sweet potato
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no well i'm glad to hear about that
 	
 	
 		try try it i was she she i picked it up i thought it was carrot at first you know we were she just had a veggie tray and i picked it up and tasted i said gee this doesn't taste like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carrot</ENAMEX> she said it isn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i took another one just to see if i could figure out what it was and i couldn't and she told me it was raw sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX> and um it is it i do i do not like sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> cooked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do not like them at all uh i really do enjoy them raw  it with this it's it's not a real uh strong flavor it's just kind of light flavor
 	
 	
 		well i'll be darned and you've eaten them
 		do you know when i was growing up
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> wouldn't let us eat raw sweet <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> she said they were poison
 	
 	
 		hum
 		oh  my goodness
 	
 	
 		so so we just you know raw <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> yes if she was peeling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potato</ENAMEX> and we were you know she'd we'd want a piece and uh but she wouldn't never let us so i suppose that is a myth isn't it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		
 
 		oh yes uh um i hope so because of i've sure eaten a lot of it since i was first introduced to it uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 		you're still alive and kicking
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are quite surprised to find out it's just not one of the things that you would think of of putting on the vegetable tray uh
 	
 	
 		no and it is colorful too
 	
 	
 		it is colorful adds a lot of color to your tray
 	
 	
 		well i have spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last twenty years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 		and so i've had a wonderful time with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> type dishes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Santa Fe</ENAMEX> influence as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tex-Mex</ENAMEX> and i have so many wonderful recipes and
 	
 	
 		oh i love that
 		uh-hum
 		uh
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> here i we're originally from this part of country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if i do any of those casseroles especially they will say um this is sort of spicy
 	
 	
 		yes i know it's funny but see i'm originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and uh the first
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> mailed us care packages of chili peppers and uh things that you couldn't condiments that you couldn't get for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> cooking here <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> cooking you know that uh uh and now of course i can get them all here
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> too because it's become popular out here too and they have several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> but when we first moved here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX> we c ouldn't find any kind of you know
 	
 	
 		finally the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bell</ENAMEX> started springing up
 	
 	
 		except for
 		yes uh well we have several uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		very well uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi Chi</ENAMEX> is uh very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> that uh serve uh uh real good you know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food but but i know uh i have visited my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> once or twice and um it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's always refreshing because it's so she always fixes something different that i've you know not
 		had so uh i need to try a few more recipes and  but you're right anybody that tastes it even the mild they are so surprised that it's uh that spicy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 		yeah they really don't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> really don't like it very well
 	
 	
 		hum-um not if it's spicy  now you have to either go completely you know and let them add the uh like the salsa or the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> to it um or um
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well it
 	
 	
 		well it depends on what you're making if you're making enchiladas it's hard to do that but uh it's well it's hard to let them add their own you know just to make it spicy you can even the enchilada <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> is a little bit spicy
 	
 	
 		really
 		um-hum well it's been fun talking to you
 	
 	
 		well it's nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		and uh good luck in your uh entertaining or cooking or get-togethers or whatever and dream on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh yes uh well you too  you too thank you um-hum bye bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	