
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you know it's uh i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> so i use computer quite a bit uh i'm not sure why they call them sometimes call them personal computers uh
 	
 	
 		i guess they mean just one that's in your home
 	
 	
 		yeah right well yeah actual i think they mean one that's that is uh
 		designed or designated dedicated for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to use primarily as opposed to uh large mainframe computer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		which you know several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> maybe use uh terminals tied to it
 		i guess that's that's my definition anyway
 	
 	
 		okay i guess that's like the ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right um i have an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> it's uh one they call the XT
 		which is one of the earlier models
 		Prior to that i had uh one that was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Heath Kit</ENAMEX> computer which is one that i
 		basically built myself
 	
 	
 		oh in your home
 	
 	
 		uh yeah and uh so i've had uh i've had a computer for uh oh about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> i guess now
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		how do you know about building you own computer
 	
 	
 		well you uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Heath Kit</ENAMEX> which is uh you know one of these uh electronic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> it's a hobby store place
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you can go there and buy a kit or at least you use to be able to i'm not sure that you can still buy those from them now
 		but you could buy a kit and build a computer it like have a would have a manual step-by-step manual
 		to go through and put all the parts together
 	
 	
 		was that a little less expensive
 	
 	
 		uh yeah it uh it then it was and of course the computer are so cheap now i'm not even sure how it would how it would compare uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		back then the computer that i built was uh one you know was a old pretty low level technology wise
 		and uh it cost me oh fifteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> i guess to build it
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and it would have cost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen hundred or so</NUMEX> to buy i think so it was you know it was not a great saving but it was a learning experience any way
 	
 	
 		oh seems like it would be more fun any way my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> gets a kick out of building stuff for his self rather than buying it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah if uh if he's if he's aware of building you know building electronic stuff he's he knows about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heath Kit</ENAMEX> probably
 	
 	
 		no he's not into electronics i'm just saying per se he just likes to build stuff but uh
 	
 	
 		not into electronic
 		right
 		but uh you know i had to had to learn a little bit about uh using a solder iron and and that kind of stuff
 		well i i say uh i said basically i built it myself when i got to a certain point i took it to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> that uh was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he uh you know he worked with help me finished putting it together you know and make it work right it uh
 		so you know if you don't know much electronics you can you know you have to have somebody with a little electronic background to make it work but uh you know the basic stuff i i did all the basics any way
 	
 	
 		somebody to help
 		do you use your computer for home uh
 	
 	
 		no well i use <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> at work i don't i don't even have one at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> any more it's uh i've got it in my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and uh matter fact i'm market for another one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		is that for your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or for your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> oh okay
 	
 	
 		no for my home you know so i mean for my for my office
 		so i'm i'm not sure eventually i'll have to i'll probably have one at home too but uh
 	
 	
 		well couldn't you like um i'm pretty sure you can do this have it
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that has the same stuff in it as your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> does or have it kind of connect it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh
 		well you can have them connected by a by a modem if you want to which is a telephone line
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but but you can can have the same software you know the same programs
 	
 	
 		just contains a
 	
 	
 		so that you take your data files from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to the other so that you can use same computer you know for the for the
 	
 	
 		okay
 		right
 	
 	
 		a a different computers for the same project
 	
 	
 		right
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so you know it's and that's that's one thing that i would like to have uh occasionally i need to work at home you know and now i don't have a computer there so
 	
 	
 		you could just bring your disk home and do it
 	
 	
 		you know that's i could if i you know if i if i had a computer there so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that was my problem in school i could not write programs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i loved messing with the computer though but i just could not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to a certain point i'd just get messed up and i would be totally lost
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 		but uh
 		you know it's uh you know the computer it's uh the you know growing thing in uh you know both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and business i i think eventually
 	
 	
 		yeah i want i'm wanting to go back to school and this time i'll try a lot harder
 	
 	
 		yeah that's but eventually  i think uh most <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> will have a computer you know for some reason uh either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well a lot of them more or less close the computers the uh
 		microwaves all have these new little buttons and
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		just about every thing is getting computerized
 	
 	
 		yeah new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> have computer in them and
 	
 	
 		yeah have you seen that uh
 		thing that shows the maps
 	
 	
 		uh no i haven't seen that but i have heard about it but i haven't seen it
 	
 	
 		i think that's neat
 	
 	
 		yeah but uh
 		i don't know i guess the uh the personal computer is it's really uh going to be a necessity that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should learn to use it i was just commenting i teach uh a couple accounting classes
 		and uh i was just commenting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> that it's uh
 		going to reach the point where um accounting classing in college have to have computer for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to use you know in every class uh right now i teach over at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brookhaven College</ENAMEX>
 		and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> that i happen to teach that that teaches the accounting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> anything about using the computer
 		if they want to use want to learn the computer they have to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> outside of the accounting area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay now a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine is trying is going for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPA</ENAMEX> and she is having to take
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or she maybe maybe it's just a preference that she's taking it on herself but she is taking a computer class
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh but yeah it's that's something that's going to be uh a necessity for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountants</ENAMEX> because you you know it's you can do so much for more work with a computer then you can do you know doing it manually
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and a lot more accurately also
 		i use the computer to do you know all of my accounting work and of course i write letters on the computer and i do income tax on the computer  so it's i use it a lot
 	
 	
 		i do our income taxes too and you're right it probably would be a lot easier if i the use a computer
 	
 	
 		yeah you know it's just it would be
 		if you have a computer you can buy you know some little cheap software that uh that uh you can buy like at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Software House</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> at uh over in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you can go over there and buy an income tax package that will run on a personal computer
 		and do your income tax and it's one of those where you can change things y <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ou</ENAMEX> know to see what happens you know you say well let's see i've got some many uh so much of my charitable contributions on my itemized deductions
 		and then you discover that you had more then you thought you did you can go in and change it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it changes everything on the return and you don't have to go back and you know change every line with you know the eraser or the
 	
 	
 		and redo everything
 	
 	
 		the uh liquid paper or whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so it's it's really convenient to have that plus you know you've got it on the computer and it does all the calculations and the math and
 		you know makes for a lot of your errors on the return
 	
 	
 		yeah well  so far i've had been able to use the easy form
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right but uh
 	
 	
 		so now i'm wanting for
 		my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s birthday is coming up and i was thinking about getting him just one of those little
 		i know i they've got toy computers more or less just for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who just starting and he'll be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i've seen it on uh like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty</TIMEX> and stuff whatever where they do have little
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> and stuff working on
 	
 	
 		yeah they uh start are starting real early on the computers when he gets to school he will probably be using a computer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know yeah <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade probably and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he'll he'll know more about computer then you will and you'll be having to go back to school just too keep up with him
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		probably but i think that's the way it goes with most parents
 	
 	
 		yeah that seems to have to learn have to learn a little bit as they go along you you suddenly discover that your educated when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		a lot
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		go ahead
 	
 	
 		well it's been a it's been interesting taking uh about computers it's uh that's one of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> and uh i really i get into talking about them so
 	
 	
 		don't know much about them
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		the main thing
 		i didn't i don't even remember them having computers on uh that little sheet
 	
 	
 		um yeah yeah i don't remember i i've checked off a bunch of stuff you know on there i don't remember what all was on there but i've talked about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> things that i wasn't you know wasn't expecting to talk about so
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		uh-huh well it's been pretty interesting so far
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah so it's been been nice talking to you and uh i guess uh maybe they'll ring us up again sometime
 	
 	
 		yes
 		all righty all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> thanks bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	