
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay obviously the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that i support would be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i say that i support them there's been just so much that's happened to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> since they got rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Landry</ENAMEX> that was just like you know blasphemy around here
 	
 	
 		well and uh we felt the same way he was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> and how how could they do that
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		i know i know i don't think i'll ever forget when one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> called me and said you're not going to believe this because i had not heard it you know and they said they have fired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Landry</ENAMEX> it's like  you know what slander how could they do such a thing
 		so uh ever you know since that i used to be such a an avid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> you know it was ridiculous but now quite honestly i i think that i support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oilers</ENAMEX> as much as anybody
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know just because it is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but i cannot stand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Jones</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		can't stand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> well uh you know i was just trying i was just trying to think of uh who who our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Oilers</ENAMEX> you probably know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah i really i don't even i don't know now
 	
 	
 		uh it'll probably come to me but i was thinking of
 	
 	
 		yeah i just i think of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bum Bright</ENAMEX> you know but that's been many many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		the
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bum Bum Phillips</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bum Phillips</ENAMEX> i'm sorry yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah well he's the one that we couldn't believe that they they let go and then we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Glanville</ENAMEX> who is guess is now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> and now we get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head coach</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> it'll come to me in a minute
 	
 	
 		yeah i can't i can't think
 	
 	
 		so we did pretty well uh
 	
 	
 		yeah how did you feel about having about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Glanville</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> either hate him or they they like him quite a bit
 	
 	
 		well i didn't really hate him or anything but i think the image of the team as a whole just had a real dark image and he he wanted to make these you know the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh kind of like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland Raiders</ENAMEX> used to be the real bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and they were they were mean and we had so many penalties and it gets really you just really get ticked off
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh uh-huh
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		when your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> keeps getting these stupid penalties and they don't seem to you know i mean that's just terrible and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah it's it's you know it aggravates me no end when you're talking about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really close</TIMEX> game and then they do something stupid like start a fight or you know they have they have something like that called and then that is aggravating yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> or do something where where you know it puts the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in a better advantage and you know just for some stupid things that we probably could have done better so
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i feel like the image of the on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oilers</ENAMEX> has really been cleaned up and like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Warren Moon</ENAMEX> and and so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are doing some good things off the field
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		so it seems like though uh it seems like all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> always you know that i that are local to me wherever i live from when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was in college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know you just never on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a given day</TIMEX> they could do anything and then on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day</TIMEX> but they the consistency just when it really gets down to the championship or or the really mean meaningful uh game
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		uh-huh yeah it seems like they blow it
 	
 	
 		they don't come through
 		course now <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> did great for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you know it was just like you were so spoiled it was such a novelty if they lost a game you know and they could lose <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> game out of you know the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would just be completely up in arms
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i really you know as far as future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> i really hate to say it but i think they're going to end up being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX> within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next couple of years</TIMEX> i really feel like that will
 	
 	
 		
 
 		think so well they've been down for a while so it kind of runs in cycles i think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah and
 	
 	
 		so you have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that stay up on top for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> and then they start
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right i think and it's a sad thing to say but i think it really depends on how much money it you know money it always comes back to money everything does
 		but if uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Jones</ENAMEX> continues to pay these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> what you know they say they're paying them i don't know you know i think it depends on you end up you know the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> will come there if they're going to be paid the most so
 		uh you know i don't know it's interesting we'll just have to see but it's just very very difficult for me to to support them it's
 		you know a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i really like you know and and uh i loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herschel Walker</ENAMEX> that just blew me away when they traded him
 		you talking you were talking about somebody that was really involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and did a lot of things for for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and stuff like that he was extremely involved in that in that aspect
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that's why i i liked him so well but uh i don't know you know when i i watch it and then i start sort of seeing myself enjoying it i'm like you're just you're just doing this for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> you know don't think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Jones</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX> either one but
 		you know it'd just be so aggravating when they did win and then uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Jones</ENAMEX> would come out of the uh you know the press box i mean i would just go uh you know wild it's like it ruined the whole game for me because i had to look at him you know
 	
 	
 		is he the owner
 	
 	
 		yeah he's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> uh-huh and he and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX> went to uh college together they played football together in college
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and so they're like this is just like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> system you know and they're of course they're not from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so that riled everybody up you know  this is like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so uh that didn't go over well so we'll see as i said i really think that they'll eventually
 		they'll eventually be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contender</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		well this should be uh we did pretty well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> so i'm thinking this ought to this ought to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good year</TIMEX> for us well have have you been involved at all in this new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Football League</ENAMEX> i haven't watched the first thing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah it's
 		no i haven't uh you know i find myself it's just it seems like it's so hard to uh i don't know why it is but it's just so hard for me to get involved in it you know i love football
 	
 	
 		well it
 		well yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know i feel like i'm not watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> for some reason it's like oh it really doesn't count you know and that's terrible but that's just sort of the way i feel about it
 	
 	
 		doesn't count but
 		well i tend to tend to uh well when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was still at home uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		course he watched everything sports and i was involved but i tend not to watch things so much now unless
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh if it's my home team
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or you know basically that's it or it's or it's some championship type games or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah i mean you you see you can definitely get involved in it more when it's somebody that you've supported all along and it's someone local because you've got all the press you know
 		you read more about them of course and and hear more about them on on television a nd and such but
 		uh i you know as much as i love it i would think that i would sit down and watch it but it just as i said for some reason it's like oh they you know they're just out there playing around they don't uh
 		they don't really they don't really count
 	
 	
 		who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> i don't even know who that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh my mind went blank i can picture his face
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my word
 	
 	
 		has he been there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple three years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah he's uh he's been here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> oh pooh
 		oh well it'll come to me as soon as we hang up i can't i cannot think of his name he's been injured they've done he's had several surgeries he's a young like a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i mean you know he's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know if he's even <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> yet i don't think but uh he uh he's had as i said several surgeries on his hand and and uh he's making a fortune of course he didn't play that much
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX> he was out for maybe you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> games so
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Moon</ENAMEX> broke his i think his was it his little finger or his thumb i forget toward the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of</TIMEX> games of the season so he was out for the you know the last part so
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah uh-huh
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		course he's not real young either he's
 	
 	
 		that's true he is he's considered an old timer i suppose
 	
 	
 		in his
 		he's probably in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early thirties</TIMEX> i would think at least uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know if we don't do something with him at the helm you know then it may be downhill then for us for a while
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah yeah you know it takes a it takes a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in that position
 	
 	
 		because we had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> the i forget the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s name the one who came in for him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and played in one game you know we made some play-offs or something toward the end it seems like and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> came in and we won i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> played beautifully and then then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next week</TIMEX> which was a really important game
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it didn't he it just fell apart didn't work but it but you talk about exciting when something you know we were just
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		oh yeah
 		just so thrilled it's true
 	
 	
 		right right when the seem like right before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Christmas holidays</TIMEX> or somewhere seem like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> was there from uh they're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alabama</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> has never watched
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> hardly in her life and she sat there with me and i was explaining some of it to her and she was getting really excited and that was so neat yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really getting into it uh-huh yeah yeah it's it's it's addictive i mean i come from a my i have several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> is just a freak about it you know she she's just as bad as anybody and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> if it's involved with ball he will watch it you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so i was i was raised with all that stuff so you know it's just like all of our holidays center on what time is the game start you know we have to hurry up and get all this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> out of the way because
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		that's kind of kind of the way way we've been too but it's it is fun i really enjoy it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah
 		yeah you know i would like to i i say i have i didn't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> to win but sure i'd like to seem them you know end up end up doing better it's just you know you you really miss it when you aren't so intense
 		you know as as we were when they were such a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah you kind of i don't know you know when they're not doing well or they consistently do poorly just kind of kind of lose interest if you don't which is a shame but that's uh way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah you know it's like why uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it's like why am i even watching this you know i it was seems like it was the height of the of the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> so to speak when uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Campbell</ENAMEX> was playing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oilers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> freak too i mean i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> so i followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Campbell</ENAMEX> over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oilers</ENAMEX> and and uh you know i kept up with that as well and and i was i was just crazy about him so i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	