
 
     		
 	
 		so i personally uh do consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> a threat i i i think that although there's been some fundamental changes and that there's uh uh the uh
 		the mood for change that there's a lot of change left to happen and that there's still uh communism which is fundamentally opposed to democracy and there's still missiles
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah well i mean that's that's certainly true i guess i'm i'm confused uh by what it means to be a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and so i'm not sure i even recognize the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> as anything to be threatened um
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		the uh i guess the main issue is is that it it seems to me that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> is breaking up into it's own internal problems
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and it would certainly be nice if the various um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX> seceded
 		on the other hand i also think it would be very nice if the various states in our union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seceded</ENAMEX> uh but that's beside the point uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it's much less than clear to me that as a military power um there's going to be anything left uh given that anything like that happens
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh they've got enough problems keeping their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> happy to worry about you know nuking other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who aren't bothering them
 	
 	
 		right well i guess that that that brings up a question is it their i think in in the long term we could see a a situation where there are in  incredible civil wars
 		and that the the structure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> breaks down and there's strife and much much death
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but until that happens between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between now</TIMEX> and then there's a lot of other uh events that could happen including a resurgence of communism with uh violent uh backlash against democracy
 		which which is where we could be in threatened i guess you'd say
 	
 	
 		i guess i'm communist why is why is communism antiethical to democracy i can understand why it's antiethical to capitalism
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry you you're right i'm am meaning to say capitalism
 	
 	
 		okay
 		uh all right but we've already got a lot of anticapitalism in this country
 	
 	
 		yes that's true uh-huh
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		but not necessarily enough from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s point of view
 	
 	
 		that could be that could be
 	
 	
 		i yeah
 	
 	
 		uh but certainly the latest rumors in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> right now is let's soak the rich some more so we can spread out the money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's certainly communism as far as i can tell
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so um you know they might be perfectly happy to sit back and wait for it to happen
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		um
 		and they so so i guess since the primary question is whether or not it's a military problem that's less than clear to me i mean if they're smart they're just going to let us head toward communism on our own very merry way
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and there seems to be enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> who are happy to do that sort of thing because they think they'd get more out of it that way
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		um
 		so from that point of view i don't consider them a threat
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		i don't think they're going to you know somehow import communism to us
 	
 	
 		i i agree with that i don't believe that will happen
 		the um well one thing that's current of interest is is if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>'s structure does break down and there is civil war at the end of those civil wars or during those civil wars in whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hands</ENAMEX> will those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and there are a lot of them uh scattered throughout the many many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">republics</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's true that's that can be a frightening thought
 	
 	
 		right almost a terroristic thought
 	
 	
 		um
 		yep yep
 	
 	
 		you know come help us or we'll bomb you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um
 		of course that's not a good way to win <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> but yeah i mean i i think there's also the whole <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world issue uh with him
 	
 	
 		that's
 	
 	
 		with uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> having um supported uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh previously and and so there there's a whole lot of political possibilities um
 		but you know just just to put this in perspective i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> was recently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 		and so for a moment <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> might have been  uh having his finger on the trigger and God knows what that would have done uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 		i know it's almost amazing how little you hear about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Quayle</ENAMEX> and when you do it's usually totally
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's a joke
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah he still wants to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame lame lame lame</ENAMEX> to say the least
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh well so that's uh what what's going to be real interesting is if when they have the next presidential elections
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is going to run with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or if he's going to run with someone else which i think would be uh i wonder if that's if there's precedent for that where uh there's uh same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> but a different vice president
 	
 	
 		uh i think so i can't think off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hand</ENAMEX> who
 	
 	
 		is it
 		but without something like death or impeachment
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i i can't recall
 	
 	
 		i mean i just can't imagine voting for anybody that has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quayle</ENAMEX> on their ticket
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right i guess in the last elections it was it was the lesser of several evils but from the
 	
 	
 		right and also he was basically unknown so i mean you're just like okay so it's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and somebody else
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right
 		yeah
 		oh well so let's see back to the that key issue uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the other part of the question was what would uh what would have to happen to convince me
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and i'd say seems to me uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> are the threat
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so what would have to happen is a complete disarmament
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and uh that's i you know i'd love to see that happen but i doubt it's going to happen in the next fifty years
 	
 	
 		you don't think so
 	
 	
 		i don't no
 		personally i i i really as i said i would really love to see it happen but i just
 	
 	
 		i just i can't see them maintaining the missile bases in fact i think if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> starts retreating you know because of these civil wars and stuff the first thing they're going to do is close down the mi ssile <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">republics</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh under the fear
 	
 	
 		because they're not going to want them to fall into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>'s hands
 	
 	
 		i see under the fear that that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow Moscow</ENAMEX> gets bombed first that's a good point that's a very good point in fact
 	
 	
 		might be used against them that's right
 		and so i think just from that there's going to be some limited amounts of disarmament they'll still be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> the ones that are under the firmer control of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh but certainly you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuania</ENAMEX> and stuff i think would lose the irs
 	
 	
 		yes i see that's a good great point
 		okay well so
 	
 	
 		so it was good talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah it was nice talking to you too <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">good day</TIMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okeydoke bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	