
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 		so do you enjoy camping
 	
 	
 		i used to love camping but since we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> our camping styles have changed dramatically
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		we've tried to go camping with them and the last time it wound up with  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> the only one that couldn't stand them left in the tent
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> wouldn't calm down they wouldn't go to sleep they were crawling all over us they thought it was just party <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">time all night</TIMEX> long you know
 	
 	
 		yeah we really haven't tried camping with with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> yet we we'd like to now she's getting a little bit older she'd enjoy it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i used to i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> all through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and everything else so i was involved in a lot of camping you know when i was younger but
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> so you're an old hand at it
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		even my desires for camping have changed uh used to be from roughing it and sleeping outside to now to to tents and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motor homes</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i like cabins they're real nice also i've found that when we've gone camping we've had some bad experiences sometimes when you even have seem to have uh
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		you know tent sites that are a little bit off the beaten path but there's a cluster of them and we wound up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like you know <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four feet</NUMEX> away from us that are just bombed out of their minds or something <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> long partying and that's not my idea of going out you know and being with nature so
 	
 	
 		yeah plus nowadays you just have to worry about being where you don't can't get behind locked doors even because you know somebody come up and knock you in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the night</TIMEX> or you heck you never know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's frightening
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh you know if i if i can get way way up you know way up in the mountains or you know way out someplace i probably be a little bit uh  you know less concerned but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yosemite</ENAMEX> and um we went we got a little cabin there and that was really nice but uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">someplace</ENAMEX> like that where you like you say you can get way out in the middle of nowhere you know where you can really be away from civilization i i would feel safer there than i would some of these little uh tent site areas you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i wouldn't mind i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> he's a big camper uh backpacker and everything and i i'd like to try that sometime with him where they they actually just take the sleeping bags and whatever food they they hike in someplace you know up to you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten fifteen</NUMEX> miles and then they they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh wow
 		oh my goodness my body can't handle that anymore i want a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> size air bed you know to go in the tent or something
 	
 	
 		they
 		yeah yeah really and truly that's that's that's more desirable course with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> you know any kind of outing is is would be good just to get away and do it uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		i found a problem here too since we moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> i was feeling like there's places with without fire <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ants</ENAMEX> or that aren't like all summer long it's so hot i you know i don't want to be out there when it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and ten</NUMEX> degrees out trying to sleep
 	
 	
 		well that's the thing there's really only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX> that you can really get out and really do anything and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's so wet in the early part of it
 	
 	
 		and you know unless you know like i say unless you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> or motor home and that and that's really what i would like to do someday i'd like to be able to afford a a trailer uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know not a real big one but just something that that would have you know air-conditioning and a and an icebox and stuff like that so you can you can feel you can feel like you're outside but yet you know have a few conveniences
 	
 	
 		contained
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah i can relate to that
 	
 	
 		uh
 		but uh
 		you know
 	
 	
 		we had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> invite us to go to a place on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks</TIMEX> that's uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">four miles</NUMEX> of dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> and they have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> that they keep permanently there a little travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> and they said we could just camp out but with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year old three days</TIMEX> without running <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> without the toilets i mean
 	
 	
 		that's a little tough
 	
 	
 		i can't imagine you know the diapers after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> forget it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's a little extreme i
 	
 	
 		yeah so you know i think we'll pass on that one but
 	
 	
 		but now you know uh
 		i know we'd like to maybe you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Disneyworld</ENAMEX> has those little campsites out there where you can you can rent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> or you know pull one or whatever and that might be kind of fun you know to spend you know spend a week doing all that stuff
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		that'd be nice yeah
 		yeah yeah that would be fun
 	
 	
 		but i don't think uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> or my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> are quite  ready for you know hiking into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campsite</ENAMEX> and sleeping under the stars and all that kind of stuff cooking over a campfire you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure i'm up to it either really yeah
 	
 	
 		fishing and then going and you know eating what you caught and all that good stuff huh
 	
 	
 		when i was younger i used to love doing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of stuff it was a challenge you know because you were with a bunch of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and you know you it was almost a competition but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		nowadays i don't care
 	
 	
 		yeah give me the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ramada Inn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah well i can understand that well we we'll have to get more supplies too i mean that's why it would be hard for me to imagine backpacking in because it seems like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>'s just totally loaded down with everything we have to go camping it's like
 	
 	
 		well of course you know you've got uh you got a whole different set of problems you still you know you need a stroller and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		my well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> said next time we go camping with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we're just going to strap them in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> seats at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock at night</TIMEX> and then we'll go back to the tent they'll fall asleep and we'll be able to enjoy nature yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's about right
 		oh i remember just like when we traveled you you end up carrying everything uh everything that you own just about to you know take care of the baby uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems like it we need a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> or something to get i mean even with if we take the dog forget it there's no room for anything else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so yeah it's hard to do without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature comforts</ENAMEX> sometimes
 	
 	
 		but
 		yeah i'm pretty rusty at it anyway i don't i don't know how i'd fare nowadays
 	
 	
 		well last time we tried we bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX> camp stove that was practically new at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> sale for next to nothing and then we brought it home and tried <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> to get it going and we could never get an even heat off of it
 		so we need somebody you know with experience to go with us sometime or come over and show us how to get it you know going so
 	
 	
 		well nowadays everything's so expensive i know like you know a good sleeping bag nowadays because like i you know all i've outgrown all that stuff and and it's been it's  worn out anyway but to go out and buy a decent sleeping bag you know you're talking you know <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh good grief
 	
 	
 		and then then a you know a decent tent you're looking at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two hundred dollars</NUMEX> and backpack all that kind of stuff i mean you could
 	
 	
 		yeah you could stay really nicely at a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">spa</ENAMEX> somewhere for a week for what it would cost you to buy all that
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly i mean by the time you get through outfitting yourself and then having to go sweat doing it uh you could you could go on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> med uh  everything inclusive vacati on
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really  oh gee
 	
 	
 		which i'd enjoy better anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah  well it
 	
 	
 		but uh but i used to be a real good camper when i was younger i i mean i used to just we just you know carry canoes and and uh we used to hike <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all summer long</TIMEX> we used to go up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and and we would uh we would do nothing but hike and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that'd be fun
 		oh gosh
 	
 	

 		and uh you know wash your clothes wherever you are and you you really get used to the outdoors
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		nowadays to for me to think even think about doing something like that i mean it's just kind of like no no not m e
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah it's amazing how when you get older you get smarter
 	
 	
 		i guess i'd like to think that anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually call that fun yeah
 		
 
 		i can't see that being really fun but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i guess i guess you know like i say if you know if you're going on a big hunting trip and you're going with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that were good at it and that kind of stuff you know it might be okay for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well they have these vacation packages i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that went on where she went uh now what do they call it when you go down the rapids like in these rubber <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boats</ENAMEX> and stuff rafting or whatever yeah
 	
 	
 		oh the white waters
 	
 	
 		and she went oh gosh to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> or someplace and i mean they had like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a gourmet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chef</ENAMEX> that put you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meal</ENAMEX> on for them wherever they tied up at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and i mean it was a whole different ball game wasn't like eating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef jerky</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah some of those things are pretty good yeah yeah some of those things would be okay
 	
 	
 		yeah just expensive
 	
 	
 		that would be a little probably a little drastic with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but for you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> it it's rough enough
 	
 	
 		yeah unless you just go and wear them out so badly that they'd collapse by the time they got off the raft they'd be wouldn't be any problem at all for the rest of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		boy i'd even i'd enjoy doing that myself
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that would be fun
 	
 	
 		but everybody i everybody i've talked to that has done that they say after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three or four days</TIMEX> of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it takes them uh i mean they're sore for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> because you know you're all the tensing and the bouncing and everything else you use muscles you haven't used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh really from all the bouncing
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh it you know that they end up staying home you know another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three or four days</TIMEX> when they get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> just to recuperate from it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh gosh that's funny
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so i don't know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i you know like i said i used to enjoy camping but anymore you know just the whole atmosphere's changed you you don't you don't hear of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that's taking their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and just going out go camping
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		you know now it's boating or or you know uh uh going on these uh
 		uh white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rapids</ENAMEX> or whatever the white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> you know raft rides and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		well i have you know hear like most of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say things like going to you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt Disneyworld</ENAMEX> and stuff like that with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> it's more of a luxury kind of vacation than it is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the roughing</TIMEX> it or whatever but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		well they have that i had it's like a water <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> or something where they have this in the wilderness <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> it's close to it where
 		you can take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and and kind of just let them go wild in that water country
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and uh you know and you and you kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out and they got little little kitchens in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX> and stuff but
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds neat
 	
 	
 		sounds like it sounds like it would be okay for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well maybe when ours get a little older and we really want to
 		get elaborate we could do something like that but for right now they think it's a thrill to put put a pool in the backyard you know one of those little <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> foot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KMart</ENAMEX> specials give them a glass of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> they're ready for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the afternoon</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they are fun
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		little toots
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		sometimes you know i i think it would be kind of neat maybe if she just wanted to get a little tent or something and you know once we get a fence in the backyard and uh and just let her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out maybe until till
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah just roast <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marshmallows</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> till she gets scared and wants to come in you know
 	
 	
 		how old is she
 	
 	
 		
 
 		she's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but she
 		yeah she she looks like she might be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outdoors person</ENAMEX> eventually but
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they
 		both my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> take after each other they they get hot real easy
 		and just being outside during the summertime
 	
 	
 		they'll just pass out huh
 	
 	
 		yeah and you know i i can go out and mow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> and everything else and and stand it just fine
 		and uh but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> she's real hot natured She she would uh she just gets gets outside for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five ten minutes</TIMEX> and she's ready to come back in So i don't i don't think camping <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of year</TIMEX> would i don't even think she'd think about it
 	
 	
 		oh gosh yeah
 		no no that doesn't sound too
 	
 	
 		it would have to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November early December</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah when we were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> all the time went in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> you know up in the mountains and stuff i don't know i can't see that either um south of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah so that that was that's nice there because you do have some cool weather and some mountains
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunnyvale</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		oh yeah the weather's really nice and then you go you know you can go up in the mountains and it'll drop <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> degrees just on your drive up there
 		so that's kind of
 	
 	
 		i used to go to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfield</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh that's real pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> up there
 	
 	
 		yeah there's a lot of nice
 		
 		
 	