
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX> do you believe that there is a problem with our public school system
 	
 	
 		i certainly do i think
 	
 	
 		and what do you think that problem is
 	
 	
 		i think we have a lousy school system and i think a lot of it has to do with the fact that we don't train our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> very well
 		and then we put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the hands of professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educators</ENAMEX> instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and the parents
 		and then oh we don't uh we put too much uh responsibility on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> for things that are really not education they're social services
 	
 	
 		hm that seems like you've thought this through quite a bit before
 	
 	
 		well i as a matter of fact i just finished editing a book on the topic so i have some rather strong opinions
 	
 	
 		that's interesting do you uh yourself
 	
 	
 		and and i'm sure they're colored by what i've edited
 	
 	
 		do you self have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with who are or have been through the public school system
 	
 	
 		yes i do and i was not very happy with the results
 	
 	
 		i see so if you were to improve it what would you do to improve it
 	
 	
 		well i think i would start with uh about with getting rid of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrators</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and all the auxiliary personnel the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> that exists mainly to perpetuate itself
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then i would provide uh use the money that we've been paying them to uh provide some special help in training and particularly uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mentor teachers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to work with the beginning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> who may have been at it a long time but have been making the same mistakes for a long time
 	
 	
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		and then let them try some innovative things and see what works and then uh have some sort of mechanism for passing that knowledge along to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> who could benefit from the same sorts of things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> side have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> get involved pay attention to what's happening talk to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> uh talk to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> about school
 		and support the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> and a instead of becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">adversaries</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> so that the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>'s in the middle
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's uh some pretty good ideas why don't you do something with those
 	
 	
 		well i've done about all i can do which is get the manuscript in good shape so that it can be published and read by a lot of people
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well you should uh run for a school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> position
 	
 	
 		oh well that i'm not so sure about i've got a lot of things to keep me busy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's
 	
 	
 		have you done anything like that anything political
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> board
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as we were coming up and uh that basically is the extent to which our
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> has been directly you know they've always been involved my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> through the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PTA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was on the school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh that was that's the extent of which i guess that's more than than some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> less than others
 	
 	
 		that's more than a lot
 	
 	
 		i would uh tend to agree with you that there is a problem
 		the methods of correcting it i haven't thought through it quite to the detail which you have but i believe that there's definitely a basic perception and image problem with the fact of even being a teacher
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if there was a way to through the public mind set that image to be a little higher esteem a little uh uh a little more prestige to being a teacher
 		and with that of course you know you have to pay them a accordingly if we paid them more it would attract more the the higher educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to to either move into that field or to continue in that field
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and then if you paid them more you'd also be able to demand a higher quality product out of them
 	
 	
 		i think that's absolutely right they the thing that worries me about that is that if you just raise salaries across the board you're going to be
 		uh rewarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've been doing a lousy job and instead of getting the uh improvement that we want so we'd have to have some way to
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh reward and recognize the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> who are doing a good job and give them uh a pat on the back and respect and some honor and more money
 	
 	
 		it unfortunately it's a and it's a business or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> that the results are not as tangible
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah it's hard to tell
 	
 	
 		as other ones so it's very it's very difficult to say that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> is doing a better job than this other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other than i guess how you know how a person scores in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and then after the class you know if there's some gauge that they could make
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> also i've always i've thought around about the idea of making
 		teaching and the before you can get a certificate you have a a certain residency period so much like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> maybe not the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> definitely but some certain type of of position where you're overseen to begin with
 	
 	
 		yeah now that's a very good suggestion
 	
 	
 		uh just something to i rather than throw someone in
 		into that environment uh you know it
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't think
 	
 	
 		i thought that maybe something
 	
 	
 		student i don't think student teaching is enough i think that at least what i used to observe in student teaching was that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who might not be all that bright to begin with was thrown into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> who was harried and overworked and uh had too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to handle and too many things to do and too many interruptions
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		to pay much attention to the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and then the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> didn't stay but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so there really was no time to try much of anything and get significant feedback that would help the the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> improve very much
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		there are lots of things that could be done in that line including things like videotaping because it wouldn't be hard
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		with all the electronic equipment that's around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> to videotape uh either a master <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> teaching a class
 		so that then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> could watch that and uh criticize the methods used and and analyze it figure out what worked and what didn't work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then also to videotape the student <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> so they could correct their own performance
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure that's good as a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a teaching aid but more you see these commercials that have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> walking into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">class late</ENAMEX> and it happens that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> who is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX>'s in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> and you know the whole electronic classroom idea
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't know if i i'm in favor yeah in favor of yeah i think especially in the younger <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> you need to have more of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person contact</ENAMEX> rather than just the fact that your machine being fed information to to learn how to learn
 	
 	
 		i don't think that's going to work
 		yeah well another thing i think would be helpful would be to have some sort of uh
 		say a national curriculum because one of the problems with getting good textbooks is that we have such a fragmented system for uh
 		curriculums that the textbook <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> produce a textbook that will sell in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and then everybody else is stuck with that regardless of what they want to teach
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">huh</ENAMEX> is that because that's where the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> biggest markets are or
 	
 	
 		because it
 		well that's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that adopt on a statewide basis
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and so it uh i used to work for a textbook <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> and it was absolutely clear that if you could get your book adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
 		then you had a built-in market because there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about three or four</NUMEX> textbooks in each subject and all you had to do is just get your share of those adopted in the individual school districts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and you know a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> market with its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> is a heck of a lot of textbooks
 	
 	
 		sure sure
 	
 	
 		and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that either don't adopt on a statewide basis or don't have as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just have to follow along and take what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> gets
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		like with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> is the biggest for elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> but <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh adopts statewide all the way through the twelfth grade
 	
 	
 		i see well definitely is a a national problem if they need to address
 	
 	
 		yep sure is
 	
 	
 		definitely is
 	
 	
 		and i hope maybe we're going to get somewhere with a little more attention being paid to it with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
 		uh new education <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> and uh you know trying to do some uh trying to produce some new programs anyway
 	
 	
 		right right well i've enjoyed speaking with you
 	
 	
 		excuse me
 		i have got to go i've got another line calling thanks bye
 	
 	
 		all righty good-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	