
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Fallen
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). The new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denzel Washington</ENAMEX> crime thriller
is said to suffer from an overwrought screenplay and a far-fetched conceit: A
detective battles a demon that jumps from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to another when they
touch. It's "what happens when too many mystics attend a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> pitch
meeting" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Critics also dislike
the hackneyed plot twists and "embarrassingly silly dialogue" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emanuel Levy</ENAMEX>,
Variety ). They find <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> his usual charming self, but some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> wonder why his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> never have romantic relations with white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> trumpets the movie here.)

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sundance Film Festival</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Park City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Redford</ENAMEX>'s annual
independent-film festival continues to lose its luster. Noting that the hits
from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s competition flopped at the box office, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> declare the
independent-film boom over. They lament a glut of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX> knockoffs
and speculate that the ski-vacation atmosphere intoxicates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>. "Movies
look better at high altitudes," suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's Rebecca
Ascher-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>' dominance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Globe</ENAMEX>
Awards-- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titanic</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> awards--is offered as evidence of their
restored hegemony. "Does this prove once and for all that size matters?"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cameron</ENAMEX> quipped at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-night</TIMEX> ceremony.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the snazzy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sundance</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               
                  Live Flesh
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM-UA</ENAMEX>). Reviewers praise <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX>
Almodóvar for abandoning his campy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proclivities</ENAMEX> to make a film noir with social
bite. Live Flesh , about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who accidentally shoots his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>, is deemed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>'s "most mature film yet" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Almodóvar</ENAMEX>'s foray into political
commentary--he indicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>'s ruling conservative
party--they wax most enthusiastic over his signature touch: kinky sex scenes.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Almodóvar</ENAMEX> is eros's last true worshiper" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> ). (A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> is available here.)

            

               Musical
            

            

               
                  Ragtime
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Center for the Performing Arts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> prove more skeptical than their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>, who
raved about this musical during its run there. They say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.L.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doctorow</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> novel about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">turn-of-the-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> gets saddled with
forgettable tunes by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Flaherty</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Ahrens</ENAMEX> and a book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrence</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McNally</ENAMEX> that is "thuddingly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">didactic</TIMEX>," especially on race (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Rose</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). The show has "the aura of something assembled by
corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>. Some label
producer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Drabinsky</ENAMEX> a megalomaniac bent on besting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> and dominating
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>.

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pillar of Fire</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years, 1963-65</TIMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of three volumes chronicling the
civil-rights movement is deemed as magisterial as the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning
first, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parting the Waters</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> gush over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Branch</ENAMEX>'s
wide-ranging narrative, which they say does justice to the mythic dimensions of
the struggle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX>, the book's central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>, emerges as "our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>'s epic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hero"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Wolfe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ) despite revelations
about his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedyesque</ENAMEX> libido. "The remarkable thing about the struggles of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> is that there now is no struggle over [their] historical
significance," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shribman</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Shadows on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hudson</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Bashevis Singer</ENAMEX>, translated by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Sherman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). A posthumously published novel by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX> garners mixed reviews. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say the 40-year-old
novel, about an adulterous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugee</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, illustrates the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Yiddish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">master</ENAMEX>'s wry humor and enchanting storytelling. It has "a strong claim to being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX>'s masterpiece," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX>.
Others say it's no coincidence the novel didn't appear until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> after
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX>'s death. "Chaotic, rambling, repetitive and parochial," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , suggesting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">translator</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> also did poor jobs. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rosen</ENAMEX>'s
review in 
                  Slate
               , and click here for an
excerpt from the book.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesdays</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). The cable
network's animated show about <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> obsessed with violence and bodily
emissions "has replaced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beavis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butt</ENAMEX>-head as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s premiere gross
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> product" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> attribute
the show's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> following to the timeless power of bathroom humor and to its
dark and clever plots, such as a thwarted assassination attempt on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathie Lee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gifford</ENAMEX>. Some predict the jokes will wear thin soon, while others call it
"definitively depraved" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (Download a
clip from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">South Park</ENAMEX> here.)

            

               Art
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arthur Dove: A Retrospective"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Critics
rediscover the virtues of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Dove</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1880-1946</TIMEX>), the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>
(and arguably the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> anywhere) to abandon representation. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dove</ENAMEX>'s
visionary abstraction was of such strength, originality and integrity," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>, "that it deserves its special place in the history
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> art." This esteem reverses the judgment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionists</ENAMEX>
who denied <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dove</ENAMEX>'s paternity of their movement and dismissed his landscapes as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">simple-minded</ENAMEX>.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.14</TIMEX>:

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Bono</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Prayer</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz Bissinger</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Frazier</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Drucker</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Beatty</ENAMEX>;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afterglow</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Arguing the
World ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Ma Vie en Rose</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boxer</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capote: In Which Various Friends, Enemies, Acquaintances, and Detractors Recall</ENAMEX>
His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turbulent</ENAMEX> Career , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Plimpton</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>;

            

               Music --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Northern Lights: The Music of Jean Sibelius</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">31:</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winter Movie Roundup</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24:</TIMEX>

            "The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review in Review</ENAMEX>"

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
