
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The
Mask of Zorro
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TriStar Pictures</ENAMEX>). The latest version of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">swashbuckling</ENAMEX> legend makes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> wax nostalgic for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> "when boyish
adventure films still had their innocence" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). This time an aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zorro</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX>) passes the mask to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Banderas</ENAMEX>. Unlike campier <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>, this movie about the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> is said to offer impeccable stunts and a genuinely witty screenplay.
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael Atkinson</ENAMEX> calls the acting "generally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lifeless</ENAMEX>, [with the] contrived feel of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving Day</TIMEX> parade." (Here's the
official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zorro</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks SKG</ENAMEX>). The hype commences, with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> pronouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> epic "a movie of staggering
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtuosity"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Reviews dwell on
the gory <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25 minute</TIMEX> opening battle scene, emblematic of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s new
obsession with verisimilitude: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ne</ENAMEX> of the greatest, most appalling things
ever done in movies" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). Applause also goes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> for bucking war movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">typecasting</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everyman Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> and such
unmacho hunks as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Burns</ENAMEX>. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthy</ENAMEX> notes that the premise--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> expends ridiculous resources on a
dubious rescue mission--is "far-fetched." (Join an online chat about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> .)

            

               
                  There's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Something About Mary</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farrelly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>' latest slapstick is said to hark back to the screwball
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">romances of the 1940s: The Dumb & Dumber</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> temper their
repulsive humor--which includes gags about a mangled penis and the mentally
retarded--with a touching love story. The plot: A sleazy private eye (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillon</ENAMEX>) falls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Diaz</ENAMEX>) he's paid to track down by a nerdy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Stiller</ENAMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> agree with 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrellys</ENAMEX>' "tenderness [and] joy in all things scatological, rendered
outrage spurious." Others are disgusted by the "sophomoric frat-house jokes"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Reed</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> ). (See the official site.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Hello</ENAMEX> Nasty
               , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beastie Boys</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Royal/Capitol</ENAMEX>). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wise</ENAMEX>-ass <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rappers</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> album in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> is taken as evidence of a new
sophistication. Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Browne</ENAMEX> calls the album "a
sonic smorgasbord in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beasties</ENAMEX> gorge themselves with reckless
abandon," sampling everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stravinsky to Tito Puente</ENAMEX>. Critics also like
their combination of high-minded lyrics about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> and the environment with
highbrow inanities about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Postimpressionist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Critics</ENAMEX> favorite line:
"I'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boggle</ENAMEX>, there is none higher/ I get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> points off the word
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'quagmire</ENAMEX>.' ") (Check out the Hello Nasty chat site.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  Lucky Bastard
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles McCarry</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). An ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>'s thriller about a skirt-chasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>'s ascent to the presidency is deemed
"Primary Colors written with imagination" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lehmann-Haupt</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McCarry</ENAMEX>'s entertaining
prose and quirky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, they focus more on the similarities between the
sexaholic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. None other than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX> complains
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> that the book "becomes a porn novel," with its
heavy focus on presidential sex. (See what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> has to say about
Lucky <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bastard</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twelfth Night</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Vivian Beaumont Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Mixed
reviews for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Hunt</ENAMEX>'s turn as a Shakespearean: Is she
delightfully down-to-earth or simply banal? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">London Guardian</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joanna</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coles</ENAMEX> says her presence is "so obvious a gimmick to draw in those who don't
normally bother to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bard</ENAMEX> that it's almost insulting." Unanimous praise
goes to The 
               Madness of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Hytner</ENAMEX>'s
staging of the gender bender, which breaks with the recent trend of
interjecting gay subtext into the play. The consensus: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twelfth Night</ENAMEX> is
"the greatest of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>'s romantic comedies" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Drudge
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News Channel</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gossip Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> milks his newfangled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX>, debuting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half-hour</TIMEX>
political chat show. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> use the occasion as another opportunity to
bash him for his "blatant bias and outrageous exaggerations" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bianco</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). Others regret that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> is less than telegenic and fails
to deliver the dish his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promos</ENAMEX> promised. Still others, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>, predict the unpredictable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX>, a "refreshingly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snarky</ENAMEX> news anchor," will shake up political television. Here's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX>, which
spawned the TV show. And here are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chatterbox</ENAMEX> 's musings on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
15

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>! --The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unknown Terrain:</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landscapes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Wyeth</ENAMEX>";

            
               Movie -- Small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Lethal</ENAMEX>
Weapon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX> ;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Embrya</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Car Wheels on a Gravel Road</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Williams</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armaggedon</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>

               Fool ;

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy Rogers</ENAMEX>;

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hitler: The Search for the Origins of His Evil</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Someone
Else's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unfinished Struggle for Integration</ENAMEX> , by Tamar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacoby</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diary</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Fielding</ENAMEX>;

            

               Performance <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Art -- The Return of the Chocolate Smeared Woman</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finley</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Out of
Sight ;

            
               Movie -- Smoke

               Signals ;

            
               Movie -- Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolittle</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Gone With</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wind</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bonnard</ENAMEX>";

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Suits Me: The</ENAMEX>
Double <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Tipton</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Wood Middlebrook</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Notebooks of Don Rigoberto</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Vargas Llosa</ENAMEX>,
translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Grossman</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>
Files ;

            
               Movie --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
Movies (AFI);

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mulan</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray"</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Walking With</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wind: A Memoir of the Movement</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lewis</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael D'Orso</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ship</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gold</ENAMEX>:
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deep Blue Sea</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Kinder</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beautiful</ENAMEX>
Mind , <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">by Sylvia Nasar</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
