
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Art
            

            
               "The
Art of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorcycle</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Besting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rauschenberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matisse</ENAMEX> retrospectives, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s display of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">114</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">motorcycles</ENAMEX> is the most attended exhibition in its history. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> find
beauty in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX>' sleek, modern designs, but most reject the exhibition as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lowbrow</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jed Perl</ENAMEX> calls it a "pop nostalgia orgy
masquerading as a major artistic statement." (Visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX>'s home page.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Lolita
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>; click here for air times). Despite the refusal of major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX> to
release it as a theatrical film, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adriane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyne</ENAMEX>'s adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Nabokov</ENAMEX>'s novel is deemed boring rather than
shocking. More faithful to the novel than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kubrick</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> version, it is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nonetheless</ENAMEX> said to lack Nabokovian wit and sexiness. A minority praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irons</ENAMEX>' portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humbert Humbert</ENAMEX>--the middle-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> obsessed with his
adolescent stepdaughter--as sufficiently smarmy, and call the film "rich beyond
what anyone could have expected" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caryn James</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Menand</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maximum Bob</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). Yet another
adaptation of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmore Leonard</ENAMEX> novel produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Sonnenfeld</ENAMEX> ( Get
Shorty , Out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sight</ENAMEX> ). This one centers on a power-hungry rural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beau Bridges</ENAMEX>) who happily doles out lengthy sentences--a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">redneck Judge</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Fretts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call it the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> , citing its twisting plot lines, eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, and
black humor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissenting</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX> calls the
show's jabs at yokels "smug and snide." (Go to the official <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Ever <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">After: A Cinderella Story</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). An
update of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Barrymore</ENAMEX> as the maligned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anjelica Huston</ENAMEX> as the social-climbing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stepmother</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huston</ENAMEX>'s
wicked performance and the renovations to the tale--this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinderella</ENAMEX> is erudite,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">resourceful</ENAMEX>, and independent. The film is said to be "the best <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cinderella</ENAMEX> movie
ever" (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mick LaSalle</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Francisco Chronicle</ENAMEX> ), though politically
minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call it "a preposterous polemic celebrating modern feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">platitudes"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Arnold</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Times</ENAMEX> ). (Here's the official
site.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Negotiator</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). A rare flop for the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character actors</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Spacey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel L. Jackson</ENAMEX>. The latter plays a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> who takes another
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop hostage</ENAMEX>, then picks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spacey</ENAMEX> as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">negotiator</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> are unable to
compensate for one-dimensional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, trite dialogue, and an overabundance
of explosions. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>, "The main things
lost in the hubbub are wit and logic." (Check out the official Web
site.)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  Burn
Rate: How I Survived the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gold Rush Years</ENAMEX> on the Internet
               ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s memoir about his own unsuccessful
attempt at running an Internet startup. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> revel in his caustic humor and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">vengeful</ENAMEX> gossip about new-media moguls (he describes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX> exec as "a fat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, an ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, sweating like crazy"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Cortese</ENAMEX>
calls the book "a fascinating cautionary tale" of the way money is shoveled at
bad, but hyped, projects. But 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Shafer</ENAMEX> disparages
widespread comparisons of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burn Rate</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis' Liar</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Poker</ENAMEX> and attacks what he deems <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolff</ENAMEX>'s disingenuousness: "[B]y repeatedly
reminding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of what a dishonest, scheming little shit he is, he seeks
to inflate his credibility." (Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shafer</ENAMEX>'s
review.)

            

               Death
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robbins</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918-1998</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obituaries</ENAMEX> rank the choreographer alongside Diaghilev
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balanchine</ENAMEX> as one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who reinvented ballet. Best known for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Broadway musicals West Side Story and Fiddler on the Roof</ENAMEX> , his
greatest contribution is said to be the integration of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Modernist</ENAMEX> innovations
and popular dance steps with classical ballet. He was "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s first great
native born ballet choreographer" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Teachout</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Critics
remember his unrelenting perfectionism (some say meanness) and his audacious
style, which "typified the make-way-for-youth spirit of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene Croce</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ).

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            
               Book--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">100 Best English-Language Novels</ENAMEX> Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>;
            

            
               Book--
               Point of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Origin</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Cornwell</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie--
               Disturbing
Behavior ;

            
               Movie--
               Pi ;

            

               Movie--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thief</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mask of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zorro</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Saving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- There's
Something <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Mary</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- Hello
Nasty , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beastie Boys</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Lucky
Bastard , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles McCarry</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Twelfth
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Night</TIMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
15

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>! --The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unknown Terrain:</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landscapes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Wyeth</ENAMEX>";

            
               Movie -- Small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Lethal</ENAMEX>
Weapon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX> ;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Embrya</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Car Wheels on a Gravel Road</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Williams</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armaggedon</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>

               Fool ;

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy Rogers</ENAMEX>;

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hitler: The Search for the Origins of His Evil</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Someone
Else's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unfinished Struggle for Integration</ENAMEX> , by Tamar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacoby</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diary</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Fielding</ENAMEX>;

            

               Performance <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Art -- The Return of the Chocolate Smeared Woman</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finley</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
