
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Getty Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>). The oil magnate's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> art
expands its collection and moves to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>--"the most expensive art
complex in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Modernist architect</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Meier</ENAMEX>'s eclectic <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, which echo <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Le Corbusier</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Lloyd</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wright</ENAMEX>, receive mostly raves. "A symphonic set of variations on the classical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Muschamp</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Time</ENAMEX> s). Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> simply replicate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meier</ENAMEX>'s
designs for other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indiana</ENAMEX>. And some <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> doesn't deserve such a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Meier</ENAMEX> plugs his
project.)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Neighborhood</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Booth Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). The
hard-edged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> turns introspective with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> autobiographical <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-acts
about his midlife crises and assimilated Judaism. "His most emotionally
accessible drama to date," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>. As
always, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> rave over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet</ENAMEX>'s sardonic humor and street-smart
dialogue. Others complain the plays are pretentious and without much plot. Some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">detractors ridicule Mamet</ENAMEX>'s language for its "terrible syntax, clichés,
non-sequiturs, idiocies--but, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, that's how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk!" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Flubber
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s remake of The

               Absent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>), with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX> in the lead role,
draws a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> (earning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10.7 million</NUMEX> its opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX>) and critical
derision. "Slow, flat and dumb" says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> find <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>' character surprisingly unlikable, causing some to
conclude that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comedian</ENAMEX> has hit a midcareer slump. The film's saving grace
is its special effects, particularly the green, gravity-defying slime that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> creates. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s site for the movie.)

            

               
                  Welcome to Sarajevo
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Respectful</ENAMEX> doubts about this film
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> who saves an orphaned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> say
its conventional use of melodrama cheapens the atrocities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX>
war. "Some of the shocks here are too sadly predictable," says the New York
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>. Still, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> applaud its explicit condemnation of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>' passive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> policy, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Harrelson</ENAMEX>'s portrayal of a
blowhard TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>.

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Housing</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>; click here for
local listings). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Veteran filmmaker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Wiseman</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three-hour</TIMEX> documentary
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> public-housing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">project</ENAMEX> wins critical approval. Reviewers praise
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wiseman</ENAMEX>'s signature minimalist style--no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX>, no music, long unedited
scenes--and his willingness to face up to the intractability of poverty. "Like
a dense poem," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Johnson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiseman</ENAMEX> reveals
"the impotence, for poverty, of the talking cure--the endless stream of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sex-education</ENAMEX> classes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX>-therapy sessions, self-esteem talks ... directed
by the haves at the have-nots," says 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s Walter Kirn</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
plugs the show.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  Release <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2.0</NUMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Design for Living</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Age</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dyson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadway Books</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> scoff at high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Dyson</ENAMEX>'s claims
that the Internet will expand democracy, build <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX>, and liberate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. "A cross between New Age philosophy and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">1950s</ENAMEX> hyperbole," says

                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Nocera</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dyson</ENAMEX> naively "downplays the [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX>'s] perils," among them new opportunities
for invasive voyeurs and shysters. Others gripe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dyson</ENAMEX> recycles her
previously published magazine articles, writes turgid prose, and puts too much
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">faith</ENAMEX> in the free market. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Release 2.0</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               Photography
            

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weegee</ENAMEX>'s
World: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life, Death, and the Human Drama"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Center of Photography</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Midtown</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). With this retrospective, the newspaper photographer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Fellig</ENAMEX> a k a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weegee</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1899-1968</TIMEX>) is judged a technical virtuoso, a
great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, and an inspiration to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> marvel at his knack
for arriving at murder scenes before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. Others blame him for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s voyeurism and disapprove of his borderline ethics (he composed
scenes that he passed off as spontaneous). "His influence was like a rock
dropped in a pond: its ripples are still spreading," says the New York
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicki Goldberg</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>'s site and here for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Weegee samples</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Update
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Ford Coppola</ENAMEX>'s The
Rainmaker generic. "Must we simply face the iron fact that current
filmmaking conditions have deprived still another individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of his
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">individuality?</ENAMEX>"

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rainmaker</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Alien</ENAMEX>
Resurrection ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>: How an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ordinary Man Became an Extraordinary Leader</ENAMEX> , by Dinesh
D'Souza;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivanov</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standing Stone</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackal</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anastasia</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet</ENAMEX>
Hereafter ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Another City</ENAMEX>,
Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Own</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Novel in the Form of a Memoir</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominick Dunne</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egon Schiele</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Leopold Collection</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern</ENAMEX>
Art).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Starship
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troopers</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wings of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dove</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Mad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Proposal ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Dark Side</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour M. Hersh</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred C.</ENAMEX>
Kinsey: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public/Private Life</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James H. Jones</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cooking: The All-Purpose Cookbook</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Warhol Look/Glamour Fashion Style"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            

               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiceworld</ENAMEX> , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> --P.S. 1
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary Arts Center</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>
Corner ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Violin</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Rice</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Kincaid</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xerxes</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Opera</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
