
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re-elected House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX> by a vote of <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">216-205</ENAMEX>. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of arm-twisting
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> chose not to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. The media
played up the size of the dissenting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> anyway. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pundits</ENAMEX> agreed that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> won the battle and lost the war: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s ethics case will drag on
through congressional hearings; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> will then force the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Ethics</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> to close the case, enabling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to cry "cover-up" for months
afterward; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> will have to vote again on his punishment; he'll be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">distracted</ENAMEX>, tarnished, and weakened; having lost prestige and twisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> just
to get re-elected, he'll have no clout left to keep his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in line; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> policy agenda will languish; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> will be forced to make
concessions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in order to pass legislation and repair his own image;
and, above all, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will sing from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s rap sheet throughout the
coming hearings on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s ethical troubles. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
reportedly were delighted by the outcome. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> chuckled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>
was replaying its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'96</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> catastrophe, clinging fast to a sinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>.
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/9</TIMEX>)
            

            A furor has erupted over
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>' immunity from prosecution for crimes committed in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>-ranking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>,
reportedly caused a series of car collisions that killed a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> allege he was drunk and speeding, and that he ran a stop sign. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belarussian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> reportedly resisted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> who were trying to ticket their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because it was parked at a fire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hydrant</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> appeared to be drunk. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giuliani</ENAMEX> demanded their expulsion and denounced the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> as scofflaws,
noting that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> mission had accumulated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">14,437</NUMEX> parking and traffic
citations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first half of 1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belarussian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>
ignored him and blamed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. Under the international policy of diplomatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">immunity</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> cannot be prosecuted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> unless their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> waive immunity, which is highly unlikely. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> rushed to join
the outcry to modify this policy to allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scoundrels</ENAMEX> to be brought to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. Acknowledgments of similar exploitation of immunity by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> abroad were buried near the bottom of most stories. (posted
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1/9</NUMEX>)
            

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advisory Council on</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> released its prescriptions for the trust fund's solvency
problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Members</ENAMEX> agreed to hike payroll taxes, raise the retirement age, and
invest some money in stocks, but failed to agree on how far to privatize the
system . <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">faction</ENAMEX> favors letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> manage their own investment
accounts; another favors leaving the stock-picking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>; <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX>
would set up individual accounts but would fund them separately through a
payroll tax hike. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> hailed the rough consensus on stock investment
as a "paradigm shift," while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> warned of leeching by Wall Street brokers
and asked whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will bail out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retirees</ENAMEX> who lose their savings
because of market volatility. Union <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> vowed to kill any privatization
scheme; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> signaled they're not ready for full privatization but are
willing to experiment with stocks as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> picks the stocks.
Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX> failed to reach a consensus that would give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>
cover, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are calling for another commission. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/9</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> are for sale. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> predicted that with its prestigious history
and associated properties, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> might fetch <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $350 million</NUMEX>, twice
the previous record for a baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX>. Sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX> noted that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Malley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> , which owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, launched <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> revolution in sports
commercialization <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years ago</TIMEX>--when they uprooted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> to
make more money in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>. Now they are completing another, as they become
the last of the old-time family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> to sell out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>-ignorant moguls. "The time is approaching when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> cannot support
a major-league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. It is the time of corporate ownership," said
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter O'Malley</ENAMEX>. Among the leading potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rupert Murdoch</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Television</ENAMEX> , or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shapiro</ENAMEX> , former <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Ueberroth</ENAMEX> , or various
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Anderson</ENAMEX> recalled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Malleys</ENAMEX>' betrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> and scoffed that they were proving once again
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> is "a business, not a game." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gov.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Pataki</ENAMEX> urged
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to bid for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, but the early line is that this
would be a long shot. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/9</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eight</TIMEX> letter bombs
disguised as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> cards and postmarked from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Alexandria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX>, were mailed
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureau</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Hayat</ENAMEX> ) and to
Leavenworth <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. All were discovered without injury. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX>
government swears they couldn't have originated there, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> think
they did and are warning everyone to beware of unexpected parcels from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> suspect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">culprit</ENAMEX> may be somebody offended by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hayat</ENAMEX> 's eclectic articles and editorials--which is to say, just about
anyone. Early speculation focused on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammad Salameh</ENAMEX>, a
Leavenworth <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> bombing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
Press <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Building</ENAMEX>, which houses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Hayat</ENAMEX> , was evacuated; the media
responded with outrage at this heinous act against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle Eastern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Hayat</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> wondered why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> would target a
paper that has been so hospitable to the views of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> weighed in with articles on how easy it is to construct letter bombs
and ship them undetected through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> mail. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/7</TIMEX>)
            

            Celebrity rites of
passage: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> announced she is divorcing him. Real-estate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mogul Harry Helmsley</ENAMEX> died, raising speculation that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leona Helmsley</ENAMEX>,
will lose control of his financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Václav Havel</ENAMEX> married
a movie and stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Mitchell</ENAMEX> agreed to marry <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Col.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">94-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> died, 17 years
after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colonel</ENAMEX> kicked the bucket. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> announced that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX> will be knighted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince Charles</ENAMEX> has reportedly installed
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camilla Parker Bowles</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">country manor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephanopoulos</ENAMEX> is said to be considering a role as campaign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Labor Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivana Trump</ENAMEX> , upset with her "abysmally constructed"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">yacht</ENAMEX>, is suing its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35 million</NUMEX> for emotional
distress. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben & Jerry</ENAMEX>'s has raised socially conscious eyebrows by hiring
its new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Repeating Arms Co.</ENAMEX>, which manufactures <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rifles</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben & Jerry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Cohen</ENAMEX> points out that at least the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
agrees with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s stand against handguns. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/7</TIMEX>)
            

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year-old</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina Panthers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacksonville Jaguars</ENAMEX> are within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> victory
apiece of meeting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>. Having already pushed aside the
once-feared <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">49ers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> Bills, the two expansion teams
ousted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Broncos</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> playoffs. Sports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">columnists</ENAMEX> declared the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> dead, lamenting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX>' traditional
season-ending choke and celebrating the demise of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>, widely
attributed to their dissolute lifestyle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Irvin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deion Sanders</ENAMEX> were
carted off the field with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>-ending injuries. Cowboy-haters insinuated that
they deserved it. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wicked Witch</ENAMEX> is dead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>," gloated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wilbon</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . Established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are now complaining that the
expansion <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>' success proves they were given too many picks in the college
and expansion drafts. Sportswriters reply that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> have had plenty of
similar chances, have blown them, and may be booted from their jobs now that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panthers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaguars</ENAMEX> have proven that it doesn't take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> to build a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/7</TIMEX>)
            

            Nature continued to punish
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX>. After <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> massive snowstorms, heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and melting
snow have caused floods, mudslides, sinkholes , and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 11</NUMEX> deaths.
While local newspaper coverage has generally been self-pitying, the comfortably
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">faraway New York Times</ENAMEX> responded with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schadenfreude</ENAMEX> , likening the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>'s woes to biblical plagues ("We finally got our natural disaster, as
if it were coming to us," conceded a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> coffee server) and reporting that
"some Northwesterners" confess to a "sheltered, even slightly wimpy quality in
their approach to the extremes of nature." (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/4</TIMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
campaign-finance scandal expanded while tightening around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Among the latest revelations: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fund-raiser</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Trie</ENAMEX> got
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to meet with a rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arms merchant</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Thai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">businesswoman</ENAMEX> and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX> with investment interests in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> met
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> policy, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> before she
forked over an illegal <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85,000</NUMEX> check to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Party</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Matsui</ENAMEX>, was included (illegally, if true) in an Asian-American
political fund-raising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> headed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>. The new disclosures
emboldened major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> to sharpen their portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as a central
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> in the sale of presidential access to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contributors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits</ENAMEX>
agreed there is still no evidence of a policy quid pro quo, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> pointedly compared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s pre-election withholding of
information on the scandal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> cover-up that led to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s resignation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> suggested that the whole affair might
actually be a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist Chinese</ENAMEX> espionage plot. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/4</TIMEX>)
            

            An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> with a
record of mental illness fired into an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> marketplace in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hebron</ENAMEX>
without provocation, wounding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> was wrestled down by
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow officer</ENAMEX> and later explained that he wanted to thwart <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s troop
withdrawal from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hebron</ENAMEX>. The attack did not provoke riots and further bloodshed,
in part because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> was a lousy shot and failed to kill anyone, and in
part because <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> expeditiously phoned
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yasser Arafat</ENAMEX> to condemn the shooting. The short-term
question was how such a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">nut</ENAMEX> got drafted into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>; the long-term
question was whether the attack would convince <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> that their own
right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX> are a greater threat to peace and security than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> are. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/4</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straws</ENAMEX> in the wind: To the
mystification of beach-goers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is proposing regulations to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">protect sharks</ENAMEX> from depletion by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fishermen</ENAMEX>. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshmallows</ENAMEX> are the new rage in fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Year-end</ENAMEX> figures show the murder rate continued falling in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; among
the factors cited are gun-control laws, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> locked away in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>,
and more cops on the beat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports that debutante
balls are coming back. A study finds promise in a new therapy for impotence: a
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug pellet</ENAMEX> that is inserted into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s urethra. (Fewer than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>
in the study backed out due to the pain.) An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Names
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have stopped naming their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> " since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. Sales of tobacco pipes are booming; the pipe industry hopes to capitalize
on--and supplant--cigar chic, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX>
still consider pipes "tweedy and prissy." (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/4</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
