
   
   
      
         
            

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Fighting between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> claimed more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> lives and injured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Bank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gaza Strip</ENAMEX>. The bloodshed
was triggered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> opened a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> entrance in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>. Among the early story lines : The rioters
were sending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Netanyahu</ENAMEX> a message that he must negotiate
fought alongside the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rioters</ENAMEX>--have collapsed; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> was not a decisive
ideologue but a aimless dawdler; concessions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>, said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Likud</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, would signal weakness and invite further attacks; and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">conflagration</ENAMEX> placed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Egypt</ENAMEX> in a precarious position as it tried to facilitate
reconciliation amid <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> rage over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s actions. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, the spin
shifted from chaos to order as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NPR</ENAMEX> reported that both sides seemed "shocked" by
the violence and hoped "to pull back from the brink."

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> 's decision to not raise interest rates reflected both
campaign politics and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">internecine</ENAMEX> struggles at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> rarely
changes rates during campaigns, the move was interpreted as benefiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
by denying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kemp</ENAMEX> an excuse to a) decry government constriction of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>; and b) blame <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> for incipient inflation. Some speculated that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>'s regional bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>, who wanted a rate hike, had leaked their
preference to pressure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX>; others worried that the leaker
might help friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> get a jump on imminent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> actions. Either way,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> to investigate the breach of security.

            British
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> raided <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX> hideouts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
suspected terrorist, arresting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> others, and confiscating <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">10 tons</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">explosives</ENAMEX>. The raids apparently thwarted a truck bombing akin to those that
killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and injured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times reported that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> had expected the IRA to commit such an
attack as a final gesture of defiance before slinking back to a cease-fire.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Major</ENAMEX> said the discovery discredited the IRA's professions
of interest in a peaceful resolution of the conflict.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> was the subject as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> opened its
51st <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Assembly.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is delinquent on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.64 billion</NUMEX> in dues and has
angered other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> by promising to veto a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> noted
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> opposition to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boutros-Ghali</ENAMEX> has only endeared him to other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Editorialists</ENAMEX> warned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is in no position to
demand reforms in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> until it pays its dues. In a visit to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> from the world's other
major nuclear powers signed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> also
triangulated off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, contrasting his warm feelings for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>
with the anti-global hostility of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">isolationists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> of the
treaty.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astronaut Shannon Lucid</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian Mir</ENAMEX> space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>, setting an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> record and a world record for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. Fire rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> expected to carry Lucid from the space shuttle,
since the weightlessness of space tends to confuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>'s sense of balance
and deplete <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, bone, and muscle strength. Instead, she stood up and walked
away, with some help. Her strength was credited to a rigorous workout regimen
on the space <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called her "a terrific inspiration" for
"young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> who may have nontraditional aspirations."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> left the campaign trail to cram for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> presidential debate.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole pal Tom Korologos</ENAMEX> explained that by "sitting on the beach," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> "shows
confidence. ... If he thought it was over, he'd be frenetically running
around." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s rhetorical talents were so pitied that when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> spokesman
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> tried to raise expectations for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>'s performance, he was accused
of cruelly mocking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> joined the legal
challenge to the debate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s exclusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross Perot</ENAMEX>, calling its
behavior "awfully close to corruption." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> continued to
blame and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hound</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> for keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perot</ENAMEX> out the debates.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-emerged as a focus of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> anxiety. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>
disclosed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> are more worried about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> in the long term than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s beefed-up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">navy</ENAMEX> is capable of cutting
off <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-fifth</NUMEX> of the world's <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> supply, and its nuclear, biological, and
chemical weapons make it a threat even beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times reported that some of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and other
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> to defend <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX> have remained, and that they have apparently
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">threatened NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> link the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX>, saying they've have been trained as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. In other
southcentral <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> news, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Islamic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fundamentalists</ENAMEX> solidified control of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">three-fourths</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> and seized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kabul</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s health gave the world palpitations. First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>
suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s heart had suffered so much damage that
it might not survive an urgently needed bypass operation. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Financial Times</ENAMEX> claimed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> had suffered an almost totally
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">debilitating stroke</ENAMEX>. Other reports asserted that his kidneys and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">liver</ENAMEX> were
failing, perhaps due to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> he had allegedly taken during his re-election
campaign. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> stock market plunged. Opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> called on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> to resign. Would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX>, led by national security chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Lebed</ENAMEX>, rushed to position themselves for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s job. Then a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> led by renowned heart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael DeBakey</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">examined Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, pronounced his condition "not bad at all," and predicted that
although his surgery would be delayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks</TIMEX>, he would probably serve out
his term. Stocks recovered, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> around the world breathed easier.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, long accustomed to evasive and deceptive reports on their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>' health, took the news of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s illness with typical stoicism.
"Think of all the awful healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> we could have," said one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Jr .</ENAMEX> married longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Bessette</ENAMEX>, on a secluded
island off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>. Gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> congratulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bessette</ENAMEX> and consoled every
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> called it "one of the best
covert operations in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>"; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> didn't inform many of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> (his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Kennedy</ENAMEX>, was among those not invited), and
the few who did attend (estimates ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than a dozen</NUMEX>) weren't
invited until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> in advance. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy</ENAMEX>
had deceived <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, about his travel plans.
Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">caterers</ENAMEX> had to sign confidentiality agreements. After years of being
hounded by paparazzi , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> reportedly exulted
in their escape. "We were so excited to have fooled everybody," said one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">attendee</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
divided a landmark immigration-reform measure into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bills, then
passed them both. The larger bill would fortify the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Patrol</ENAMEX>, facilitate
deportations, and restrict the benefits available to illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX>; the
detached bill would let states exclude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> of illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aliens</ENAMEX> from public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> bill was dismissed as veto bait, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> were
deemed to have scored a victory by detaching it and thereby removing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
excuse to veto the larger bill. Liberal interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
scrambled to find new objections to the larger bill: Among other things, they
warned that it threatens legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> with deportation and diminishes their
safeguards against job discrimination. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> issued a letter pretending to
have spearheaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>'s separation of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> bills, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> disclosed that congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> had actually forced the idea
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX>. A further <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> article suggested that ultimately, the joke was
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>: Its crackdown on legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> is scaring them into becoming
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX>, and they're overwhelmingly registering to vote as
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram Co.</ENAMEX> expanded plans to advertise 
               liquor on
television, defying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plea to honor the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half-century-old</TIMEX>
voluntary ban. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagram</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sympathizers</ENAMEX> pointed out that the product is legal,
and dismissed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s warning as a political stunt designed to endear him to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stations</ENAMEX> running the ads claimed that they wouldn't air them during
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s normal viewing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> noted that
liquor-industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> are disgruntled with the ban because it prevents
them from competing on the tube with beer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            The
birth-control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> is reportedly making a comeback. A comprehensive
international review of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> studies concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> doesn't heighten a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>'s long-term probability of getting breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> also
discounted previous concerns that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> contributed to cardiovascular
trouble, and touted studies indicating that it reduces the risk of ovarian and
endometrial <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, a new survey by a contraceptive pharmaceutical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX> has surpassed sterilization as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s
most popular birth-control method. The breast-cancer scare was cited as an
apparent factor in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pill</ENAMEX>'s previous decline in popularity.

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Wives Club</ENAMEX>
               , a revenge-comedy about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>, grossed
more on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first weekend</TIMEX> than any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s film in history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equivocal</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Kempley</ENAMEX> called it "stale feminist
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fluff</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Carlson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> pronounced it "an antidote to
the zeitgeist of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>, when middle-aged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tycoons</ENAMEX> and their acolytes could
suddenly drop an inconvenient <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> without social opprobrium," and
predicted the film would spark the kind of debate provoked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma &</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> envisioned a reversal of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bias</ENAMEX> toward male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>: "Could it be that being middle-aged and female has
become a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> box-office asset?"

         
      
   
