
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Godzilla
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TriStar</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say they'll take the marketing
campaign (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Size Does Matter"</ENAMEX>) over the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$130 million</NUMEX> remake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1954</ENAMEX> classic,
from <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Independence Day</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Devlin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roland Emmerich</ENAMEX>. The
movie is "so slapdash it makes <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Independence Day</ENAMEX> look like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX>,"
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>. Nostalgia reigns for the campy
charm of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> original. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devlin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Emmerich's Godzilla</ENAMEX> is
accused of being annoyingly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spielbergian</ENAMEX> and lacking personality as well as
wits: "Any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">forefather</ENAMEX> (and, given his reproductive capacities, foremother) of a
new <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> that chooses to travel halfway around the globe to lay his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> in
the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> doesn't seem built to survive, evolutionarily speaking"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
               ). The film's failure (it's doing relatively
poorly at the box office) may also be due to overexposure to disaster movies.
We have become "programmed to expect these artificial thrills" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clips</ENAMEX> are available here.)

            

               
                  Fear <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">and Loathing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brazil</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Gilliam</ENAMEX>'s adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter S. Thompson</ENAMEX>'s junkie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">roman √</ENAMEX>†
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clef</ENAMEX> is declared "a pointless mess" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah Rozen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ). Besides
the lack of a plot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say, there's a senselessly spinning camera meant to
depict drug trips in scenes reminiscent of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Warhol</ENAMEX>'s very worst movies.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Depp</ENAMEX> wins the only praise offered with his impersonation of the gonzo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Cannes</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Film Festival</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundup</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perennial</ENAMEX> gripes about the annual glitz-fest:
It showcases mediocrity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood</ENAMEX> uses the occasion to push blockbusters
rather than quality films. "It's become a carnival midway of commercial
attractions" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> profess
surprise that the festival's top honors go to the controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX> director
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theo Angelopoulos</ENAMEX> for his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eternity</ENAMEX> and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX> , the story of a dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX>.
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Three years ago</TIMEX>, Angelopoulos bad-mouthed <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX> when his film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ulysses</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaze</ENAMEX> didn't win.) Other films to emerge from the festival are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Haynes</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Velvet Gold Mine</ENAMEX> , a tribute to glam rock, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life Is Beautiful</ENAMEX> , a comedy about the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>.

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Freedomland
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Price</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadway Books</ENAMEX>). Price's
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ripped-</ENAMEX>from-the-headlines novels ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clockers</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wanderers</ENAMEX> ) win
comparisons to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zola</ENAMEX>. This fictionalization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Smith</ENAMEX> case--a white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX> claims that a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> kidnapped her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>--"will be read in the future
as much for its social history as its compelling story" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom De Haven</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Price's virtues are said to include his insights
into urban decay and race, as well as his cinematic dialogue, acquired in his
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">screenwriter</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  Remembering Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: The Invisible Art of</ENAMEX>
Editing
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ved Mehta</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overlook Press</ENAMEX>); 
                  Here But Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here: A Love</ENAMEX>
Story
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lillian Ross</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Hagiographic</TIMEX> memoirs about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legendary New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> from an adoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mehta</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawn</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mistress</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>). Most mock <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mehta</ENAMEX> for his overwrought prose and
depictions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawn</ENAMEX>'s impeccable editing. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ,
ex- <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Bernstein</ENAMEX> accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mehta</ENAMEX> of glossing over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawn</ENAMEX>'s inadequacies as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> and his fatal failure to groom a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successor</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> wins some applause for her dishy revelations, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawn</ENAMEX>'s fondness for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">racetracks</ENAMEX> and sex, but also criticism for her ill-wrought prose and overheated
tone. Many scold <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> for publishing her memoir while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawn</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">92-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>
is still alive. Conspiracy theory of the moment: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Did Tina Brown</ENAMEX> ... who is
often accused of vulgarizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shawn</ENAMEX>'s great <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, urge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX> to tell all?"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Shapiro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holt</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry Sanders Show</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 31</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). After hyping then
panning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> finale, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> now lament the end of The

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Larry Sanders Show</ENAMEX> . "No series has ever made meanness more satisfying,
more funny," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>. Encomiums for the
sitcom--which depicts the goings-on behind the scenes of a TV talk show--praise
star and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Shandling</ENAMEX>'s deadpan humor, the show's skewering of show
biz, and its blurring of life and art with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity cameos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> on the
final episode include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Beatty</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>). Critics
dwell on the finale's unhappy backdrop--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shandling</ENAMEX> has a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> suit
against his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, who allegedly swiped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> for
other shows. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> plugs the show here.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20:</TIMEX>

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> finale;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulworth</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whisperer</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everlasting Story of Nory , by Nicholson Baker</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cities</ENAMEX> of the
Plain , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cormac McCarthy</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Identity</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milan Kundera</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Asher</ENAMEX>.

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">13:</TIMEX>

            Movie<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Deep</ENAMEX>
Impact ;

            Movie-- Character ;

            Music-- Into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Lennon</ENAMEX>;

            Book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Titan: The Life and</ENAMEX>
Times of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Rockefeller</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Chernow</ENAMEX>;

            Book<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Time of Our</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>;

            Book-- A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Widow</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One Year</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Irving</ENAMEX>.

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- He Got
Game ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mis√©rables</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer Movie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundup</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newsmagazine Roundup</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Easy Riders</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raging Bulls</ENAMEX>: How the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sex-Drugs-and-Rock 'n' Roll Generation Saved</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Biskind</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manifesto</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Marx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Engels</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- The Judas Kiss</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX>
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Sliding

               Doors ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX>

               Gate , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Stone</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Other Powers</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age of Suffrage, Spiritualism</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scandalous Victoria Woodhull</ENAMEX> , by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Goldsmith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Notorious Victoria: The Life of Victoria</ENAMEX>
Woodhull , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncensored</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Gabriel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algonquin</ENAMEX>).

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calder</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898-1976</TIMEX>";

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Opera --Kirov Opera</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
