
   
   
      
         
            

            A civil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> liable in the wrongful-death and battery-related
charges brought against him by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. The unanimous
verdict was less surprising than the whopping <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.5 million</NUMEX> in compensatory
damages the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>. Whereas the cynical
view of the criminal trial was that a black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> ignored its instructions by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acquitting Simpson</ENAMEX> in order to sock it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, the cynical
view of the civil trial is that a white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> ignored its instructions by
inflating the compensatory-damage figure in order to sock it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reporters</ENAMEX>, however, scrupulously pointed out that a civil trial only requires
proof by a "preponderance of evidence" rather than proof "beyond a reasonable
doubt." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have always believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> guilty took the civil
verdict as vindication of that belief. The spin on the trial is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> did
himself in by contradicting photographic evidence and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>'
testimony on the stand. Next comes a short hearing in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> will
decide the punitive damages. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> agree that while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> has several
good grounds for appeal, none of them is good enough. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/5</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> delivered his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Pundits</ENAMEX>
found it long on grand exhortations but short on government action, confirming
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s rightward drift. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Apple</ENAMEX>, speaking for
many, pointed out the incongruity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s call to action at a time when
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> faces no great threat. (Thesis sound bite from the speech: "The enemy
of our time is inaction.") The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> topics that caught the most attention were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s pleas for racial reconciliation and a crusade to raise educational
standards. The good news: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Reviewers</ENAMEX> deemed it his best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX>
speech so far. The bad news: It was completely overshadowed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> verdict , which came down simultaneously. Television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> forced
themselves to cover the speech, but raced to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> the second it was
over. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Brokaw</ENAMEX> accidentally referred to the deliverer of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican</ENAMEX>
response, (black) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> wagered
that the racial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> reflected in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> verdicts would overwhelm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s noble words to the contrary. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/5</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan Stanley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean Witter</ENAMEX> announced that they will merge. The
combined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entity</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $20 billion</NUMEX> in equity and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$270 billion</NUMEX> in
assets under management, will be the biggest securities <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> in history. The
idea is to combine the strategic savvy of an elite investment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>) with the huge small-investor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clientele</ENAMEX> of a major brokerage house
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dean Witter</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> predicts a frenzy of copycat
marriages in the securities business. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/5</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Duchess of York</ENAMEX> , will be paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> to promote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weight</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watchers</ENAMEX> products in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. Brits are outraged at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fergie</ENAMEX> for debasing her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">royal</ENAMEX> title, particularly since she only married into it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Advertisers</ENAMEX> predict
the sponsorship agreement will be a smashing success: Brits scorn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fergie</ENAMEX> for
her adultery, kinky sexual practices, contempt for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX>, and general
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">infamy</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> love her for precisely the same reasons. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times sees two trends in the deal: the prostitution of the royal family
("The next thing we'll see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX> doing commercials for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Depends</ENAMEX>," says
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> ad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s sick fondness for notorious sinners.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/5</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> agreed to recognize opposition victories in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>'s local elections. His attempt to annul them had triggered an
uprising that increasingly threatens to force him from power. The pessimistic
view, based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s history of deceit, is that he's only faking the
retreat because he's on the verge of losing control. The optimistic view is
that he's serious about it, for the same reason. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/5</NUMEX>)
            

            There
were new breaks in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> campaign-finance scandal . The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX>-connected stock swindler had been
invited to one of the infamous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> klatches. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX> reported that the new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> finance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>
had lobbied for regulatory breaks for nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> while he was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) a
nursing-home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) raising big money for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>
had it that former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Ickes</ENAMEX> had asked for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">donation</ENAMEX>, part of which was to go to a tax-exempt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> (which, if true,
is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich Heresy</ENAMEX>). Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> has subpoenaed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX>, and others in its investigation of possible
contributions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>, which are generally illegal. (See "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gist</ENAMEX>" from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX>)
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/3</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> leaked its new budget proposal . The key items are
tax cuts for education and for capital gains on the sale of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> congratulated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for moving in their direction but chided him
for not going far enough. Chat-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> gagged on the talk of bipartisan
harmony and tried to egg the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> into a fight, with little success.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/3</NUMEX>)
            

            The
progress of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> nominations was a mixed story. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Only two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Herman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lake</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>), have been pulled over
for closer inspection. The latest word is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman</ENAMEX> will get through (having
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mollified Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>), while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX> is in more serious
trouble. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> problems: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) his (inadvertent, he says) failure to sell
some energy stocks in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, when he became national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adviser</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> alarm that he might be a dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lefty</ENAMEX>, based on his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>
resignation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security Council</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>'s invasion of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambodia</ENAMEX>, and on his more recent refusal to confirm that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alger Hiss</ENAMEX> was a staff
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/3</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Welfare reform was the hot topic at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Governors</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> meeting. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> supported
restoration of aid to legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> (which was cut in the new welfare law).
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> reportedly hit the roof over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">defection</ENAMEX> and, under that pressure, they fudged their stand somewhat. But a
similar fuss is expected over a cap on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> are
considering. As with welfare, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> will have to pick up part of the bill.
Conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> complain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX> are chickening
out on the principle of returning authority to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> now that it's costing
them money. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> are gloating for the same reason. The popular bet now is
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governors</ENAMEX>' refusal to let go of the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teat</ENAMEX> will doom
ratification of the balanced-budget constitutional amendment. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/3</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coalition</ENAMEX> unveiled the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samaritan Project</ENAMEX>," a
public/private package of proposals to aid inner-city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX>. The
proposals include abstinence education, school vouchers for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>,
faith-based <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX>-rehabilitation programs, and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> tax credit for anyone who
does <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 hours</TIMEX> of volunteer work for the poor during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX>
construed the project as a coalition bid for mainstream credibility; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> portrayed it as a halfhearted repackaging of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coalition</ENAMEX>'s standard fare. Although coalition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Reed</ENAMEX> described the
project as a private alternative to government programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> noted that
it depends on some <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 billion</NUMEX> in government spending and lost revenue. Civil
libertarians denounced it as an improper church-state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX>, a sectarian
scheme to milk the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>, and a feel-good diversion from the rest of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coalition</ENAMEX>'s agenda. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/31</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s human-rights record worsened in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has stifled every remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissident</ENAMEX> through
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exile</ENAMEX>, imprisonment, or intimidation. The report also cites <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s transparent
intentions to abolish <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>'s civil liberties when it assumes control of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">territory</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>. Questioned about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> at his press conference,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> admitted for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that his
"constructive-engagement" policy hasn't improved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s behavior, but he
maintained that it will in the future. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Editorialists</ENAMEX> applauded his candor but
dismissed him as timid and naive. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/31</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> installment of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Wars Trilogy Special Edition</ENAMEX>" opened in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">theaters</ENAMEX> everywhere. The original Star Wars , sporting touched-up audio
and new visual effects, will soon be followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Empire Strikes Back</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Return of the Jedi</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are bubbling with nostalgia for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s nostalgia. The fairy-tale version of the Star Wars legacy,
promulgated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most of this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">retrospectives</ENAMEX>/reviews, is that it
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reacquainted America</ENAMEX> with the magic of myth, sacred lore, and the romantic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quest</ENAMEX>. The less reverent version is that it launched the era of gaudy action
movies and movie-based mass merchandising, and that its carefully scripted
revival--complete with licensing deals for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tacos</ENAMEX>, toys, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmas</ENAMEX>
ornaments--does it perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/31</NUMEX>)
            

            Straws
in the wind: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santeria</ENAMEX> , the West
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> religion notorious for animal sacrifice, is gaining <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> adherents
and coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>. New studies show that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) one in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> can't vote because of a felony conviction; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Midwest</ENAMEX> are more segregated than those in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> now have
a higher poverty rate than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. Government figures indicate that cigarette
consumption is holding steady and may be rising. Sales of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruno Magli</ENAMEX>
shoes are up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientist-temps</ENAMEX> are becoming more common
in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . Reports of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">deformed frogs</ENAMEX> are spreading across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> warns that this may be an "early warning sign" of an emerging
environmental peril. Medical advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are pushing a home test for
colorectal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>; it requires <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to collect <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fecal samples</ENAMEX> and mail
them to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that despite the best
efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>, the cryonics industry remains lifeless. On the bright
side, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twinkies</ENAMEX> are making a comeback. And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astrologer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeane Dixon</ENAMEX> died of a heart attack <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25</TIMEX>, exactly as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>
had predicted. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/31</NUMEX>)
            

            Stock-market index
funds made Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> news in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> . Mutual-fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> are increasingly shifting their investments
from traditional managed funds--which try to outsmart the whole market at
picking stocks--to index funds, which distribute their assets evenly and ride
the market's rising average. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>, the index strategy has triumphed
because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) stock-picking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> charge more in fees than they've added in
above-average performance, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> often keep some money in
steadier cash and bonds to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in the event of a market plunge.
The news accounts portrayed managed-fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">unproductive leeches</ENAMEX> in
comparison with index-fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mangers</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1/29</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
