
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Grease
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1950s</NUMEX> nostalgia film, panned when it was
released in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>, fares better on re-release as a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1970s</NUMEX> nostalgia film.
The remastered version takes in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its first weekend</TIMEX>, just behind
Titanic at the box office. Critics also come around. "As timeless as its
bad-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>-meets-good-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> plot" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). Most
reviewers celebrate the career of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>, then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23</TIMEX>: "an
invaluable cultural icon ... an important and enduring movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
Ebert, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lisa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX> discovers latent homosexuality in the "intense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy-boy</ENAMEX> communion"
within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travolta</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newton Boys</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). A lukewarm response to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dazed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Confused director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Linklater</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> venture beyond Gen
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">X.</ENAMEX> His western about the most accomplished bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">robbers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> history is
faulted for lacking the conventions--exciting chase scenes, gunfights, and
black-hatted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">villains</ENAMEX>--that give the genre its enduring appeal. The characters
played by young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew McConaughey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Hawke</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent D'Onofrio</ENAMEX>
are said to suffer in comparison to the real-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, clips of whom
Linklater weaves into the film. "It's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bland Boys</ENAMEX> almost all the way" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy</ENAMEX>
Taubin, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ). (A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> is available here.)

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  From
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moon</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>; click here for
schedule). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Apollo</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> produces a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$68 million</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 hour</TIMEX>
docudrama about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>, from the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> launch (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>) to the last moon
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">voyage</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> declare it a noble failure. They're taken with its
enthusiasm for space exploration, which has lost its mystique since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX>.
But they also say the series is "too long, too prolix, too cable" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ) and gets bogged down in irrelevant details. In one
episode, notes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Collins</ENAMEX>, "the only source of suspense ... is
a worry over the winds on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> of lift-off." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> plugs the show here.)

            

               
                  Teletubbies
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>; click here for schedule).
Controversy over this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> show, just reaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> itself as the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> program for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. Is the show, about
the picaresque adventures of futuristic toddlers, bad for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">& World Report</ENAMEX> cites <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychologists</ENAMEX> who argue that it will addict babies
to television, hindering their mental development. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> calls
Teletubbies a marketing ploy cloaked as education. Others find camp
virtues in the "sublimely ridiculous experience" of the show (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucker</ENAMEX>) and note
that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> it has a large following with gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>.

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The
Sound of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Beck Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> find no
reason for this revival of the treacly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> musical. "The most saccharine of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>" collaborations, says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX>.
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> grant that this production benefits from some nuanced
performances, they still conclude that "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Sound of Music</ENAMEX> isn't really
for grown-ups" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). They predict
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> will continue to devour the show's sentimental story anyway.

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">True Travels and Adventures of Lidie Newton</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Smiley</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). After writing a polemical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> essay attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huckleberry Finn</ENAMEX>
as immoral, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer Prize</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner Smiley</ENAMEX> sets out to improve on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twain</ENAMEX> with a
novel about an abolitionist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in antebellum <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas Territory</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> don't
like the book any more than the essay. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Mallon faults Lidie Newton</ENAMEX> for "dutiful caricatures of white
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">degeneracy</ENAMEX> and black nobility ... the purest P.C." 
                  Slate
               's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerr</ENAMEX> says that "for someone so bent on unmasking pieties, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smiley</ENAMEX> is not
above her own kind of sanctimony." (To read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chapters</ENAMEX>, click
here.)

            

               
                  Consilience: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity of Knowledge</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.O. Wilson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">famed Harvard</ENAMEX> sociobiologist argues that all phenomena--art, economics,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX>--can be understood by studying the brain's neural pathways. Critics
line up on opposing sides. Some praise his emphasis on biology as "a strong
antidote to the trendy campus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fatalists</ENAMEX> who hold truth to be subjective" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.Z.</ENAMEX>
Sheppard, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Skeptics</ENAMEX> renew old attacks on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sociobiology</TIMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX>-encompassing view of human nature. "He is the Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magoo</ENAMEX> of scientific
theory, genially oblivious to everything he can't or won't see" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel</ENAMEX>
Mendelsohn, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> ). (In 
                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>
praises the book. Click here to read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

            

               Fashion
            

            
               Fall
Lines . The unveiling of fall lines in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three weeks</TIMEX>--accompanied by unprecedented cable TV coverage--leads the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Time</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">s'</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth La Ferla</ENAMEX> to declare <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">runway</ENAMEX> shows "the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spectator</ENAMEX>
sport of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s lines are noted for representing a backlash
against feminism--"fashion's new womanliness," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's Ginia Bellafante
calls it--with a return to pinks, pleats, and furs. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> fault the
younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> for not taking risks, preferring the continuing inventiveness
of such <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Lagerfeld</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Valentino</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Paul Gaultier</ENAMEX>.
(
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Hollander</ENAMEX> explains the pleasures of the runway
show.)

            

               Update
            

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar-</ENAMEX>winning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cameron</ENAMEX>
savages the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s chief movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, for panning his movie on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> separate occasions. "Nobody's interested in the vitriolic ravings of a
bitter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who attacks and rips apart movies that the great majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>
find well worth their time and money."

            
               Recent "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>"
columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25:</TIMEX>

            

               Event --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Academy Awards</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- Sitcom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundup</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Primary
Colors ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Wild</ENAMEX>
Things ;

            
               Movie -- Taste of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cherry</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cabaret</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lohengrin</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Man in</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron Mask</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Love and</ENAMEX>
Death on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Men With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lateline</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- Significant 
               Others (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilgrim</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Clapton</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cycle: Inside the Clinton Propaganda Machine</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Halberstam</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebowski</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Primary
Colors hype;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Twilight</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshals</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beauty Queen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leenane</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- One Nation</ENAMEX>,
After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Wolfe</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- A History of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Johnson</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smithee Film: Burn Hollywood Burn</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krippendorf</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tribe</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lolita</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> of
Light , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian Institution</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Close"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>).

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
