
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The
Capeman
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Marquis Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). The eagerly awaited but
troubled collaboration of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer-songwriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Simon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Walcott</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">choreographer Mark Morris</ENAMEX> is judged to be worse than expected. "It's like
watching a mortally wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brantley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say the show, about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Puerto Rican</ENAMEX> teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang member</ENAMEX> and
convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>, fails to make its protagonist sympathetic even as it
moralizes smugly about racism. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>'s score, a combination of salsa and '50s
doo-wop, is singled out for praise. "There's more musical invention in a song
like 'Trailways <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bus</ENAMEX>' than in the entire score of the much ballyhooed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragtime</ENAMEX> ," says 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Steyn</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Sideshow:</ENAMEX>
Picketers castigated the show for glorifying a killer. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audio</ENAMEX> clips are
available here.)

            

               Television
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-Sex<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-Scandal Coverage</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> rail against irresponsible
reporting on the scandal but admit that they like watching it. Their main
points: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24-hour</TIMEX> news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX>' unremitting coverage made the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX>'
nightly broadcasts look "more like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaurs</ENAMEX> than ever" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Fretts</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Because the story's main outline emerged so
fast, it lacked the sustaining drama of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ginsburg</ENAMEX> appeared on too many talk shows,
discrediting themselves as publicity whores. (
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Jacob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisberg</ENAMEX> has a different take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginsburg</ENAMEX> and the talk-show circuit. Click
here
for his "dispatch" on the subject.) <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s apologies for their
excessive coverage were on target but tiresome. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Donaldson</ENAMEX>, who returned
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> beat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> before the scandal, thrives out in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX>, not in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawson's Creek</ENAMEX>
                (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). The fledgling WB
network hopes that this prime-time teen soap opera, alongside its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult</ENAMEX> hit
Buffy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vampire Slayer</ENAMEX> , will launch it toward <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>-like legitimacy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> scoff. They profess revulsion at such vulgar subplots as a high-school
student's affair with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> who masturbates while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">watching Katie Couric</ENAMEX>. "It makes Melrose Place look like Petticoat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junction</ENAMEX> ," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Marin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> say the show is
long on pop-culture allusions and short on psychological acumen. "My
So-Called Life without the life" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ).
(The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX> plugs the show.)

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Expectations</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> aren't
buying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonso Cuarón</ENAMEX>'s transposition of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Dickens</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1861</TIMEX> novel to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">present-day Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. It "plays like a dead battery disguised as an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">objet d'art "</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). They are especially
irked by the movie's artsy pretensions (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pip</ENAMEX> is turned into a tortured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>)
and earnestness (its un-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickensian</ENAMEX> fulminations about undying love), as well as
flat performances by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Hawke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cuarón</ENAMEX> is praised as
"a voluptuous visual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stylist</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) who
turns in beautiful shots of beaches and the naked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paltrow</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            

               
                  Desperate Measures
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TriStar Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Keaton</ENAMEX> is said to
waste an intense performance on a silly film. He plays a psychotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX>
hunted by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Garcia</ENAMEX>) who needs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keaton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone marrow</ENAMEX> to save his dying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. Aside from an absurd premise that "most TV medical dramas would wrap up in
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20 minutes</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ), the film is riddled with
overwrought hospital scenes and numbing car chases--"clichés that mount like
fallen bricks" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>
Libre
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmore Leonard</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delacorte</ENAMEX>). Acclaim for the pulp-fiction
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">34 th</NUMEX> novel. Set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> war,
the novel is part Western (the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Tyler</ENAMEX>, is an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> cowboy)
and part noir (he's in on an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>-smuggling scam gone bad). The book is said to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">display Leonard</ENAMEX>'s usual "flair for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and capers" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ) and period detail. Dissenting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pico Iyer</ENAMEX> finds <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX> Libre vapid: "The central moral
question raised ... is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler</ENAMEX> should be played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Val Kilmer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX>."

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Gun</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nadine Gordimer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel</ENAMEX>
Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> produces a clunker: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say she's stuck in
pre-democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>. "She has yet to come to terms, artistically ...
with her <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s drastically changed landscape" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ). Tired harangues about capital punishment and gun control are
said to come at the expense of developing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, who "don't behave
like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn See</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). Others pay the
customary obeisance to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gordimer</ENAMEX>'s nuanced depiction of morally confused white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, in this case an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> whose son is accused of murder.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Wag the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Gingerbread
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX>
World ;

            
               Book -- Birthday
Letters , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Night</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Train</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Enduring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McEwan</ENAMEX>;

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXXII</ENAMEX>;

            

               Dance --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Baryshnikov</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evening of Music and Dance With the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Oak Chamber Ensemble</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- Fallen ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Sundance Film</ENAMEX>
Festival;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Live</ENAMEX>
Flesh ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Musical</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragtime</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pillar</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fire: America in the King Years</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963-65</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor Branch</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shadows</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Bashevis Singer</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>);

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arthur Dove: A Retrospective"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14:</TIMEX>

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>
Bono;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Prayer</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz Bissinger</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Frazier</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Drucker</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Beatty</ENAMEX>;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afterglow</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Arguing the
World ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Ma Vie en Rose</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boxer</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capote: In Which Various Friends, Enemies, Acquaintances, and Detractors Recall</ENAMEX>
His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turbulent</ENAMEX> Career , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Plimpton</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music --"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
Lights<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: The Music of Jean Sibelius</ENAMEX>."

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
