
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Rounders
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' darlings (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Malkovich</ENAMEX>) fails to win this poker movie
much-hoped-for rave reviews. Individual performances are said to be inspired;
the card hall settings are said to be gritty; the dialogue is said to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pleasingly</ENAMEX> peppered with <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">poker jargon</ENAMEX>--but the film is deemed "unable to do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justice</ENAMEX> to its potential" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ).
Objections: a sluggish plot and a predictable setup. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> call the film
"snappy and ingratiating" (
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>) and
"completely enjoyable and, at its climactic moments, thrilling" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>). (Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denby's</ENAMEX>. Or read this interview with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norton</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  One
True Thing
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Renée Zellweger</ENAMEX> as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> forced to reconcile in the face of grave illness earn
praise in this "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> yuppie Terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endearment</ENAMEX> " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The film is based on a novel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Quindlen</ENAMEX> and,
though small, is said to be emotionally powerful. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> interviews with the stars
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of this film.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX>
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birch</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> agree that this
"reduction" of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Irving</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Prayer</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Meany</ENAMEX> is--in the unkind
words of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Harvey</ENAMEX>--"syrupy hash." Large parts of the
complicated plot and all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Irving</ENAMEX>'s dark humor have been excised, resulting in
the loss of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s blessing and the right to use the novel's name. What's
left is a string of corny adventures shared by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, one of whom
believes he is on a special mission from God. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minority</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> praise the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>, most notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Siskel</ENAMEX>, who gives it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and calls it "one of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s best" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> ). (Read an interview with small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Michael Smith</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Touch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). Based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orson Welles</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX>
page memo detailing his objections to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s cut of his
much-tinkered-with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1958</TIMEX> noir classic, this re-edited version "unspools with all
the complex, unnerving menace and nihilistic subtext its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX> had in
mind all along" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> take
the occasion to rethink the movie itself: "A jammed, discordant, discomforting
experience--a nightmare, in fact, but a nightmare that <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">leaves</ENAMEX> in the wake of
many complications a moral significance of disturbing perversity and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brilliance</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denby</ENAMEX>). "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX> was at the peak of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> in Touch of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> , but let's never forget what an abrasive, high-wire, self-destructive
talent he was" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>). (Read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denby's</ENAMEX>. Find out more about the alternate versions of this film.)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frank</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melissa Müller</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Books</ENAMEX>). In researching this
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biography</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Müller</ENAMEX> came across <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> additional pages of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX>'s original
diary that had been removed by her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> before publication, largely because
they reveal unhappy details of his marriage. These pages overshadow the
contents of the biography in news coverage of the book, but those who do
comment call it "superb" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Shapiro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). (This page of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX>-related links includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catherine Bernard</ENAMEX>'s essay "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cultivation of the Inspirational Victim</ENAMEX>.")

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Mechanical
                <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Manson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nothing/Interscope</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heretofore</ENAMEX> dismissed as "a freak show accompanied by a soundtrack" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorraine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> comes out with an album that is
"wickedly engaging" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N'Gai Croal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). The music is said to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX> and intense, full of pomp and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'70s</ENAMEX> style high-glam <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">à la Ziggy Stardust</ENAMEX>.
The lyrics are the usual--<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, grim humor, self-hatred, sci-fi sex--but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manson</ENAMEX> is "no longer instantly dismissible as scam <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> or sight gag" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim</ENAMEX>
Farber, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> ). (Check out audio and video clips from the album.)

            

               
                  Teatro
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Nelson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Island</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nelson's</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">214</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
album. All his trademark "stark, heart-tugging" lyrics (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hunt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> ), plus more musical frills than expected. Producer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Lanois</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dylan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Time Out of Mind</ENAMEX> ) is given credit for pushing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>'s sound in
unfamiliar directions. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call it his "best album in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scherman, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Others are bemused by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lanois</ENAMEX>' addition
of xylophones, organ, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> rhythm, and atmospheric hoopla. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Ratliff</ENAMEX> marks the appearance of what he calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>'s "first
trip-hop" song. (Listen to clips from this album.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Without
Limits ;

            
               Movie -- Knock
Off ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next Stop</ENAMEX>
Wonderland ;

            
               Death --Akira
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kurosawa</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professor</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Madman</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Winchester</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- At Home in the World</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Blade</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie--
               Why Do Fools
Fall in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farming</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bones</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edwidge Danticat</ENAMEX>;

            

               Music--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Miseducation of Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance With</ENAMEX>
Me ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Your Friends</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Neighbors</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Unmade
Beds ;

            
               Television -- The

               Rat 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pack</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Hillerman</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deliverance: A Memoir of Father and Son</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Dickey</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- Kaaterskill 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegra Goodman</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avengers</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie--
               Return to
Paradise ;

            
               Movie--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slums of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Music--
               Whitechocolatespaceegg , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Phair</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> of
Spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward L. Bernays</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birth of Public Relations</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tye</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book--
               Philistines
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hedgerow: Passion and Property in the Hamptons</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaines</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
