
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The
X-Files
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> deem the hit show's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX> film adaptation a "glorified TV episode" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd McCarthy</ENAMEX>,
Variety ). Some attack its incomprehensibly labyrinthine plot, which is
wrapped around an alien-government conspiracy. "A narrative as obtuse as a tax
form" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Kempley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). Others praise its stylish,
dark colors; terse dialogue; and self-referential humor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Agents</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mulder</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duchovny</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scully</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillian Anderson</ENAMEX>) win praise for ratcheting up the sexual
tension, a central part of the TV show's appeal. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> reviewed the
film in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Movies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Film Institute</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>'s list of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">100 best</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> films (as chosen by a poll of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 1,500</NUMEX> "prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>")
pleases no one. Only the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen Kane</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casablanca</ENAMEX> , win unanimous approval. The main gripes: The list rates
living filmmakers (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX>) above great dead ones (no
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preston Sturges</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buster Keaton</ENAMEX>). Recent <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> fare such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gump</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> rank ahead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of classics
(nothing by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard Hawks</ENAMEX> appears higher than No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">97</NUMEX>). Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call the
list a marketing device for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>--which fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>--to sell videos. "AFI
went with the money" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (See the full list. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culturebox</ENAMEX>" has its own complaints with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFI</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Mulan
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney's</ENAMEX> animation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> rebounds from a series
of disappointments ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pocahontas</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hercules</ENAMEX> ) with a feature based on
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> legend about a cross-dressing female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warrior</ENAMEX>, winning praise for
featuring a proto-feminist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX> instead of its usual submissive maidens.
Other trumpeted virtues: A minimalist aesthetic inspired by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> art, and a
wisecracking sidekick, whose voice is provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Murphy</ENAMEX>. One dissenter,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, chides the film's political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">correctness</ENAMEX> and bland score: "the most inert and formulaic of recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
animated films." (Visit the official site.)

            

               Art
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Ray"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> bash the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">postmodern artist</ENAMEX> on the occasion of his midcareer retrospective.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s works--including portraits of him masturbating and a fiberglass
re-creation of an auto wreck--are faulted for being self-referential, overly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">clever</ENAMEX>, and emotionless. The hoopla is evidence "that the art world takes
itself way too seriously" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kimmelman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX> cites the inflation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s reputation as evidence
of declining expectations for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>: "Small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bass</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> carp are
treated as potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moby Dicks</ENAMEX>." (Get more
information on the exhibit.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Walking With the Wind: A Memoir of the Movement</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lewis</ENAMEX>,
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael D'Orso</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D-Ga.</ENAMEX>,
for his candid memoir of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his days</TIMEX> as a young civil rights radical. They praise
his insights into the tumultuous internal politics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Non-Violent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coordinating Committee</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> he headed. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> mythologize
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>' life as an up-from-sharecropping success story: "Of all the surviving
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX> of the civil rights movement ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> remains most committed to its
original creed" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack White</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate, Brent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> argues the book's real value lies in its revelations of the class
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rivalries</ENAMEX> within the movement.)

            

               
                  Ship of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gold: In the Deep Blue Sea</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Kinder</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Press</ENAMEX>). Overlooking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinder</ENAMEX>'s occasionally clunky prose,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> are enraptured by his page-turning account of an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1857</TIMEX> steamer wreck
and the eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who recovers <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> worth of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> from it. Some
complain it's too much like other recent real-life adventure tales ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Into</ENAMEX>
Thin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air</ENAMEX> , A 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perfect Storm</ENAMEX> ) and disaster stories. "It's a
terrible challenge to interest a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> that's already had Titanic up
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> nostril and out the other" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark Harris, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ).

            
               
                  A
Beautiful Mind
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Nasar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). Unified acclaim
for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Nash</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>, who went mad. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> pioneered game theory, became schizophrenic, recovered,
then won a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> late in life. Reviewers praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasar</ENAMEX> for her clear
explications of recondite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> and marvel at the bizarre details of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disease</ENAMEX> (he rejected a tenure offer because he believed he was about to become
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Antarctica</ENAMEX>). They find it ironic and poignant that someone capable
"of conceiving of a nuanced theory of rationality could descend into madness"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Boynton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Holt</ENAMEX> reviews <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Beautiful Mind in</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Six Days</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seven Nights</TIMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The Opposite
of Sex ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>
Art ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nightingales</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magic Hour</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Gain</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Powers</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>
Show ;

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect</ENAMEX>
Murder ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Sex and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> --The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
Awards;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>
Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX>-Dreamer";

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold New World</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Finnegan</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Last</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Disco</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX>
Floats ;

            
               Television -- More
Tales of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bright Shining Lie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>) and Thanks of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grateful Nation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rothko</ENAMEX>";

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> .

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Godzilla</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Fear and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loathing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes Film</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Festival Roundup</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freedomland</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Price</ENAMEX>;

            
               Books -- Remembering
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: The Invisible Art of Editing</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ved Mehta</ENAMEX>;
Here But Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here: A Love Story</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lillian Ross</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Larry Sanders Show</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>).

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
