
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Event
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">70 th Academy Awards</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>). At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nearly four hours</TIMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> ceremony was longer and more predictable than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> . Despite the
movie's romp to a record-tying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX> awards, the broadcast is still judged "the
most entertaining and painless <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscarfest</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). Credit goes once again to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crystal</ENAMEX> for jokes
about his own flagging career and l'affaire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> . On the downside,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX> were deemed boring: less gothic and showing less cleavage
than usual. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> unanimously zinged <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Director-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cameron</ENAMEX>
for the arrogant "I'm the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> of the world" (a line from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> ) in
his acceptance speech. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s pre- and post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> dispatches.)

            

               Television
            

            
               Sitcom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundup</ENAMEX>. Reviewers dismiss the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">midseason</TIMEX> replacement sitcoms as derivative
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> and not at all funny. "[E]ven the laugh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tracks</ENAMEX> are wondering
what they're laughing at," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin Kitman</ENAMEX>. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franken</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lateline</ENAMEX> is said to have any merit. The other shows--especially
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Rules</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT) and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Guys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">A Girl</ENAMEX> and
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza</ENAMEX> Place (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wednesdays</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT)--are chided for their now
formulaic depictions of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">twentysomething lifestyles</ENAMEX>, replete with tired pop
culture references and "blather ... about relationships and commitment"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shales</ENAMEX>).

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Primary Colors
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> of
hype and raves, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX>' political satire opens to mediocre reviews.
Several newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>--including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>--say the film isn't nearly
as entertaining as reality. Others gripe about the film's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and half hour</TIMEX>
length, its mishmash of a plot, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Travolta</ENAMEX>'s inability to do more than a
"skillful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub impersonation</ENAMEX>" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>,

                  Slate
               ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            

               
                  Wild Things
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). Unexpected praise for this lurid
teen drama. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> like the labyrinthine twists of the story, about two
high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neve Campbell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Richards</ENAMEX>) who accuse their
high-school guidance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counselor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Dillon</ENAMEX>) of rape. But mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> admit
to enjoying the "guilty pleasures, including banzai bikini footage" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ) and "babelicious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbians</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Others wonder how the movie got away with an R
rating and find it lacking even "the saving spark of low art or high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the
official site.)

            

               
                  Taste of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cherry</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reviewers</ENAMEX> rhapsodize over
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbas Kiarostami</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes film festival</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> about a man
contemplating suicide. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiarostami</ENAMEX> "comes as close to defining the sublime
nature of living ... as a filmmaker is ever likely to do" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). They praise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> for his courage in addressing the
subject of suicide, which the theocratic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> generally considers
taboo. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> dissents, suggesting critics
are swooning over this pretentious, sluggish "lifeless drone" for political
reasons. (The official site, available here, has a history of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  Cabaret
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Miller Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Applause for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">32-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Mendes</ENAMEX>' reinterpretation of the musical about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Weimar Germany</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Kander-Ebb</ENAMEX> show to be revived recently
( <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> has been on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mendes</ENAMEX> improves
upon the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> film version of the musical, which starred <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liza Minnelli</ENAMEX>, by
rendering it dark and raunchy. They hail <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natasha Richardson</ENAMEX>'s unglamorous
portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sally Bowles</ENAMEX>--an aging, seedy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bisexual nightclub singer</ENAMEX>--as the
"performance of the season" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissenting</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Rose</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> "can't
phrase a song."

            

               Opera
            

            

               
                  Lohengrin
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Audiences</ENAMEX>
literally boo <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wilson</ENAMEX> for his minimalist staging of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Wagner</ENAMEX>'s classic opera, and most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> agree with the verdict. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX>
uses a stage backdrop of nothing but stark blue and projects bands of white
light across it, while his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> stand almost motionless. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> find
the set dull and the "frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kabuki</ENAMEX> poses ... sadistic" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ). A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>'s boos as evidence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opera-goers</ENAMEX>' conservatism. "Met <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> have shown little interest in any of
the innovations that have transformed opera over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past half century</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
Swed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ).

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Man in</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron Mask</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Love and</ENAMEX>
Death on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Men With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lateline</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- Significant 
               Others (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilgrim</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Clapton</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cycle: Inside the Clinton Propaganda Machine</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Children</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Halberstam</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebowski</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Primary
Colors hype;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Twilight</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshals</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The Beauty
Queen of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leenane</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- One Nation</ENAMEX>,
After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Wolfe</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- A History of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Johnson</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Smithee Film: Burn Hollywood Burn</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krippendorf</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tribe</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lolita</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX> of
Light , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian Institution</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Close"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25:</TIMEX>

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Experience</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wedding</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- The
Closer (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>);

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palmetto</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cloudsplitter</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Banks</ENAMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernand LÃ</ENAMEX>©ger"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>);

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freak</ENAMEX> .

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
