
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Without Limits
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> biopic about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">record-breaking superstar runner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Prefontaine</ENAMEX> is deemed worthier than its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Prefontaine</ENAMEX> . "[A] richly intimate sports fable," says
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crudup</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prefontaine</ENAMEX>)
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Sutherland</ENAMEX> (as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bowerman</ENAMEX>) are said to be at the top of
their game. So is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> and co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Towne</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Personal Best</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinatown</ENAMEX> ), who "holds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enigma</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prefontaine</ENAMEX>'s self-propulsion up to
the light, turns it this way and that, and then wisely leaves us more or less
in the dark" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daphne Merkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). (Explore this collection of photos of the
real <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prefontaine</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  Knock Off
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Entertainment/TriStar Pictures</ENAMEX>). The
only film released on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day weekend</TIMEX>, the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Claude Van Damme</ENAMEX>
vehicle is trashed for its preposterous plot: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mafia</ENAMEX> has put
miniature bombs in the buttons of jeans in order to blackmail the world. "Pay
up, or your pants explode," as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Kehr</ENAMEX> puts it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Directing</ENAMEX> (by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hark Tsui</ENAMEX>) and cinematography are said to be imaginative and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> scenery interesting, but the performance of "the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX> blowhard"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Dreher</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ) is dismal. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX> disagrees, calling it "one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Van Damme</ENAMEX>'s best movies
ever." (Visit the official site .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next Stop Wonderland</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer-director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Anderson</ENAMEX>'s "beguiling, if slight" film (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah Rozen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ). It follows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> interesting but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely singles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope Davis</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Gelfant</ENAMEX>) who keep almost meeting each other around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
admire the witty "amused sense of yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tragicomedy</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ), others say the film "isn't really much more than
a beautifully acted, finely edited sitcom" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). Everyone loves the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> bossa nova soundtrack. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> more
about the film on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sundance</ENAMEX> Web site.)

            

               Death
            

            
               Akira Kurosawa
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910-1998</TIMEX>). The legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of such films as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashomon</ENAMEX> ,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven Samurai</ENAMEX> , and Ran is canonized: "one of the handful of
truly important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> has produced" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Lyman</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX> calls him "the pictorial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> of our
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>." A perfectionist and demanding taskmaster--he was often referred to as
"the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emperor</ENAMEX>"--he was more popular abroad than at home and late in his career
had to ask foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX> for financial backing. Also
noted are hints of nationalism in his last few films, which were not as well
received as his early masterpieces. (Here is a complete listing of his filmography.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Madman: A Tale of Murder, Insanity, and the Making of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oxford English Dictionary</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon Winchester</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>). A dual
biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Murray</ENAMEX>, the primary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford English</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dictionary</ENAMEX> , and his most prolific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contributor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W.C. Minor</ENAMEX>, a convicted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderer</ENAMEX> who spent most of his life in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> for the criminally insane.
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he linguistic detective story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the decade</TIMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> . Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> concur. Quibbles: Doubts are
raised about explanations offered for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor</ENAMEX>'s sexual mania, which tormented him
so severely that he amputated his penis. Also considered a stretch is the
suggestion of romance between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minor</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>. (You can
buy this book at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  At
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Home</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">World: A Memoir</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Maynard</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Picador</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> reaction
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX>'s memoir, based mainly on a pre-publication excerpt in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> : instant dismissal. The crimes against taste of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX> is
accused include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) cashing in on her former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">paramour</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.D. Salinger</ENAMEX>'s fame (she
held out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before dishing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> on him); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) not respecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinger</ENAMEX>'s
fanatically guarded privacy; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) bad writing; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) self-importance. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>
wave of reviews amount to a backlash against the backlash. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> says the book "is not a sleazy tell-all
memoir" and is a "leap forward in maturity and emotional candor." In the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katha Pollitt</ENAMEX> calls the book "riveting and
disturbing," though she adds, "I often found myself wondering how much of her
own story <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX> understands." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX>'s life on her
photo-filled Web
page.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Blade</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie--
               Why Do
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fools Fall in Love</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">54</NUMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farming</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bones</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edwidge Danticat</ENAMEX>;

            

               Music--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Miseducation of Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance With</ENAMEX>
Me ;

            
               Movie -- Your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends & Neighbors</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Unmade
Beds ;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rat Pack</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Hillerman</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deliverance: A Memoir of Father and Son</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Dickey</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaaterskill Falls</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegra Goodman</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avengers</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie--
               Return to
Paradise ;

            
               Movie--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slums</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Music--
               Whitechocolatespaceegg , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Phair</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Father</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward L. Bernays</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birth of Public Relations</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tye</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book--
               Philistines at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedgerow</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passion</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Property</ENAMEX> in the
Hamptons , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven S. Gaines</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
               Snake
Eyes ;

            
               Movie--
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Halloween:</ENAMEX>
H20 ;

            
               Movie -- How <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX>
Got <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her Groove Back</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainbow</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J</ENAMEX> erry
Seinfeld: I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Telling You for the Last Time--Live</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upright Citizens Brigade</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>).

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
