
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winter Movie Roundup</ENAMEX>

             

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Brown</ENAMEX>
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX>'s first film since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp Fiction</ENAMEX> reinforces
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>' mixed opinion of him as clever but self-indulgent. His trademark
dialogue--street toughs riffing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about daily</TIMEX> trivia with pseudoprofundity--still
delights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. They also welcome his rehabilitation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">'70s</ENAMEX> blaxploitation
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heroine Pam Grier</ENAMEX>, who stars as a money-laundering stewardess trying to scam
both her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel L. Jackson</ENAMEX>) and a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Keaton</ENAMEX>). But
most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Brown</ENAMEX> lacks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp Fiction</ENAMEX> 's inventiveness
and drags on too long (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 and a half hours</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarantino</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, has taken "one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elmore Leonard's</ENAMEX> lesser novels and draw[n] it
out as if it were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>." (
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> likes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Brown</ENAMEX> . And click here for the official site.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX>
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics crown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Levinson</ENAMEX>'s film the wittiest of the
recent political comedies. A spin <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert De Niro</ENAMEX>) and a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
producer (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX>) orchestrate a fake war to divert attention from a
presidential sex scandal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX> is said to have given "one of the most subtle
and precise comic performances ... since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tootsie</ENAMEX> " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). Critics also like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>'s screenplay for its
jabs at the news media, out-of-touch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>, and "everything that's awful in
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> life nowadays" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissenting</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daphne Merkin</ENAMEX> bemoans the film's "sophomoric" humor and its "cozy,
video-ready cynicism." (See the official site. Also see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s dissection of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s narcissistic take on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  As <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good As It</ENAMEX>
Gets
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony/TriStar</ENAMEX>). Reviewers split over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James L. Brooks</ENAMEX>' romantic
comedy about an obsessive-compulsive, misanthropic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Nicholson</ENAMEX>) and
a struggling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waitress</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Hunt</ENAMEX>). Some say it "echoes the quirky appeal of
[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>'] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadcast News</ENAMEX> " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) and
call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholson</ENAMEX>'s performance his best in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Others say the film's schmaltzy
dialogue and contrived plot have the "staying power of cotton candy" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merkin</ENAMEX>,
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> plugs the
film.)

            
               
                  The Postman
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). Near-unanimity on the verdict: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actor-director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX>'s
latest is "truly awful" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The
post-apocalyptic Western about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mailmen</ENAMEX> who save the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> is
faulted for its ridiculous premise, mawkish dialogue, and megalomaniacal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">directing</ENAMEX>, among other things. It would have been "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half-hour</TIMEX> shorter without
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costner</ENAMEX>'s close-ups of his own horizon-scanning mug," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Kempley</ENAMEX>. Some hope the film will convince <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> to
stop letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> direct. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> is available here.)

             

            
               
                  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX> Never
Dies
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM/United Artists</ENAMEX>). Despite a critical drubbing, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">18 th</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bond</ENAMEX> film still grossed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$66 million</NUMEX> in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> say the film, a "conventional techno-thiller" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ), lacks its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">predecessors</ENAMEX>' tongue-in-cheek charm,
and they insist it's time to retire the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond</ENAMEX> franchise. As the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> Bond,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce Brosnan</ENAMEX> is said to be debonair but not strong enough to overcome the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s clichés. Another common complaint: egregious product placements--"enough
blatant endorsements to make the film itself incidental" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). (An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> site celebrates the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bond</ENAMEX> franchise.)

            
               
                  Kundun
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Touchstone Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics pronounce</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX>'s biopic about the
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> beautiful but dull. They admire the film's scenic mountain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">vistas</ENAMEX> and elegiac tone, saying the latter resembles "a meditative and
incantatory piece of music" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pico Iyer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> ).
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> respectfully note that the lack of a plot and the lengthy scenes
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> in prayer don't make for high excitement. "[E]verything a
movie about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> should be except dramatically involving" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
Turan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Menand</ENAMEX> says
that despite surface differences, it's just another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">flick:</ENAMEX>
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kundun</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Casino</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhists</ENAMEX>." (See 
                  Slate
               's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX> and the film's site.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24:</TIMEX>

            "The Year
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review in Review</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Scream
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Ally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBeal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>);

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Hogarth: A Life and a World</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenny Uglow</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amistad</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Good Will</ENAMEX>
Hunting ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amistad</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book -- A Certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.D. James</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:</TIMEX>

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
Neighborhood , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flubber</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Welcome to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarajevo</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
Housing (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Release 2.0</ENAMEX>:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Design for Living</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Age</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Dyson</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photography</ENAMEX> --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weegee's World: Life, Death, and the Human Drama</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Center of Photography Midtown</ENAMEX>).

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
