
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  My
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> wonder why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crystal</ENAMEX>'s recent
movies aren't as funny as his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX>-night performances. This time they say he
is outperformed by co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gheorghe Muresan</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7-foot-7-inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> player
who can hardly speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX>. They say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX> tries too hard to be likable
even though his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> is a slimy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> who exploits <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muresan</ENAMEX>.
Others blame the story, co-written by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crystal</ENAMEX>, for its facile morality lessons.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy</ENAMEX> and pathos keep getting in each other's way," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clips</ENAMEX> are available here.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lukewarm</ENAMEX> reviews for a remake of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wim Wenders</ENAMEX>' art film Wings of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Desire</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>). "As
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">literate</ENAMEX> and understated as one could expect" from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pluses</ENAMEX>: beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panoramas</ENAMEX> of Los Angeles
and great chemistry between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minuses</ENAMEX>: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s New Age spirituality, its sentimental ending, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>'s lack of acting
range. He speaks, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, in "a hushed,
gee-whiz semi-whisper that's meant to convey profundity but ... sounds like the
shallow come-on of a cult <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official
site.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big One</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). Another documentary in which left-wing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">provocateur Michael Moore</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger & Me</ENAMEX> ) hounds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX>. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> love his pointed satire, especially such antics as offering <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nike</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> a free ticket to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX> so he can visit his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s sweatshops
there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>'s shtick, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>,
"shows more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> enterprise than anything it's attacking." Others find
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> self-aggrandizing. This film is "about the upsizing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Moore</ENAMEX>,"
who is guilty of "oily smugness and sublime narcissism" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave New World</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 19</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). Applause
for the made-for-TV version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldous Huxley</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX> dystopian novel. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX>
like its fidelity to the book and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Nimoy</ENAMEX>'s turn as an apparatchik. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> amazement at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huxley</ENAMEX>'s uncanny foresight. "Certain features of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huxley</ENAMEX>'s
imagined universe--set <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six centuries</TIMEX> into the future--would in fact become
realities within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few decades</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Rabinowitz</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissenting</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leonard</ENAMEX> says the show
gratuitously injects a happy ending and melodrama: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huxley</ENAMEX> has been networked."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> plugs its show here.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flawed Giant</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> and His Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961-1973</TIMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallek</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford University Press</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> installments in the
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX>'s biography of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">th president</ENAMEX> is deemed
"sound and judicious," and a corrective to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Caro</ENAMEX>'s polemical anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tomes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Wilentz</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> seize on
the lurid details, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX>'s exposing himself to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> to his
behind-the-scenes machinations during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1968</TIMEX> presidential campaign. The
book's prodigious research is taken to validate the view of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s
presidency as a Shakespearean tragedy in which his megalomaniacal commitment to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> ruined his ambitious liberal domestic agenda.

            
               
                  Nat
Tate: An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928-1960</TIMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Boyd</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishing</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> delight in "one of the great literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hoaxes</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Lister, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX> ), in which a best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> tries
to pass off his "biography" of a nonexistent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> as authentic. At an A-list
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soho</ENAMEX> book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boyd</ENAMEX>'s co-conspirator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bowie</ENAMEX> read a passage to a
credulous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>'s gullibility proves the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York</ENAMEX> art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">establishment</ENAMEX>'s "utter obliviousness to the ridiculous" (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guardian</ENAMEX> ). Stateside, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Plagens</ENAMEX> insists that
"hardly anybody was duped."

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Quarantine</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Crace</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). The
celebrated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arcadia</ENAMEX> ), who has been short listed for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Booker Prize</ENAMEX>, wins praise as an anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX> for his brash
novel about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>' life. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Crace</ENAMEX>'s version, a rebellious, bratty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> dies of
starvation at the end of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-day</TIMEX> sojourn in the wilderness. Unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mailer</ENAMEX>'s
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">autobiography" of Christ, The Gospel According to the Son</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quarantine</ENAMEX> is lauded for its historical accuracy, lyrical prose, and
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">risqué</NUMEX> plot.

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  Wait
Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooks Atkinson Theatre</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pulp</ENAMEX>

               Fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quentin Tarantino</ENAMEX>, debuting as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> actor
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opposite Marisa Tomei</ENAMEX>, "should be humiliated" by his performance (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent</ENAMEX>
Canby, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). His faults are said to range from the small
(he can't render accents) to the large (he exhibits the "charisma of a week-old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lettuce</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News ' Fintan O'Toole</ENAMEX>). The
play itself, a revival of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> thriller, fares no better: "a tediously
contrived wind-up toy that yells 'Boo!' just before it winds down" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben</ENAMEX>
Brantley, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Still, the show, having sold out its
initial run, is being extended.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Lost in</ENAMEX>
Space ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butcher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boy</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- Left of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Imbruglia</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- Push (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frontline: From Jesus to Christ</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Christians</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- An Instance
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fingerpost</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iain Pears</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavedweller</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Allison</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Grease</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- From
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teletubbies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- The Sound</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All-True</ENAMEX>
Travels and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adventures of Lidie Newton</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Smiley</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book--
               Consilience:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity of Knowledge</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.O. Wilson</ENAMEX>;

            

               Fashion --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fall Lines</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25:</TIMEX>

            

               Event --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Academy Awards</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television --Sitcom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundup</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- Primary
Colors ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Wild</ENAMEX>
Things ;

            
               Movie -- Taste of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cherry</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cabaret</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lohengrin</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Man in</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron Mask</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Love and</ENAMEX>
Death on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Men With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lateline</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- Significant 
               Others (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilgrim</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Clapton</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cycle : Inside the Clinton Propaganda Machine</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Children</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Halberstam</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
