
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Sphere
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). Despite an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">all-star cast</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Hoffman</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel L. Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharon Stone</ENAMEX>) and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Crichton</ENAMEX> story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Levinson</ENAMEX>'s
latest directorial effort is a big-budget bust. The undersea sci-fi adventure
is dismissed as "another variation of the same old supernatural junk" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> deplore the film's pretentious pronouncements
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s place in the universe and say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinson</ENAMEX> is "out of his element"
trying to build suspense (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Kempley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissenting</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>'
performances irresistible and salutes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinson</ENAMEX> for tackling a new genre. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here for the
official site.)

            

               
                  Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dalloway</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Look Pictures</ENAMEX>). Finally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say, a film
adaptation that does its novel justice. They praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marleen Gorris</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Line</ENAMEX> ) for retaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virginia Woolf's</ENAMEX> stream-of-consciousness
style (via voice-overs) and mingling of memory and reality (using flashbacks).
The screenplay, too, "succeeds in preserving the mandarin lyricism of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woolf</ENAMEX>'s
language without slipping into the 'poetic' " (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daphne Merkin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ). Critics also applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Redgrave</ENAMEX>'s turn as the wistful
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">middle-age English</ENAMEX> socialite--the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Denby, "large enough to hold together this plotless story." (A clip is
available here.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wedding Singer</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). This Reagan-era romantic comedy is
said to herald the replacement of '70s chic with '80s nostalgia. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night Live</ENAMEX> alum <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Sandler</ENAMEX> successfully transforms himself from bumbling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wise</ENAMEX>-ass into lovable leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> like the jokes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLoreans</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX>'s glove, and other timepieces but say the movie never
transcends its formulaic plot. "Little more than an excuse for a soundtrack
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">album"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). Others object that it "reconfigures the
'80s as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX> of goofy lost innocence" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Lawyer</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doubleday</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> pan the
best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s thriller about a white-shoe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who quits his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">champion</ENAMEX> the homeless. Even for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Grisham</ENAMEX> novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Street Lawyer</ENAMEX> is
said to be insubstantial, with "an unlikable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>, a slapdash plot and some
truly awful prose" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> commentary is called both worthy and heavy-handed: His "depictions of
the poor read like something turned in by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cub</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deirdre Donahue</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). The book is expected to sell out its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.8-million</NUMEX>-copy first
run. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Gladwell</ENAMEX>'s less derisive review in

                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riven Rock</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T. Coraghessan Boyle</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> remain
divided over the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Road to Wellville</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>: Is he a gothic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> or
annoyingly smug? His latest novel, about an insane <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to a manufacturing
fortune who's forbidden to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>, is deemed diffuse and stocked with
caricatures. But even those who pan the novel continue to celebrate his
"caffeinated prose, his bravura showmanship [and his] ... entertaining gallery
of madmen" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kakutani</ENAMEX>).

            

               Television
            

            

               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">th Winter Olympics</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nagano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> say the
anemic ratings for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> games are deserved. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'96</TIMEX> Summer
Olympics programming, many complain, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>'s coverage features not enough
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">athleticism</ENAMEX> and too many sappy human-interest stories. "How much melodramatic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hokum</ENAMEX> can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> take?" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). Others
complain there aren't enough such stories, citing the compelling drama
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure skater</ENAMEX> whose abusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> kicked her in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with
his skate. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> overall plus: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Tesh</ENAMEX> works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Rosenberg</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vagina Monologues</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein Ballroom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of
battered women's advocacy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> recasts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14</TIMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Vagina Day</TIMEX>. Critical
acclaim ensues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> sponsored a celebrity-filled benefit, featuring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Close</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Sarandon</ENAMEX>, and others performing excerpts
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve Ensler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">off-Broadway Vagina Monologues</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>'
favorite bits: a celebration by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Close</ENAMEX> of the word "cunt" and a pitch by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldberg</ENAMEX> for the use of fuzzy stirrups in gynecological exams. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ensler</ENAMEX>'s riotous
work is said to refute the rap that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX> are humorless: "What it was like
to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Bruce</ENAMEX> perform in the beginning" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Gates</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ).

            

               Updates
            

            

               Spin and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> simultaneously run covers extolling the
virtues of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Park</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> attributes the show's success to
its comic sensibility, "a sort of humor that's distinctly no-brow--an edgy,
rude point of view" (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">David Wild</ENAMEX>). ... In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> trite and sentimental: "It forces magic and pure
rhapsodies on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> like a demented anesthetist bullying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">laughing gas</ENAMEX>."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Nil By
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouth</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Blues</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers 2000</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Nominations</ENAMEX>, early
reviews ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fucking</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Maggs</ENAMEX>: A
Novel , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carey</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Quindlen</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- Yield ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Jam</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"China: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Years"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capeman</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-Sex<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-Scandal Coverage</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
Expectations ;

            
               Movie -- Desperate
Measures ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>
Libre , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmore Leonard</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Gun</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nadine Gordimer</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Wag the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Gingerbread
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX>
World ;

            
               Book -- Birthday
Letters , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Night</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Train</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Enduring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McEwan</ENAMEX>;

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXXII</ENAMEX>;

            

               Dance --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Baryshnikov</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evening of Music and Dance With the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Oak Chamber Ensemble</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- Fallen ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Sundance Film</ENAMEX>
Festival;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Live</ENAMEX>
Flesh ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Musical</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragtime</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pillar</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fire: America in the King Years</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963-65</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor Branch</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shadows</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Bashevis Singer</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Dove</ENAMEX>: A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Retrospective"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX>).

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
