
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Searchlight Pictures</ENAMEX>). Despite raves for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey Jr.</ENAMEX>'s performance in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Toback</ENAMEX>'s comedy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> deem Two
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Girls bathetic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey</ENAMEX> plays an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> who's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-timing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>,
played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Graham</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Gregson Wagner</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> find the women's
continued attraction to him implausible and object to the film's lugubrious
dialogue about the futility of love. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, a self-destructive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liar</ENAMEX>, reminds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downey</ENAMEX> himself--a recovering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX>. He "has
clearly had a lot of practice trying to explain the unexplainable in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>-step
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
               ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
for the official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sliding Doors</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> debate the merits of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwyneth Paltrow</ENAMEX>, more than anything else in this "slender romantic comedy"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kempley</ENAMEX> calls Paltrow a "fair reminder of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audrey Hepburn</ENAMEX>," but
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX> says her "image project[s]
better in fashion-magazine stills than in motion." The film is credited with a
clever conceit (it weaves together <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> versions of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>'s life)
but is said to suffer from simplistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, windy dialogue, and a facile
moral message (life is predestined). (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>
reviews the film in 
                  Slate
               . Miramax plugs it here.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Damascus Gate</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Stone</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin</ENAMEX>). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outerbridge</ENAMEX> Reach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s meditation on religious fervor, set
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Land</ENAMEX>, comes up short. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX>'s thriller about the sojourns of a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old City</ENAMEX> is said to cut to
the heart of zealotry. But its take on religion is simple-minded: "In this
novel one is either a messianist or a nonbeliever" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Rosen</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> say he succeeds entirely: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leave</ENAMEX>
it to a goy to write the definitive novel about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daphne Merkin</ENAMEX>, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> ).

            

               
                  Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age of Suffrage, Spiritualism</ENAMEX>, and the Scandalous
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Woodhull</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Goldsmith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>); 
                  Notorious
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Victoria: The Life of Victoria Woodhull, Uncensored</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Gabriel</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algonquin</ENAMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> biographies--the first serious ones since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>--win praise for
rescuing the colorful <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodhull</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1838-1927</TIMEX>) from historical oblivion. Her claims
to fame: A onetime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>, she founded a brokerage house, ran for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, championed free love, and brought down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Ward</ENAMEX>
Beecher by publicizing a sex scandal involving him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goldsmith</ENAMEX>'s biography is
deemed novelistic but sensationalist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>'s scholarly but dry. Still unsure
of her significance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> declare Woodhull "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s most bizarre feminist"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francine Du Plessix Gray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Merlin
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26 and 27</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the costliest
made-for-TV movies--a telling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">King Arthur</ENAMEX> legend from the wizard's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>--is judged one of the best. It "deserves to be shown <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annually</TIMEX>,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX> expenditure is
said to have paid off, with realistic special effects (fire-breathing dragons,
a talking horse more convincing than Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>) and all-star performances from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sam</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helena Bonham Carter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabella Rossellini</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Short</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relieved Merlin</ENAMEX> has none of the campiness endemic to medieval TV dramas.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> plugs its "television event" here.)

            

               Art
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Calder</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898-1976</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Gallery of Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>). A retrospective rescues the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> sculptor from his reputation as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unsubstantial</ENAMEX> "user-friendly modernist" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberta Smith</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> say the show highlights the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Surrealism</ENAMEX> inspired
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calder</ENAMEX>'s now-forgotten grotesque sculptures from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. His own
innovations--especially the mobile--are credited with influencing other major
sculptors, including <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Picasso</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Smith</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> chalk up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calder</ENAMEX>'s
previous low standing to the abundance of sculptures he made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX> for
corporate plazas, which are labeled "mostly boring" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">National Gallery</ENAMEX> site.)

            

               Opera
            

            
               Kirov
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Opera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> applaud the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Petersburg</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 day</TIMEX> stint in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. "Just long enough to leave
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> opera world with a welcome legacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russianization</ENAMEX>," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Davidson</ENAMEX>. A spate of profiles <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">heaps</ENAMEX> praise on the
flamboyant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conductor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valery Gergiev</ENAMEX>, who saved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirov</ENAMEX> financially as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>
went capitalist. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gergiev</ENAMEX>'s promotion of lesser-known works by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX> and on his unusual arrangements. While "the great orchestras
are all sounding pretty much alike, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirov</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> all its own"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Gurewitsch</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Wild Man</ENAMEX>
Blues ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Object of My</ENAMEX>
Affection ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Bitch: In</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Praise of Difficult Women</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Wurtzel</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Closed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Eyewitness Account of the Epic Struggles Inside the Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Lazarus</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shadows of a Hand: The Drawings of Victor Hugo</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- My
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>

               of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The Big
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flawed Giant</ENAMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> and His Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961-1973</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Dallek</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Tate</ENAMEX>: An
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928-1960</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Boyd</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quarantine</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Crace</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Wait 
               Until 
               Dark .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Lost in</ENAMEX>
Space ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butcher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boy</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- Left of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Imbruglia</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- Push (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frontline: From Jesus to Christ</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Christians</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- An Instance
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fingerpost</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iain Pears</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavedweller</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Allison</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Grease</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- From
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teletubbies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- The Sound</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All-True</ENAMEX>
Travels and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adventures of Lidie Newton</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Smiley</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book--
               Consilience:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity of Knowledge</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.O. Wilson</ENAMEX>;

            
               Fashion --Fall
Lines.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
