
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Amistad
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s eagerly awaited
docudrama about an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1839</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>-ship <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mutiny</ENAMEX> inspires much enthusiasm and some
disappointment. As with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schindler</ENAMEX>'s List , many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> celebrate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> for creating a film of "emotional and moral weight" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Schickel, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) that awakens the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> to a historical tragedy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Benin</ENAMEX>-born model <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Djimon Hounsou</ENAMEX> as the lead mutineer and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anthony Hopkins</ENAMEX> as his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Quincy Adams</ENAMEX>, are singled out for praise. But
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> complain the film is "more dutiful than dramatic" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah Rozen</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ) or just "a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> drama of dull, soapbox ponderousness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Owen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleiberman, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official
site.)

            

               
                  Good <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Hunting</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> conclude that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wunderkind Matt Damon</ENAMEX>--the film's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> and (with co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Affleck</ENAMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-author</ENAMEX>--lives up to his hype. His screenplay, about a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Boston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX>
revealed to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, is called a "wise, inviting story" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). And his performance as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX>, says the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, exhibits "a coiled strength that hasn't
been seen since the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlon Brando</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX>' turn as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savant</ENAMEX>'s
shrink is said to revive his career, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> after it was pronounced stalled
in the reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flubber</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Good Will Hunting</ENAMEX>
"conventional" and fraught with "traditional sticky sentimentality" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
Turan, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (Miramax plugs the film.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breast Men</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 13</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EST</TIMEX>/PST). Applause for this
morality tale about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inventors</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast implant</ENAMEX>, who go from being star
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">surgeons</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> to coke <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boogie Nights of</ENAMEX>
the fake-boob industry" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Fretts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Critics
admire the show's witty satire of sleazy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, as well as the performances
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Schwimmer</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> ) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Cooper</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lone Star</ENAMEX> ). New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leonard</ENAMEX> gripes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Breast Men</ENAMEX> simply exploits cable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>'s independence to show gratuitous flesh: "In an exuberance meant to be
Rabelaisian, it crosses the line from peep show into pornography." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> plugs the show.)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The
Diary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Music Box Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> credit
this revival of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning play with correcting many of
the original's faults. The revival "doesn't diminish the magnitude of the
events behind it" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> down
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>'s Judaism. Both the script and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Portman</ENAMEX>
( Everyone Says I Love You ) are said to render <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX> less of a
caricature than before. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> echo <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Ozick</ENAMEX>'s criticism in an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>
issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> that the play remains "infantilized,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Americanized</ENAMEX>, homogenized, [and] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sentimentalized</ENAMEX>." (See the play's site.)

            

               Opera
            

            

               
                  Amistad
                (performed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyric Opera of Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Civic Opera</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Composer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Davis</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">librettist cousin</ENAMEX>, Thulani
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm X</ENAMEX> ), offer their rendition of the
suddenly hot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX>-ship saga. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> like the movie better. They chide the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">opera</ENAMEX> for making <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> folk deities the major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> at the expense of
explaining the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> revolt itself. The score, which borrows from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benjamin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Britten</ENAMEX> and bebop, is called incoherent and "bland" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Griffiths</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ). "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the biggest missed opportunities the operatic world
has seen in a while," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Patrick Stearns</ENAMEX>.

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  A
Certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.D. James</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">best-selling English</ENAMEX> crime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>'s latest whodunit. Some condemn the novel,
in which an arrogant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barrister</ENAMEX> who defends <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rogues</ENAMEX> is murdered, for its clichéd
depiction of lawyering and its unconvincingly tidy ending. "The moral and
emotional questions she asks do not admit of such neatness," says the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Macintyre</ENAMEX>. Others say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> ascends from pulp
fiction to high art, with well-drawn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and turns of phrase "of which
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Austen</ENAMEX> might have been proud" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Kaufman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> ). (An excerpt is available at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>'s site.)

            

               Update
            

            A modest
rebound for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>'s widely panned <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toward the</ENAMEX>
End of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> declares it one of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>'s "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> best books," and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Carol Oates</ENAMEX>, writing in The 
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> (for which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Updike</ENAMEX> often writes), calls it "the most inventive of his
myriad fiction. ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Updike</ENAMEX>'s prose, as always, is distinguished by passages of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">lyric</ENAMEX> beauty."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:</TIMEX>

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
Neighborhood , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flubber</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Welcome to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarajevo</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
Housing (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Release 2.0</ENAMEX>:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Design for Living</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Age</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Dyson</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photography</ENAMEX> --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weegee's World: Life, Death, and the Human Drama</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Center of Photography Midtown</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rainmaker</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Alien</ENAMEX>
Resurrection ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>: How an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ordinary Man Became an Extraordinary Leader</ENAMEX> , by Dinesh
D'Souza;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivanov</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standing</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackal</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anastasia</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet</ENAMEX>
Hereafter ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>, Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Own</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominick Dunne</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egon Schiele</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Leopold Collection</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern</ENAMEX>
Art).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Starship
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troopers</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The Wings
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dove</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Mad</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Proposal ;

            
               Book -- The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX>
Side of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour M. Hersh</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred C.</ENAMEX>
Kinsey: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public/Private Life</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James H. Jones</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cooking: The All-Purpose Cookbook</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Warhol Look/Glamour Fashion Style"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX>).

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
