
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance With Me</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Entertainment</ENAMEX>). Despite great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX>
music, athletic dancing, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">gorgeous stars</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanessa Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rican</ENAMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sensation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chayanne</ENAMEX>), this movie falls flat. Calling the script
"dreadfully predictable" and a "cliché-hugging melodrama" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> complain that it lacks the fun of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other recent
dance movie successes, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shall We Dance</ENAMEX>? and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Strictly Ballroom</ENAMEX> . As
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wilmington</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Tribune</ENAMEX> says, "The dances aren't just
musical highlights. They're relief from the rest of the film." (Visit the official site.)

            

               
                  Your <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends & Neighbors</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gramercy Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil LaBute</ENAMEX>'s
follow-up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sundance</ENAMEX> sensation, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In the Company of Men</ENAMEX> , is
just as nasty as his first film and leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> arguing over whether the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer/director</ENAMEX> is trying to make a moral point or just delights in inventing
callous bastards. The action revolves around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> singles) who betray and manipulate each other in various combinations in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biting</ENAMEX>, misanthropic sexual satire. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, are repulsed, calling it "a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> of humiliation,
embarrassment, and misery." But some find the bleakness compelling and praise
the dialogue and flashes of black humor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Kehr</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>
calls it "cool, sharply funny." (Read this interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaBute</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unmade Beds</ENAMEX>
                (not in distribution). This quasidocumentary follows
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> real single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> living and looking for love in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Barker</ENAMEX> has taken some crucial liberties--the dialogue in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> is scripted, based on conversations with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are
fascinated by the new possibilities opened up by this license and call the film
"one of the more original movies of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ).
Others are uneasy about the intimate, sad, and somewhat mocking portraits that
emerge of these deeply flawed and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely individuals</ENAMEX> and call the film
"depressing and undeniably cruel" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Gates</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barker</ENAMEX>'s quest for "larger dramatic truths.")

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rat Pack</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>; click here for show times). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>'s movie on the famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of '60s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">entertainers</ENAMEX> has a fatal flaw: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Liotta</ENAMEX> isn't convincing as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Sinatra</ENAMEX>.
Without <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>'s personal magnetism and charisma, no amount of lavish period
set design or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Cheadle</ENAMEX>'s show-stealing performance as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Davis Jr.</ENAMEX>
can rescue the film. Most agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ,
who says watching this film "is like having a hangover without the fun of
getting happily plastered in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place." Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX> is the lone dissenter, claiming the film possesses an "irreverent
energy and a swaggering style that does its subject proud." (Visit the official
site.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Eagle</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Hillerman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillerman</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">13 th</NUMEX> mystery novel set in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Navajoland</ENAMEX> meets the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' high
expectations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Leaphorn</ENAMEX>, now retired from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Navajo</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>, and his
colleague acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lt.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Chee</ENAMEX> must solve a murder and explain the disappearance
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> who was studying the reservation's plague-carrying desert
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katy Kelly</ENAMEX> writes, "The plague problem, which
should be riveting, is so well-explained that it wearies the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>." But most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillerman</ENAMEX>'s storytelling and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deft</ENAMEX> handling of "the intersection
of science and myth" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Blumenthal</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). (Buy this book from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summer of Deliverance: A Memoir of Father and Son</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christopher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickey</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Journalist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Dickey</ENAMEX>'s combination
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">memoir</ENAMEX> and biography of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deliverance</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dickey</ENAMEX>, is praised as a "loving, ruthless portrait" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance Morrow</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Although he cleaned up his act <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> before dying,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickey Sr.</ENAMEX> spent much of his life boozing, telling self-aggrandizing tall
tales, and openly cheating on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> draw parallels to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cheever</ENAMEX>'s memoir of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Home Before Dark</ENAMEX> , but find this book
less shocking because unlike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cheever</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickey Sr.</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">demons</ENAMEX> were widely
publicized. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Cheever</ENAMEX> questions the
"understanding" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickeys</ENAMEX> reach at book's end, as does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>
Lehmann-Haupt of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>, who claims "the book offers
incomplete catharsis." (Buy this book from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaaterskill Falls</ENAMEX>
               ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allegra Goodman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dial Press</ENAMEX>). After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
highly acclaimed story collections, this "young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> fiction"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Dunford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ) has written a warm, subtle, understated novel
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about the daily</TIMEX> lives of a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jews</ENAMEX> who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> in a small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catskills</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodman</ENAMEX>'s finely honed descriptive abilities and
"instinctive grasp of familial dynamics, the ways in which dreams and emotional
habits are handed down ... from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). A few, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl K. Bell</ENAMEX> in the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , find "a surfeit of sweetly obedient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">docility</ENAMEX>" in the novel and say
parts are "perilously at the edge of sentimentality." (Read an essay by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> and an excerpt from the novel here.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avengers</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie--
               Return to
Paradise ;

            
               Movie--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slums of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Music--
               Whitechocolatespaceegg , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Phair</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> of
Spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward L. Bernays</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birth of Public Relations</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tye</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book--
               Philistines at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedgerow</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passion</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Property</ENAMEX> in the
Hamptons , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven S. Gaines</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
               Snake
Eyes ;

            
               Movie--
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Halloween:</ENAMEX>
H20 ;

            
               Movie -- How <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX>
Got <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her Groove Back</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainbow</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX> ;
            

            
               Television
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
Seinfeld: I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Telling You for the Last Time--Live</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television
               -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upright Citizens Brigade</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Art of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorcycle</ENAMEX>";

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lolita</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maximum</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Movies -- Ever After:</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cinderella Story</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movies -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Negotiator</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- Burn
Rate , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wolff</ENAMEX>;

            

               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome Robins</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            
               Book-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">100 Best English-Language Novels</ENAMEX> Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>;

            
               Book--
               Point of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Origin</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Cornwell</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie--
               Disturbing
Behavior ;

            
               Movie--
               Pi ;

            

               Movie--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thief</ENAMEX> .

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
