
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  He
Got Game
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> rank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spike Lee</ENAMEX>'s Oedipal
basketball drama--starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denzel Washington</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">convict</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> as his estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>--at the top of his oeuvre . After paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s
recent films scant attention, they declare him "underrated" and "overlooked"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). They're pleased to find that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>
can act, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has a mean streak, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> critiques capitalism
more than he does racism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> gripe about cheap high-mindedness,
especially the caricatures of money-grubbing sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
                and here for the official
site.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les</ENAMEX>
Misérables
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> film version of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Hugo</ENAMEX>'s novel, this one from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Danish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bille</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, wins modest
praise despite its familiar story and conventional telling. Strong performances
are credited: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Rush</ENAMEX> uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javert</ENAMEX> as a portrait of
zealotry, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liam Neeson</ENAMEX> makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valjean</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> without a
"recognizable human flaw," seem complex (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ).
Others praise the film's slow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> pace as an antidote to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>'s manic
style. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Detractors</ENAMEX> complain it's just plain boring. (Here is
the official site. And a recent "Summary
Judgment" has an item on <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hugo</ENAMEX> chic.)

            
               Summer
Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roundup</ENAMEX>. Few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> movies are even trying to duplicate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX> 's success, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> press reports. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> sensibly
scaled down" in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christmastime</ENAMEX> smash hit, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Cox</ENAMEX> forecasts fewer action flicks and
"more offbeat weepies than usual." Highly touted are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s World
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War II</ENAMEX> drama Saving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> (starring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Damon</ENAMEX>) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Weir</ENAMEX>'s satiric <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Truman Show</ENAMEX> , about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX>) whose
entire life is televised. The exception is a remake of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godzilla</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">creators of Independence Day</ENAMEX> ; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> predict it will be the summer
box-office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX>.

            

               Television
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newsmagazine Roundup</ENAMEX>. Rumors that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> may replace their nightly
news shows with prime-time newsmagazines trigger laments about the genre's
decline. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s tabloidy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dateline</ENAMEX> , already on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times a week, is
called "as close to local TV news as anything the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> have yet come up
with" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Zoglin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Meanwhile, a highly praised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
documentary about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hewitt</ENAMEX> prompts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> to note
that show's downfall as well. Citing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Rooney</ENAMEX>'s dithering commentaries and a
story bashing gay studies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> declares the once
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">high-minded CBS</ENAMEX> show "alarmingly behind the times."

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Easy Riders, Raging Bulls: How the Sex-Drugs</ENAMEX>-and<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">-Rock 'n' Roll Generation</ENAMEX>
Saved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Biskind</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon & Schuster</ENAMEX>). As 1970s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> enjoys a critical renaissance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> lap up the gossip in a
book about its groundbreaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>. Reviewers share the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s view that
these auteurs--including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Ford Coppola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Scorsese</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
Friedkin, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Schrader</ENAMEX>--reinvented <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cinema</ENAMEX> with their gritty
dramas but arrogantly overindulged in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and sex. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> rant about
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">present-day Hollywood</ENAMEX>: "[F]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ew</ENAMEX> of the films of the earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> would get the
green light <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Excerpts</ENAMEX> are
available here.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist Manifesto</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Marx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick Engels</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verso</ENAMEX>). The
left-wing publishing house <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Verso</ENAMEX> has reissued the classic of political
philosophy on its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">150 th</NUMEX> anniversary, marketing the book at chic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">clothiers</ENAMEX> as "an accessory, a stocking-stuffer, a badge of consummate
capitalist cool" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Ehrenreich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> ). Left-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> stress
the tract's continued relevance as a critique of labor relations, while
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> redefine <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marx</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engels</ENAMEX> as prophets of capitalism who respected
the economy's dynamism and strength. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scholarly reviewers</ENAMEX> honor it as "an
enduring masterpiece that immediately catches up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> in its transpersonal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">force</ENAMEX> and sweep" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Marcus</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> 
               Book
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Judas Kiss</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadhurst Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liam Neeson</ENAMEX> brings
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Wilde</ENAMEX> chic to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> in a new play by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hare</ENAMEX>,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are unimpressed. The brawny Neeson "is a calamity" as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>, says
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hare</ENAMEX>'s script is faulted for making <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>
inhumanly noble and for blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>'s celebrated fall entirely on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lord Alfred Douglas</ENAMEX>. The revival of interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX>--another play about him
( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gross Indecency</ENAMEX> ) and a new movie ( <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilde</ENAMEX> )--continues to delight
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. "All that's missing ... are the dashboard statuettes and the black
velvet portraits," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kirn</ENAMEX>.

            
               Recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX> columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girls</ENAMEX>
and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guy</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Sliding

               Doors ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Damascus</ENAMEX>

               Gate , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Stone</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Age of Suffrage, Spiritualism</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scandalous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Victoria</ENAMEX>
Woodhull , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Goldsmith</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>); <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Notorious Victoria: The Life of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Woodhull</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uncensored</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Gabriel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Algonquin</ENAMEX>).

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calder</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1898-1976</TIMEX>";

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Opera --Kirov Opera</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Wild Man</ENAMEX>
Blues ;

            
               Movie -- Object

               of 
               My 
               Affection ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Bitch: In</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Praise of Difficult Women</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Wurtzel</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Closed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chambers</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">First Eyewitness Account of the Epic Struggles Inside the Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Lazarus</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shadows of a Hand: The Drawings of Victor Hugo</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- My
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The Big
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- Flawed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> and His Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961-1973</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Dallek</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Tate</ENAMEX>: An
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928-1960</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Boyd</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quarantine</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Crace</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Wait Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Lost in</ENAMEX>
Space ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butcher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boy</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The

               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Spanish</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- Left of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Imbruglia</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- Push (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frontline: From Jesus to Christ</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Christians</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- An Instance
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fingerpost</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iain Pears</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavedweller</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Allison</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
