
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wild Man Blues</ENAMEX>
                (Fine Line Features). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Documentarian Barbara Kopple</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlan County, U.S.A.</ENAMEX> ) follows <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clarinetist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX> on tour
with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> jazz <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. Reviewers assert <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX> is "even more amusing and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurotic</ENAMEX> in real life than in his own movies" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah Rozen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ). (He
suffers an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anxiety</ENAMEX> attack on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Venetian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gondola</ENAMEX> and rarely leaves his hotel
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX>.) Soon-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yi Previn</ENAMEX>, now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, comes off as a strong-willed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foil</ENAMEX> to
the famously whiny filmmaker. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cynics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> used the film to counter bad
press and deliberately hammed up his insecurities for the camera.

            
               
                  The
Object of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Affection</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tepid</ENAMEX> reviews for
this romantic comedy by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Hytner</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Madness</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> )
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Aniston</ENAMEX>) who wants her gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rudd</ENAMEX>) to help raise her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. It is "[r]iddled with cultural stereotypes,
woe-is-me neurotic mopiness, and glib therapeutic compassion" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aniston</ENAMEX>'s performance is called lackluster.
"Actresses get attention for their hair when they don't draw you in with their
features," says 
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'s David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Wloszczyna</ENAMEX> says the film signals the
death of a genre. "Romantic comedy has been in a funk since women's lib and the
pill popped the champagne bubbles of sexual tension." (A <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> is available
here.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trimark Pictures</ENAMEX>). Stunning shots of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">alleys</ENAMEX> and markets are said to overcome a flimsy plot in The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy Luck</ENAMEX>
Club <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Wang</ENAMEX>'s "love letter to his native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Thomas</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). In the story, co-written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>
Theroux, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are metaphors for their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>: A dying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">journalist</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Irons</ENAMEX>) interviews a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> hustler and falls in love with
a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> ex-whore (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX> for capturing "the essence of
a great metropolis in the throes of change" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Seinfeld : <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Final-Episode Roundup</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 14</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). Hype
for the sitcom's upcoming finale. Cover packages in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> laud the show for having
"reinvented the sitcom form" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Hirschberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> ) by
abandoning the traditional <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-plot structure and introducing more
sophisticated and subversive humor. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> buck the trend. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Rosenberg deems Seinfeld</ENAMEX> 's characters
predictable and despicable: "Lower their grammar a few notches, and you can see
this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Springer</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mocks</ENAMEX> "the endlessly repeated mantra that the show's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX> is that it's 'about
nothing.' " (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>'s synthesis of critical opinion
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> decided to retire.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bitch: In Praise of Difficult Women</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Wurtzel</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doubleday</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Prozac Nation</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Wurtzel</ENAMEX>'s marketing strategy
works: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Critics</ENAMEX> heap attention on the dust jacket photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wurtzel</ENAMEX> topless and
flipping her middle finger. The book itself--about "high-maintenance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>"
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Fisher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sylvia Plath</ENAMEX>--is said by some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> to consist of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inchoate</ENAMEX> fulminations on feminism and familiar rants on being single. Others
say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wurtzel</ENAMEX>'s notoriety as "someone so bent on self-destruction" makes it
"redundant to bash" the book (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yahlin Chang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). A few find
Bitch less smug and more authentic than <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prozac Nation</ENAMEX> . (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here to read
"Culturebox" on craziness as a career strategy.)

            

               
                  Closed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chambers: The First Eyewitness Account of the Epic Struggles</ENAMEX>
Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Lazarus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Books</ENAMEX>). Critics
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">chide Lazarus</ENAMEX> for his kiss-and-tell about his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> clerking for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Blackmun</ENAMEX> for betraying confidences and "sacrificing the dignity
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Painter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). But
they still lap up his gossip. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tidbits</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurgood Marshall</ENAMEX> spent his days
watching soap operas; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justices</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Connor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> are known as intellectual
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">midgets</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lazarus</ENAMEX>' claim that zealous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> run the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> is deemed
"overstated" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Garrow</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Art
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shadows of a Hand: The Drawings of Victor Hugo"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Drawing Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>). On a wave of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hugo</ENAMEX> chic--the publication of a new biography and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollywood</ENAMEX> versions of The 
               Hunchback of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Notre Dame</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Misérables</ENAMEX> --an exhibit reveals the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>
to have been a great draftsman as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugo</ENAMEX>'s drawings, many of them abstract
images presaging the work of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 th century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Dubuffet</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franz Kline</ENAMEX>, are "one of the most striking testimonies to the power of the
unconscious in all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> art" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (In

                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Berman</ENAMEX> remarks upon the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hugo</ENAMEX> renaissance.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- My
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angels</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The Big
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New World</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- Flawed
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyndon Johnson</ENAMEX> and His Times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961-1973</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Dallek</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nat Tate</ENAMEX>: An
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928-1960</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Boyd</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quarantine</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Crace</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Wait Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Lost in</ENAMEX>
Space ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butcher</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boy</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- Left of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Imbruglia</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- Push (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Frontline: From Jesus to Christ</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Christians</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- An Instance
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fingerpost</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iain Pears</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavedweller</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Allison</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Grease</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- From
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teletubbies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- The Sound</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All-True</ENAMEX>
Travels and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adventures of Lidie Newton</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Smiley</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book--
               Consilience:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity of Knowledge</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.O. Wilson</ENAMEX>;

            

               Fashion --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fall Lines</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25:</TIMEX>

            

               Event --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Academy Awards</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television --Sitcom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundup</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- Primary
Colors ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Wild</ENAMEX>
Things ;

            
               Movie -- Taste of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cherry</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cabaret</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lohengrin</ENAMEX> .

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
