
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Blade
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). This hip urban vampire tale is either
admirably true to its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marvel Comics</ENAMEX> origins or boring and brooding, depending
on who reviews it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naysayers</ENAMEX>: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>]trictly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman revisited"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Kehr</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Advocates</ENAMEX>: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">P</ENAMEX>]ure visceral imagery" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). The eponymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> is a tortured <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX>-vampire
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wesley Snipes</ENAMEX>) on a classic comic book mission to rid the world of his more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">murderous</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">brethren</ENAMEX>. The film is filled with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>-style fighting, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>,
and special effects and is said to radiate a grim beauty. But neither script
nor plot measures up: "The noir atmosphere doesn't quite smother the dialogue's
cheesy smell" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Seymour</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the official
site.)

            
               
                  Why
Do <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fools Fall in Love</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nava</ENAMEX>'s latest pop-star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biopic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doo-wopster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankie Lymon</ENAMEX> a
sort of "comic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rashomon</ENAMEX> of rock-and-roll" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Van Gelder</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Lymon, who became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> and died of a drug
overdose at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">25</NUMEX>, married <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> without divorcing any of them; only after
his death did the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> find out about one another. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say the film never
really explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lymon</ENAMEX>'s motives. Despite some nice performances from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halle Berry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vivica A. Fox</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lela Rochon</ENAMEX>), he remains "a cipher." (Check
out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lymon</ENAMEX>'s headstone.)

            

               
                  54
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Films</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> Studio 54/disco movie of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">summer</ENAMEX> is pronounced "tacky, tiny and about as seductively nostalgic as those
videotapes of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s wedding" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kehr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily News</ENAMEX> ). The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s weaknesses: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a moralizing story line--"a cleaned-up version of The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rake</ENAMEX>'s Progress " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) poor acting from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">leads Ryan Phillippe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neve Campbell</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) cramped sets that fail to convey
Studio <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">54</TIMEX>'s extravagance and debauchery. The highlight of the film: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Myers</ENAMEX>'
performance as creepy club <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Rubell</ENAMEX>. Otherwise, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">d</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ecadence</ENAMEX> has
rarely looked so pathetic, lethargic and dispiriting" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watch</ENAMEX> the trailer.)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farming of Bones</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwidge Danticat</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soho Press</ENAMEX>). At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Danticat</ENAMEX> has
been named <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granta</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> best young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelists</ENAMEX>, had a short story
collection ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Krik</ENAMEX>? Krak! ) nominated for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">National Book Award</ENAMEX>, and had
her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> novel ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Breath, Eyes</ENAMEX>, Memory ) picked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>'s book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Early</ENAMEX> reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Danticat</ENAMEX>'s latest novel suggest that, miraculously, she
doesn't disappoint. "It's a testament to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> that the novel, while
almost unbearably sad, is still a joy to read" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Van Boven</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). The "powerful, haunting" tale (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher John Farley</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ) recounts the life of a young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Haitian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amabelle Désir</ENAMEX>, who
lives through a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX> massacre of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Haitians</ENAMEX> living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominican Republic</ENAMEX>.
(Buy this book on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amazon</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Music
            

            
               
                  The
Miseducation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauryn Hill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ruffhouse/Columbia</ENAMEX>). The
former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Grammy-</ENAMEX>winning hip-hop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trio</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fugees</ENAMEX> draws raves for her
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> solo album. Popular points of comparison: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aretha Franklin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie Wonder</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Marley</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> things <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX> earns praise for: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) eschewing the heavy
production and packaging common in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">R&B</ENAMEX> and hip-hop; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) writing and
producing the album herself; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">3</ENAMEX>) a high quotient of live instrumentation and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">improvisation</ENAMEX>. The album is "shockingly raw for mainstream pop, with the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>-take immediacy of much great reggae" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Weisbard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> each give it <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Powers</ENAMEX> calls it "music that touches the essence of soul."
(Listen to a sample of the album.)

            

               Updates
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saving Private Ryan</ENAMEX> backlash begins. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of</ENAMEX>
Books , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Menand</ENAMEX> declares that "[t]here is nothing unconventional about
this story. It is possibly the most tried and true dramatic plot known to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Canby</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spielberg</ENAMEX> has "revived a type of
patriotic war movie you might think went out of fashion" after the glut of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>-horror flicks of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '80s</TIMEX>. ... In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daphne Merkin</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegra Goodman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kaaterskill Falls</ENAMEX> "a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">throwback</ENAMEX> to a time before fiction turned graphic and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior</ENAMEX> and hot to the
touch." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merkin</ENAMEX> also marvels at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodman</ENAMEX>'s "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th -century</ENAMEX>
ability to create a sense of linkage, of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> existence impinging on the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next</TIMEX>."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dance With</ENAMEX>
Me ;

            
               Movie -- Your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Friends & Neighbors</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Unmade
Beds ;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rat Pack</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony Hillerman</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Summer of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Deliverance: A Memoir of Father and Son</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Dickey</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaaterskill Falls</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allegra Goodman</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avengers</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie--
               Return to
Paradise ;

            
               Movie--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slums</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Music--
               Whitechocolatespaceegg , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Phair</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Father</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward L. Bernays</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birth of Public Relations</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tye</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book--
               Philistines at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedgerow</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passion</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Property</ENAMEX> in the
Hamptons , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven S. Gaines</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
               Snake
Eyes ;

            
               Movie--
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Halloween:</ENAMEX>
H20 ;

            
               Movie -- How <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX>
Got <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her Groove Back</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainbow</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J</ENAMEX> erry
Seinfeld: I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Telling You for the Last Time--Live</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upright Citizens Brigade</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Art of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorcycle</ENAMEX>";

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lolita</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maximum Bob</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movies -- Ever
After: A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cinderella Story</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movies -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Negotiator</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- Burn
Rate , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wolff</ENAMEX>;

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robins</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
