
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Titanic
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Cameron</ENAMEX>'s
budget-busting epic, expected to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Waterworld</ENAMEX> -style flop, winds up
getting mostly good reviews. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> for evoking vintage
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">romances</ENAMEX> rather than schlocky disaster movies. "Titanic floods
you with elemental passion in a way that invites comparison with ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D.W.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffith</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>. Critics
especially like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Winslet</ENAMEX> as the star-crossed young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> gripe about hackneyed dialogue, stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, and too
much melodrama. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> reviews the
film in 
                  Slate
               . And clips are available here.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX>
                (Fine Line Features). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">28 th</NUMEX> feature--about a misogynistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> who disguises his own
life in his stories--is deemed his darkest. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> gush over it, ranking
it alongside his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">'70s</NUMEX> classics. They laud his intermingling of fiction and
reality, his fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">one-liners</ENAMEX>, and the all-star ensemble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> (which includes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Demi Moore</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kirstie Alley</ENAMEX>). Others find the humor too
vicious to be funny and accuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> of justifying his own misdeeds. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> has wound up making a fetish of himself, and it's beginning to be
embarrassing," says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">review</ENAMEX>
in 
                  Slate
                and the movie's official site.)

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Scream 2</ENAMEX>
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dimension Films</ENAMEX>). A Nightmare on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Elm Street</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Craven</ENAMEX>'s
sequel to his self-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">parodic</ENAMEX> horror movie is said to be almost as amusing (and
scary) as the original. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hink</ENAMEX> of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday the 13</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
                as
written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Ionesco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luigi Pirandello</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craven</ENAMEX>'s self-knowing winks (a film
within the film spoofs the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scream</ENAMEX> ). Some find the
self-consciousness over the top. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]hat once was a fun <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> of twisting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">corridors</ENAMEX> is now as endlessly reflective as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> of mirrors" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Gliatto</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  Ally
McBeal
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. EST</TIMEX>/PST). After premiering to mixed
reviews, this show about a neurotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>-educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> gains a cult
following. Giving it a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> look, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> attribute the show's appeal to its
unconventional plots and insights into contemporary young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. "Irresistible
television, whether you experience it as a sexual-differences safari or as a
blueprint for your own life" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Tucker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). Others
attack it as retrograde: a "male <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>'s wet dream of ... [the] postfeminist
career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, ... beaten down, and not so secretly hungry for a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to
fill the aching void of her life," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Carson</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> .

            

               Art
            

            

<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX>'s retrospective of the campy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>'s clothing stirs up
debate. Some praise the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> for its uncharacteristic timeliness and for
recognizing that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Versace</ENAMEX> "was one of the fashion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">titans</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX>
Szabo, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). Others say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Met</ENAMEX> unwittingly reveals the mediocrity
of his designs, which got noticed only because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> wore them. In the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francine Prose</ENAMEX> accuses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> of inflating
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">designer</ENAMEX>'s import with implausible claims that he was influenced by Yeats
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kandinsky</ENAMEX>. (The exhibit is plugged here.)

            

               Architecture
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>); renovation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yoshio Taniguchi</ENAMEX>. The
unveiling of plans for an annex to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX> caps a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> of architectural
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extravaganzas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taniguchi</ENAMEX>'s design plan to double <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA</ENAMEX>'s
exhibition <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> by building on top of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX> original. "Its lucid integrity
should go far toward raising the standards of architecture in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>,"
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Muschamp</ENAMEX>. Taniguchi, acclaimed for his
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">sleek Tokyo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>, plans to use unassuming materials--glass, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX>, and
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slate</ENAMEX>--which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say won't distract from nearby masterpieces by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pelli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Johnson</ENAMEX>.

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  Hogarth: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> and a World
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Uglow</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giroux</ENAMEX>). A literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX>'s biography of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th -century</TIMEX> satirical
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> wins praise for "bringing [her] subject and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">milieu</ENAMEX> alive"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Cook</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Book World</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> accept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uglow</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">revisionist</ENAMEX> claim that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogarth</ENAMEX>'s famous moralizing was accompanied by a
prurient fixation on sex. (In <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> painting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> watch a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> masturbate in
front of a mirror.) Critics also like the book's gossip about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogarth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Fielding</ENAMEX>.

            

               Update
            

            Newspaper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> weigh in against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amistad</ENAMEX>. Their biggest complaint: It's too much of a Spielbergian
spectacle. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]oo much of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amistad</ENAMEX> feels as if it's been lifted from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lore</ENAMEX> and language of movies rather than life," says the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amistad</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Good Will</ENAMEX>
Hunting ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amistad</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book -- A Certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.D. James</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:</TIMEX>

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
Neighborhood , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flubber</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Welcome to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarajevo</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
Housing (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Release 2.0</ENAMEX>:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Design for Living</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Age</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Dyson</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photography</ENAMEX> --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weegee's World: Life, Death, and the Human Drama</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Center of Photography Midtown</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rainmaker</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Alien</ENAMEX>
Resurrection ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>: How an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ordinary Man Became an Extraordinary Leader</ENAMEX> , by Dinesh
D'Souza;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivanov</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standing</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackal</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anastasia</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet</ENAMEX>
Hereafter ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- Another
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX>, Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Own</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominick Dunne</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egon Schiele</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Leopold Collection</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern</ENAMEX>
Art).

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
