
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wag</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dog</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> can't resist noting the "scary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prescience</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Levinson</ENAMEX>'s
acclaimed satire about a fake war orchestrated to divert attention
from a presidential sex scandal. Their spin on the eerie parallel between art
and life: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> does understand <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The movie
may stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>, since that move would seem contrived. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">L'affaire Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is the superior drama: "Nobody writes better scripts
than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). Sidebar:
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Studios</ENAMEX> is panicking over when to release
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Nichols</ENAMEX>' adaptation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> satire Primary Colors , currently
due out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s dispatch in

                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingerbread Man</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PolyGram</ENAMEX>). Having expected a disaster, most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> confess surprise that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Altman</ENAMEX>'s direction redeems this thriller,
which began as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hokey</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX> story. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchcock</ENAMEX> would have been
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">intrigued</ENAMEX>, and maybe envious," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morgenstern</ENAMEX>. What keeps this from being yet another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grisham</ENAMEX> movie is,
apparently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>'s idiosyncratic camera work and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Branagh</ENAMEX>'s winsome
performance as a slick <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> complain that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s plot
is unbecoming material for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX>'s caliber. "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> feels great
risks were not taken, which is unusual for even the worst <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altman</ENAMEX> films," says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Sarris</ENAMEX>.

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice World</ENAMEX>
               
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>). Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> echo the music
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' pans of the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> and conclude that "sometimes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> counts for squat" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kronke</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s feature film, in which they're harassed by a tabloid
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, is trashed as a "plotless, pointless, mirthless" knock-off of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Day's Night</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Harrington</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). The pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> do get credit for exhibiting self-deprecating humor
and apparent awareness that "they have achieved ludicrous measures of fame and
fortune on the strength of markedly limited talents" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clips</ENAMEX> are available.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Birthday Letters
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). An
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">autobiographical</ENAMEX> book of verse by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet laureate</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>
of iconic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Plath</ENAMEX> revives the cultish fascination with her suicide in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 30</TIMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> for breaking his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year</TIMEX> silence
about his marriage and admitting his insensitivity and infidelity, which some
claim drove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plath</ENAMEX> over the brink. Others, including feminist literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Showalter</ENAMEX>, complain that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> doesn't sufficiently own up to
the consequences of his adultery. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> should have been as merciless to
himself as she was with herself" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kroll</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). Still others
dismiss the poems as "clumsy stuff" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Hamilton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Telegraph</ENAMEX> ).

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Night Train</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harmony Books</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> bad-boy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> tries his hand at an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> novel and draws mixed reviews.
Some dismiss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis</ENAMEX>' use of police lingo and his intricate story about a suicide
investigation as bad parody. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luc Sante</ENAMEX> in

                  Slate
               , seem to be "cut and pasted from a vague memory of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Miller</ENAMEX> ." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> and others
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">relish Amis</ENAMEX>' verbal cleverness and defend the book as a "deliciously readable,
highly polished diversion." (An excerpt is available.)

            
               
                  Enduring Love
               ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McEwan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doubleday</ENAMEX>). Applause for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cement Garden</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>'s
thriller about a science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and an evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drifter</ENAMEX> who's obsessed with
him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McEwan</ENAMEX>'s plot twists (you're not sure if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian</ENAMEX> is
psychotic until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>) and theoretical bent (high-minded riffs on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darwin</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keats</ENAMEX>). In 
                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Truax</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">compares McEwan</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Hardy</ENAMEX>, another "great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of morality,
psychology, and circumstance, but ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McEwan</ENAMEX> makes you nervous." Others find
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McEwan</ENAMEX>'s intellectualism too snooty, making the novel feel like "a storified
lecture" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Eder</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excerpt</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Event
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Super</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowl XXXII</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>). An exciting game and watchable halftime show deflated
the perennial gripes with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> only the overhyped,
overpriced commercials to kvetch about. "Surely a future <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> will see
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> selling commercial space on their butts," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>. Reasons for outrage: exorbitant cost (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX> for a
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-second</TIMEX> spot) and banal products. The biggest disappointment was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> ad, narrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>, that allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> to log on to the
Internet to vote for its ending, to no apparent consequence.

            

               Dance
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Baryshnikov</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evening of Music and Dance With the White Oak</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber Ensemble</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). On the occasion of his
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 th</NUMEX> birthday, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX> ascends to mythic proportions with a
majestic solo concert. "The profundity of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> such as we won't see again
for some time" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kaufman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> forgive his
use of goofy gimmicks--he improvises a dance to his own heartbeat, which is
amplified by a device affixed to his chest--focusing instead on the credibility
he has given modern dance, having switched from classical ballet in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">midcareer</ENAMEX>.

            

               Update
            

            The
conventional wisdom about the musical Ragtime
continues to fluctuate. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> dub it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Musical</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lahr</ENAMEX>, who pronounces it "a
theatrical watershed: an awesome pyrotechnical display of theatrical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">showmanship</ENAMEX>."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- Fallen ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Sundance Film</ENAMEX>
Festival;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Live</ENAMEX>
Flesh ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Musical</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragtime</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pillar</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fire: America in the King Years</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963-65</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor Branch</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shadows</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Bashevis Singer</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>);

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arthur Dove: A Retrospective"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14:</TIMEX>

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny Bono</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Prayer</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz Bissinger</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Frazier</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Drucker</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Beatty</ENAMEX>;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afterglow</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Arguing the
World ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Ma Vie en Rose</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boxer</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capote: In Which Various Friends, Enemies, Acquaintances, and Detractors Recall</ENAMEX>
His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turbulent</ENAMEX> Career , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Plimpton</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>;

            

               Music --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Northern Lights: The Music of Jean Sibelius</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">31:</TIMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winter Movie Roundup</ENAMEX>

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
