
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). Critics
say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Eastwood</ENAMEX>'s adaptation of the best-selling travelogue set in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Savannah</ENAMEX> fails to capture the book's quirky charm. The film, about a gay
antique <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>'s murder trial, is called "listless, disjointed and
disconnected" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). Problems: endless
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">digressions</ENAMEX> and a "simply unfilmable" book (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ).
Praise goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cusack</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Spacey</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison Eastwood</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, for whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> predict stardom. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s
review in 
                  Slate
                and the official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX>'s The Rainmaker
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Ford</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s legal thriller is judged the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grisham</ENAMEX> film to date, as well as a
modest comeback for the once-great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. Reviewers especially like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>, who plays an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist lawyer</ENAMEX> taking on a venal insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, and
also praise co-stars <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny DeVito</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Danes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> say the movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retains Grisham</ENAMEX>'s shallow moralizing and is unworthy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coppola</ENAMEX>'s talents. "Any
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">run-of-the-mill</ENAMEX> episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law & Order</ENAMEX> would be more subtle, more
sophisticated, and more compelling," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lisa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzbaum</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stills</ENAMEX> and clips are available here.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alien Resurrection</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
installment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigourney Weaver</ENAMEX>'s battle with space aliens prompts some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
to call for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 18-year-old</TIMEX> series to be retired. "The regular pattern of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suspense</ENAMEX> has worn thin," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>. This film's
conceit--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weaver</ENAMEX> is resurrected by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and gives birth to an alien--is
labeled especially ludicrous. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> art-house <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Pierre Jeunet</ENAMEX>
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delicatessen</ENAMEX> ) disappoints <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> by not replicating the gothic
ambience of his other films. A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> still applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weaver</ENAMEX>'s "fierce
determination and ironic detachment" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah Rozen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX>
here for the official site and here for

                  Slate
               's review.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>: How an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ordinary Man Became an Extraordinary</ENAMEX>
Leader
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dinesh D'Souza</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Free Press</ENAMEX>). The right-wing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">polemicist</ENAMEX>'s
biography is accused of idolizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gipper</ENAMEX> and lacking "intellectual honesty"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Marx</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Book World</ENAMEX> ). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Berke</ENAMEX> says the book retells hackneyed anecdotes and is
not "particularly revealing about what drove him." Others take D'Souza to task
for his far-fetched theory that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s "gaffes" were calculated. Conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> use the occasion to lionize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> some more. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>'Souza debates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>'s legacy
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.J. Dionne</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivanov</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anton Chekhov</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vivian Beaumont Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
City). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raves for Kevin Kline</ENAMEX>'s charismatic performance as the angst-ridden,
adulterous protagonist of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX>'s first play. "[H]ere even the most lumpish
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">spectator</ENAMEX> must recognize greatness," says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX>. British
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hare</ENAMEX> wins praise for adapting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chekhov</ENAMEX> into colloquial
language, though the melodrama of the original is said to remain. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lahr</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> simply can't understand
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chekhovian</ENAMEX> ennui.

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Standing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMI</ENAMEX>). The ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beatle</ENAMEX>'s symphony
gets a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Hall</ENAMEX> debut and tops <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Billboard</ENAMEX> 's classical chart, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> dismiss it as embarrassingly amateurish. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Teachout</ENAMEX>
says the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">75-minute</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">work</TIMEX>'s "themes are nondescript, its harmonies blandly
predictable, [and] its structure maddeningly repetitious." Most point out that
McCartney can't read musical notation and was aided by professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX> argue that the piece brings a wider <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> to classical music,
proving it "isn't something to be feared" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrymore Laurence Scherer</ENAMEX>, the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Updates
            

            In The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX> defends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>-bashing book: "The fact that [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> has] found more muck in
this particular Augean stable than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want to acknowledge is hardly
his fault." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX> says in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> that
"[i]n his mad zeal to destroy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camelot</ENAMEX> ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hersh</ENAMEX> has] <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">disassembled</ENAMEX> and
obliterated his own career and reputation."... Enthusiasm for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s
Broadway production of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Lion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> dwindles. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Heilpern</ENAMEX> says it's "too
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long</ENAMEX>, too weighty" for a "somewhat preachy story that was always slender."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">19:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackal</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anastasia</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet</ENAMEX>
Hereafter ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Another City</ENAMEX>,
Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Own</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominick Dunne</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egon Schiele</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Leopold Collection</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern</ENAMEX>
Art).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Starship
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troopers</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wings of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dove</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Mad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Proposal ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Dark Side</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour M. Hersh</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred C.</ENAMEX>
Kinsey: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public/Private Life</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James H. Jones</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cooking: The All-Purpose Cookbook</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Warhol Look/Glamour Fashion Style"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            

               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiceworld</ENAMEX> , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> --P.S. 1
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary Arts Center</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>
Corner ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Violin</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Rice</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Kincaid</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xerxes</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Opera</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gattaca</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Less</ENAMEX>
Ordinary ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Triumph</ENAMEX> of
Love ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speaking</ENAMEX>
Truth to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita F. Hill</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinderella</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Clark</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Journey</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Discovery</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Music -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rope</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Jackson</ENAMEX>;

            

               Dance -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merce Cunningham</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forward & Reverse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Academy</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX>).

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
