
   
   
      
         
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>!
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown Years</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992-1998</TIMEX>). Brownian buzz surrounds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>'s move
from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>. The assessments of her career: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) She
modernized Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, adding photos and topical
stories. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) She reshaped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> "in her own image--brainy, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Anglophilic</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">profane</ENAMEX> and more than a little starstruck" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lacayo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
She succeeded in her true goal: making herself the center of attention. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>'s middlebrow tendencies triumphed under her leadership. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) She made a
gutsy midcareer change. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) Her new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX> is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Mouse</ENAMEX>'s latest step toward total cultural domination. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) She will be a victim
of synergy, reduced to "scrounging around for tony material to turn into tacky
movies" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (For more on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of her in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               Art
            

            

               "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unknown Terrain: The Landscapes of Andrew Wyeth</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> attempts to redeem the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Realist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painter</ENAMEX> from his reputation as a vapid schlockmeister, deeming him a precursor
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abstract Expressionism</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> hate him as much as ever: "His art is
not just premodern; it's stone dead" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin Tomkins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ).
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Roberta Smith avers</ENAMEX>: "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wyeth</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying,
'I'm not very nice.' For all its restraint, this exhibition bears him out."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> can't understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curators</ENAMEX> chose to exclude <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyeth</ENAMEX>'s best paintings
(his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helga</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina</ENAMEX> series). And they accuse the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney</ENAMEX> of pandering to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX>' bad taste to garner huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX>. (For the lowdown on the show, click
here.)

            
               Movies

            

            

               
                  Small Soldiers
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks SKG</ENAMEX>). Because of its unexpectedly
gratuitous violence and grotesqueries, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> lay into this "merchandising
tie-in in search of a movie" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). Its seemingly
harmless plot: An avaricious toy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> places vivifying microchips into
action figures. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Dante</ENAMEX> is chided for wasting realistic special
effects and the voices of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Lee Jones</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Borgnine</ENAMEX> and for failing
to reprise the biting humor of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">magnum opus</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gremlins</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> dwell
on the irony of the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Hartman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> getting caught in crossfire.
(The synergistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> site is available here.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lethal Weapon 4</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-old</TIMEX> action franchise
"begs for a mercy killing" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ).
Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> even wax nostalgic for the psychological acumen of earlier
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lethal Weapon installments</ENAMEX>. They regret that the once-complicated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny</ENAMEX>
Glover-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Gibson</ENAMEX> relationship has been reduced to shtick and car chases.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> occupy themselves with explaining the film's popular appeal: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t's
not a good movie, but things blow up really good in it" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Seiler</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buffalo</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Gate Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> either tout or trash this
farce by ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvin Klein</ENAMEX> model <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Gallo</ENAMEX>--the movie's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>. Some see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gallo</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scorsese</ENAMEX> and the '70s
neorealists, with the "audacity and flair of a major filmmaker" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Owen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gleiberman, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). They applaud his stylistic flourishes
(collage shots, freeze frames), his self-deprecating humor, and audacious
premise--a newly released <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX> kidnaps a teen tap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Ricci</ENAMEX>)
to be his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fake wife</ENAMEX>. Others find that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallo</ENAMEX> overdoes the artsy stuff. It is
what "it would be like reading papers for a freshman creative writing course"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Embrya
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxwell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>). A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> chart topper from "pop's
reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover man</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Harrington</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). Critics
remain undecided about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX>'s virtues. Some like his silky falsetto voice
and praise him for reviving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '70s</TIMEX> soul music of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin Gaye</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pendergrass</ENAMEX>. Others attack his pretensions to being a Sensitive New Age <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy</ENAMEX>,
and they damn him with the faint praise that he makes good late-night mood
music. (For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX>'s lyrics, click here.)

            
               
                  Car
Wheels on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gravel Road</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Williams</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX>). High praise for
the latest effort from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">44-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> roots <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>, dubbed "album of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX> . Her charms: a craggy voice and unsentimental
(sometimes gothic, sometimes macho) lyrics, refreshing in a world inundated by
"cookie-cutter <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lilith-</ENAMEX>ready wimps" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Browne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> predict that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> will finally emerge from her long sojourn as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cult star</ENAMEX> to become a genuine pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercury</ENAMEX> plugs the album here.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

             

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armaggedon</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX>
Fool ;

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX>;

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hitler: The Search for the Origins of His Evil</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Someone
Else's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unfinished Struggle for Integration</ENAMEX> , by Tamar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacoby</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diary</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Fielding</ENAMEX>;

            

               Performance <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Art -- The Return of the Chocolate Smeared Woman</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finley</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Out of
Sight ;

            
               Movie -- Smoke

               Signals :

            
               Movie -- Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolittle</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Gone With</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wind</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX>;"

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Suits Me:</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Double Life of Billy Tipton , by Dianne Wood Middlebrook</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Notebooks of Don Rigoberto</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Vargas Llosa</ENAMEX>,
translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Grossman</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>
Files ;

            
               Movie --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
Movies (AFI);

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mulan</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>;"

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Walking With</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wind: A Memoir of the Movement</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lewis</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael D'Orso</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book --<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ship</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gold</ENAMEX>:
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deep Blue Sea</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Kinder</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beautiful Mind , by Sylvia Nasar</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Six Days</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seven Nights</TIMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
Opposite of Sex ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>
Art ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nightingales</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magic Hour</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Gain</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Powers</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
