
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

             

            
               
                  The
Jackal
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). This big-budget remake is deemed a
bastardization of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Zinnemann</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> political thriller, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Day</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jackal</ENAMEX> . "At best generic, at worst nonsensical," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>. Main gripes: an implausible and uninspired
premise--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> recruits an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> to hunt down an
elusive professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assassin</ENAMEX>--and an excess of gratuitous explosions. Stars
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gere</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Willis</ENAMEX> are said to have given lackluster performances.
Nobody in the film "seems to believe in it one bit," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site, and here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  Anastasia
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s cartoon musical
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>'s lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is dismissed as a knockoff of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s cartoon
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">musicals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">all-star cast</ENAMEX> of voices (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meg Ryan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cusack</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Lloyd</ENAMEX>) and the animation, which get "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> house style down
cold" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). But they profess
disappointment at the story, especially at the part where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rasputin</ENAMEX> causes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Revolution</ENAMEX> by casting a magic spell. Prediction: Without the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>
name, the movie won't succeed financially. (Here's the official site.)

            
               
                  The
Sweet Hereafter
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fine Line Pictures</ENAMEX>). High praise for art-house
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atom Egoyan</ENAMEX>'s adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russell Banks</ENAMEX>' novel about a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> that
loses all its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> crash. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say the film, which won
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Grand Prize</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes</ENAMEX>, avoids mawkishness despite its heart-wrenching
subject matter. Critics especially like its intricate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> (it has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
different narrators and is told in nonchronological fragments). It "carries the
exhilaration of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crystal</ENAMEX>-clear artistic vision," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Holm</ENAMEX>'s portrayal of a guilt-wracked yet greedy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> is said
to be especially skillful. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clips</ENAMEX> are available here.)

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion King</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">New Amsterdam Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). After decrying the
Disneyfication of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> rave over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>
adaptation of its cartoon movie. "Far more textured and original than the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lahr</ENAMEX>. Special praise goes to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Taymor</ENAMEX> for the costumes, which integrate puppets and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masks</ENAMEX> and are said to be stylish and innovative. Critics also like the way the
story has been rewritten to add some psychological depth (it's now an Oedipal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">allegory</ENAMEX>). The score, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elton John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Rice</ENAMEX>, has been reworked using <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Zulu</ENAMEX>
choral harmonies.

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  Another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">City</ENAMEX>, Not <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Own</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dominick Dunne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>-trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> writes his "lightly fictionalized memoir"
about the case. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> applaud the book for detailing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX> high society
rather than rehashing the courtroom drama. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX>'s gift for melodrama and
exaggeration, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Toobin</ENAMEX>, makes him the
"perfect chronicler for the case." Others criticize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX>'s penchant for name
dropping and gossip <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mongering</ENAMEX>, particularly his boasts of having given <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Taylor</ENAMEX> regular <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> briefings. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> express
bewilderment at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunne</ENAMEX>'s decision to novelize the trial, since he ends up using
real names for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> but himself.

            

               Art
            

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egon</ENAMEX>
Schiele: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Leopold Collection</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
City). In a new retrospective, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX> modernist (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890-1918</TIMEX>) wins <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>'
grudging respect. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiele</ENAMEX> is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">modernism</ENAMEX>'s more exotic honorable
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mentions</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland Cotter</ENAMEX>. They say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiele</ENAMEX>'s
appeal is less aesthetic than pornographic. His signature pictures--of
adolescent girls exhibiting their genitalia--"contain most of this show's
electricity" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> ). Several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> observe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schiele</ENAMEX> can only do nudes. (MoMA plugs the
exhibit.)

            

               Update
            

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jed Perl</ENAMEX> deflates the hype surrounding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rauschenberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> retrospective. His work "is a parody of an
artistic achievement. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t seems to not make the slightest difference that
his raw materials are clichés, and that his handling of the medium--of any
medium--is inert."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Starship
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Troopers</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wings of</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dove</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Mad</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">City</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Proposal ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Dark Side</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camelot</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seymour M. Hersh</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred C.</ENAMEX>
Kinsey: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public/Private Life</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James H. Jones</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joy</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cooking: The All-Purpose Cookbook</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Warhol Look/Glamour Fashion Style"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            

               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiceworld</ENAMEX> , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> --P.S. 1
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary Arts Center</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX>
Corner ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Violin</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Rice</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brother</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Kincaid</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xerxes</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Opera</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gattaca</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Less</ENAMEX>
Ordinary ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Triumph</ENAMEX> of
Love ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speaking</ENAMEX>
Truth to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita F. Hill</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinderella</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Clark</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Journey</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Discovery</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Music -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rope</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Jackson</ENAMEX>;

            

               Dance -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merce Cunningham</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forward & Reverse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Academy</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>'s
Advocate ;

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michener</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Rampersad</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Side
Show ;

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey Performing Arts Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>);

            
               Fashion --Wearable
Computers (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Media Lab</ENAMEX>);

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psyché</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Franck</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Philharmonic</ENAMEX>).

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
