
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Armageddon
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Touchstone Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> napalm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>'s
second <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth-</ENAMEX>meets-asteroid movie, "an assault on the eyes, the ears, the
brain, common sense and the human desire to be entertained" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
Ebert, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Hunter</ENAMEX> finds it "so predictable it could have been
written by a chimp." The most irksome aspects of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$140 million</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spectacle</ENAMEX>: its jingoism, ear-splitting sound effects, trite one-liners, and
unlikely premise--the planet's fate rests with redneck oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drillers</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dissenting,</ENAMEX> 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>
says the film got him "pumped, bellowing, pogoing backward up the aisle playing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">air guitar</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clips</ENAMEX> are available at the official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Fool</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). Indie auteur <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal Hartley</ENAMEX>'s
least mandarin and most likable film to date. A morality play about a garbage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX>'s ascent to literary fame, it is deemed "a perfect modern parable" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
Maslin, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ), with devastating send-ups of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> and
the publishing world. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> complain it's pretentious--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camille Paglia</ENAMEX>
plays herself--and so "self-conscious it feels uncomfortable with its own skin"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. Hoberman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            

               Death
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911-1998</TIMEX>). A nostalgia fest for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Singing Cowboy</ENAMEX>, with
obituaries declaring him a "soothing presence" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Zimmerman</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ) and "that almost unimaginable thing, the domestic cowboy"
(the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> harp on his loyalty to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale</ENAMEX> and horse
Trigger and his tendency to express himself through ballads, not fisticuffs.
The sociological spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boomers</ENAMEX>, the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buckaroos</ENAMEX> who worshiped <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RR</ENAMEX>, will now
begin feeling their own mortality.

            

               Books
            

            

               
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). High praise for this explication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">explainers</ENAMEX>--profiles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">filmmakers</ENAMEX> who study
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Führer.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>'s purpose: to show how portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> reflect
broader cultural assumptions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> revel in his elegant deflation of bunk
theories, finding in his work "qualities in increasingly short supply in
academic circles: old-fashioned moral rigor and plain old common sense"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Some regret that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX> does
not proffer his own theory clarifying the mysterious origins of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s evil.
(In 
                  Slate
               , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX> praises <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenbaum</ENAMEX>'s ironic style.)

            

               
                  Someone Else's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">America's Unfinished Struggle</ENAMEX> for
Integration
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamar Jacoby</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Free Press</ENAMEX>). A predictably partisan
response for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>'s study of how guilty white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> and black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX>
exacerbated racial polarization in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> slobber over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacoby</ENAMEX>'s conservative denunciations of affirmative
action. As a dig at the left, they compare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jacoby</ENAMEX>'s reportage favorably with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Lemann</ENAMEX>'s in his liberal classic, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Promised Land</ENAMEX> . Meanwhile,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> carp that her tone mirrors the anger of the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> she
depicts.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget Jones</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diary</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Fielding</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viking</ENAMEX>). All the rage
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, this hilarious account of neurotic single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> becomes
the critical rage here. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seizing on Fielding</ENAMEX>'s allusions to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pride</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prejudice</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> declare Diary an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austenlike</ENAMEX> comedy of manners
that captures the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> . They praise the protagonist's caustic humor
for providing an antidote to her "perfectly coiffed ... <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> Ally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBeal</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamsin Todd</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post Book World</ENAMEX> ).
Others find she shares <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBeal</ENAMEX>'s whininess and resembles a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouse</ENAMEX> "who prattles
on incessantly, never asking a more challenging question than 'Do these pants
make me look fat?' " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Zacharek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read

                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Club</ENAMEX>" on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridget Jones</ENAMEX> .)

            

               Performance Art
            

            
               
                  The
Return of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chocolate Smeared Woman</ENAMEX>
                (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Flea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).
Performance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Finley</ENAMEX> reprises her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> show--she spread chocolate
over her naked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX>--which made her the poster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> for right-wing
denunciations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> find her
angry monologues about rape and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Helms</ENAMEX> "obvious" and "dull" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Winer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). Predictably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> pronounce her smut unworthy of
government funding. Less predictably, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> admit to attending her
performance multiple times: "If new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> has been added since her first
chocolate-smeared headlines, it's not really apparent" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX> ).

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- Out of
Sight ;

            
               Movie -- Smoke

               Signals :

            
               Movie -- Dr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolittle</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Gone With</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wind</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnard</ENAMEX>;"

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Suits Me:</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Double Life of Billy Tipton , by Dianne Wood Middlebrook</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Notebooks of Don Rigoberto</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Vargas Llosa</ENAMEX>,
translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Grossman</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>
Files ;

            
               Movie --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
Movies (AFI);

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mulan</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>;"

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Walking With</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wind: A Memoir of the Movement</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lewis</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael D'Orso</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book --<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ship</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gold</ENAMEX>:
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deep Blue Sea</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Kinder</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beautiful Mind , by Sylvia Nasar</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Six Days</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seven Nights</TIMEX> ;

            Movie-- The Opposite of
Sex ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>
Art ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nightingales</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magic Hour</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Gain</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Powers</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>
Show ;

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect</ENAMEX>
Murder ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Sex
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> --The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
Awards;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>
Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX>-Dreamer";

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold New</ENAMEX>
World , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Finnegan</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
