
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The
Apostle
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">October Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actor-director</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Duvall</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>--about a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pentecostal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> who beats his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> into a coma--is
deemed "the best movie ever about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of God" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ).
The film's strength is said to be its uncompromising psychological complexity:
It shows the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">preacher</ENAMEX> as both very good and extremely evil, without lapsing
into moral condemnation. Unlike most films about evangelicalism, it is not a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">condescending</ENAMEX> "put-down of redneck religion" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ).
The most vigorous plaudits go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duvall</ENAMEX>'s performance; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> predict that it
will revive his career from a slump and win him an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Oscar nomination</ENAMEX>. (The movie
is plugged here.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Searchlight Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> debate the
merits of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillian Armstrong</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">My Brilliant Career</ENAMEX> ,
Little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX> ): Is she "one of the best filmmakers of her time" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ) or a filmmaker with promise who
consistently disappoints? Many consider her adaptation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carey</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Booker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prize-winning</ENAMEX> novel--about a romance between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> eccentric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gamblers</ENAMEX>, played by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Fiennes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cate Blanchett</ENAMEX>--to be disjointed. Others praise its depiction
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiennes</ENAMEX>' performance. All
agree that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Armstrong</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stylist</ENAMEX>, producing images "suitable for framing"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clips</ENAMEX> are available here.)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Boxer</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> claim to be weary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> political dramas but admire this one anyway. High praise goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day-Lewis</ENAMEX> for his portrayal of a washed-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boxer</ENAMEX> and former IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> just
released from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. "His most substantial role in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Lim</ENAMEX>, the
Village <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Voice</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are relieved that the film uses politics only as
a backdrop for a romance between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Day-Lewis</ENAMEX> and a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> (played by Emily
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> find the film rife with political caricature and clichés:
"standard-issue IRA dramatics" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ).
(See the official site.)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Seinfeld
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC; Thursdays</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics laud</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX>'s decision to retire his sitcom after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX>, "leaving at the top
of his game" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Kim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). They say the show's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shtick</ENAMEX>--a comedy about self-involved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing goofy things--had begun to
wear thin. Appreciations deem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the nine-season</TIMEX>-old show the best of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> and
a trenchant critique of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-20 th -century</TIMEX> social mores.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Television</ENAMEX>'s first genuine comedy of manners since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Leave It to Beaver</ENAMEX> ,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Handy</ENAMEX>. Prediction: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> 's departure will
end <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s prime-time hegemony, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> filling the void. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> trumpets its prize show.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman Capote</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Which Various Friends, Enemies, Acquaintances</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Detractors Recall His Turbulent</ENAMEX> Career
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Plimpton</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nan A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Talese/Doubleday</ENAMEX>). A gossipfest about the notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> and gadabout. Most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> take the opportunity to sum up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capote</ENAMEX>'s career: They recall with regret
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capote</ENAMEX> spent more time schmoozing than writing, and deem his work less
memorable than his social appearances, particularly at his fabled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Black</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Ball</ENAMEX>" and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tonight Show</ENAMEX> . Critics also chide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plimpton</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rehashing</ENAMEX>, rather than investigating, old accusations, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Capote</ENAMEX>'s alleged
lying and drinking problems. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>
Lehmann-Haupt calls the compilation "fluff," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of</ENAMEX>
Books ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Hardwick</ENAMEX> thinks that its tone suits its subject.

            

               
                  Paradise
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>'s first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-Nobel</ENAMEX> novel, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faulknerish</ENAMEX> tale of an all-black <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, are
mixed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Allen</ENAMEX> says it is "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">p</ENAMEX>]roof
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> continues to change and mature in surprising new directions."
The New 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Menand</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> "the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">strangest</ENAMEX> and most original book that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX> has written," then criticizes it
for its lack of cohesion, its failed forays into magical realism, and its
willful allegorizing. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX> calls it
"a heavy-handed, schematic piece of writing, thoroughly lacking in the
novelistic magic Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morrison</ENAMEX> has wielded so effortlessly in the past." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> posts a page on the book.)

            

               Music
            

            "Northern
Lights<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: The Music of Jean Sibelius</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). A spate of
recent performances of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Finnish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>'s work--at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn Philharmonic</ENAMEX>--sparks <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sibelius</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865-1957</TIMEX>) revisionism.
The old conventional wisdom: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sibelius</ENAMEX> was a vulgar nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">(à la Wagner</ENAMEX>)
and a windy Romantic bore. Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> declare him a cerebral modernist who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">eschewed</ENAMEX> convention: He used "a nineteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vocabulary</ENAMEX> but speaks with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">twentieth-century</ENAMEX> voice" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). The revisionists
rate him one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>'s great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX>.

            

               Update
            

            In a
cover story in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Ferguson</ENAMEX> takes the field of
evolutionary psychology to task by attacking its standard bearer, How the
Mind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Works</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinker</ENAMEX>'s seeming
endorsement of infanticide in a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> article
exposes the ethical failings of the wildly popular new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">branch</ENAMEX> of science.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ferguson</ENAMEX>, echoing a charge made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>, says that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinker</ENAMEX> wants us "to see [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">infanticide</ENAMEX>] not as a moral horror
but as a genetically encoded evolutionary adaptation, as unavoidable as depth
perception or opposable thumbs." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinker</ENAMEX> has denied the accusation, arguing
that he is trying to understand infanticidal behavior, not condoning it.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">31:</TIMEX>

            Winter
Movie Roundup

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24:</TIMEX>

            "The Year
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review in Review</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Scream
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Ally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBeal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>);

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Hogarth: A Life and a World</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenny Uglow</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amistad</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Good Will</ENAMEX>
Hunting ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amistad</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book -- A Certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.D. James</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
