
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman Show</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). Raves mount for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> smash, in
which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Carrey</ENAMEX> plays a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose entire life has been televised without his
knowledge. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he nerviest feature to come out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> in recent memory,"
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weir</ENAMEX>'s comedy about Orwellian mind control and entertainment-age pop culture
"nails the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zeitgeist</ENAMEX> " (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX>
declare <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Truman Show</ENAMEX> overhyped considering its clunky plot and
simple-minded message, which boils down to "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">E</ENAMEX>]ither you are a grotesque victim
of the moguls or an unmitigated rebel" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Rothstein</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site and here for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edestein</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect Murder</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Hitchcock</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> thriller Dial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder</ENAMEX> transposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>, "sexed up, opened out, and finished
off with a disappointing bang-bang climax" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>,

                  Slate
               ). Surprisingly, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> declare it better than the
stagy original, "more fluent and sensuous" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). The virtues of the remake: It has a darker edge and a stronger
cast, which includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gwyneth Paltrow, Viggo Mortensen</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Douglas</ENAMEX>.
It's also said to replicate the original's flaws, in that it isn't very scary.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for
the official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX> and Courtney
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roxie Releasing</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> welcome the chance
to review <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">documentarian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Broomfield</ENAMEX>'s controversial portrait of
grunge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rockers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Love</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Cobain</ENAMEX>. The film, which considers (then
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rejects</ENAMEX>) the theory that Love murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cobain</ENAMEX>, was pulled from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sundance Film Festival</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> threatened to sue. Reviewers delight in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broomfield</ENAMEX>'s portrayal of Love as a violent control freak. "Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> shreds her
own credibility," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Pareles</ENAMEX>. A few attack
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broomfield</ENAMEX>, who also made a film about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">madam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi Fleiss</ENAMEX>, as a "lame
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sensationalist</ENAMEX>" engaged in "character assassination" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  Sex
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> roll their eyes at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>'s latest sitcom, an adaptation of sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candace Bushnell</ENAMEX>'s memoirs.
They chide the series, produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Melrose Place creator Darren Star</ENAMEX>,
for being unfunny and sodden with easy moral outrage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">set crowd</ENAMEX>. "Is
it any wonder that the self-absorbed, the promiscuous, the drugged and the
drunk ... lead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lonely</ENAMEX>, empty lives?" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Phillips</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Jessica Parker</ENAMEX>, who plays the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bushnell</ENAMEX> character, is said
to lack her usual charm. "She's in love with the camera. Unfortunately, it's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unrequited</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the show's risqué
site.)

            

               Theater
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Awards</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> congratulates itself on its recent success--ticket
sales increased <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>--which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> grudgingly attribute to
investments by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Ovitz</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livent</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This season</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>
went corporate," says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Gerard</ENAMEX>. The revived awards show
also gets credit, especially its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">emcee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Donnell</ENAMEX>, who proselytizes
incessantly for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great White Way</ENAMEX>. Sourpusses call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Donnell</ENAMEX> a tacky <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>:
"Are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tampax</ENAMEX> jokes that <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">funny?</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clive Barnes</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Art
            

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>
Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX>-Dreamer" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> retrospective for the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th century</ENAMEX>
English pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raphaelite</ENAMEX> tries to redeem him from his reputation as a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sentimentalist</ENAMEX>. It partly succeeds. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> celebrate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX>' use of
eclectic media (paint, tapestry, stained glass) and varied imagery (Arthurian,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">classical</ENAMEX>, pastoral). Others continue to dismiss his work as sappy and say he
"can't paint very well" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Stevens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burne-Jones</ENAMEX> has become popular because "confrontational Modernism
is losing its mandate in our fin de siècle ." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Benfey</ENAMEX>'s
review of the show in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cold New World: Growing Up in a Harder Country</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finnegan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). High praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s stories
about disaffected youth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finnegan</ENAMEX> for his in-depth reporting
and sympathetic portrayal of the lives of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> banger, a crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX>, and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">skinhead</ENAMEX>. A few carp that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finnegan</ENAMEX>'s dry prose shows how far literary
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX> has fallen from the pyrotechnics of its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">originators</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX>. Others take issue with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finnegan</ENAMEX>'s claim that these are especially hard
times to grow up in: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">One</ENAMEX> wants to ask, 'Harder compared to what?' To life in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dust Bowl</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX>?" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance Morrow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ).

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Last</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Disco</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX>
Floats ;

            
               Television -- More
Tales of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bright Shining Lie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>) and Thanks of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grateful Nation</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rothko</ENAMEX>";

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> .

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Godzilla</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Fear and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loathing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes Film</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Festival Roundup</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freedomland</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Price</ENAMEX>;

            
               Books -- Remembering
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: The Invisible Art of Editing</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ved Mehta</ENAMEX>;
Here But Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here: A Love Story</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lillian Ross</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Larry Sanders Show</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>).

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20:</TIMEX>

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> finale;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulworth</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whisperer</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everlasting Story of Nory , by Nicholson Baker</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cities</ENAMEX> of the
Plain , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cormac McCarthy</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Identity</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milan Kundera</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Asher</ENAMEX>.

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">13:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Deep</ENAMEX>
Impact ;

            

               Movie -- Character ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Into the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Lennon</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titan</ENAMEX>: The
Life and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Rockefeller</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Chernow</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> of
Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Widow</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">One Year</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Irving</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
