
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Early Christmas</TIMEX>
shopping was up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, sparking economic jubilation on
front pages across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crowded Stores Buoy</ENAMEX> Hopes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Retailers</ENAMEX>,"
crowed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . Not everyone was happy. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seasonal</TIMEX> products
and decorations ... are about to clog shop aisles and windows like bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cholesterol</ENAMEX>," grumbled a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> editorial. On the opposite page, an
op-ed headline suggested, "Kwanzaa alternative to commercialism." (posted
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12/3</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> rejected a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> request for an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> to
investigate <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fund raising. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> said she had yet to find "specific,
credible evidence" implicating a high-ranking government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> (i.e., higher
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">than John Huang</ENAMEX>)--the legal requirement for an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. Instead, she
created a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> to look into the matter.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Reno</ENAMEX>, but the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-morning</TIMEX> TV
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pundits</ENAMEX> opined that the independent<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-counsel system</ENAMEX> had already been
irretrievably politicized. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision
"suspicious," but, cheered on by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , vowed to get at
the facts through congressional hearings. Meanwhile, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> reported that in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> letter, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mochtar Riady</ENAMEX>
urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to normalize relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. The early spin was that the
letter didn't prove a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">quid</NUMEX> pro quo, but was yet another example of documents
sat on by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stonewalling</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/3</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbian President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> cracked down on political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>
of escalating public demonstrations. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protests</ENAMEX> were over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s
annulment of municipal elections that appeared to have been won by opposition
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> arrested several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protesters</ENAMEX>, and threatened the rest with
unspecified "consequences." The short-term betting favors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, on the
grounds that the working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> is too distracted, ignorant, and cowardly to
join the opposition. The long-term betting favors a bloody ouster of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>,
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> tradition. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idealists</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lewis</ENAMEX> in the New York
Times ) accused the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> of idly standing by while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> tyrant oppresses his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. More skeptical news reports indicate
that the opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> are no angels. Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> are quoted
"privately" saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is easier to reform, because he's trying to
undo his reputation as a butcher. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/3</TIMEX>)
            

            A panel of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>
appointed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is expected to propose a new inflation index to replace
the Consumer Price Index . The new index will reduce the official
inflation rate, thereby trimming annual cost-of-living increases in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security</ENAMEX> and other federal benefits. This increasingly looks like the way
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will agree to prune entitlements, while sharing the
cover of a technical correction. A "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" piece in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> observed that if the lower inflation numbers are applied to the
economic statistics of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past couple of decades</TIMEX>, the perceived stagnation of
real wages turns out to have been a healthy increase. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/3</TIMEX>)
            

            
               Deathwatch: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> perished, apparently from a heart attack. "He died singing 'Tiptoe
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thru</ENAMEX>' the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tulips</ENAMEX>,' " reported his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> remembered
him as "a romantic in pursuit of a beautiful dream," but noted that his career
tailspin had forced him to move back in with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>. Abortion-clinic killer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Salvi</ENAMEX> asphyxiated himself in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>; his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and lawyers
portrayed him as the victim of an "inhuman" corrections system. Mother
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teresa</ENAMEX> suffered a near-fatal <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX>, checked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> for
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, received an emergency angioplasty, staged a
surprising recovery (attributed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to her "spiritual strength"),
suffered another setback, then improved slightly, but remained in critical
condition with chronic lung and kidney trouble. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX>
reported that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> "were reconciled to the prospect of [her] death."
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/3</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-examined in his civil trial. He failed to explain the cuts on his hand or
the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bronco</ENAMEX>, and said he had never struck or beaten <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Simpson</ENAMEX>.
He further suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole</ENAMEX> might have caused the red marks on her face by
picking at pimples, and that she might have split her own lip by falling down.
News accounts agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s testimony contradicted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicole</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">diary</ENAMEX>, his own phone records, notes from his interview with a defense
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, and a photo of him wearing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruno Magli</ENAMEX> shoes. (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photo</ENAMEX> was real but the shoes depicted in it were a "fraud.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times called it "potentially the most damaging day yet of his civil trial."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">For Slate</ENAMEX>'s take, see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harry</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s latest dispatch from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camp O.J.</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">O.J. pundits</ENAMEX>
explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Petrocelli</ENAMEX> had learned from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>' mistakes in the criminal trial and was correcting them, chiefly by
presenting his evidence more quickly and selectively. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Rosenberg</ENAMEX> scoffed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> had also written off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early days</TIMEX> of the criminal trial. Moreover, several legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> called
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s leniency toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petrocelli</ENAMEX> (e.g., allowing him to mention <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s
failure on a lie-detector test) good grounds for an appeal if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> loses.
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/26</TIMEX>)
            

            In an interview with
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX> suggested that she would like a
"formal role " in guiding the implementation of the welfare
reforms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> reluctantly signed into law <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>. She
stipulated that she wasn't proposing anything like her dominant role in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-'94</TIMEX> health-care debate. Television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> pounced on the
story anyway. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> standard lines of analysis were: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first lady</ENAMEX>
would try to tug her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> back to the perilous left; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> don't want her to take a public role, because she'll become a
lightning rod; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are secretly rooting for her to take a public
role, for both the above reasons. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/26</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zemin</ENAMEX> met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> and agreed to visit
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. It would be the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> state visit since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1989</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> touted the state-visit agreement as a
major step forward, and averred that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> had spoken firmly against
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s abuse of human rights. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> concluded, with
equal unanimity, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had accomplished nothing. Reaction was divided on
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point: Some accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> of selling out human rights and nuclear-arms
reduction (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is a major nuclear proliferator) for free trade, while others
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accused Clinton</ENAMEX> of selling out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> principles for a photo op.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Editorialists</ENAMEX> grumbled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had come off as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimp</ENAMEX> and a patsy;
Sino-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> called the shortsighted, conniving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> no match for
the farsighted, conniving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, in its latest attempt to prove
its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> right, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> threatened trade sanctions against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> on the
grounds that a movie being co-produced by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> "is intended to
glorify the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>, so it is an interference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s internal affairs."
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/26</TIMEX>)
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> hijacked
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ethiopian</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">airliner</ENAMEX> and forced an emergency landing in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ocean</ENAMEX> that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">175</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>. The story,
which played on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> front pages for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX>, featured several peculiar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">angles</ENAMEX>. The hijackers used the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s safety devices--an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ax</ENAMEX> and a fire
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">extinguisher</ENAMEX>--as their principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX>. They demanded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> be flown
from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, purportedly "to make history," and refused to believe
that there wasn't enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> to get there. Early reports said <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of
the hijackers were in custody; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> reports indicated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> had grabbed
the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/26</TIMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold James</ENAMEX>
Nicholson was arrested and charged with spying for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> . He allegedly
sold the identities and profiles of new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120,000</NUMEX>. Though the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">highest-ranking CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> ever accused of espionage, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholson</ENAMEX> appears to
have done less damage than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aldrich Ames</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> touted this arrest as
proof that they had fixed the bureaucratic bungling that had allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ames</ENAMEX> to go
undetected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editorialists</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholson</ENAMEX> had made the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>' job comically easy (he even climbed into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> with diplomatic
plates registered to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Embassy</ENAMEX>) and, even so, hadn't been caught and
busted soon enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> also debated whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mole</ENAMEX>'s exposure
proved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> was still a duplicitous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> offered
moral indignation; the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> offered cynical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nonchalance</ENAMEX>. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/22</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>
troubles eased, while its legal peril deepened. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> settled a
racial-discrimination lawsuit for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$176 million</NUMEX>, including a raise for every
black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX>. Reportedly the biggest payment made in such a case, it is
hardly a nick in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>'s annual revenue of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $30 billion</NUMEX>. Black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> (e.g., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeWayne Wickham of USA Today</ENAMEX> ) praised <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> for acting quickly, called the boycott of independent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> gas
stations misguided, and argued that the crusade against corporate racism should
move on to more egregious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">culprits</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circuit City</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile,
though, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> filed charges against former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Lundwall</ENAMEX>,
in what many saw as a maneuver to pressure him for new leads in the
evidence-destruction criminal case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> juicy discovery:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lundwall</ENAMEX> apparently released the tapes of the now-infamous "jelly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bean</ENAMEX>" meeting
to punish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texaco</ENAMEX> for downsizing him. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/22</TIMEX>)
            

            The federal government
decided to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> to disconnect their air bags, which,
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> estimates, are killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> per month and are on
track to kill <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> per week as more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> feature them. (The
deaths are generally caused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s impact against the bag, or against
the seat on the rebound.) The decision was viewed as a vindication of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">automakers</ENAMEX>, who warned of such injuries <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX>; the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> touted the "humbling retreat" of former air-bag evangelist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Claybrook</ENAMEX>. Auto-safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editorialists</ENAMEX> insisted that air bags save
many more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> than they kill, and worried that the backlash will go too far.
Everyone agreed that the solution is technology: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Automakers</ENAMEX> favor
slower-inflating air bags, while consumer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> want new gizmos to detect
the size of each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> and adjust the inflation speed accordingly.
(posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/22</TIMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straws</ENAMEX> in the wind:
It's been <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a bad month</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> , with election defeats in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulgaria</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lithuania</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Romania</ENAMEX>, on top of prior losses in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> reported that marijuana is becoming more
potent and more widely available. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> says the telecommuting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolution</ENAMEX> has fizzled, in part because office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">teamwork</ENAMEX> is becoming more
important. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>, rationing, and other
medical-insurance nightmares conjured up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> health-care plan are coming to pass anyway. A group of former
independent counsels (a k a special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>), including <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archibald Cox</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iran-Contra</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Walsh</ENAMEX>, agreed that independent
counsels are being appointed too indiscriminately. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX> ratings indicate
that young <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are giving up television in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> surfing
and other pastimes; the television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> are challenging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nielsen</ENAMEX>'s data and
threatening to create a rival ratings <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX>. (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/26</TIMEX>)
            

         
      
   
