
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Experience</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23 and 24</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT).
Bipartisan applause for a documentary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gipper</ENAMEX>'s life and times. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX>
praise its evenhanded take on his policies as well as his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>: He's
said to have been both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectual simpleton</ENAMEX> and political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Conservatives</ENAMEX> profess shock that something so "remarkably balanced" was
produced by "offensively biased" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Nordlinger</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> ). An exultant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial says the show
signals that "honest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX>" have found a "new appreciation" for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>
plugs the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX> here.)

            
               
                  The
Wedding
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 22 and 23</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). Book-club <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winfrey</ENAMEX> wins even more encomiums for bringing "great art to the mainstream"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caryn James</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winfrey</ENAMEX> for producing
a miniseries based on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlem Renaissance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy West</ENAMEX>'s novel about an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interracial</ENAMEX> relationship in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX>. Plaudits to the series for popularizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West</ENAMEX>'s underappreciated novel (written in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX>) and for
exposing the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bourgeoisie</ENAMEX>'s own snobbery. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> assail the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX>-opera
plot: "[H]istorical information ... is no substitute for drama" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kock</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> ). (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Stevenson</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winfrey</ENAMEX> in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  The
Closer
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mondays</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magnum P.I.</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Selleck</ENAMEX>
becomes the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> to attempt a comeback via a sitcom (about a glitzy
advertising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> who loses his job). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selleck</ENAMEX>'s good looks
can't make up for his inept comic timing or for the show's witless
humor--mostly cheap sexual innuendo and predictable punch lines. "A dismal
sitcom that seems to embody all that is wrong with dismal sitcoms" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Movie
            

            

               
                  Palmetto
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Castle Rock Entertainment</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Volker</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schl√∂ndorff</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Tin Drum</ENAMEX> ) tries his hand at film noir, but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
say he should stick to "adapting serious literary works" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). They complain that his film--about an ex-con (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Harrelson</ENAMEX>)
who falls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisabeth Shue</ENAMEX>) of a dying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX>--overdoes the
shadowy lighting and complicated plot twists of the genre. Schl√∂ndorff, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>, wants to "out-noir every other film
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">noir</ENAMEX>." Others praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrelson</ENAMEX>'s humorous turn as a dullard and profess
surprise that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shue</ENAMEX> makes such a sexy seductress. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Palmetto</ENAMEX> 's official site.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  Cloudsplitter
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Banks</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HarperCollins</ENAMEX>). Praise for
The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sweet Hereafter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Banks</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> historical novel, about
the abolitionist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zealot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Brown</ENAMEX>. "[H]is best novel, a furious, sprawling
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">drama</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Skow</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> tells the story from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective of Brown</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, who joined his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> in his famous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1859</TIMEX> raid on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harpers Ferry</ENAMEX>--a narrative choice that allows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Banks</ENAMEX> to show "the familial
repercussions of living with a visionary and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michiko Kakutani</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> complain that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banks</ENAMEX> sermonizes.

            

               Art
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernand L√</ENAMEX>©ger
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">painter</ENAMEX>'s first major <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> show in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">43 years</TIMEX> occasions critical revision.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> find <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">L√</ENAMEX>©ger less the "stolid, ruminative" <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Marxist</ENAMEX> and more the witty
"virtuoso" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). While they still celebrate his
depictions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early-20 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">city</ENAMEX>, they now also notice his
little-known forays into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dadaism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fauvism</ENAMEX>. His endurance is chalked up to
his training as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> and his embrace of bright colors. "Even the lesser
L√©gers ... exist at an esthetic altitude that few living <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> will ever
reach" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton Kramer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> ). (MoMA plugs the show
here.)

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  Freak
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Cort Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). With his latest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-man
show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Leguizamo</ENAMEX> is said to join the ranks of great such comic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">performers</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Pryor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily Tomlin</ENAMEX>. The most hilarious bits, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
say, are his riffs on masturbation and on growing up as a working-class <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX>.
His ability to act out a conversation among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> leads the New York
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> to conclude that "[t]here's a whole <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> inside this
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s slender frame." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissenting</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyons</ENAMEX> complains that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leguizamo</ENAMEX>'s rants about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latino</ENAMEX> stereotypes make him "a
self-important bore."

            

               Updates
            

            Raves for
Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dalloway</ENAMEX> keep coming, but a more critical take also emerges.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX> says the film proves "that some
novels resist adaptation to the core of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beings</ENAMEX>." The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX> chides the film for turning "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Redgrave</ENAMEX>, one
of the most vibrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> of our time, into a passive, opaque, mannequin of
regret." ... <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> seek to explain the stunning success of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Theories: 1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo DiCaprio</ENAMEX> is a teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idol</ENAMEX> for the
ages. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Winslet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> "helps us understand that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">liberation</ENAMEX> is not a dated concept" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Schoemer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> dies, and that's what we want to see. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Everybody needs a good cry.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Sphere</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Mrs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalloway</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Wedding</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Singer</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyer</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Grisham</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Riven
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T. Coraghessan Boyle</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">th Winter Olympics</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>);

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Vagina Monologues</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nil</ENAMEX> by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouth</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Blues</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brothers 2000</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Nominations</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">early</ENAMEX> reviews;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fucking</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Maggs</ENAMEX>:
A Novel , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carey</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Quindlen</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- Yield ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Jam</ENAMEX>;

            

               Art --"China: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Years"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capeman</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-Sex<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-Scandal Coverage</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
Expectations ;

            
               Movie -- Desperate
Measures ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>
Libre , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmore Leonard</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Gun</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nadine Gordimer</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Wag the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Gingerbread
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX>
World ;

            
               Book -- Birthday
Letters , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Night</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Train</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Enduring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McEwan</ENAMEX>;

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXXII</ENAMEX>;

            
               Dance --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail</ENAMEX>
Baryshnikov: An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evening of Music and Dance With the White Oak Chamber</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ensemble</ENAMEX>."

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
