
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Lost in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Space</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). Yet another pan of yet another
screen adaptation of an old TV show. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90 million</NUMEX> remake of the sci-fi
series is said to lack the original's campy charm. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silliness</ENAMEX> has been replaced
by stupidity" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> problem: a
bad screenplay full of pop-psychological clichés about dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>.
Another problem: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 750</NUMEX> special effects. Nonetheless, the movie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dethrones Titanic</ENAMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>'s top box office draw. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Audiences</ENAMEX> must
have lost their will to be entertained," laments the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Time</ENAMEX> s'
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
               ,
here for
the film's official site, and here to read
more of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ebert</ENAMEX>'s complaints in his 
                  Slate
                "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Diary</ENAMEX>.")

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Butcher Boy</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Crying Game</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Jordan</ENAMEX> for his dark coming of age tale. They particularly like
his deft black humor and "gift for genuinely shocking his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
Maslin, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope-basher Sinead O'Connor</ENAMEX> portrays the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgin Mary</ENAMEX>. The story, set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, concerns a homicidal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-year-old</TIMEX>;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> note the parallels to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonesboro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ark.</ENAMEX>, massacre. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish Prisoner</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth cinematic</NUMEX> directorial effort--which, like his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Games</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homicide</ENAMEX> , concerns a big con--is declared his best. The plot is said to
be sinuous and suspenseful, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mamet</ENAMEX> is credited with eliciting an
uncharacteristically strong performance from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Martin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Die-hard Mamet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">haters</ENAMEX> complain he's still too abstract, can't write female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, and
"remains a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of the theater" who doesn't get film (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> ). (
                  Slate
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">'s Edelstein</ENAMEX> reviews The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prisoner</ENAMEX>. Here is the official site for the film.)

            

               Music
            

            
               
                  Left
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Imbruglia</ENAMEX> (RCA). The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">23-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Australian</ENAMEX>
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX>-opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> is crowned the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl</ENAMEX>, "a pop juggernaut in the
making" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tracey Pepper</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say Imbruglia
combines feminist power-pop à <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">la Alanis Morissette</ENAMEX> and devastating beauty. "A
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audrey Hepburn</ENAMEX> as refashioned for the post-grunge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elysa Gardner</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cynics</ENAMEX> contend she's a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>'s puppet," a
pretty face who can't write songs or sing (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Thigpen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  Push
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m. EST</TIMEX>/PST). This Melrose
Place- style soap about aspiring <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> is deemed the most uncouth
of the new teen and twentysomething shows. "Should embarrass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>. Push
is smarmy on every level" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bianco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ). Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> say
the show is little more than a vehicle for showing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> romping around in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">leotards</ENAMEX> and swimsuits. Others regret it squanders its potential for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
plugs the show here.)

            

               
                  Frontline: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">From Jesus to Christ</ENAMEX>--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Christians</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>; click
here for a
schedule). Respectful praise for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-part documentary on the "real"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, served up for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Week</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are pleased with its agnosticism: The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> neither support nor refute claims of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>' divinity. Instead, they
feature <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> talking about his small, fractious sect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissenting</ENAMEX>, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Louis Wilken</ENAMEX> criticizes its focus on trendy
concerns (power politics, "narrative") at the expense of spiritual content.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> presented in this series is the one fashionable in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late-twentieth-century</TIMEX> academic culture." (Here is the official site.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  An
Instance of the Fingerpost
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iain Pears</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverhead Books</ENAMEX>). British
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">journalist Iain Pears</ENAMEX>' best-selling murder mystery, set in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century England</ENAMEX>, is compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Umberto Eco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Name of the Rose</ENAMEX> .
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pears</ENAMEX> uses the thriller as an occasion to wax philosophical, meditating on
scientific method and political liberalism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise his skill at
depicting famous historical figures (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">philosopher</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Locke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Wren</ENAMEX>) and call his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rashomon</ENAMEX> -style narrative "baroque and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ingenious"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Miller</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ).

            

               
                  Cavedweller
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Allison</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutton</ENAMEX>). The author of
Bastard out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> , known as a confessional memoirist par
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excellence</ENAMEX>, writes about someone other than herself, and earns mixed reviews.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Feminists</ENAMEX> approve of the novel, about an aging rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> and her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> abandoned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, because it coldly documents the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s abuse and is "clear-eyed
about the economic forces that shape women's lives" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valerie Sayers</ENAMEX>, the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). Others say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allison</ENAMEX> "leans precariously toward
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">melodrama</ENAMEX>" and tries too hard for "gut-wrenching emotion" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Richardson</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Updates
            

            More
hubbub about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teletubbies</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> show aimed at toddlers: "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>,
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> reportedly watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teletubbies</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">long nights</TIMEX> of dancing
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ingesting chemicals</ENAMEX> surely banned from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Teletubbyland</ENAMEX>," says the New York
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caryn James</ENAMEX>. Ecstasy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tablets</ENAMEX> featuring the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faces</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teletubbies</ENAMEX> have
been spotted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> raves. ... In an essay on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of realism
today, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jed Perl</ENAMEX> pans the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck</ENAMEX>
Close retrospective at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX> as "the work of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>
who has no sensibility and is proud of it."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Grease</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boys</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- From
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teletubbies</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Theater -- The Sound</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">All-True</ENAMEX>
Travels and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adventures of Lidie Newton</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Smiley</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Consilience</ENAMEX>:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unity of Knowledge</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.O. Wilson</ENAMEX>;

            

               Fashion --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fall Lines</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">25:</TIMEX>

            
               Event --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy Awards</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- Sitcom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roundup</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Primary
Colors ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Wild</ENAMEX>
Things ;

            
               Movie -- Taste of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cherry</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cabaret</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lohengrin</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">18:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Man in</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iron Mask</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Love and</ENAMEX>
Death on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Men With</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Guns</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lateline</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television -- Significant 
               Others (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pop</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pilgrim</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Clapton</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cycle : Inside the Clinton Propaganda Machine</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Children</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Halberstam</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The Big
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lebowski</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Primary
Colors hype;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Twilight</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marshals</ENAMEX> ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The Beauty
Queen of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leenane</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- One Nation</ENAMEX>,
After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Wolfe</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- A History of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Johnson</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
