
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Snake Eyes</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paramount Pictures</ENAMEX>). Despite great filmmaking,
including a virtuosic single-shot opening scene, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian De Palma</ENAMEX>'s latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">thriller</ENAMEX> is pronounced a failure. The problem: a disappointing ending. It's
"the worst kind of bad film: the kind that gets you all worked up and then lets
you down," declares the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX>. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daphne Merkin</ENAMEX> says the film "underrates our intelligence."
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX> wonders, "[H]as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian DePalma</ENAMEX>
finally lost his mind?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Morgenstern</ENAMEX> is
alone in finding the ending plausible--he claims "it all makes perfect sense,
at least eventually." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raves</ENAMEX>, however, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicolas Cage</ENAMEX>'s performance as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sleazy</ENAMEX>, brown polyester clad <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Santoro</ENAMEX>, a crooked local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Carr</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glows</ENAMEX>, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cage</ENAMEX>] suggests an oven-fresh, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX>-filled,
glazed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meatloaf</ENAMEX>." (
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> is more pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">De Palma</ENAMEX>
than most. Read his review.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Halloween:</ENAMEX> H20
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax Film Corp.</ENAMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years</TIMEX> after starring
in the original horror classic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Lee Curtis</ENAMEX> is back in
her original role as scream queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie Strode</ENAMEX> (now an alcoholic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headmistress</ENAMEX>), facing off with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">knife</ENAMEX>-wielding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maniac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Myers</ENAMEX>. Critics
call this version more polished than the low budget original and better than
the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> sequels but say nonetheless that it is predictable, devoid of
scare power, and overly fond of the current horror movie trend of "smirky pomo
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">self-consciousness</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Lim</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ). (Visit the official site.)

            
               
                  How
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Stella Got Her Groove Back</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). Hype is
underway for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> film adaptation of a best-selling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry McMillan</ENAMEX> novel,
after the unexpected success of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Waiting to Exhale</ENAMEX> . The story: A
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40-year-old</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workaholic stockbroker</ENAMEX> and single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Bassett</ENAMEX>),
goes with her best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regina</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX>) on a vacation to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX>,
where she falls in love with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> 20 years her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX>. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">W</ENAMEX>]omen [should]
giggle with vengeful glee," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allison Samuels</ENAMEX>; the "big
dose of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-girl</ENAMEX> humor" is sure to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> pleaser. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> pant at the
steamy, tearful sex scenes between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX> and young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winston</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taye Diggs</ENAMEX>),
although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX> dissents, calling it "soft-pore
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cornography</ENAMEX>."

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainbow Six</ENAMEX>
               ,by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Putnam</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of the
technothriller delivers the goods, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">752</NUMEX> pages of thrill-a<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-minute</TIMEX> action
scenes, incredibly detailed descriptions of cutting edge military technology,
and enough acronyms to set your head spinning. This isn't great literature but,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> say, within the genre, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clancy</ENAMEX> remains the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>. Despite the usual
carps about his "tortured" prose (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dana Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> )
and cardboard cutout <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> admit the novel is "a ripping
read" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Publishers Weekly</ENAMEX> ). (Read an excerpt of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rainbow Six</ENAMEX> .)

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX>: I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Telling You for the Last Time--Live</ENAMEX> on
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Broadway</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> over-hyped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Seinfeld</ENAMEX> finale of the year
(<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX> of his international tour and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-show run at the Broadhurst
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theatre</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> point out it's a rehash of his best trademark observations
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about everyday</TIMEX> life, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> give him standing ovations. Praise goes to
his pitch-perfect delivery, timing, and confidence. Pans go to the routine,
which lacks the requisite "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">free-associative</ENAMEX> lunatic spirit" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan Stuart</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Sun-Times</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shales</ENAMEX> calls
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> "stiff" and the material "painfully familiar." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visit HBO</ENAMEX>'s home page).

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upright Citizens Brigade</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wednesdays</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 p.m. ET</TIMEX>/PT). A
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>-based sketch comedy and improvisation group rides a wave of critical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">approbation</ENAMEX> to the choice post- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Park</ENAMEX> spot on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foursome</ENAMEX>'s live shows, most recently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saigon Suicide Squad</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bucket</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX> , win applause for their originality, cleverness, and flair for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anarchic</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Strauss</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> calls them "hilarious,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">surreal</ENAMEX>, and completely off-kilter." (Check out
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">page</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>).

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Art of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorcycle</ENAMEX>";

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lolita</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maximum</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Movies -- Ever After:</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cinderella Story</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movies -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Negotiator</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- Burn
Rate , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wolff</ENAMEX>;

            

               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome Robins</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            
               Book-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">100 Best English-Language Novels</ENAMEX> Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>;

            
               Book--
               Point of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Origin</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Cornwell</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie--
               Disturbing
Behavior ;

            
               Movie--
               Pi ;

            

               Movie--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thief</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mask of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zorro</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Saving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- There's
Something <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Mary</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- Hello
Nasty , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beastie Boys</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Lucky
Bastard , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles McCarry</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Twelfth
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Night</TIMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
15

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>! --The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unknown Terrain:</ENAMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Landscapes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Wyeth</ENAMEX>";

            
               Movie -- Small
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Soldiers</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Lethal</ENAMEX>
Weapon <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">66</NUMEX> ;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Embrya</ENAMEX> ,
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maxwell</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Music -- Car Wheels on a Gravel Road</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda Williams</ENAMEX>.

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
