
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Music
            

            
               
                  Spiceworld
               , by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> pop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> a triumph of
marketing over taste (their debut album sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18 million</NUMEX> copies). Their new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">album</ENAMEX> is deemed particularly offensive. "[B]land, half-hearted harmonizing ...
so slickly produced that most techno-pop sounds positively organic by
comparison," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Nichols</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> is
said to have overplayed its fame by appearing in too many commercials.
Prediction: It will soon become a pop-history footnote. (A dissenting minority
calls the new album irresistible and compares the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> band
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABBA</ENAMEX>.) ("Hi! We're the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>" is the official site. For

                  Slate
               's take, see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Plotz</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>.")

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
            

            
               P.S.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contemporary Arts Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX> elementary
school turned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">art gallery</ENAMEX> undergoes an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.5-million</NUMEX> renovation and becomes the
"world's largest contemporary art <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX>." Art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> welcome the expansion,
pointing out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">gallery</ENAMEX> now can exhibit oversized installations most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">museums</ENAMEX> can't accommodate. Works by young, experimental, and overlooked artists
are also displayed in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">basements</ENAMEX>, stairwells, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX>. Highlights:
an entirely white painting by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Ryman</ENAMEX> hanging in an old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coal bin</ENAMEX> and a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-story steel chair by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marina Abramovic</ENAMEX>. "[A] highly entertaining
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">spectacle</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Stevens</ENAMEX>.

            

               Movie
            

            
               
                  Red
Corner
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MGM</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> applaud <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Gere</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-bashing activism but
sneer at his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>-bashing movie. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gere</ENAMEX> plays an arrogant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wheeler</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> who is accused wrongly of murdering a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and then
subjected to the horrors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> judicial system. The plot twists are
dismissed as hackneyed, borrowed from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold War</ENAMEX> thrillers and courtroom
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">melodramas</ENAMEX>. The depiction of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> life is said to be so grim that it "verges
on the xenophobic" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (See the
Red <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">Corner site</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Violin
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Rice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Has the gothic horror <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and
sometime soft-core pornographer lost her touch? Her "overwrought prose has gone
grotesquely rococo," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Friedman</ENAMEX>. This
novel, about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> who finds happiness communing with ghosts, switches
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">narrators</ENAMEX> and plot lines so often that it is said to be unreadable--and
pretentious, particularly when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX> holds forth on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> theology and
classical music. But some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> claim to have relished the book's spirit of
kitschy fun. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> has a gothic page devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rice</ENAMEX>.)

            
               
                  My
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Brother</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica Kincaid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kincaid</ENAMEX>'s
memoir of her impoverished childhood in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Antigua</ENAMEX>, occasioned by the death of her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">half-brother</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>. Some reviews praise the book, which was nominated for a
National <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Book Award</ENAMEX>, for sidestepping the clichés of the genre. She refuses "to
oversimplify, overanalyze or sentimentalize," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Quindlen</ENAMEX>. Others take her to task for revisiting her favorite
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obsession</ENAMEX>, her childhood. It's time for her "to tell us something new" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
Skow, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kerr</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
                and
here
for an excerpt from the book.)

            

               Opera
            

            

               
                  Xerxes
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. F. Handel</ENAMEX>, libretto by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nicolo Minato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silvio</ENAMEX>
Stampiglia, performed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Opera</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York State Theater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX>). Raves for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> debut of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">31-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">countertenor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>, hailed as the " <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'next Pavarotti</ENAMEX>' ... who stirs inarticulate passion by
singing very much like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Levine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ). Critics
are surprised by the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Opera</ENAMEX> at transposing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Handel</ENAMEX>'s
piece from ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. On other
occasions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has seemed more like a "postgraduate workshop for the
promising and ill-prepared" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Holland</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for a schedule.)

            

               Updates
            

            Raves give
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> to pans for the musical Triumph of
Love. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Simon</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> adaptation of the
comedy by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierre Marivaux</ENAMEX> includes
"rowdiness and bawdry [which] are as out of place as a belch in a declaration
of love." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Heilpern</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>
"oversell their wares." ... In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Boyers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">condemns John Updike</ENAMEX> for setting his sci-fi novel <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Toward the End of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> in the aftermath of a horrific conflagration. "It uses the moral and
historical grandeur of a world war to promote its cranky local obsessions to a
level of universality and interest that they do not deserve."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gattaca</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Less</ENAMEX>
Ordinary ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Triumph
of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Speaking</ENAMEX>
Truth to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita F. Hill</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinderella</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">& Clark</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Journey</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Discovery</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Music -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Velvet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rope</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Jackson</ENAMEX>;

            

               Dance -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merce Cunningham</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forward & Reverse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Academy</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Music</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>'s
Advocate ;

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michener</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Rampersad</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Side
Show ;

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey Performing Arts Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>);

            
               Fashion --Wearable
Computers (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Media Lab</ENAMEX>);

            

               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psyché</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Franck</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Philharmonic</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Seven Years</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Boogie

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Nights</TIMEX> ;

            
               Fashion --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Versace</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spring/Summer '98 Collections</ENAMEX>;

            
               Product --Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Award --Nobel Prize</ENAMEX>
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Literature, Dario Fo</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- How the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mind Works</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- U-Turn ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Square ;

            
               Movie -- Soul
Food ;

            

               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bilbao</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Toward the</ENAMEX>
End of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>;

            

               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
