
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  Nil
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mouth</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Oldman</ENAMEX>'s directorial
debut about a dysfunctional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South London</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is praised for avoiding the
moralizing mawkishness of the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> working-class drama. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leigh</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sans</ENAMEX> cuteness" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. Hoberman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ). Reviewers praise
the movie's frighteningly realistic violence, especially a scene in which a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> beats his pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, causing her to miscarry. Watching the film,
says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lane</ENAMEX>, is like "getting whacked over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> with a shovel." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blues Brothers</ENAMEX> 2000
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal</ENAMEX>). Would this sequel to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>
comedy based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Aykroyd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Belushi</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> have made a "better concert film," as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Ebert</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun-Times</ENAMEX> says? Maybe. Colorful performances by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.B. King</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brown</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aretha Franklin</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> & B legends can't keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> from
complaining that the movie feels like a retread of the original <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blues Brothers</ENAMEX>
flick--a blues <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> traveling cross-country, chased both by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tuneless</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Goodman</ENAMEX> can't measure up to the late
Belushi, whose absence "is fatal in itself" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Clips</ENAMEX> are available here.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nominations</ENAMEX>, early reviews.
            

            Critics
deem the roster free of surprises. Titanic , with its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> nominations
(more than any movie since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">All About Eve</TIMEX> ), is pegged as the likely
best-picture winner. The No. 2 contender is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">L.A. Confidential</ENAMEX> , which has
swept the film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' awards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> failed to expect only one inclusion and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">omission</ENAMEX>: The indie feel-good movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Full Monty</ENAMEX> got a best-picture
bid, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amistad</ENAMEX> didn't. Among the performer
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nominations</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>' sentimental favorites are aging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> staging
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comebacks</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Fonda</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ulee's Gold</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Reynolds</ENAMEX> ( Boogie
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nights</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Duvall</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Apostle</ENAMEX>). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSNBC</ENAMEX> lists all the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominees</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shopping</ENAMEX> and Fucking
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Theatre Workshop</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> respond to the hit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> play with either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fulsome</ENAMEX> praise or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revulsion</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Lyons</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> hails <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playwright Mark Ravenhill</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarantino</ENAMEX> laced with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Céline</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burroughs</ENAMEX>." Others find the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>' nihilistic rants merely trite and their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sexcapades</ENAMEX>--a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14-year-old</TIMEX> begs to be sodomized with knives--disgusting.

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX>
Maggs: A Novel
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Carey</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Unanimous acclaim for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Australian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Booker Prize-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>'s update of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Dickens</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
Expectations . "An audacious and wholly successful act of writerly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reinvention</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Carnegie</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ). Reviewers praise
the way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> re-examines the oppressive aspects of Victorian <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> literature, even as he spins a crack adventure story. "If you've read
[<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>], you get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX>'s chuckle. If not, you still get a good yarn"
(Lakshmi
Gopalkrishnan, 
                  Slate
               ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excerpt</ENAMEX>.)

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black and Blue</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Quindlen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Quindlen</ENAMEX>'s
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> novel--a thriller about domestic violence--is seen as yet another way to
repackage her old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> columns. Issue advocacy comes at the
expense of realistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and a coherent plot. And why is it, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
ask, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quindlen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>, the abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX>, sounds so
much like a sophisticated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> congratulate
Quindlen for having moved beyond veiled autobiography.

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Yield
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Jam</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Epic</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX> grunge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> has grown up.
It has overcome its penchant for "overblown, chest-beating angst," according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Sheffield</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> , with its most mature album to date,
which features clever, self-mocking lyrics and bears the influence of '70s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">supergroup Led Zeppelin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pearl Jam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detractors</ENAMEX> still can't stand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie</ENAMEX>
Vedder: They say he's unbearably self-important and limits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s appeal
by refusing to "sell out" and make videos. General consensus: "The fabled '90s
alt-rock revolution is over" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Sinclair</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Art
            

            
               "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>:
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Years"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> marvel at this exhibit of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sculptures</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ceramics</ENAMEX>, and paintings, most of them never seen before outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. But they knock the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX>'s presentation. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Gripes: 1</ENAMEX>) The exhibit
aims to sum up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in the same amount of space recently devoted to a
single Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rauschenberg</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Afraid of alienating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
government, which lent the works, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> includes no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> critical
of communism. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Curators provide too little context and explication. It is "a
triumph of institutional chutzpah ... an esthetic showcase of immense ambition
in search of a solid reason for happening" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holland Cotter</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> plugs the show here.)

            

               Updates
            

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fenton</ENAMEX> defends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>. " 'Plath <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>' will never forgive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> for having been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plath</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>--a role which in their fantasies they would much better fill." A rising
consensus deems <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Birthday Letters mediocre poetry:</ENAMEX> "slack and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secondhand</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Benfey</ENAMEX>, 
                  Slate
               ). ... After initial
jeers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> extend a warmer welcome to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> novel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Night Train</ENAMEX> . "The novel draws its energies
from the linguistic pyrotechnics of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nabokov</ENAMEX> and the human immensities of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellow</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lanchester</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> , where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amis</ENAMEX> is regularly
published.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Feb.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:</TIMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capeman</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-Sex<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">-Scandal Coverage</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Creek</ENAMEX> (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
Expectations ;

            
               Movie -- Desperate
Measures ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cuba</ENAMEX>
Libre , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmore Leonard</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Gun</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nadine Gordimer</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Wag the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Gingerbread
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice</ENAMEX>
World ;

            
               Book -- Birthday
Letters , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Hughes</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Night</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Train</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Amis</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Enduring
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Love</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian McEwan</ENAMEX>;

            
               Event --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">XXXII</ENAMEX>;

            

               Dance --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikhail Baryshnikov</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Evening of Music and Dance With the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Oak Chamber Ensemble</ENAMEX>."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">21:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- Fallen ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">--Sundance Film</ENAMEX>
Festival;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Live</ENAMEX>
Flesh ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Musical</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ragtime</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pillar</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fire: America in the King Years</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963-65</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taylor Branch</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shadows</ENAMEX> on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudson</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Bashevis Singer</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>);

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arthur Dove: A Retrospective"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitney Museum</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">14:</TIMEX>

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>
Bono;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- A Prayer</ENAMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz Bissinger</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Frazier</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX>
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Drucker</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Beatty</ENAMEX>;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afterglow</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Arguing the
World ;

            

               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Ma Vie en Rose</ENAMEX> .

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
