
   
   
      
         
            

            The
balanced-budget constitutional amendment appears to be dead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
Torricelli, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>, who holds the swing vote, announced he had decided to vote
against the amendment because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> rejected changes he had proposed.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26</NUMEX>)
            

            Update
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> fund-raising scandal : <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
handwritten note shows that he directly approved and encouraged a plan to
reward big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> with coffees, stays in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>, and
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> perks. The initial media spin is that this was scandalously
legal. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington</ENAMEX> 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> from an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">developer</ENAMEX> who serves in an
advisory capacity within the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> "sought specific sums" from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> in exchange
for coffees with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Washington</ENAMEX> 
               Post
reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Fowler</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> to relay
requests from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fowler</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> it was part of his job. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reported that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> have evidence of
illegal donations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Venezuelan</ENAMEX> banking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. Update on the
investigation : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sens.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel P.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Feingold</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bradley</ENAMEX>, all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, in
calling for an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26</NUMEX>)
            

            A
leading abortion-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> indicated that he and his pro-choice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have lied about the rarity of partial-birth abortions . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitzsimmons</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of a national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abortion clinics</ENAMEX>, said
that contrary to assertions by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and abortion-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>,
the vast majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> who have the procedure (technically known as
intact dilation and evacuation) are healthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> with healthy fetuses that
have gestated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 20 weeks</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26</NUMEX>)
            

            
Multimillionaire wrestling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John E.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">du Pont</ENAMEX> was convicted of
murdering a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wrestler</ENAMEX> at his estate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. The compromise verdict--that du
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pont</ENAMEX> wasn't legally insane but was mentally ill--reduces his sentence from life
to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">between five and</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of which he will spend in a mental
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX> concluded that "the wealthiest murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>
in the history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>" (sorry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX>) has been brought to justice.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Bombs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> scares dominated the news. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jacksonville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fla.</ENAMEX>, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Orthodox Jew</ENAMEX> has been charged with planting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservative</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">synagogue</ENAMEX>
less than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">40 feet</NUMEX> from where former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shimon Peres</ENAMEX> spoke a
few <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours later</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> wasn't detected, but it failed to go off. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> of
God, a fundamentalist anti-abortion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, has apparently claimed
responsibility for the bombings of an abortion clinic and a gay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">nightclub</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investigators</ENAMEX> are looking into whether the bomb had something to do
with the club <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, a nationally known practitioner of late-term
abortions. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> canceled a nationwide "terrorist threat advisory"
after discovering that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> who were thought to be assembling a huge
fertilizer <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> were average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> working for an industrial cleaning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s reported intention to certify <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> as an ally
in the drug wars is in trouble. Congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> cite <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) the recent
arrest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jésus Gutiérrez Rebollo</ENAMEX>, on charges of
dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kingpins</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) new testimony, from the longtime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> to one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s patriarchs, of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">narcotics</ENAMEX> dealings involving
high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Supporters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recertification</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebollo</ENAMEX>'s arrest
demonstrated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>'s resolve in the drug wars. But some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> argued
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> had failed to notify the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> of the arrest for almost two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>, thereby jeopardizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">informers</ENAMEX> about whom the general
had been briefed. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26</NUMEX>)
            

            A
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Abu Kamal</ENAMEX>, shot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the observation deck of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Empire State Building</ENAMEX> , killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abu Kamal</ENAMEX> then killed
himself. An anti-terrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">task force</ENAMEX> had been put on the case, but a note
written by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX> seems to confirm police suspicions that he was deranged
and acted alone. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/26</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> have cloned an adult mammal . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> who performed the
experiment (on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>) said their technique will allow the engineering of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> to produce helpful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> pointed out that the
technique can be applied to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> has no laws against
it, and that such laws couldn't be enforced anyway, since the procedure can be
done in almost any lab anywhere in the world. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> point to
hypothetical benefits (e.g., saving endangered <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, replicating a dying
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX>), media reaction has focused on ethical nightmares (e.g., breeding human
organ <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> or supermen, replicating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>, resurrecting the dead). Moreover,
"there'd be no need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>," notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ursula Goodenough</ENAMEX>. A presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bioethics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> is expected to take up the question. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/24</NUMEX>)
            

            

<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teachers</ENAMEX>, died. Shanker crippled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>'s school system in the late
1960s with strikes against school decentralization. He later endorsed strong
standards for both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, which annoyed many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> but made
him a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> to school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>. But he'll be best remembered for a line in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleeper</ENAMEX> , about how civilization was destroyed
when "a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Shanker</ENAMEX> got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/24</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> decided not to quit after
all. Reports attribute his decision not to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepperdine</ENAMEX>
University to angry objections from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> say
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has proved his integrity by admitting his mistake. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pundits</ENAMEX>, however,
agree that the reversal fails to erase the widespread conclusion that he has
given up on indicting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX>--and that it only confirms his lack of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">judgment</ENAMEX>, further weakening the investigation's credibility. Meanwhile, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gazette</ENAMEX> retracted its much-ballyhooed report that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> had held mock trials in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clintons</ENAMEX> were acquitted. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Foster</ENAMEX>'s suicide will
debunk right-wing theories that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX> was killed. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/24</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang Zemin</ENAMEX> is attracting scrutiny now that his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mentor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng Xiaoping</ENAMEX>, is dead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> consider <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jiang</ENAMEX> a clumsy weakling
compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX>, and are debating whether <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) he will continue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng</ENAMEX>'s reforms
or return to authoritarianism and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) he can consolidate power or will be
outmaneuvered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">rivals</ENAMEX>. Most agree that he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-style "weather vane,"
adapting his positions to the demands of contrary constituencies ranging from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> to Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/24</NUMEX>)
            

            Former
heavyweight-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riddick Bowe</ENAMEX> quit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX>
of basic training. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowe</ENAMEX> was scrapping his
much-publicized attempt to serve in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corps</ENAMEX> (his boyhood dream) because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> training turned out to be a lot harder than his boxing training regimen
(<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> of work interrupted by a nap), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowe</ENAMEX> didn't like being told what
to do. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX> dismissed him as a pampered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wimp</ENAMEX> who jerked around both the
military and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> gained new respect for having broken
him. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/24</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boone</ENAMEX> 's television show, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GospelAmerica</ENAMEX> , was canceled after an uproar
over his dabbling in heavy metal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boone</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">62</TIMEX>, had appeared onstage at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Music Awards</ENAMEX> in a bare-chested leather <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> to promote his new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">album</ENAMEX>, in which he croons famous metal tunes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boone</ENAMEX> claims that the album's
purpose is to attract metal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiasts</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, and that his get-up was a
spoof of his old choirboy image. Nevertheless, outraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> complained to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> television network that had been airing his show, causing its
cancellation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Callers</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> are being advised to pray for him.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/21</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Singleton</ENAMEX>, a
notorious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rapist</ENAMEX> who hacked off his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s forearms and then spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, has been arrested in the stabbing to death in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> of
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>. Outraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commentators</ENAMEX> are scorning the folly of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rehabilitation</ENAMEX> and demanding tougher sentencing laws for sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX>. The
irony is that such laws are already in place, inspired in part by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Singleton</ENAMEX>'s
previous release, but they don't cover him retroactively. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/21</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
