
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Deep <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Impact</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DreamWorks/Paramount</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX>'s two
comet-meets-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> movies rakes in an opening <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nonholiday-</TIMEX>weekend record of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$41.9</NUMEX>
million but flops with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. It wins credit for downplaying special effects
in favor of story and "exploring the salutary effects of imminent doom" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet</ENAMEX>
Maslin, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). But it's said to be otherwise soporific,
with too few action scenes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who seem oddly cavalier about their
impending death. (<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Trailers</ENAMEX> are available here.)

            

               
                  Character
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> of the Best
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Film Oscar</ENAMEX> is judged less treacly than other recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX>. Critics
are seduced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dickensian</ENAMEX> depths of this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> thriller, set in 1920s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rotterdam</ENAMEX>, about a spiteful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and his resentful bastard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daphne Merkin</ENAMEX> says it's akin to "a great nineteenth<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> novel
that presumes on its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>'s infinite patience." Others say it's muddled by
poorly demarcated flashbacks and instances of incomprehensible <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> humor.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            

               Music
            

            
               
                  Into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sun</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Lennon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Royale</ENAMEX>). The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lennon</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sons</ENAMEX> to trade on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s name in launching a pop career. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lennon</ENAMEX> deserves acclaim for his songwriting, independent of his pedigree, but
dwell almost exclusively on how much the album sounds like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Beatles</ENAMEX>.
"[<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>]erivative" and "lacking intensity," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Gates</ENAMEX>.
Profiles repeat quotes from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lennon</ENAMEX> saying that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government murdered his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>.

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Titan: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John D. Rockefeller</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Chernow</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). A new biography prompts a round of comparisons between the
Standard Oil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">magnate</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1839-1937</TIMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>--both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">exploit</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ed</ENAMEX>) labor and use(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">d</ENAMEX>) unfair tactics to dominate new industries.
Chernow, who had unprecedented access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller</ENAMEX>'s papers, wins praise from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> for bringing an unusually fine "moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX>" to the declining art of biography. His tale is said to transcend
the simplistic views of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mogul</ENAMEX> as either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horatio Alger</ENAMEX> success story or
venal monopolist. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chernow</ENAMEX>'s verdict: He was both (as well as a skirt chaser, a
pathological tightwad, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">philanthropist</ENAMEX> whose giving was motivated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX>
concerns).

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Our Time</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). A <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,286</NUMEX> page, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>

         
      
   
