
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  Out
of Sight
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Pictures</ENAMEX>). TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Clooney</ENAMEX>, long maligned
for his "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-trick-pony acting style ... [of] ducking his handsome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and
raising his eyes" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Travers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> ), finally emerges as a
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> delight in the chemistry between his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, a charming
bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">robber</ENAMEX>, and that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Lopez</ENAMEX>, a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soderbergh</ENAMEX> ( sex, lies and videotape ) wins praise for preserving the
humor, unorthodox narrative, and genre-bending of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmore Leonard</ENAMEX>'s
noir-thriller-romance novel. (Visit the official <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">site</ENAMEX>; also read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edelstein</ENAMEX>'s review in 
                  Slate
               .)

            

               
                  Smoke Signals
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>). Billed as the first feature film by
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native Americans</ENAMEX>, this picaresque tale wins <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>' admiration for being
"palpably authentic" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Schickel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> like the story,
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who set out to retrieve his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s ashes,
for eschewing "the high seriousness and dubious mysticism" of most films about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indians</ENAMEX>' plight (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). Although everyone enjoys
its wry humor and cutting observations about life on the reservation, a few say
its aimless plot betrays its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">makers</ENAMEX>' inexperience.

            
               
                  Dr.
Dolittle
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). After reviving his career with
a smash-hit remake of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Nutty</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professor</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Murphy</ENAMEX> reprises
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Harrison</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX> role as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>--but to less
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">acclaim</ENAMEX>. Forgetting that the original <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolittle</ENAMEX> was also panned, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pine</ENAMEX> for "the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">good old days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s movies" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Dreher</ENAMEX>, the New York
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ). They lament the remake's addition of "a witless barrage of off-color
bathroom humor" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ) and its use of
sophisticated computer graphics to make cute <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> engage in sexual innuendo.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murphy</ENAMEX>'s comic talents are said to be underutilized. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> trumpets the
site here.)

            

               
                  Gone With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wind</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Line Cinema</ENAMEX>). A critical backlash against
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1939</ENAMEX> classic on the occasion of its remastered rerelease. "Overrated,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">overlong</ENAMEX> and overdue for oblivion," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX>. The revisionists harp loudest on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GWTW</ENAMEX> 's racist romanticization
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old South</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> still consider it a masterwork and celebrate the
virtuosity of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vivien Leigh</ENAMEX>'s performance and the film's Old <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> grandeur.
The counterrevisionist spin: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leigh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Gable</ENAMEX> are unsentimental "moderns
... who have no time for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fake politeness</ENAMEX> of this fatally genteel world"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). (The official site offers tie-ins
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">galore</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Art
            

            

               "Bonnard" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Modern Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). With his first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
show in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1867-1947</TIMEX>) overcomes his dismissal by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Picasso</ENAMEX> on the grounds that "he's not really a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> declare
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bonnard</ENAMEX>'s landscapes, nudes, and self-portraits more than dated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Impressionism</ENAMEX>,
deeming them "[s]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ome</ENAMEX> of the most extraordinary paintings of his quickly ending
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christopher</ENAMEX>
Benfey, 
                  Slate
               ). They say that his dreamlike images show a
"Proustian" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> of perception and that his later nudes
are "tinged with necrophilia" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francine Prose</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ).
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MoMA's</ENAMEX> site serves up a slew of paintings.)

            

               Books
            

            

               
                  Suits <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Me: The Double Life of Billy</ENAMEX> Tipton
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dianne Wood</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middlebrook</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houghton Mifflin</ENAMEX>). A new biography of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Tipton</ENAMEX>--an obscure
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jazzman</ENAMEX> who was revealed, only at death, to have been a jazzwoman--elevates its
subject into the "pantheon of legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who have successfully passed as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holly Brubach</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). Middlebrook, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX>, uses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tipton</ENAMEX> to support the postmodernist contention that
gender is a historic construction, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> mostly wax prurient. They obsess
over how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tipton</ENAMEX> duped her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> into believing she was male. Some chastise
Middlebrook for resting her speculations on scant evidence.

            
               
                  The
Notebooks of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Rigoberto</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Vargas Llosa</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grossman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are divided over the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">novelist</ENAMEX>'s latest, about the fantasies of an insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> whose
estranged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> slept with his preadolescent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are tickled by
his parody of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">machismo</ENAMEX>, his scatological humor, and his
taboo-busting musings about sex. "[I]t would be pornographic, if it weren't
art" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Kendrick</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ). Others find that
the novel's format--a combination of letters and rambling diatribes--makes the
story repetitious and tedious.

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX>
Files ;

            
               Movie --<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Years</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX>
Movies (AFI);

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mulan</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>;"

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Walking With</ENAMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wind: A Memoir of the Movement</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lewis</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael D'Orso</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ship</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Gold</ENAMEX>:
In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deep Blue Sea</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Kinder</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Beautiful Mind , by Sylvia Nasar</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Six Days</ENAMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seven Nights</TIMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The Opposite
of Sex ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX>
Art ;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">About</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nightingales</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Magic Hour</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Gain</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Powers</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>
Show ;

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect</ENAMEX>
Murder ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Sex and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> --The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
Awards;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>
Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX>-Dreamer";

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold New World</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Finnegan</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Last</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Disco</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX>
Floats ;

            
               Television -- More
Tales of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bright Shining Lie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>) and Thanks of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grateful Nation</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rothko</ENAMEX>";

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> .

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
