
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

             

            

               
                  Gattaca
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rookie director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Niccol</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sci-fi</ENAMEX> film about a futuristic dystopia wins praise for its moral stand against
genetic engineering. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Hawke</ENAMEX> plays an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">idealist</ENAMEX> who suffers discrimination
because he was naturally conceived. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Niccol</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stylist</ENAMEX> and laud
his minimalism and use of pale colors. Others say the film has the "earnest
simplicity of a freshman philosophy paper" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ) and "ends in the cheesiest of plot twists" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Kempley</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stills</ENAMEX> and clips are available here.)

            
               
                  A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Less Ordinary</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> profess
surprise that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Boyle</ENAMEX>'s follow-up to the much-praised
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trainspotting</ENAMEX> should have turned out to be a "pileup of spectacular
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flakiness</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ). They call the plot,
in which a disgruntled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ewan McGregor</ENAMEX>) kidnaps and then falls in love
with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Diaz</ENAMEX>), "pure, vintage fluff" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Scenes involving angels, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delroy Lindo</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holly Hunter</ENAMEX>, are said to be especially silly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> predict that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGregor</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> will be huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX>. (See the official site.)

            

               Theater
            

            

               
                  Triumph of Love
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Royale Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). This musical
adaptation of an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> farce about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">princess</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> a philosopher is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX>'s surprise success. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise it for
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">bucking Broadway</ENAMEX> trends: It is both low-budget and brainy (one of its goals is
to mock Enlightenment rationality). The score by first-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey</ENAMEX>
Stock earns approval for being more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Sondheim</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Webber</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissenting</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX> says its over-the-top book confuses
bathroom humor with witty repartee.

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  Speaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth to Power</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita F. Hill</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doubleday</ENAMEX>). Critics
wonder why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Hill</ENAMEX> even bothered writing her side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>
controversy--she adds nothing to her case that hasn't been said before in other
books. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sympathizers</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, like the book's "straightforward,
earnest" tone (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Mehren</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX>
cannot help noting it bears "the mark of a truly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> complainer" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O'Rourke</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly Standard</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Television
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodgers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hammerstein</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinderella</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX>; <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">EST</TIMEX>/PST). A remake of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX> made-for-TV musical wins praise for its
African-American lead and multiracial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX>, which includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Alexander</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitney Houston</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX>. "Finally, a sister is getting to go to
the ball," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Veronica Chambers</ENAMEX>. Others observe that even
remakes with good intentions cannot overcome the blandness of the original,
whose score is said to be vastly inferior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> film version's.

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis & Clark</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Journey</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Discovery</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>;
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 4 and 5</TIMEX>; click here for times). The backlash against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Burns</ENAMEX> documentary
machine kicks into high gear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call the subject of the film inherently
intriguing but complain that it has been "marred by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burnsian</ENAMEX> sensibility,
... the same sentimentality and earnestness he throws over every subject"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Collins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). Techniques recycled from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>' documentaries on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>--including background fiddle music and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>
reading wistful letters--are singled out as especially grating. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> note
the emergence of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> chic (a miniseries and a movie about the
explorers are imminent). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> previews the series.)

            

               Music
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velvet Rope</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Jackson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virgin</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Jackson</ENAMEX>'s album is said
to secure her place in the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tier</ENAMEX> of pop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">divas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> praise her eclectic
style--funk, blues, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, and dance--and dwell on her racy lyrics. Topics
include: phone sex, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ménage à trois</ENAMEX>, and lesbian trysts. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> find her
raunchiness far more introspective than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>'s--"closer in spirit to the
unabashed emotionalism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joni Mitchell</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. D. Considine, Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Audio</ENAMEX> and video samples and photos are available on the official site.)

            

               Dance
            

            

               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merce Cunningham</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forward &</ENAMEX> Reverse
               , choreographed by Merce
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham</ENAMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brooklyn Academy of Music</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). The performance of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
new pieces by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">78-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">avant-garde choreographer</ENAMEX> occasions
pronouncements about his influence on contemporary dance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are surprised
that his signature style, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX>' movements are determined by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coin-tosses</ENAMEX> and dice-rolling, still works. Praise also goes to his
collaborations with other downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rauschenberg</ENAMEX> (sets), Rei
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kawakubo</ENAMEX> (costumes), and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cage</ENAMEX> (music). Some carping, however: Costumes by
Kawakubo are said to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX> look like they have "incipient <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX>-man
disease" and to obscure their movements (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Acocella</ENAMEX>, the Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ). (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.A.M.</ENAMEX> plugs the show.)

            

               Update
            

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Wood</ENAMEX> criticizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
DeLillo for succumbing to the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX> he means to depict.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Underworld</ENAMEX> proves, once and for all, ... the incompatibility of
paranoid history with great fiction."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil</ENAMEX>'s
Advocate ;

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michener</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Biography</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Rampersad</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Side
Show ;

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey Performing Arts Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>);

            
               Fashion --Wearable
Computers (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Media Lab</ENAMEX>);

            

               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Psyché</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Franck</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Philharmonic</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Seven Years</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Boogie

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Nights</TIMEX> ;

            
               Fashion --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Versace</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spring/Summer '98 Collections</ENAMEX>;

            
               Product --Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Award --Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> for
Literature, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dario Fo</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- How the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mind Works</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- U-Turn ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Square ;

            
               Movie -- Soul
Food ;

            

               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bilbao</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Toward the</ENAMEX>
End of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>;

            

               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
Edge ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peacemaker</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Big Trouble:</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder in a Small Western Town Sets Off a Struggle for the Soul of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Anthony Lukas</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timequake</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Vonnegut</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Out of
Mind , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX> , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stones</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER :</ENAMEX>
"Ambush" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensations: Young British Artists From the Saatchi Collection</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Academy of Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>).

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
