
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Death
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935-1998</TIMEX>). After his death in a skiing accident, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>-turned-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> is elevated from a "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">hen-pecked</ENAMEX>, dim bulb" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ) to "a symbol of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> capacity for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reinvention</ENAMEX>" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ). Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bono</ENAMEX> was not as
buffoonish as his public image, which they claim he self-consciously cultivated
to advance his career. They judge him an underappreciated songwriter and say
his lasting legacy will be The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonny & Cher Comedy Hour</ENAMEX> , "one of the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> to slickly package the counterculture for mass consumption" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Kim</ENAMEX>,
Entertainment <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Prayer for the City</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buzz Bissinger</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX>). Raves for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> Prize-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>'s account of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Rendell</ENAMEX>'s
battle against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s decrepitude. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Fishman</ENAMEX> compares <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bissinger</ENAMEX>'s book to "such classics of urban
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reportage</ENAMEX> and analysis as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Anthony Lukas</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Common Ground</ENAMEX> ." <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX>
especially like its scope: Bissinger interweaves the stories of a shipyard
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> and a poor black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> with political history. The Wall Street
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Siegel</ENAMEX>, among others, praises <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bissinger</ENAMEX> for showing both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rendell</ENAMEX>'s courage (he took on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unions</ENAMEX>) and the limits of his old-school
liberalism. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Random House</ENAMEX> plugs the book.)

            
               
                  Cold
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mountain</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Frazier</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Monthly Press</ENAMEX>). The debate over
the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National Book Award-winning Civil War</ENAMEX> novel, which has sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1 million</NUMEX>
copies so far, escalates. Several recent reviews buck the critical consensus
and deride the book, the story of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Confederate</ENAMEX> deserter, for being too
self-consciously novelistic (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Gardner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> ). Like "a
literary approximation of an already literary idea of reality," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wood</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Standar d</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. Bottum</ENAMEX> rebuts that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">highbrow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> misunderstand its middlebrow virtues. It is "a perfectly
enjoyable piece of sentimental fiction, straight from those golden <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the
1950s." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for an excerpt.)

            
               
                  The
World According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Drucker</ENAMEX>
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Beatty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Free Press</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> anoint the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>-born management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Drucker</ENAMEX> a great
intellectual. "Alone among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guru class</ENAMEX>, he grabbed hold of business and made
it do and say extraordinary things" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lewis</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review</ENAMEX> ). They emphasize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drucker</ENAMEX>'s philosophical influences (he studied
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kierkegaard</ENAMEX> and political theory), his vast oeuvre , and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">long-standing</ENAMEX> doubts about free markets. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatty</ENAMEX> wins praise for his clear
explications of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drucker</ENAMEX>'s writings but is chided for "reducing what may have
been scintillating intellectual biography to ... a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">layman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guide</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian</ENAMEX>
Wooldridge, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Movies
            

            

               
                  Afterglow
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> wax effusive about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Christie</ENAMEX>'s performance in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Rudolph</ENAMEX>'s romantic drama. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> (a former horror-movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>) and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nick Nolte</ENAMEX>), their
marriage damaged by grief over their runaway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, pursue extramarital
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">affairs</ENAMEX> and unwittingly swap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX> with a younger yuppie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christie</ENAMEX>
"renders such a captivating performance that she alone justifies the price of
admission," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Variety</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Klady</ENAMEX>. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> fault the film on
other counts, particularly its languid pacing, stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolte</ENAMEX> plays a
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">seductive handyman</ENAMEX>), and melodramatic dialogue. It "descends into a silly
season" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX> trumpets the
movie here.)

            

               
                  Arguing the World
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Run Films</ENAMEX>). A documentary about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">famed New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intellectuals</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irving Howe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Glazer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irving Kristol</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Bell</ENAMEX>) occasions outpourings of nostalgia for the "vanished intellectual
era" of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Margolick</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). The film wins
praise for charting the tumultuous friendships among these popular social
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, as well as the evolution of all but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howe</ENAMEX> from '30s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">radicals</ENAMEX> to '60s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neoconservatives</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Documentarian Joseph Dorman</ENAMEX> is credited with producing "one
of the deepest portraits ever filmed of the fluidity of ideas" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Holden</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ).

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ma</ENAMEX>
Vie en <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rose</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> applaud rookie <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Belgian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Berliner</ENAMEX>'s film, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a 7-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> who yearns to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>,
for giving "an inside report ... from the enchanted, irradiated island of
childhood" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Corliss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> appreciate its avoidance of
hackneyed gender politics, and its presentation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s colorful,
cartoonlike fantasies. Praise goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georges Du Fresne</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child actor</ENAMEX> "who
seems, in some prodigious way, to understand" his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Kauffmann</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dissenting</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morgenstern</ENAMEX> says the movie is cloying, "cheerful nonsense" and that its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX> don't realize that "this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> is profoundly troubled." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stills</ENAMEX> and
clips are available here.)

            

               Updates
            

            In the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> savages <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Allen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX>: "This movie is not art. It is a clinical
document, an anthology of unexamined prejudices, a tiresome <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> whine."
... <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> continues to divide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX>
on its cover and raves, "To read the novel is ... to confront questions as old
as human civilization itself." In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate, Brent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staples</ENAMEX> finds that the novel's "absence of workaday and historical detail keeps
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> at a distance; many of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are impenetrable to the
mind's eye." ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Republic</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jed Perl</ENAMEX> bashes the newly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opened J. Paul Getty Museum</ENAMEX>, designed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Meier</ENAMEX>, whose
architecture, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perl</ENAMEX>, "only works in coffee-table books. ... What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meier</ENAMEX>'s
work lacks is heat, an organic flow."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apostle</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucinda</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boxer</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Capote: In Which Various Friends, Enemies, Acquaintances, and Detractors Recall</ENAMEX>
His <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turbulent</ENAMEX> Career , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Plimpton</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Morrison</ENAMEX>;

            

               Music --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Northern Lights: The Music of Jean Sibelius</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">31:</TIMEX>

            Winter
Movie Roundup

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24:</TIMEX>

            "The Year
in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Review in Review</ENAMEX>"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Scream
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Ally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBeal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>);

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogarth</ENAMEX>: A
Life and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenny Uglow</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
