
   
   
      
         
            

            This time
of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, for some reason, all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> publish their "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best of 1997</ENAMEX>" lists,
ranking their favorite books, movies, albums, and other cultural fare.

                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> thought it only fitting to use this special
installment of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment" to summarize the Best of everyone's Best of</ENAMEX>
lists--a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> review of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year-end</TIMEX> reviews.

            

               Fiction
            

            Critics
pronounce <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> a landmark year, studded with career-topping masterworks by
literary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
DeLillo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Ozick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas</ENAMEX>
Pynchon, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Roth</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mason</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixon</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pynchon</ENAMEX>'s epic about
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 th -century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surveyors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>, tops most lists. "A book of
heart, fire and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>," says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> . More
controversial is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Frazier</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold Mountain</ENAMEX> , a surprise best seller
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> deserter, which, to the dismay of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, beat out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DeLillo</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Underworld for the National Book Award</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> book
reviews all leave it off their lists, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> considers
it the best of a "banner year for adventure stories." (See

                  Slate
               's reviews of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ozick, Pynchon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frazier</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Nonfiction
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX>
single out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Krakauer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Into Thin Air</ENAMEX> , an account of a disastrous and
deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mount Everest</ENAMEX> expedition, among <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s best nonfiction. Otherwise,
no consensus emerges. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> book reviews like such highbrow biographies as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermione Lee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Virginia Woolf</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book Review</ENAMEX> ) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jorge Castañeda</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Compañero: The Life and Death</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Che Guevara</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
Eder, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> fill their lists with
celebrity memoirs, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mia Farrow's What Falls Away</ENAMEX> --a trend some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> bemoan. "Why not pay real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> to write?" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> grumbles.
(
                  Slate
                <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reviews Lee</ENAMEX>'s book and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrow</ENAMEX>'s memoir.)

            

               Movies
            

            The
neo-noir <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> flick <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>
Confidential, based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Ellroy</ENAMEX> novel, crowns most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>' <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX>-best
lists. It alone "truly exceeded its advance hype," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atom Egoyan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">The Sweet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hereafter</ENAMEX>, about a school-bus accident, also impresses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>, winning him
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">plaudits</ENAMEX> as a "postmodern Hitchcock" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> ). Other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> include Donnie
Brasco, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wings of the Dove, and Face/Off</ENAMEX>, while the well-reviewed Boogie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nights</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Titanic</ENAMEX> both fail to make many lists. Looking back on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">'97</NUMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> lament the ubiquity of disaster movies, mindless screenplays, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX>, who, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX> says, is waging "a campaign to suck
our affection for him to its <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX>." (See 
                  Slate
               's reviews of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">L.A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Confidential, The Sweet Hereafter, Donnie Brasco</ENAMEX>,
The Wings
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dove, Boogie Nights</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Titanic</ENAMEX>.)

             

            
               Pop
Music
            

            In a "year
dominated by generic" acts and "studio creations" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Hilburn</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> declare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>'s comeback album <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Out of
Mind and diva <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Erykah Badu</ENAMEX>'s debut Baduizm the best of the bunch.
Badu, "the most thrilling new voice in pop" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ), wins praise for
bucking genres (she blends <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX>, jazz, and hip-hop) and writing edgy lyrics.
Critics also declare <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>--dominated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spice Girls</ENAMEX>--as the "year of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">woman</ENAMEX>" in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Never</ENAMEX> in pop history have female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singers</ENAMEX> been quite so
aggressively, shrewdly marketed on the basis of gender alone" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Schoemer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> ).

            

               TV
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> 's coming out is hailed as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s highlight, a "seminal moment"
in television history (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Rosenberg</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). Critics
say the sitcom was witless and pointless until it focused on its main
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>'s sexuality; "[e]ver since ... it has radiated with the sheer joy of
creative freedom" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX>) . Critics also lavish praise on
the animated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> sitcom <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">King of the</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> , the latest series from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beavis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butt</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head creator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protagonist</ENAMEX>, a red-neck
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">propane</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX>, is deemed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> and Archie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunker</ENAMEX> . Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX>'s tongue-in-cheek action series Buffy the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vampire Slayer</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a 15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-heroine</ENAMEX>: "A postfeminist parable
on the challenge of balancing one's personal and work life" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Technology
            

            Top honors
go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riven</ENAMEX> --an upgrade to the best-selling computer game of all
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myst</ENAMEX> --about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> marooned on an island. "Big, bloody and
beautiful," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> . High marks also go to the postcard-sized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palm</ENAMEX>
Pilot, a computer that retrieves e-mail and reads handwriting. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">excoriate Digital Pets</ENAMEX>, a noisy, interactive version of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1970s</NUMEX> fad the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rock</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Pets</ENAMEX> are labeled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>'s worst innovation and a "nightmare for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> drafted to babysit" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People</ENAMEX> ).

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">17:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Titanic</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deconstructing Harry</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Scream
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Ally
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McBeal</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan Museum of Art</ENAMEX>);

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Art</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>);

            

               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Hogarth: A Life and a World</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jenny Uglow</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amistad</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Good Will</ENAMEX>
Hunting ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breast</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Men</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diary</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Frank</ENAMEX> ;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Opera</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amistad</ENAMEX> ;

            

               Book -- A Certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P.D. James</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Dec.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:</TIMEX>

            
               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Paul</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Getty Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old</ENAMEX>
Neighborhood , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Mamet</ENAMEX>;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flubber</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Welcome to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sarajevo</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public</ENAMEX>
Housing (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Release 2.0</ENAMEX>:
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Design for Living</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Digital Age</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Dyson</ENAMEX>;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photography</ENAMEX> --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Weegee's World: Life, Death, and the Human Drama</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Center of Photography Midtown</ENAMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Nov.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">26:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Garden</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grisham</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Rainmaker</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Alien</ENAMEX>
Resurrection ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>: How an <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ordinary Man Became an Extraordinary Leader</ENAMEX> , by Dinesh
D'Souza;

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivanov</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standing</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stone</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>.

            

               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

             

         
      
   
