
   
   
      
         
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deng Xiaoping</ENAMEX> finally died. The early obituary line was that he made
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> safe for capitalism, openness, and prosperity. References to his
purported authorization of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre were politely buried.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> are already handicapping the power struggle among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s next
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> of would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/19</NUMEX>)
            

            
Pretrial hearings began in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> bombing case. The defense tried to
exclude testimony from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> who claim they saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy McVeigh</ENAMEX>
rent the truck used in the bombing. Arguments: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> has changed
his story. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>'s identification of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> was influenced by
seeing him in handcuffs on television. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McVeigh</ENAMEX> rented the
truck with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, the mysterious "<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">John Doe No. 2</ENAMEX>," for whom the
government can't account. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> reported that the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> has a long
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> record and has allegedly bragged that he stands to gain much of the
government's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> reward for nabbing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX>. Television
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondents</ENAMEX> agree that all this significantly wounded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s case.
Early media indicators, e.g., the hiring of on-screen network "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultants</ENAMEX>" to
state the obvious, suggest that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> will replace the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J.</ENAMEX> trial as
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s premier legal circus. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/19</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater</ENAMEX> independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> will resign his post to become a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dean at Pepperdine University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. Pundits inferred that the
investigation would soon end without indictments of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> or first
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> were reported to be celebrating. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>
worried that uncooperative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> (i.e., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX>) would hold out if
they thought the investigation was about to close. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> insisted to the
press that he had made his decision without regard to the investigation's
outcome--whereupon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pundits</ENAMEX> concluded that he was a cad to leave precipitously.
Liberal editorialists, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of denouncing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s dogged partisanship,
called him a quitter. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Conservatives</ENAMEX> consoled themselves with the prospect that
an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> will be appointed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> money scandal.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/19</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Liberals</ENAMEX> assailed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s welfare-reform policy at what was
supposed to be a friendly gathering. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and several putative supporters
met to discuss how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> could provide jobs. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graves</ENAMEX>, the publisher of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Enterprise</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, said it was wrong "to
expect the private sector ... to sacrifice profit margins in order to do the
government's job." A welfare recipient compared <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s workfare program to
"slavery" and protested that it was "demeaning" to clean toilets. Meanwhile,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> announced a drive to unionize welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX>, in part to
discourage <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and cities from hiring them to replace better-paid union
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/19</NUMEX>)
            

            Nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> agreed to open their phone markets to foreign competition .
The agreement covers <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of the world's current telecommunications. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> say it will eventually cut the average per<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-minute</TIMEX> price of
international calls originating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 to 20 cents</NUMEX>.
Contrary to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s complaints by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Buchanan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dole</ENAMEX> that the World
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trade Organization</ENAMEX> would become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>' tool for conquering the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> are now complaining that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WTO</ENAMEX> has become the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>' tool for conquering the world. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/17</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> released documents showing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> had warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> against consorting with shady <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> who
have since become infamous in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> campaign-finance scandal .
The document release was meant to prove the integrity of then-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NSC</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake</ENAMEX>, thereby persuading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> to confirm him as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. Instead,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> responded by demanding to know why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> had
disregarded the warnings. The other scandal-related disclosure of the weekend
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> 
               Post report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> embraced a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> financially beneficial to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guam</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">locals</ENAMEX> gave <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DNC</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">campaign</ENAMEX>. Special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny Davis</ENAMEX> replied: "There's
no governmental actions affected by contributions to this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/17</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> halted a strike by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Airlines</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> . Using the
rarely invoked <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Railway Labor Act of 1926</ENAMEX>, he forced the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> to postpone the
strike for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> while federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediators</ENAMEX> try to resolve the dispute. The
key issue is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s plan to assign more flights to lower-paid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">commuter-airline</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>. As compensation for this, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> want a big
raise. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Travelers</ENAMEX> are outraged at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>' current, widely quoted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$120,000</NUMEX>
average salary. Editorialists are having trouble picking sides because both the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> seem to be making too much money. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> agree that the
benefits of intervention (pleasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passengers</ENAMEX> and saving jobs in politically
important <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>) and the low political cost (angering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> who are
mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and are isolated from the rest of organized labor) made this
a no-brainer for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The catch is that other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> headed
for similar confrontations may be encouraged to hold out for absurd demands in
the expectation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will bail them out, too. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/17</NUMEX>)
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgian Republic</ENAMEX> waived prosecutorial immunity for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX>
implicated in a collision that killed a teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Police</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX> appeared to have been drinking and speeding. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
Department portrayed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>'s decision as extremely unusual and praiseworthy.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/17</NUMEX>)
            

            
Suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> shot a defector in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Han Young</ENAMEX>, is reportedly near death, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> is on a
terrorism alert. This is the latest in a series of incidents--a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX>
submarine crew infiltrating the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologist</ENAMEX> seeking
asylum in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>--that have escalated tensions between
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Observers</ENAMEX> worry that their reconciliation process might
collapse, possibly provoking <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> to resume its nuclear-weapons program.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/17</NUMEX>)
            

            Tara
Lipinski, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX>, became the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">figure</ENAMEX>-skating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> in
history. She upset <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Kwan</ENAMEX>, who fell down twice
during her routine. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lipinski</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> quickly unveiled her Web site and booked her
on television talk shows. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
certified her as the newest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> in sports but worried that she'll end up
warped or burned out like other recent teen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prodigies</ENAMEX> in gymnastics, skating,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">tennis</ENAMEX>. The cynical view is that she's got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year or two</TIMEX> at the top before
she chokes under the pressure, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kwan</ENAMEX> did. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/17</NUMEX>)
            

            The
Dow Jones industrial average topped <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,000</NUMEX> . Financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>, while
proclaiming once again that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">optimists</ENAMEX> have been vindicated, are having more
and more trouble finding anyone on Wall Street who was this optimistic. Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> who had argued for loosening the old standards, by which the market
was clearly overvalued, now think it has maxed out for a while. The rosy view
is that the market's remarkable rise makes sense because conditions have been
perfect. The pessimistic view is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> have been spoiled by the
perfect conditions and will panic as soon as something goes wrong. The Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> calls the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">7,000 mark</NUMEX> a perfect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> affirmation
of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six-year</TIMEX> love affair with stocks." (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/14</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> tried to steer foreign donations to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Committee</ENAMEX> , according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> leak to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> said "electronic eavesdropping"
bolstered the case. The disclosure gives the scandal an important new twist and
ratchets up pressure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Department</ENAMEX> to appoint an independent
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> says there is still no evidence to
confirm conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX>' suspicions of a conspiracy between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chinese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lippo Group</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Huang</ENAMEX>. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
committee investigating the scandal has collapsed into partisan feuding,
and several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> in the scandal, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huang</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Associate</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Attorney General</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster L. Hubbell</ENAMEX>, have refused to provide documents.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/14</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officials</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boulder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colo.</ENAMEX>, have hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ex-stars from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defense</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> --<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Scheck</ENAMEX> and forensic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Lee</ENAMEX>--to
help in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JonBenet Ramsey</ENAMEX> murder case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX>'s
explanation--"I'm going to be ready to match the resources of anyone"--was
taken by some as a sign that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">probe</ENAMEX> may now be focusing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, who have hired their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detectives</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> while
still refusing to be interviewed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">headquarters</ENAMEX>. The more cautious
interpretation is that the case <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> don't want to repeat the forensic
errors made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> case, and they figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scheck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> know the
pitfalls better than anyone. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/14</NUMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> approved
spending for overseas family-planning programs . An alternative measure
reinstating a ban on funding for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that also perform or promote abortions
passed by a wider margin, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is expected to oppose such a
restriction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birth-control</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX> called the vote an important victory in
their efforts to disentangle support for contraception from the contentious
abortion issue. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/14</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
