
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  The
Avengers
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX> refused to have an advance
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> screening for this update of the beloved 1960s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> TV show, and the
reason is now obvious: The movie is "an unqualified disaster" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Kehr</ENAMEX>,
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Fiennes</ENAMEX>' painfully awkward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Steed</ENAMEX> and Uma
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurman</ENAMEX>'s beautiful but empty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma Peel</ENAMEX> are said to have none of the charm and
sexual tension that graced their TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Seymour</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , writes the closest thing to a positive review the movie is
likely to get, calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurman</ENAMEX>'s Peel "agreeably droll" and praising the
"suitably preposterous plot." (Visit the official Web site.)

            

               
                  Return to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradise</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polygram Filmed Entertainment</ENAMEX>). Outstanding
performances from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Vaughn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Heche</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joaquin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> are thwarted by
a so-so story line. The plot is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manichaean</ENAMEX> moral dilemma: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> traveling
buddies buy a brick of hash while on vacation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> gets in trouble
for it, and if the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> don't admit their complicity (and do time in a
dangerous prison <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">system</ENAMEX>), the one who was caught will be executed. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX>
praise it as having "the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moody</ENAMEX>, disquieting undertow of a true moral thriller"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Gleiberman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ), while others call it "too
implausible for anyone to rescue" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Turan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ). 
                  Slate
               's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Edelstein</ENAMEX> is basically pro: "The upshot
might be melodrama, but it's melodrama with heart, bones, sinews, and tear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ducts</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here to read his review.)

            
               
                  The
Slums of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beverly Hills</ENAMEX>
                (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th Century Fox/Fox</ENAMEX> Searchlight
Pictures). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamara Jenkins</ENAMEX>' writing and directing debut is as
refreshingly awkward and original as the film's teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heroine</ENAMEX>, Vivian
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abramowitz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natasha Lyonne</ENAMEX>). The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vivian</ENAMEX> struggles with her
developing sexuality and the crazy dynamics of her less than affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>,
which includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Arkin</ENAMEX> as her baffled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marisa Tomei</ENAMEX> as her
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">drug-addled</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are slightly irritated by the film's tendency
toward sitcom jokes and timing but nevertheless embrace the "affectionate
humor" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> shows toward her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>. (Visit the official Web site.)

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Whitechocolatespaceegg
                by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Phair</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Matador/Capitol</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Reviewers</ENAMEX>
had speculated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> about the effect of marriage and motherhood on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> of sexual bravado and confessional songwriting. The consensus:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phair</ENAMEX>'s long-awaited offering lacks the gritty low-fi feel and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">raunchy</ENAMEX> lyrics
that characterized Exile in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guyville</ENAMEX> , her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> album, which won the
Village Voice Pazz <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">& Jop Album of the Year Award</ENAMEX>, but the new album
is more diverse musically. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronica Chambers</ENAMEX> claims the more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grown-up Phair</ENAMEX> is "far more interesting than the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she used to be."
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Read</ENAMEX> more about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phair</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX>.)

            

               Books
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spin</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward L. Bernays</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Birth of Public Relations</ENAMEX>
                by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Tye</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> marvel at the life and accomplishments of this
public relations <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX>. Bernays was best known for his inventive publicity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stunts</ENAMEX> and manipulation of the public's buying patterns through now commonplace
tricks such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrity</ENAMEX> endorsement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Tye</ENAMEX> is
praised for thorough research and the ability to see through his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subject</ENAMEX>'s
inflation of his accomplishments. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are not impressed with the book's
confusing nonchronological structure. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Gladwell</ENAMEX>
argues that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernays</ENAMEX> is not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of public relations; that honor
should go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lester Wunderman</ENAMEX>. Others wonder at the brief treatment given to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bernays</ENAMEX>' relationship with his famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigmund Freud</ENAMEX>, "which should have
formed the intellectual heart of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tye</ENAMEX>'s book" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Chernow</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). (Read the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> chapter.)

            

               
                  Philistines at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedgerow</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Passion</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Property</ENAMEX> in the Hamptons
               
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven S. Gaines</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little, Brown & Co.</ENAMEX>). This "satisfyingly insiderish"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alexandra Jacobs, Entertainment Weekly</ENAMEX> ) history of life in the Hamptons
is being compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Berendt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Midnight in the Garden of Good and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX> . Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> relish the combination of eccentric real-life characters
and celebrity dirty laundry. Others dismiss the book for its dearth of sources
and persistent focus on malicious gossip. M.G. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Post calls the book "a smarmy, distasteful document in which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gaines</ENAMEX> fawns
over the rich and powerful and attacks the weak and the dead." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay McInerney</ENAMEX>,
however, finds the book "eminently beachworthy" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Yorker</ENAMEX> ).
(Buy this book from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amazon.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com</ENAMEX>.)

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie--
               Snake
Eyes ;

            
               Movie--
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Halloween:</ENAMEX>
H20 ;

            
               Movie -- How <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX>
Got <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Her Groove Back</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainbow</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Six</TIMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX> ;
            

            
               Television
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>
Seinfeld: I'm <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Telling You for the Last Time--Live</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            

               Television
               -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Upright Citizens Brigade</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Comedy Central</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:</TIMEX>

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Art of the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorcycle</ENAMEX>";

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lolita</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maximum</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Movies -- Ever After:</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cinderella Story</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movies -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Negotiator</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- Burn
Rate , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Wolff</ENAMEX>;

            

               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerome Robins</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">29:</TIMEX>

            
               Book-- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">100 Best English-Language Novels</ENAMEX> Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX>;

            
               Book--
               Point of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Origin</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Cornwell</ENAMEX>;

            
               Movie--
               Disturbing
Behavior ;

            
               Movie--
               Pi ;

            

               Movie--
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Thief</ENAMEX> .

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">22:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mask of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zorro</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Saving
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private Ryan</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- There's
Something <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">About Mary</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Music -- Hello
Nasty , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beastie Boys</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- Lucky
Bastard , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles McCarry</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- Twelfth
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Night</TIMEX> ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drudge</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>).

            
               --Eliza
Truitt
            

         
      
   
