
   
   
      
         
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">O.J.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson</ENAMEX> 's civil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> ordered him to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million</NUMEX> in punitive
damages to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Goldman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Brown Simpson</ENAMEX>, on top of
the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.5 million</NUMEX> in compensatory damages already awarded. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million</NUMEX>
figure is based on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s assets and potential <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">lifetime</TIMEX> earnings, and is
designed to make sure he can't keep any money he makes from his notoriety in
the case. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX> point out that the jury neglected to deduct <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s debts
in calculating his net worth, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> or an appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> will probably
reduce the damages accordingly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> used the occasion to
reopen the debate over excessive punitive-damage awards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Goldman</ENAMEX>'s father
offered to renounce his claim for damages if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> would publish a detailed
confession. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/12</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> met with congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of both parties.
The meeting produced an agreement to try to agree on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> issues :
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">education</ENAMEX>, juvenile crime, family tax cuts, tax credits for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> that
hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off welfare, and experimenting with urban-renewal ideas in the
District of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Pundits</ENAMEX> were impressed by the cordial atmosphere, which
was in contrast to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s. But they pointed out that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> sides <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) left
out campaign-finance reform; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) blocked each other's pet initiatives (e.g., the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">balanced-budget</ENAMEX> amendment and health insurance for poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>); and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) disagree
sharply even where they ostensibly agree (e.g., the federal role in education,
and the size of tax cuts). (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/12</NUMEX>)
            

            

               Independent films dominated the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Academy Award</ENAMEX> nominations .
("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Independents Day</ENAMEX>," declared both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> .) The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Patient</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> nominations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shine and Fargo</ENAMEX> got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> apiece. Several big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX>
were shut out of the top categories. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evita</ENAMEX> and its star, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX>, got
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stiffed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milos Forman</ENAMEX> blamed no best-picture nomination for The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> on hostile lobbying by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feminists</ENAMEX>. A best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> nomination
went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Scott Thomas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The English Patient</ENAMEX> , which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">20 th Century Fox</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> had dropped because they wanted Demi
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> to play the role. Consensus spin: The nominations are a signal that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are sick of big-budget action flicks and hungry for good, well-written
stories. Consensus prediction: The big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> will be embarrassed for a few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX> and then will go back to churning out mindless blockbusters.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/12</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Authorities</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> agreed to spare the life of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> that
killed a rooster . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prince</ENAMEX> was sentenced to die under a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> strikes"
ordinance against vicious <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Strike One</ENAMEX> was the rooster. Strikes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> were escapes from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. The case inspired outcries throughout the country
and was widely covered by national television and the foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hampshire</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> hinted she would pardon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> if necessary. Eventually,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> buckled and agreed to reduce <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX>'s penalty to exile.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/12</NUMEX>)
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter jets</ENAMEX> dogged passenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incidents. <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-16</ENAMEX>
followed a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">727</NUMEX> descending into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>--setting off the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">727</ENAMEX>'s alarms and
causing its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> to attempt violent evasive maneuvers. Then another commercial
pilot reported that several <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-16s</ENAMEX> flew dangerously close to him. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
reports played big on television, with dark hints that top-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> might be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">joyriding</ENAMEX>. But the scare was deflated by reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) air-traffic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">controllers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">727</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> bore the blame for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> incident; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) the
pilot who alleged the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> incident still hasn't filed a report; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>)
near-collision reports between military and civilian <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">planes</ENAMEX> have actually
fallen sharply in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this decade</TIMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/10</NUMEX>)
            

            
               The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Whitewater</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McDougal</ENAMEX> is
now claiming (contrary to his previous story) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> knew about an
illegal <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> loan issued to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX>'s then-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougal</ENAMEX> isn't corroborating the story. The juicy part of the saga is a quarrel
between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDougals</ENAMEX>, conducted through the press, over whether she was
"intimate" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. She says she's too moral to have done such a thing,
and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim McDougal</ENAMEX> is sick, bitter, and desperate to avoid <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>.
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/10</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert H. Rubin</ENAMEX> observed that "we have had a strong
dollar for some time now." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> and central bankers
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interpreted Rubin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delphic</ENAMEX> utterance as a sign that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> would
stop its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> effort to push the dollar higher against other currencies. A
more expensive dollar has allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to undercut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX>, but it also makes it harder for them to attract capital investment.
dollar should go neither higher nor lower. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/10</NUMEX>)
            

            
Foreign-policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> worried that if <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Zairian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> defeat government
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">forces</ENAMEX>, this could lead to the disintegration of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">nation-</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> whose boundaries are the arbitrary products of the colonial era.
What the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> didn't explain was why, if the boundaries are artificial,
their disintegration should be of concern. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/10</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Straws</ENAMEX> in the wind : <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> now has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 5 million</NUMEX> illegal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> reports that as environmental
concerns have waned, disposable diapers are driving cloth diapers into
extinction. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wrigley</ENAMEX> has developed a more biodegradable
chewing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gum</ENAMEX> . In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> satellites will be available for
commercial hire. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America Online</ENAMEX> , having offered refunds to pacify users
who couldn't get online, is now under fire for failing to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> about
other phone routes that are less jammed but cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> more money.
High-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are requiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to undergo Breathalyzer
tests at dances, proms, football games, and other after-school events.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is giving female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> bigger roles in action movies in order
to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to see them. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> , once the exemplar of citizen
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">solidarity</ENAMEX>, is trying to replace its old universal-military-service rule with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">week-long</ENAMEX> seminar on volunteerism and civics (its <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Clintonian</ENAMEX> title:
"citizen rendezvous"). (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/10</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> won the right in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> to air a movie <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> about the
murder of a teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>--also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>--even though the
accused have yet to be tried. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> said the movie would provide
instructive lessons about the "issues <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-agers</ENAMEX> face." Yeah, sneered a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> editorial, everyday lessons like whether "a newly engaged couple
should cement their relationship by exterminating former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>."
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/10</NUMEX>)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> is "cozying up to the left" and "should
change course or step down." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s specific gripes are that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">honored Jesse Jackson</ENAMEX> by inviting him to sit with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speaker</ENAMEX>'s box during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) apologized to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.C. Watts</ENAMEX>' reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> and other liberal black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>-hustling poverty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pimps</ENAMEX>." (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Watts</ENAMEX>, a black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX>,
delivered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s reply to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kristol</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> is speaking for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">conservatives</ENAMEX> who worry that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s image is
so tattered, he's being forced to soften his partisan edge. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times sees it as the latest sign that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>, having made sure that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> didn't oust <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>, may do so themselves. On the bright side,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX>'s attack compelled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> editorial page to defend
and praise <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>. (See <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Weisberg</ENAMEX>'s "The
Conservative Collapse.") (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/7</NUMEX>)
            

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> officially released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his 1998</TIMEX> budget . He says it will
boost investment in education, cut taxes, and eradicate deficit spending for
more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years</TIMEX>. Press reviews unanimously portray his budget balancing as a
sham: It doesn't specify where programs will be cut. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Budget</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raines</ENAMEX> dismissed such details as "boring.") Also, it offers no long-range
solvency plan for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, assumes there won't be a recession, and defers
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">three-fourths</ENAMEX> of the cuts and revenue-raising measures till <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is out of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> pitifully observed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> will be
left holding the bag. The political consensus is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are ready
to deal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and will work out a compromise budget, which won't balance
either. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/7</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> announced they will donate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70 million</NUMEX>
to establish a "humanitarian fund for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>." This is an
attempt to resolve the scandal over whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> ingratiated themselves to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> and stole deposits made by <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Commentators</ENAMEX>
agree that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swiss</ENAMEX> haven't really repented and are just trying to restore
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trustworthy-banker</ENAMEX> reputation and stave off a boycott organized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The boycott has been called off, but demands persist for full
disclosure of records of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' assets, and there's little sign the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss</ENAMEX> will recover their pristine image any time soon. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/7</NUMEX>)
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Harriman</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>, legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX>
Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX>, and serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX> to great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">century</ENAMEX>, died of a brain hemorrhage at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">76</NUMEX>. Obituaries focused on her pattern of
gaining influence and prestige by romancing rich and powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward R. Murrow</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heir</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fiat</ENAMEX> fortune, etc.). Critics
chalk it up to sluttish ruthlessness; <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defenders</ENAMEX> argue that, like most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of
her day, she had been socialized to build her plans around <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. Intent on
proving that she was more than a seductive dilettante, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are touting her
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">success</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>, meanwhile, are praising her seductive
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">charms</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/7</NUMEX>)
            

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
revealed to the world, and to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> herself, that the new
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary of state</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX>
who fled the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazis</ENAMEX> and raised their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX>. Her grandparents
died in concentration <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> were eager to absolve <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s parents
for abandoning their heritage, but were unable to find anybody making the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">accusation</ENAMEX>. (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2/7</NUMEX>)
            

         
      
   
