
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movie
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Devil's Advocate</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Warner Bros.</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> can't decide whether this
fable by An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gentleman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor Hackford</ENAMEX> is good
kitschy fun or a "never-never land of movie <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">awfulness</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Denby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX> ). Praise goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Pacino</ENAMEX>'s frenetic performance as the devil--a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>--who wants to corrupt his naive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior partner</ENAMEX>, played by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keanu Reeves</ENAMEX>. "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he best theater you'll see on screen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>. Others call the film's moralizing overwrought,
its plot absurd, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reeves</ENAMEX>' performance typically bad. (See the film's
official
site.)

            

               Death
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michener</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1907-1997</TIMEX>). The popular historical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelist</ENAMEX> doesn't get the usual
posthumous reputation-inflation. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> continue to deride his mammoth
tomes as hopelessly pedestrian, with "the formulaic plots and the formulaic
prose and the formulaic leap to the top of the best-seller list" (the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> ). Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> grudgingly praise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michener</ENAMEX>'s prolificacy, breezy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prose</ENAMEX>, and extensive research, while gleefully bashing the snobbery of his
highbrow bashers. (The hagiographic <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jamesmichener</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">com</ENAMEX> provides a bibliography and
biography.)

            

               Book
            

            
               
                  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Robinson</ENAMEX>: A
Biography
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Rampersad</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knopf</ENAMEX>). Despite the familiarity of the
path-breaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ballplayer</ENAMEX>'s story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> mostly like the new biography. They
deem its tone appropriately "admiring but not worshipful" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bernstein</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). And they praise its focus on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX>'s stubbornly
independent political activism. (He campaigned for both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX>.) Its edge over other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robinson</ENAMEX> biographies: His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princeton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX>, unprecedented access to his correspondence.

             

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  Side
Show
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Rodgers Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>). Mixed reviews for a
musical about the tragic lives of a pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>. "One is astonished
to see something so bold, offbeat, and unsettling is on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Patrick Stearns</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> are especially fascinated with the
show's frank treatment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX>' sex lives. They say wrenching portrayals
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Skinner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Ripley</ENAMEX> set "a new standard for crackerjack <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teamwork</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Brantley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ). Others call the score, by
Dreamgirls <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Krieger</ENAMEX>, un-catchy and uneven.

            

               Architecture
            

            
               New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey Performing Arts Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Newark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.J.</ENAMEX>). The centerpiece of a new plan
for the decrepit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s renewal wins more praise for its intentions than for
its design. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> complain that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barton Myers</ENAMEX>'
postmodern <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>, consisting of concert <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX>, looks like a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">cineplex"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Swed</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ), with interiors that verge
on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">kitsch</TIMEX> (examples of overkill: steel rods poking out of ceilings; floors
inlaid with colored stones). But complaints are downplayed because "the
building's heart is in the right place" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Muschamp</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ).

            

               Fashion
            

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wearable Computers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Media Lab</ENAMEX>).
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MIT</ENAMEX> computer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nerds</ENAMEX> collaborate with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> fashion schools
on a line of clothes with embedded computers. The duds get heavier or lighter
depending on climate, and they automatically play music in response to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wearer</ENAMEX>'s moods. "The results looked like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Versace</ENAMEX> melded with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blade</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Runner</ENAMEX> ," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Levy</ENAMEX>. Criticisms of the line: The
computers do nothing useful, and the futuristic designs are not anything
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> might actually want to wear" ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Week</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Music
            

            

               
                  Psych√©
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Franck</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Philharmonic</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> scratch
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Philharmonic</ENAMEX>'s penchant for reviving obscure works
by lesser-known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composers</ENAMEX>. This one--an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1888</TIMEX> symphony by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> Romantic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">composer</ENAMEX>--is called an "interesting failure" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Holland</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ). Its overwrought, "meandering" score (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Bernheimer</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ) is accompanied by a highly praised and newly commissioned
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narration of the Psych√</ENAMEX>© myth by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Guare</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Six Degrees of</ENAMEX>
Separation ).

            
               Snap
Judgments
            

            The
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standard</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Caldwell</ENAMEX> bashes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Book</ENAMEX>
Review . Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are mostly second-rate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novelists</ENAMEX> who write turgid prose
and "rave about demonstrably bad books." ... The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gummo</ENAMEX> , a movie about self-destructive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teens</ENAMEX>, "the
worst film of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>."

            

               Update
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kimmelman</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Gehry</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bilbao</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, "hogs the spotlight. ... [<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">I</ENAMEX>]t is more
compelling than much of the art inside."

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">15:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Seven Years</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- Boogie

               <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Nights</TIMEX> ;

            
               Fashion --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Versace</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Spring/Summer '98 Collections</ENAMEX>;

            
               Product --Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Explorer 4.0</ENAMEX>;

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Award --Nobel Prize</ENAMEX> for
Literature, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dario Fo</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- How the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mind Works</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Pinker</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- U-Turn ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Square ;

            
               Movie -- Soul
Food ;

            

               Architecture --<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim Museum</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bilbao</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>);

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Toward the</ENAMEX>
End of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Updike</ENAMEX>;

            

               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Lichtenstein</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The
Edge ;

            
               Movie -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peacemaker</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Big Trouble:</ENAMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder in a Small Western Town Sets Off a Struggle for the Soul of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Anthony Lukas</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timequake</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Vonnegut</ENAMEX>;

            
               Music -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> Out of
Mind , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Dylan</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Babylon</ENAMEX> , by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Stones</ENAMEX>;

            
               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ER :</ENAMEX>
"Ambush" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>);

            

               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sensations: Young British Artists From the Saatchi Collection</ENAMEX>"
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Academy of Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>).

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">24:</TIMEX>

            
               Book -- The
Royals , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelley</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underworld</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don DeLillo</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great</ENAMEX>
Apes , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Will Self</ENAMEX>;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rauschenberg: A Retrospective"</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Guggenheim Museums and Ace Gallery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>);

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thousand</ENAMEX>
Acres ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice</ENAMEX>
Storm ;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Veronica's Closet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>).

            

               --Compiled by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> .
            

         
      
   
