
   
   
      
         
            

            

               Movies
            

            
               
                  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Seven Nights</ENAMEX>
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buena Vista Pictures</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lipstick lesbian Anne Heche</ENAMEX>
wins praise for her first leading role since coming out. Though some had
doubted she'd make a convincing straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Kempley</ENAMEX> gibes that "[s]he seems to have mastered the nuances of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heterosexuality</ENAMEX>." A few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heche</ENAMEX> and co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Ford</ENAMEX>, marooned
together on a tropical <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">island</ENAMEX>, lack chemistry. Others say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">comic director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reitman</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ghostbusters</ENAMEX> ), who made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fathers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day</ENAMEX> ,
has lost his touch and is now just recycling old lines and plots.

            
               
                  The
Opposite of Sex
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony Pictures Classics</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> call rookie director
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Roos</ENAMEX>' romantic comedy one of the most original in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. "A happy exception
to the rule that any movie with 'sex' in the title must be mediocre" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
Sarris, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Observer</ENAMEX> ). A precocious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year-old</TIMEX>, played by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Ricci</ENAMEX>--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lolita</ENAMEX>'s evil twin" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Maslin</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times )--runs off with her gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Reviewers</ENAMEX> like the
unpredictable plot twists, witty asides about sexual identity, and the casting.
Many predict stardom for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ricci</ENAMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Addams Family and The Ice</ENAMEX>
Storm ). <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dissenters</ENAMEX> fault the film for turning sentimental at the end.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            

               
                  High Art
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">October Films</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eighties Brat Packer Ally Sheedy</ENAMEX>
revives her career playing a cult <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lesbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX>. But apart from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheedy</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">melancholic</ENAMEX> portrayal of the doped-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX>, the film is said to be
"full of itself and its artistic pretension" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mathews</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ) and saddled with clichéd depictions of bohemianism. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say it
uses saucy lesbian love scenes simply to attract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> and to make up for its
insubstantial plot.

            

               Theater
            

            
               
                  Not
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">About</TIMEX> Nightingales
                (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alley Theatre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>). A long-lost <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> play from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> makes its <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> debut. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say it offers fresh
insights into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">playwright</ENAMEX>'s tortured mind. They're shocked by the violence
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 27-year-old</TIMEX>'s portrait of a prison revolt. "The sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> would
be the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> you would associate with this play," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kroll</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Detractors</ENAMEX> call the dialogue overwrought: It "sounds like bad
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tennessee Williams</ENAMEX>" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Zoglin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> ).

            

               Television
            

            
               
                  The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Hour</ENAMEX>
                (click for local listings).Applause for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Johnson</ENAMEX> as a role
model, jeers for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Johnson</ENAMEX> as talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> find the
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> irresistibly likable, his show "is a crashing bore" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin</ENAMEX>
Kitman, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> ). His monologues are judged clunky and not funny, and
"his mode of interviewing consists mainly of salivating over <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guests</ENAMEX> for being
on the show" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Rosenberg</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). It uses the same
A-list of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> who appear on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leno</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Letterman</ENAMEX>, leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> to wonder,
"How many talk shows does any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> need?" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caryn James</ENAMEX>, the New York
Times ) (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Click</ENAMEX> here for the official site.)

            

               Book
            

            

               
                  Gain
               , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Powers</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farrar, Straus & Giroux</ENAMEX>). Mixed
reviews for the latest from the hyperintellectual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Gold Bug</ENAMEX>
Variations . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powers</ENAMEX> tries to shed his reputation as inaccessibly scholarly
by writing a straightforward novel about a soap <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> who
gets <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">ovarian cancer</ENAMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> praise his insight into the dark nature of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> business and his riffs on subjects from chemotherapy to free markets.
Others say his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> just deliver long, boring speeches on esoterica. "It
hardly seems fitting ... to call it fiction" (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail Caldwell</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> ).

            
               Recent
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Summary Judgment</ENAMEX>" columns
            

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Truman</ENAMEX>
Show ;

            
               Movie -- A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect</ENAMEX>
Murder ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Courtney</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Television -- Sex
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>);

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> --The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tony</ENAMEX>
Awards;

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>
Burne-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Victorian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Artist</ENAMEX>-Dreamer";

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cold New World</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Finnegan</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:</TIMEX>

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- The Last</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Disco</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX>
Floats ;

            
               Television -- More
Tales of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            
               Television -- A
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bright Shining Lie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>) and Thanks of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grateful Nation</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>);

            
               Art --"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rothko</ENAMEX>";

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> .

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">28:</TIMEX>

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Godzilla</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">-- Fear and</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loathing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie --<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cannes Film</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Festival Roundup</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freedomland</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Price</ENAMEX>;

            
               Books -- Remembering
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX>"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">: The Invisible Art of Editing</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ved Mehta</ENAMEX>;
Here But Not <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Here: A Love Story</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lillian Ross</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Larry Sanders Show</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showtime</ENAMEX>).

            May
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">20:</TIMEX>

            
               Death --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sinatra</ENAMEX>;

            

               Television -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seinfeld</ENAMEX> finale;

            

               Movie -- <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bulworth</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Movie -- The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horse</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whisperer</ENAMEX> ;

            
               Book -- The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Everlasting Story of Nory , by Nicholson Baker</ENAMEX>;

            
               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cities</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Plain</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cormac McCarthy</ENAMEX>;

            

               Book -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Identity</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milan Kundera</ENAMEX>, translated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Asher</ENAMEX>.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Foer</ENAMEX>
            

         
      
   
