
 
     		
 	
 		um well um guess it's logical to ask do you exercise any
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well unfortunately very little uh much less than what i need to
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm about the same way i i do a little bit my my job kind of hinders me from
 		exercising i'm a night <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operator</ENAMEX> here at a
 		industry down here and i don't really get out a lot during
 		because of my job to to exercise
 	
 	
 		well i uh am an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>  and uh in business technology and i've
 		i think the most exercise i've gotten in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three or four month</TIMEX> is just jumping up and down to go answer the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>' questions it keeps me pretty busy but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's not really the kind of exercise that gets your heart rate going and and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know really exercise is so important and i realize that
 	
 	
 		it is
 		um-hum that's that's the way i feel i'm used to being in pretty good shape because when i was in high school i stayed in pretty good shape playing a little basketball and stuff like that but i've gotten now i'm in college and i go to school during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> and work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 		i can tell that i've not really done a whole lot
 	
 	
 		when you uh exercise what do you do do you do it at home or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		well uh i usually i'm i usually play at home we live out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'ll play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> and have a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> come over and play or a lot of times we're we're up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> we'll play volleyball
 		stuff like that
 	
 	
 		i got a hold of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Simmons</ENAMEX>'s tape uh
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		what is it uh i can't even think of the name of it right offhand uh
 		with the oldies
 	
 	
 		oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweating</ENAMEX> to the Oldies
 	
 	
 		Sweating with the to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldies</ENAMEX> yeah and that's not bad
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		that's pretty upbeat so you know i every once in a while i'll put the cassette in and go with it but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		not often enough to have a routine
 	
 	
 		right i'll
 	
 	
 		my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schnauzer</ENAMEX> wishes i would get out and walk with her
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		i don't know by the time i get home all i wanna do is just collapse or sit down at my computer and my fingers exercise more than anything now
 	
 	
 		right that's the way i am i just want to sit down and relax too tired to exercise
 	
 	
 		yes uh
 		do you ever ride a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> or anything like that
 	
 	
 		i did i started riding my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a couple of months ago</TIMEX> and i'd ride <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two or three miles</NUMEX> a day but but it'd last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a couple of weeks</TIMEX> and it got real cold for a little while so i gave it up
 	
 	
 		here about the
 		the most common exercise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> is to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> and walk them
 	
 	
 		walk around
 	
 	
 		because they're enclosed and no matter what the weather is they can walk at a pretty good clip and and not have to worry about the weather <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> or winter
 	
 	
 		right
 		right i've noticed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing that down here too i'll be in town or something and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will walk around the mall
 	
 	
 		and it's safe
 	
 	
 		it it is it's fairly safe
 	
 	
 		that's uh you know inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> may be not safe going to the parking <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage lot</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah certain parts of it
 	
 	
 		i know a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> once told me it it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine uh suggested swimming as being the best exercise there is
 	
 	
 		right
 		right i used to do a lot of swimming we have we have a swimming pool and but it's an old concrete pool we've been having trouble with it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX>
 		so we haven't got to use it much but i love to swim and water ski and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		the uh swimming they say uses more muscles than any other exercise with
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> takes the resistance
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		right and you don't get the soreness
 		i've i've done some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> exercises
 		but our pool is not is not heated so it's
 	
 	
 		right you can't do it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> round
 	
 	
 		summertime only
 	
 	
 		right that's the way ours is
 		just in the summertime
 	
 	
 		you don't go out when it's
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> some odd degrees and and go out to the swimming pool
 	
 	
 		no
 		no no it's too cold
 	
 	
 		hot tubs are not not uh not too bad but
 	
 	
 		i could deal with a hot tub those are nice
 	
 	
 		so what part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> are you from
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">whereabouts</ENAMEX> is that
 	
 	
 		that's  way down towards the south not quite on the coast but we're about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> from the coast
 	
 	
 		oh and you do have cold weather down there
 	
 	
 		yes yes ma'am it well it started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about yesterday</TIMEX> i believe it started raining and got real cold
 	
 	
 		ours started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh from there just well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was pretty
 		but uh
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> the snow and ice came in
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh there was no exercise
 		
 		
 	