
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 		okay what do you feel are some of the main problems
 	
 	
 		
  
 		well i'm in a i'm in an urban area i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we're finding that crime is going up very quickly and has become a major problem uh even a more major problem uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> some of the major problems um
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> seems to be related related to quite a bit of the crime we have now there is a lot of theft a lot of assault dealing with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to get money for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i think that's a national problem though it's not unique
 	
 	
 		it it it's pretty bad here too we've had a lot of murders drug related and stuff and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham</ENAMEX> which is right next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well now we're pretty close to the golden triangle aren't you
 	
 	
 		yeah that that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham Raleigh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel Hill</ENAMEX> is the triangle
 	
 	
 		right research triangle and all of that and um
 	
 	
 		right
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i'm sure you have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> there uh and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> so you you may have a
 		you know perhaps a little better economic climate but in all your <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> now it seems like there there's a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> that's really effected by this bill
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's really it's and and i've seen in more in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham</ENAMEX> than i have in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raleigh</ENAMEX> or or
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chapel Hill Chapel Hill</ENAMEX> is kind of a a ritzy
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		city or whatever i mean it's kind of
 		i'm i'm sure there's problems with it but it has a pretty low crime rate compare compared to to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Durham</ENAMEX> has probably got the worst
 		they've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like forty eight</NUMEX> murders since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning of the year</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> of it's been drug related
 	
 	
 		really
 		hm
 		well here uh i'm not sure how many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> has had i've
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Houston</ENAMEX> is averaging <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or three or four</TIMEX> i I don't know a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number every week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Dallas</ENAMEX> is having quite a few it seems like most of ours are occurring in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX> or or like i say drug related
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		uh i guess the other thing was that are causing a lot of the crime now is the decrease in values seems like a a lot of people
 		don't hold human life quite as high as
 		perhaps they used to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		i
 	
 	
 		well that and the and the economy's so bad and
 	
 	
 		the economy is lousy
 	
 	
 		and so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have been laid off and stuff they've done special stories on the news local news here we've had a lot of bank robberies and different lot of break-ins and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i know like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or so ago</TIMEX>
 		i live in a in a town <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> which is you know it's a pretty nice neighborhood
 		and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> was going to work she came home and everything in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was total gone light fixtures everything and
 		nobody thought any different they just thought she was moving it was a moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> pulled right up to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> broke in and stole everything she owned
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that really that really takes someone who's bold to do that
 	
 	
 		well yeah it's it's it's pretty bad
 	
 	
 		well now do you find that security is very good in in a in a town home
 	
 	
 		um i would say so for the majority in in our in my little section of the neighborhood because
 		there's always somebody at home and we all know one another and and on our one little section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> we all know one another and know that we're not moving  and different things like that it's i i'm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that
 	
 	
 		i'm probably the one of the youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that live over here most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are are retired or or
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		or you know they're they're in their forties or or whatever so
 		and i'm in my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenties</TIMEX> so i i'm i'm out more than they are but they're at home at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> so i really don't worry about anything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think you hit on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point there is you know each other i'm i'm in a neighborhood where we try to keep up with everything uh i am
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
  
 	
 	
 		oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about three</NUMEX> blocks off a major <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> and uh a couple of blocks off another <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> that kind of runs
 		i guess you would say the neighborhood road it runs between the high school and the the commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> and uh i'm over the northeast part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and it's a in a nice neighborhood the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> here
 		uh before the recession were running <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred thousand or so</NUMEX> and course everything's down <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">twenty percent</NUMEX> now
 	
 	
 		yeah see that's the same thing here
 	
 	
 		but we have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> thing that effects us is we have <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> that are probably <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a half mile</NUMEX> away
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and now that the economy is bad they have trouble keeping those full so they've dropped the uh
 		uh they're not nearly as selective as they used to be
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and course that's kind of like a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in an apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> you start letting that happen and they go down and then before you know it you have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and a lot of other things so uh i'm sure that aggravates it also
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but unemployment now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> is up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">around six</NUMEX> point
 		
 		
 	