
 
     		
 	
 		okay  what do you like  do you watch TV much
 	
 	
 		
  
 		okay
 		what do i like
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> watch it quite a bit i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> and so no they they watch um
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		TV probably more than i would like for them to we watch really we watch VCR more than we watch TV but i'll tell you what show i don't like rather than what i do like
 	
 	
 		really
 		oh yeah
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Married with Children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i don't watch that in the i did watch it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the beginning</TIMEX> when it was new and it was kind of funny a couple of times and then i don't i don't watch it
 	
 	
 		do you ever watch it
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like it they all think it's funny and they all say good grief you're just too  you're too old fashion it's just a spoof but i really dislike what it says about marriage i dislike what it says about raising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		everybody says oh it's it's just supposed to be funny i don't find it funny i find it insult
 	
 	
 		it was just for a kick i know
 		yeah but look at the soap operas
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i don't  i work so i'm not a soap opera <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and so i just never watch them
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too i know yeah i'm not a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i haven't been a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and i really
 		didn't even know what was ever on and then this year for some reason i have a twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> and for some reason we've just gotten real comfortable with these little sitcoms at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		which ones do you like
 	
 	
 		oh just the little funny things we love Full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		i love Full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> i think that's probably one of my favorite shows
 	
 	
 		you know i just
 		yeah it's mine too and i just
 		it's nice and wholesome and there aren't very many of those you know so we look forward to that and i love i just love that little bitty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> on there  she's so cute yeah
 	
 	
 		no there aren't
 		she's a sweetie and it's uh it's really neat because they really have watched her grow up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> did you see it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks ago</TIMEX> when they had her <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> birthday that was so precious
 	
 	
 		yes they went through all
 		yeah it was really well done
 	
 	
 		it was and i hadn't realized that she'd been on the show that the show had been on that long that she was so tiny
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and that she was just i remember when it very first came out i remember watching the very <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode
 	
 	
 		oh i don't remember
 	
 	
 		and God they were all so young well you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DJ Cameron</ENAMEX> that's um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Cameron</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> do you ever watch Growing Pains
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 		right right yeah i know who he is i don't watch it i don't like it very much
 	
 	
 		do you watch that
 		oh really huh that's interesting now i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Growing Pains</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i just never i never got into it and it might be the time that it's on and i'm not sure when it's on but
 	
 	
 		it used to be on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> well first it was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesdays</TIMEX> and then they switched it to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesdays</TIMEX> and i hated that time frame because i had church <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">choir</ENAMEX> and now it's on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know why i don't know why i never watch it maybe because it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>
 		could be could be
 	
 	
 		and i'm not home a lot but
 	
 	
 		i think i liked it when it first started better than i like it now yeah
 	
 	
 		really i never got into it very much and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> loves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum Leap</ENAMEX> and i hate that show
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i've never watched it it's just
 	
 	
 		oh he's so it's such a strange thing have you ever seen it
 	
 	
 		not me
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quantum Leap</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's he changes he has a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> that's sort of like a conscience or something i'm not sure and he goes to a different time
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		you know a time in the past it's sort of like a back to the future theme and he goes back and he changes things
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so that they're not like somebody doesn't die but he  becomes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i mean he's already been a pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and had a baby i mean it's it's uh it's a ridiculous
 	
 	
 		
 
 		ooh
 		hm i think i might have trouble with that
 	
 	
 		it's a really uh i have trouble with it it's just a really ridiculous show i just hate it my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> looks forward to it she likes it
 	
 	
 		but but your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> likes it
 		that's funny
 	
 	
 		i yeah i guess so i don't know but i just i like that kind of thing and i like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Brooklyn Bridge</ENAMEX> that's a new one to see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> Bridge
 	
 	
 		you like what
 		i don't watch it either
 	
 	
 		it's a new one that just came on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and i like it because it's the fifties back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh see i would probably like that too i enjoy things like that
 	
 	
 		well being from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> i relate to when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brooklyn</ENAMEX> and i mean back you know and so it's like that time and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are little when i was kind of little you know and it was
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's sort of like that so it's a little bit nostalgic for me and the things that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> talks about a lot of them are in the show you know so that kind of thing yeah  so i like that
 	
 	
 		i understand
 		well i think  i need to be going because i'm trying to get dinner on the table for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and me
 	
 	
 		oh can we do that we don't have to tell them i mean they don't tell us when to hang up
 	
 	
 		huh
 		they only tell us when um
 		when we're down to the last
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i didn't know that oh okay well you better pull your little paper out you better pull your little paper out and keep going then  it's not over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> when you have to hang up because you've run out of time
 		i know i forgot  well maybe someone will call me again
 	
 	
 		maybe they will oh it's been fun to talk to you  you too bye-bye thanks
 	
 	
 		i hope so listen i've enjoyed talking to you have a nice <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	