
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right i think that gets us off to discussing the topic for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		which is movies correct
 	
 	
 		that is correct are you a movie buff
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um yeah i don't like going to see them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> but outside of that
 		rent a lot watch them on TV mostly
 	
 	
 		well i have a VCR and i see most all of mine there what have you seen recently that you enjoyed
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i don't know um actually earlier <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> we were watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">To Live and Die</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> have you seen that movie
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		it's a kind of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those psycho ones
 	
 	
 		now i i live alone consequently i don't like these things psycho things
 	
 	
 		oh it's not too bad one of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> thrillers but
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		have you seen the movie if do you have a VCR
 	
 	
 		yes we do
 	
 	
 		have you seen the movie Class Action with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Hackman</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no i haven't yet
 	
 	
 		i saw it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> and it is uh to me an outstanding outstanding movie i thoroughly enjoyed it
 		he is uh an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> and she has a suit against
 		his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you know it's one of those things but there's a lot of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well well it's just
 		it's something that anyone can watch and enjoy
 	
 	
 		yeah he's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		beg pardon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Gene Hackman</ENAMEX>'s a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> i think uh do you see Hoosiers
 	
 	
 		yes he is
 		yes i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoosiers</ENAMEX> saw it just again <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> for my
 	
 	
 		yeah actually i we saw her just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> too
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 	
 	
 		yeah and it's one of our favorite movies i i live with um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of us we've seen that movie probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last six months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you seen the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Crossing</ENAMEX> Delancey
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now that's one i have watched oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or eight</NUMEX> times i always feel so good when i get through with that movie
 	
 	
 		yeah i like those movies that you watch time and time again
 	
 	
 		i do too <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dirty Dancing and Crossing Delancey</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my favorite
 		so well what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> are you in
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm an electrical engineer
 	
 	
 		oh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> all right
 	
 	
 		i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		oh all right okay
 		so is everything going all right up there
 	
 	
 		um it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only about um half an hour</TIMEX> i  live with on the border
 	
 	
 		oh well that's not bad then if <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> we do that just going to downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		see we live up in tax free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> and drive down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> to work
 	
 	
 		that makes a lot of sense
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but um we are you a native of that part of the country
 	
 	
 		yeah i i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> it seems southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Portsmouth</ENAMEX> it's
 		i don't know fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass</ENAMEX> border and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> from the main border we live right in the corner
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that one little spot in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX> we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> miles of coastline i live on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those that little <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> mile spot
 	
 	
 		uh sounds wonderful did you have damage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> with hurricanes
 	
 	
 		not up um where i live but further down the coast in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> they they got hit pretty bad
 	
 	
 		i happened to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX>
 		and we got the backlash of that thing
 		and they had record high waves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty year</TIMEX> high waves come in there and it was quite an experience so well what movies are you looking forward to seeing now
 	
 	
 		um well i'm i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only twenty seven years old</TIMEX> so The Doors movie
 		that's out on video i wanna watch that
 	
 	
 		okay have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Card</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that would be pretty good
 		no i haven't seen that one
 	
 	
 		that's a real
 		warm movie it it really just turned out nicely so i would recommend that if you have a chance
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm in for it we rent a lot of movies so we we often sit around and say what movies should we rent and we don't know
 	
 	
 		well if you if you can get Green Card go for it
 	
 	
 		all right we'll try that one
 	
 	
 		i have been working at uh as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> at the medical school here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and i have watched um
 		Gross <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anatomy</ENAMEX> have you seen that one
 	
 	
 		yeah i did
 	
 	
 		okay
 		and i don't know i can associate with some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in that movie because of
 		the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> i see over at the medical school
 		but i hope you have a very merry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		you too
 	
 	
 		i'm looking forward to it
 	
 	
 		i think we're going to have a white <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> up here just like the song says
 	
 	
 		well
 		
 		
 	