
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so how is the weather out there
 	
 	
 		um it's really cold and it's supposedly for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of the year</TIMEX> it's <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">unseasonably cold</ENAMEX> and they've gotten more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> than they've ever had
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		you have breaking records for coldness and all that kind of stuff how about you guys
 	
 	
 		hum um it's just it's a it's about same the usual i think
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so nice for skiing and
 		all that kind stuff
 		it's good
 	
 	
 		yeah well the weather
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		let's see well the snow here is different from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s because i've lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really what part
 	
 	
 		and um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provo i</ENAMEX> was going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> yeah and um the snow is like really cold i mean it's like really humid so it seems uh wetter or something like that than
 	
 	
 		oh really okay
 		it's more humid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> than there
 		or there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it's more humid in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		okay right okay
 	
 	
 		and it seems like when the winds blow it's real it goes right through you it's really different from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s weather i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> was cold but i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> is a lot colder
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah see that's how it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> too because when it's cold it's really cold
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't think there's any mountains to stop the wind
 	
 	
 		so
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		i don't think there's any mountains to stop the wind
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah so the humidity i think is what does it
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's true
 	
 	
 		because i i noticed when i got here too because like i'd when it would snow in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> um i would just i mean we'd be freezing really cold and we'd have to get really warm and here you can almost not even wear a coat outside when it's snowing and you you don't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it is true
 	
 	
 		you don't feel super cold it was weird
 		but
 		so how long ago did you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> or did you or
 	
 	
 		um i graduated in nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> got his doctorate at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> so that's and so he just graduated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh so you just barely moved away
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah we really miss well we really miss <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>  we miss the mountains
 	
 	
 		huh do you like it out there
 		you do
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because it's like really flat here  well not flat but <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hilly</NUMEX> and but no big mountains or anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so you just moved away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		um in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 		just really recent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but um let's see
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		let's see what else can i say about the weather um
 		well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> was warmer  it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh warm
 	
 	
 		so what's the temperature up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> over there
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> it's got to be like it's probably
 		fifty fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> maybe
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		maybe not that warm probably about uh
 		um yeah it's not it's not that cold really
 	
 	
 		and whenever i remembered the weather reports in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> i never really remember them talking too much about wind chill but they talk about wind chill here all the time because
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah
 		yeah that's a big deal in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		they said it could be like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six degrees</NUMEX> outside and like negative forty one wind chill
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so that's something we're not used to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true that's makes a big difference
 		huh
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so oh i
 	
 	
 		so did you used to ski when you were out here
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		did you used to ski when you were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i've only i've only skied in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> once i've only skied once my whole life
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but do you do a lot of skiing there
 	
 	
 		well
 		um not tons but i like to when i get a chance i've only been once so far but had the opportunity <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> times since then
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just saving my money for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> things and that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so is this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">your first year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um no this is actually my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> year
 	
 	
 		and you're going to school there oh at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U of U</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> yep
 		no at BYU
 	
 	
 		oh really oh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so but i'll be here a long time
 		at this rate
 	
 	
 		what's your major
 	
 	
 		um it was nursing but i'm in the process of changing it right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh oh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because it's really really competitive at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> you have to have like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three seven</NUMEX> to get in so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		it's really
 		i'm gonna look into some other fields i'd like all the science classes and that i'm just not really enjoying too much so i think i better get into something that i can enjoy the process
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of going to school so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		did you graduate in
 		a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		um education i got a double major
 	
 	
 		in
 	
 	
 		uh elementary and special ed uh-huh
 	
 	
 		really that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> did yeah you might know her her name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lori Bird</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		maybe not  i think she graduated around then too though <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> probably
 		but
 		she got her double
 	
 	
 		yeah well i can't
 		there are so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in all my classes i can't remember how many people
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah because they just since um stopped that program i mean where you can where you can get it doubled pretty easily
 	
 	
 		oh have they
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i mean it's hard it's really
 		
 		
 	