
 
     		
 	
 		okay uh i guess our topic is about movies
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh what a coincidence we got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX> and we went to the movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh so did i
 	
 	
 		and we saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cape</ENAMEX> Fear
 	
 	
 		oh i heard that was excellent is it um i wanted to see that i was deciding between that and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh My Girl</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> and i went to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Girl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it is it's really good
 		oh how's that
 	
 	
 		oh it was excellent it was a really really good movie i'd recommend it
 	
 	
 		i i heard that's a a movie that uh you really can't take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> is that true
 	
 	
 		um i heard the opposite that um you should take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to see it
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		um there were quite um few uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in there with their parents
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah um i don't know though i i've heard that and then what you just told me so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah because uh the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> dies
 	
 	
 		right yeah it was sad it was really sad but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		his it kind of shows how his um best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> deals with his death and how i think maybe how <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should deal with death maybe
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		but it was really good it was sad very sad
 	
 	
 		oh i wanna see that one well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cape Fear</ENAMEX> was was more suspenseful it was really suspenseful so that that's that's a real good movie to see
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		i heard it was um
 		sort of like um
 		not um too violent but it was kind of like um
 		gross kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">like um Silence of the Lambs</ENAMEX> like
 	
 	
 		uh no and no it uh it's kind of i don't know it's kind of both i guess but it's not it's not as bad as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> of the Lambs
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		but uh it's just as suspenseful i think and it it was a real good movie
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and then we saw
 		Beauty and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Beast</ENAMEX>  because we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fievel Goes West</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		uh
 		oh i've seen um
 		previews for them on TV but i
 	
 	
 		but uh those were those were okay
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so and then oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> it's been it's been so long since we've been to the movies but i we've rented some videos
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i like to rent movies too
 	
 	
 		and i think the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i rented was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mortal Thoughts with Demi Moore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i
 		oh i i didn't see that
 	
 	
 		and um that that that's okay that's pretty good oh and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um What About Bob</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i've seen that at the theatres yeah that that was cute
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah we rented that one
 		and uh uh i guess that's probably about it have you rented any movies lately
 	
 	
 		um
 		the last movie i rented was <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Hard Way</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J Fox</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that was good we rented that one too
 	
 	
 		yeah i liked that i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael J Fox</ENAMEX> a lot  he's one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i like his movies
 	
 	
 		so do you go to the movies often or
 	
 	
 		no not too often i i hadn't been to the movies for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX> long time except for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last weekend</TIMEX> but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's been movies out that i've been wanting to see i just you know don't get a chance to get out and see them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so it's hard for us to get out and go to the movies we have to dig up a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitter</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		and that's only the only time we can go out so
 		our time is scarce
 	
 	
 		yeah oh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		but um
 		we we we try we you know we're we're big movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and and we try and do and i don't i don't know about the last movie i've seen on TV that was real good um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh i watched that movie with um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX> um oh what was her name
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> that um her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> got killed and um
 		she had a baby the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband husband</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX> and he had murdered her
 	
 	
 		oh yeah um
 	
 	
 		that was that was pretty good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bertinelli</ENAMEX> or what's her name
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valerie Bertinelli</ENAMEX> that's it yeah
 	
 	
 		i can't yeah yeah yeah
 		yeah  yeah that was real good i saw that one uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> part series and i heard it was a true story
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that was probably the last movie i've seen too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and then i saw that other movie about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um Mother Daughter Mother Wife Murderer</ENAMEX> did you see that one
 	
 	
 		oh um with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">um Judith Light</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		did you see that one that was was really good too that's supposed to be a true story too
 	
 	
 		yeah i did see that yeah i did it that was on a while ago wasn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks ago</TIMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		um yeah i saw that um-hum
 		yeah that was pretty good i
 	
 	
 		boy we have we we see all the same movies
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i like um the true stories they're more interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's hard to believe that you know this really happened some of them are pretty bad
 	
 	
 		i know yeah
 		yeah yeah
 		huh
 		well  we sure do have a lot in common
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you're ever in town we'll go see a movie
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but and we don't really do y'all have do y'all still have drive-ins up there or
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum yeah do you have them there
 	
 	
 		hm
 		we may have just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> over here
 		
 		
 	