
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes
 		um
 		i guess my
 		initial view is
 		our tax burden hasn't gone down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> despite our total tax burden despite tax cuts but
 		among industrialized <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> we have one of the
 		lowest in in the world and in part of the matter you get what you pay for we're gonna have national health insurance which seems likely it's necessarily gonna involve more taxes
 		uh i suspect they take the view that cutting income tax rates has been good for the the economy that most other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have a higher share of the tax burden
 		in various kinds of sales taxes uh
 		energy taxes particularly and that to the extent we need to raise more taxes that's the direction we should look
 	
 	
 		right well i guess i kind of have mixed feelings
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um you know you always sit there and out of each pay check so much comes out of it and you wonder you know where's it all going and we have such a huge uh national deficit and
 	
 	
 		where it's all going
 	
 	
 		and i guess a lot of times there's questions wondering well if it's doing a whole lot of good i know there's a lot of social programs out there that need help
 		but you kind of always wonder well where where's the money going
 	
 	
 		well <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one one</NUMEX> of the big tax that has gone up a lot in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is the social security tax which in principle is going into into a big trust fund but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that is a particularly regressive tax uh it's a tax on the first dollar earnings
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s uh proposal to to to cut there i think would makes a lot of sense
 	
 	
 		i'm sorry i couldn't i couldn't hear that
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moynihan</ENAMEX>'s proposal to to cut the social security tax which isn't really going to going to beef up up up the social security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> could make a lot of sense
 	
 	
 		right right yeah i agree with that
 		as far as other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i'm not um i don't keep up on it too much just as far as what you know as what they're doing i know we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and i know that the tax there is extremely high much higher than we pay here but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		but as far as other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i'm not uh up to par on
 	
 	
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is probably about equal to ours
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and other major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are higher i had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> were amazed at the sales taxes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> of things when they went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>  not so long ago
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and as a whole most other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have a higher level of cradle to grave government services
 		and it's a real real they're they're real trade-offs there
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		yeah but and and you sit there and wonder um
 		i guess this doesn't really have to do with taxes but just money in general and and um wondering if you're gonna have enough when you retire  to live on
 	
 	
 		uh i that that's a scary thing with this
 		no no real knowing about uh the the there's a lot of inflation risk that isn't taken care of in most private pension plans
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's true
 		but um are you involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> up there or since
 	
 	
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they're part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX>
 		here in  here in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gaithersburg Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i was just wondering since you said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> and you and you picked this topic i was just kind of curious
 	
 	
 		well well
 		i i i didn't pick it uh
 	
 	
 		oh you didn't
 	
 	
 		i um i like i don't really recall what i may have filled out on the on the form but i i certainly think certainly been given topics different from the ones that i'd mentioned before
 	
 	
 		oh did you see i haven't placed any calls did they automatically assign the topic
 	
 	
 		yes yes when you place a call topic is given to you
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't know that i thought whoever made the call could choose what topic because i haven't made any calls yet i've just received some
 	
 	
 		oh you should try it
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't realize that  okay
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		yeah because it's kind of a it can be a rather controversial subject depending on who you're talking to
 	
 	
 		uh many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> are uh
 		and taxes
 		taxes especially um one thing that has kept kept our tax burden high and this will change somewhat in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX> is the is the level of defense of the defense budget
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and that's that same subject
 		
 		
 	