
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay what do you feel are everyday occurrences that are invasion of privacy in your opinion
 	
 	
 		well uh i guess uh one that comes to mind is um
 		the way the credit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaus</ENAMEX> operate
 	
 	
 		i i agree <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one hundred</NUMEX> percent especially whenever it's like  they keep stuff on your record like for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> and they don't bother like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i know at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i was unemployed or something and and they kept they kept it on my record for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX> even though that i <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years</TIMEX> even though that like you know i i um
 		yeah they sent a letter in but they didn't bother to include the letter  for the explanation where i got behind or anything like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we had a problem with them back
 		oh i don't know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five or seven years ago</TIMEX> where it uh some stuff was on there that was incorrect and it was and it was real hard to
 	
 	
 		and well that too
 	
 	
 		get it  get it fixed  but they um they share that information with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 	
 	
 		well that happened with me i um i had had a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s appointment at at uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Chapel Hill Hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Parrishes</ENAMEX> and they were charging me for this other person
 		and i went through like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> of you know because they kept billing me and billing me and billing me i was like  you know i'm not this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i'm not seeing  seeing  you why are you charging me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i mean they turned me into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit Bureau</ENAMEX> they even held my taxes
 	
 	
 		oh they did
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it went a long ways and it
 	
 	
 		you mean they held your uh refund
 	
 	
 		over my refund that you you know and it was it was a mess and finally i got it straightened out but it it took me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a year</TIMEX> to get that straightened out and it was for something you know uh
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Parrish</ENAMEX> that wasn't paying his bills or either else they wasn't you know charging him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it was really weird
 	
 	
 		huh
 		well
 		let's see um
 	
 	
 		i think the biggest thing i think that are is not just well not for the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i i think like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>'s is is getting a little bit overboard on the invasion of privacy on
 		like different on public figures yeah that  some of the stuff that they're they're like
 	
 	
 		on public figures
 	
 	
 		like the tabloids and stuff are are saying that it's like really like i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Collins</ENAMEX> i believe is believe right now is having a lawsuit against
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		think it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> for taking pictures of her when she was getting undressed in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and  published them and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i some things i think should be private i would hate to know if i was getting undressed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> somebody was taking pictures of me you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		someone someone between the curtain was
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and i believe they've got  something now i read in some science <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> or something where they have a
 		infrared camera that can take pictures like with inside your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to see if you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or anything like that i think that's kind of an invasion of privacy too
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah i guess um another thing comes to mind is some of the
 		quote unquote routine uh traffic stops they do that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they did that around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX> all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they set those roadblocks up
 	
 	
 		oh yeah to see if you've been drinking and driving
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and you know and and uh
 		boy they just you know they have no reason to be stopping you and they just uh they stop you and and uh
 		look in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> a little bit you know lean in the windows anyway
 	
 	
 		well i i i had something like that happen to me too um i worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton</ENAMEX> for a while as a banquet waiter and um
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> whenever i got off work you know it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>  it was a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and you know i pulled out of that little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> where you know pull out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton</ENAMEX> on the old <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wake Forest Road</ENAMEX> going home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i looked up and it was i seen you know blue lights on and i thought God i just pull on the road it can't be me
 		so you know like i pulled off the road and i pulled you know pulled off the side <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> and the car followed you know the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> followed you know pulled me over and next thing i know there was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and they all got out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		you're kidding
 	
 	
 		and it it really scared me really bad
 	
 	
 		and they were just stopping you because you were leaving a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a night</TIMEX> spot probably
 	
 	
 		well uh they they said that i it was suspicious behavior and i looked at you know the highway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrol</ENAMEX> and i said how could it be suspicious behavior of me
 		uh waiting to a light was green making a left hand turn in the correct lane what's to make you know and they had they went all through my car
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and you know while  the highway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrolman</ENAMEX> pulled me back there or and and i i think they gave me a ticket for driving without my license
 	
 	
 		they did search your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> though
 	
 	
 		they did yeah without my permission
 	
 	
 		oh
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so i i thought i'd i was really offended by that i thought that was a severe invasion of privacy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think some of the laws that they're trying to pass right now um
 		especially in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> uh i mean we
 		
 		
 	