
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		do you have anybody uh in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that you ever had to put in a nursing home or
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> uh is the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> so far and um i basically think for her you know it was it was the best thing she was pretty out of it by the time she went into the nursing home
 	
 	
 		okay
 		was that here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> and so it was in uh  it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix Arizona</ENAMEX> and uh that was hard but i it wasn't too hard a decision because there was sort of no other option by the time we put her in the nursing home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right
 		did did you have to put her in yourself or
 	
 	
 		no i didn't my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> did uh she lived with well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> she lived with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and then it got to where she was not manageable anymore she was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she didn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> but um she was pretty much out of it and you know so they finally had to do that how about you
 	
 	
 		understand understand that
 		well my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> that i kind of grew up with uh
 		was in a nursing home she did have <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> and we had to put her in the nursing home because of that but uh this was up in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was a situation that's probably as good as you're gonna get uh it's associated with uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what they do my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> is in is a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terrace</ENAMEX> which it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Luther Manor Terrace</ENAMEX> and uh these are condominiums you buy into
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		when you know whenever you know you're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> or whatever you know whenever you want to buy into this thing and these are
 		very nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominium</ENAMEX> things and uh the idea is once you are in this program you are taken care of the rest of your life and they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they have a nursing home if you can't
 		maintain your own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> or your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominium</ENAMEX> uh you automatically go into that and from there they also have a health care area if you can't you know if you need more intensive care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		even the best there is isn't a nice situation with uh like you say when you get to a point where
 		uh well she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety four</NUMEX> and she was uh in the nursing home and the health care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> for i would guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year</TIMEX>'s time
 		but uh
 		it's a hard decision to make i tell you what it's uh
 	
 	
 		well it is now was your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> uh she was she no longer had her mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">faculties</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		that's that was really the price and that it gets very hard and on anybody uh i'd go up there and visit and and she'd recognize me but as soon as i was out down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> she didn't even know i was there
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's it's sad you know it
 	
 	
 		well it is sad i think i don't think for me it would be as hard a decision if their minds were gone i think it's a harder decision if they're still
 		if if their minds are still good but they're completely  their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> are gone you know i think that would be really hard to put someone in a nursing home in that situation um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i think there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some</NUMEX> times when you there's just nothing else that can be done but i my uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s dead and and so i just have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and she's in real good health but i would hate to have to make that decision for her um
 	
 	
 		well it's it's but what's really hard is the differences of care you know if you aren't fortunate enough to have a situation like with my mother
 	
 	
 		you know i hope that that won't happen
 		right
 	
 	
 		right now she's got terrible <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> in her knees and it's probably not real long where she won't be able to you know get along on her own and she probably
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know hopefully it will be a number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but she's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy nine years old right now</TIMEX> and now she understands that someday you know if she can't handle her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> that uh you know she'll have to go in the nursing home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if you have situations where you don't have that kind
 		you know it's you're confronted with it and if you look at all the different nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> uh that are out there it it is kind of frightening some of these places uh it's like put them in a cubbyhole and you know they don't
 		they're they're more caretakers kind of it's almost like putting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in a kennel you know some of these places and they stink and they're it it's a tough decision and you know if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't have the resources for uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's i i don't know about in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> but around here i understand it's it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from about twenty three hundred</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three thousand dollars</NUMEX> a month in a a nursing home
 	
 	
 		i'm i'm sure that's probably true i i don't know anymore now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s was the same idea as what you're telling me she
 		we when we put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> in um she was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> by her you know she had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> and but her
 		her care wasn't completely hospital yet but uh and then she went into the hospital part so it was one of those progressive care
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh kinds of situations and it was also affiliated with our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> so it was a really nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> but it would be terrible if you had no funds and and had to put someone in a nursing home and not know what kind of care they were really getting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and of course it's hard to know that unless you're there all the time um
 	
 	
 		well and that's the other thing that helps is that you have a relative a close relative that'll look in on them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even the best ones if you don't
 		look in on them they have a tendency to just sedate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> so they don't have to bothered you know and
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	