
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra</ENAMEX> uh what we are supposed to talk about this morning are and i i can tell that you're must be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> child care services
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		and my my first question is
 		what criteria
 		is normally applied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> when they are selecting child care
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what are they looking for in other words
 	
 	
 		well
 		well in my experience um i've never i've been fortunate enough to be able to stay home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		but um i have given day care to other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		and those that have come asking me to give you know to tend their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um i guess it depends on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> whether they're looking for a preschool type situation where they want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to learn
 		you know different skills and um school type things or whether they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are younger and they just want somebody to be there loving and nurturing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		what age would you say uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> should be before you could start applying this business of teaching them a little bit preschool information we talking what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six or seven</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four or five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		um  in my opinion i would i'm
 		would feel that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> at the very earliest i i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> need to learn how to get along with one another and to play and to be creative and and to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they do seem to have a very much improved uh intellectual sort of a spirit they're bright they look around and and they they know what's going that's that i guess that's as important to say
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i agree yes i agree in fact a lot of the kindergarten <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that i've spoken with said that they would prefer that preschools
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		per se would be done away with and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> just had a chance to you know develop the social skills that they say the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that come to school that have been to the preschool type settings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um are are almost far enough ahead that they're bored with school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they need to learn to get along but um have you ever had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in day care
 	
 	
 		i'm trying to think uh yes we've had uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in day care a little bit but not much i  the interesting comment i was going to make was that when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> grew up i felt very normal and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with them and i didn't consider a lot of these little details that we're talking about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but now that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> are growing up i look at them in a totally different style style
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i i watch very closely their activities when i see them and like and i can tell when they're speaking more clearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> and and when they are understanding situations more carefully
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i i don't remember doing it maybe i did automatically with my own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but i'm i'm just looking with a much higher technical detail at at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh uh-huh maybe you have more time as a grandfather oh oh
 	
 	
 		well i wish i did i'm still working but i'll be retiring soon
 		it it's it's just that uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> they are for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short period of time</TIMEX> and you just look at them and you absorb anything you can from them and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you start reviewing comparing when you get from them with what you got from your own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but it was really a different environment
 	
 	
 		oh yes how many ooh that's been what probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty twenty years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		something like that
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		well let me ask you this is it difficult to find a day care when you have a a specific criteria of your own is that is that hard to find
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i think it is in fact i know that um around here one of the major problems that the working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> have said they have is they will find a day care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">provider</ENAMEX> and then
 		she will stick with it for oh you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five six months</TIMEX> and then have something else come up and so then they are looking again for another one
 		unless they go to the commercial day care providers and i know in the community i live in a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> prefer just to have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> go to someone's home
 		and i know that that's um
 		there's a risk with that with the insurance and and different things like that but i know most of them prefer to have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> just in a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> home type environment
 	
 	
 		i see uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um i guess it just depends on what you're looking for and whether you mind if it was myself i would rather have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in that type of environment rather than the the big commercial day cares just simply for the fact that
 		there's so much illness that the little ones pass around and and you you know that type of a thing and the um
 	
 	
 		that's true yes
 	
 	
 		and i don't know what the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or you know what the ratio is for the adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">providers</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but i would think that if you had a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> it would be
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		that would be my preference anyway so
 	
 	
 		well my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam Holland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and they have over there what they call a creche
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> go to this creche which is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an all day</TIMEX> well about a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six hour</NUMEX>
 		
 		
 	