
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what do you think
 	
 	
 		well um gosh it set up on a scale <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah one being total control
 		total uh restriction and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> being none well i'm probably dead in the middle
 	
 	
 		uh you know i i think i would too i think i'd straddle the fence
 	
 	
 		because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he travels a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> and i'm always thinking of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and all of them now they get <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s got <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> should i say
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		got the strictest gun control law there is supposed to be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it look what it done
 		it's it's nothing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> than than anywhere from <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		so the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the only thing that i think gun control does to me is it keeps the normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or should i say law-abiding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> from having <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> going to get their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right yeah
 	
 	
 		it's not going to do any good to now if they ban like the automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and all that from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		period then you know then if they catch them with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> then fine but just gun control ain't going to stop them from having a gun
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		then then that you know
 	
 	
 		oh well see i agree with you uh it seems like the the crime rate has gone up even more um here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they're talking about uh there're more murders in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> um almost uh since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that broke in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> stole a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> didn't have a a burglar alarm or something and that that to me that was stupid they should at least make him have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		an alarm or make it a requirement on them on them gun stores
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you would think  but they
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah so yeah but i i just i wouldn't want to ban it completely um but uh somehow there needs to be the one thing that i did like was that where you had to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> um you know um
 	
 	
 		well
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i don't mind waiting that's that that i could care less
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you know waiting waiting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> so that they can make sure that check it out and everything's okay and to me that was uh that was perfectly acceptable
 	
 	
 		you know but
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know because if you are a law-abiding citizen you're not going to want to you know it's not going to matter to you if you have to wait a little while
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX> and see the the the thing about it to me that they was talking about having gun control so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wouldn't kill anybody but
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i am a true believer that if somebody wants to kill somebody okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't care if they can't get a gun they'll find something else
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  oh yeah
 	
 	
 		it doesn't matter that they the only thing is is the gun is the quickest way they they had or they had accessible to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if they don't have a gun they'll find something else especially if they want or they'll wait on their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> because they're not crazy
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yet i mean you know they haven't proved to nobody that they're crazy or they're in no federal no no no uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh what do you call it record or nothing so they'll get a gun then they can go kill somebody and then that'd be it
 	
 	
 		yeah  oh i agree with you yeah um
 	
 	
 		and then they still going to get it so
 		i don't think the gun control is going to help as far as
 		you know just taking everybody's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> away because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> well is it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> one of those those foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> has gun control but all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob people</ENAMEX> have guns
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		yeah no i i don't think that they should ban it i really i really don't um you know i i don't have a gun in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> myself because i have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and uh you know feel really uncomfortable about that but if i was by myself i'd definitely have a gun
 	
 	
 		well i have a gun you know my well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s fifteen but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and me he knows that he don't even touch it and it's not a hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> see
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shotgun</ENAMEX> so it just sits there
 		and it's in it's in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and he's not allowed in there anyway so
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		uh-huh yeah so that's that's a great
 	
 	
 		but it's not nothing that he can like  and that's another thing with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with these <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> i blame more the parents
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		because i grew up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> i guess you know in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had a gun cabinet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we wasn't allowed to touch it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lord</ENAMEX> help us if we did
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 		yeah but see these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know they keep them up underneath their pillows and you know sitting right on top of their dresser drawers i mean it's no wonder you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get in there and then they blow uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> away so you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no
 		yeah little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i don't like that i don't like it when they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> little small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because uh when i have small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> over i close my door
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is i live i live in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> so you know if the door opens i can see like what are you going into my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> for  it's not like a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> to where's i can't see if they go in my room
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah yeah  yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'll know if they go in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> because there ain't but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> so it's like right there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah so that um yeah but that that's about the biggest reason why i just never never and and i won't even let my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> play with play <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> either you know not even get that idea about about them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think the only gun my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intendo</ENAMEX>  you know with the TV thingy that's about it because
 	
 	
 		yeah there you go there you go that's right there you go yeah me too
 	
 	
 		the the you know i don't i don't like that i don't that's that's i don't know i just hum-um but i don't think the gun control as far as
 		i guess i would probably vote right in the middle if if if there is a way to vote
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	