
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX> and i'm calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hi this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie</ENAMEX> and i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay um would you like me to go first
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sure
 	
 	
 		okay um i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> who are in regular school uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight year old</TIMEX> and then my little one
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year old</TIMEX> is in um a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Gymnastics</ENAMEX> it's a a preschool and um i think it was really hard to um to pick the right uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		day care or preschool or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX> Out i guess you can classify them all together um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some of the qualifications that i look for was that uh you know the cost and um exactly what they did if it was structured or nonstructured if they had a little academic
 		um uh in there and um you know um you know what the qualifications the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' were and if the place was clean and um the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just just kind of going by word of mouth and finding out if anybody else has been pleased with their program that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		right
 		well we don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but we're gonna have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>  thanks so um that's something that i'm probably gonna be looking at
 	
 	
 		oh well congratulations
 		right
 	
 	
 		maybe in the future we haven't quite decided if i'm gonna i'm working part time now and i don't know if i'll be doing that or what we're gonna do but if we do then
 	
 	
 		or staying home
 	
 	
 		i'm gonna need to find somebody and our our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day Out</ENAMEX> program which they started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and we know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> so i would feel very confident with leaving
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's a very good place to start i think um-hum yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day Out</ENAMEX> programs and that's where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon</ENAMEX> had started in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day Out</ENAMEX> program and um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> always have i think a uh pretty good program and
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you have to make sure that you um that you apply pretty early because they do have a lot of places have very long waiting lists and um and another question to ask is if they're um state certified
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um you know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> have um their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s degree in in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> education and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um child</ENAMEX> development um you know what what kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> is is it going to be um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s a little bit older like a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three year old</TIMEX> you'd be more concerned with if there's a type of care that it's torture for them to lay down and take a nap is there like a mandatory nap time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		time uh-huh
 	
 	
 		what they do at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Shannon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is have a video tape going and if and they lay on these little mats and if they fall asleep they kind of let them sleep and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> stays with the sleeping ones and the other ones get up and go do something else so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she doesn't have to necessary take a nap there you know which is which is nice
 	
 	
 		right
 		um-hum um you know it's kind of scary i guess because you hear so many bad things about day cares lately and so it's
 	
 	
 		um
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		i guess it's such a growing concern but then there's a lot of good things you don't hear
 	
 	
 		right and sometimes when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s a lot younger before they're really um before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years old</TIMEX>
 		you know like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is a good program and sometimes you even consider um you know having a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> come to your own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> when they're real little or or something like that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and another consideration is how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are they what's the ratio of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> to to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because that makes a um
 	
 	
 		to children
 		right
 	
 	
 		a difference and if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> would be maybe sleeping in that crib <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX> just your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and or do they just put any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in any crib and you you know you'd want maybe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to have their own sheets all the time and not have another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> use that bed you know but i'm sure that um
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		whatever you decide you'll be happy with and and it's exciting time to have a new one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we're pretty excited to
 	
 	
 		i bet that's that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah that that you know we have been thinking about that but it's a little ways off in the future but um i figure you know i'd probably start asking
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		asking right
 	
 	
 		around at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> because i know that they have a limit as to how old they can be before they you know before you can bring them in
 	
 	
 		some some places um start them as early as i think well some some places take them as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> i guess you know like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight weeks</TIMEX> even
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um there's a place to look into um
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> is was telling about a wonderful new place that opened some place in on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifteenth Street</ENAMEX> up it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> somewhere where
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um nurses</ENAMEX> that used to work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> take care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infants</ENAMEX> and then only up to like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years old</TIMEX> and it's it's supposed to be really a um
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know some places just specialize in just real little ones and then other ones uh are the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it is a difficult situation i think and they're when they're little it's almost easier to leave them because when they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and they're cry
 		
 		
 	