
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay would you like to um begin or would you like me to start
 	
 	
 		uh oh i can start i i think one of the the biggest uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		improvements in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is that finally you're starting to see them get into uh management
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and you're seeing them uh get uh elected to uh political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> uh not near enough i know there's still a long way to go especially in top management
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes i agree
 	
 	
 		you're not seeing uh you know looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> you see them in management but you're not seeing them up there as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VPs</ENAMEX> and i have a sister that's an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma City</ENAMEX> and i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that she was with
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> didn't have have near the positions the levels that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men attorneys</ENAMEX> had and were not uh given the same respect
 	
 	
 		right
 		i agree with that i i think you do see
 		more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> out there in politics too as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayors</ENAMEX> or um you know in in helping to maybe um get some legislation passed to to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> have more rights i think still
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		even with that whole um  thing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> and and um you you still felt like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was the one that you would maybe discredit <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> or something the way they had it
 		the trial and um  i just think that it's it's still gonna take another generation or so before  before the women
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really could really feel that they're really equal in the business world or that they work just as hard or harder  um
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but it's still um
 		going from hm from homemakers into um corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> is still a big step
 	
 	
 		right i also think that uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as homemakers are beginning to get more respect than they used to be it used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would say do you work and
 		you'd say no i work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and it was it was then it was almost like a put down particularly particularly even by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the work force
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i think now i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are realizing that the roles <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> are very very important and it's getting the respect and which is about time
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 
 		i think it's true i think also <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> at a older age so maybe like um you know you go through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and then you maybe work for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> and then you have your first child
 	
 	
 		yes very definitely
 	
 	
 		and um you know you you know both sides of the coin
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you know what it's like and how much work it takes to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> running smoothly and to take care of
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and  and then uh maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are just working and think oh you just stay at home but then when they're in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> and have their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> it's like
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they lose it  they say wow this is harder than i thought well hm  you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		yes and and and to those that have never worked worked and had you know and have stayed home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		kind of does your heart good  because i know i stayed home with <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> and didn't start working until <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> were in high school and uh
 	
 	
 		i know it  i know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you know it it kind of does me good i think also one of the things that that's really tremendous and it doesn't necessarily have to do with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> but the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> are so involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> which again i think helps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s role
 	
 	
 		are so involved yes
 		right right their role has to change to kind of accommodate us too i know i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and my oldest is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and i've pretty much been home um since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> was born
 	
 	
 		you know i
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um just recently i went back to work um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last school semester</TIMEX> to tutor um high school age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> with learning disabilities and i was just out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i thought wow this is really hard only and it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only two days</TIMEX> and i was home before <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> but getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> to day care getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> off to school i still did everything i always do
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> still got up and went to work but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it it only those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> it made a big difference i thought wow a full time i don't think i could swing that
 	
 	
 		well i had to course i work full time but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> were out of town
 	
 	
 		personally
 	
 	
 		so i had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX> during uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football soccer</ENAMEX> season
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		and so i would work and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> would take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but i would have to get them picked up from there get them fed get them to practices get homework done get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX> i was absolutely exhausted and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		picked up
 		dinner
 		right
 		i bet i bet
 	
 	
 		and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> that are waiting until they're in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their late thirties</TIMEX> or early forties to have their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children children</ENAMEX> i think are absolutely crazy
 	
 	
 		well i i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i know i had my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> when i was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> and  that's not considered really young <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> that's almost you know but um i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just starting kindergarten and they're they're forty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> and and then like maybe a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> at home and i think
 		boy i i'm i'm in my thirties
 		
 		
 	