
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hi my name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Donahue</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX> hi i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Randall</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		okay i have a cold this morning so you have to excuse my my sound here um i'm from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX> where are you from
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay that's nice and easy um let's see would you like to to start or would you okay
 	
 	
 		yes
 		sure that'd be just fine we might as well go ahead
 	
 	
 		okay um
 		did you want me to start oh i'm sorry oh i have to start okay well um my oh i did i did push one shall i push it again you think no okay  um my um
 	
 	
 		yeah you have to you have to push the button uh-huh push one
 		did you yet push the button oh okay okay no no that's that's it
 	
 	
 		i love to cross stitch and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who is now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> watch so much sports on TV that lately i have been
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just in a cross stitch frenzy because i cannot stand being in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> with the TV on with all the sports so so much that i have to sit i can sit there as long as i'm cross stitching and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		while i'm doing that so that that's one of my my favorite hobbies that i that i like to what what about you
 	
 	
 		well i do cross stitch also
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		in fact i was just sitting here getting ready to start some things so um i've done it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a number of years</TIMEX> and uh so that is one of my favorite things to do also i find it very relaxing and and so like if i um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		i do too i
 	
 	
 		you know if i haven't done it for a while i like to have a i just like to have a project going um because i think it it's it's just a real good thing to have
 	
 	
 		yes
 		it is i i enjoy it too and i have found a wonderful framer on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifteenth Street</ENAMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Old Plano</ENAMEX> um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two</NUMEX> doors down from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nooks</ENAMEX> and Crannies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um who who does he's really an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> and he does a wonderful wonderful job with i just give him my things and he triple mats everything and he has really nice frames
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think when you it's very satisfying after you do something like that to have it framed and hang it up um it it's always that's kind of the fun part
 	
 	
 		now do you think he's reasonable in terms of prices
 	
 	
 		very reasonable i have brought something to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michaels</ENAMEX> and i was very disappointed in it and it was just a small little picture for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in fact there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little cross stitches i did for her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		apparently <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> framed them differently they <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> took instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> doing doing the framing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did it because the mats were just different sizes and to put them next to each other it just didn't look right and um
 	
 	
 		right uh um-hum
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he is so reasonable that um and he has all these unusual frames that he uses his name is um i guess i can just tell you his name it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Inc</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		and it's um i think the address is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten eleven and a half</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifteenth</ENAMEX> because it's a skinny little door next to i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bows</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		so is it is it so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> and this little skinny door it's right on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifteenth Street</ENAMEX> right down right down by the railroad tracks his name is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i'm glad to know that
 		okay so it's closer to the railroad tracks then from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crannies</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		yes closer to the right down down from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crannies</ENAMEX> and it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Matte M A T T E Inc I N C</ENAMEX> period
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and um he does such a beautiful job i'll take something in i do simple cross stitches mostly samplers and a few that are a little bit more complicated but i don't really um with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> running around it's it's hard for me to get something too intricate
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i like something that's kind of quick and and i love i like doing the samplers i have a whole wall of them and he'll just take this sampler which is just you know mediocre not so great and when he puts the colors he picks out little bits of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		little bits of um colors that he'll pick from your from your work and and matte it with that little color and it just it just makes this wonderful piece of art um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um i'm real real happy with them and they have some really nice books down there have you seen the books in the small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> in um
 	
 	
 		oh yes uh-huh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fifteenth Street</ENAMEX> you know i'm fairly fairly new to the area so i'm always glad to find a nice little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> that has different books but uh
 	
 	
 		i basically i basically  buy most of my things there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crannies</ENAMEX> at that at that store um there used to be a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifteenth</ENAMEX> but it closed and she had fabulous things but
 	
 	
 		do you uh-huh
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's been closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> so really in my now i didn't i in fact i was just there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> but i didn't go across the street i saw that there's a place across the street i didn't go in to that place but i generally buy most of my things in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crannies</ENAMEX> uh-huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you um now i really usually don't get the real expensive linens to work on which uh maybe that's what you do it's probably really really beautiful to do that but i i just get the regular piece of cloth you know and do it on that but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well it depends on what i'm doing i tend to um see i make up most of my own things and and so um
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		in fact i make up almost everything i do now i used to do uh you know kits and all or i'd use books but i i tend not to do that much anymore um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it depends on what i'm doing as to what i use i recently did <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">linen</ENAMEX> and that's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	