
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 		okay
 	
 	
 		what what's your favorite show
 	
 	
 		um hm
 		i like um like
 		shows like um sitcoms i don't like have a favorite i don't watch a lot of TV but i like um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like Full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> it's a cute show
 	
 	
 		yeah i like that one too
 	
 	
 		um
 		and like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Growing Pains</ENAMEX> and
 		just the cute little comedy shows i don't think i really have a favorite um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosbys i</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cosbys</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that's an that's a good show too
 	
 	
 		what else do i watch i watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fresh Prince</ENAMEX>
 		don't like that new one the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Family</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like that one with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redd Foxx</ENAMEX> but then i don't know what they're going to do now
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i don't know
 	
 	
 		because he's gone so wonder what they're going to do about that one
 		uh what is that with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urkel</ENAMEX> on it my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> likes that one
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Matters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i like that one i guess because they're so they're they're funny
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i don't get too serious at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 		if i do i'm i prefer to watch a movie than a series
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because then you miss stuff i mean you know where the movie you can watch as many as it
 		i don't know too many sitcoms and
 		oh i guess i like TV but just nice light comedy i guess that's what you call it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		nothing too serious nothing too bad so
 		
 
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		hum-um i don't like a lot of violence
 	
 	
 		oh me neither
 	
 	
 		so the only time i like violence is in an action packed movie
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but other than that hum-um
 		now oh and i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Trials</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Near</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what was that
 	
 	
 		Trials of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie O'Neil</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		with uh oh goodness she played in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cagney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lacey</ENAMEX> that woman
 	
 	
 		ah
 	
 	
 		she's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX> or something
 		but that's probably the only one i do like
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		i used to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX> and then they went crazy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't really watch that too often
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and then i used to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Knots Landing</ENAMEX> but they got ridiculous
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i don't know i guess since they took all the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off there's really nobody bad on the show
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yes but we got to have a villain
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		if you're gonna watch a series like that like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">JR</ENAMEX> you know  you can't get rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JR</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		without effecting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		sometimes they try too hard  the TV shows
 	
 	
 		yeah and then then it gets like really sick
 		a lot of those stories i used to watch them but i got tired of them because all they do is sleep with everybody's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> that's all the thing is about
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and i don't like that i don't like that idea
 	
 	
 		yeah i used to watch it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Hospital</ENAMEX> that soap
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but yeah and i used to watch that when i worked day when i worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		and then i started when i works started working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> i started watching <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">like Dynasty</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but
 		can only watch so many of them
 		so
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		there's only so much plot they can give i guess
 	
 	
 		right they try to get um your interest by thinking of something really good but it ends up being really stupid nobody likes it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he likes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Channel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah because it's you know it's got all all nice movies on it anyway or little programs which is good
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> should be watching you know shows like that they don't need to see all this violence there's enough violence in real life you know let alone
 	
 	
 		yeah see that's another thing most of the TV programs now that's all it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> movies or something law and i get enough of that watching TV regular news
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't need to sit down and be depressed more
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		because that's about all it does to me is depress me
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i could see that probably does that to a lot of people
 	
 	
 		so i don't know
 		it's okay
 		uh different shows what else you like
 	
 	
 		um
 		hm
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		oh i've  you remember i like like the older um shows like they show only on like you
 		you know the weird <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> that are hardly ever on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um like Happy Days</ENAMEX> was one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> and the Brady Bunch when i was little  i really liked those shows and every
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		
 
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		once in a while i'll be flipping through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> and you'll see a really older rerun or something
 	
 	
 		now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX> was good
 		did you ever watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		now that one i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah me too
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah the black and white show
 	
 	
 		she's hilarious
 		
 		
 	