
 
     		
 	
 		so so what have you seen lately that um you think is worthwhile
 	
 	
 		
  
 		um the last movie i saw was Regarding Regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry</ENAMEX> have you seen that yet
 	
 	
 		no i i saw the previews
 	
 	
 		it's really good i loved it um it's um
 	
 	
 		does does he does it have a happy ending or
 	
 	
 		yeah really good ending um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um it was just it's one of the best movies i've seen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> i generally don't get into movies that much but i saw that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and then before that one i saw um
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Naked Gun Two and a Half</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that was funny wasn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah did you have you seen that one
 	
 	
 		yes and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and</ENAMEX> and the regular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Naked Gun and Airport</ENAMEX> and you know
 	
 	
 		yeah it's exactly like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Airplane One</ENAMEX> and  but it was silly
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right
 		so now these are fairly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> very different movies one one  absolutely slapstick comedy and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> clearly you know serious subject
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i i guess i have similarly broad tastes um my most recent um
 		movie that i that i liked a lot not my most recent movie was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fifth</ENAMEX> i only only rented it you know maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX> and it's been out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> but have you seen that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i haven't seen that yet um-hum
 	
 	
 		well it's it's a it's an adaptation of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> play uh and it is beautifully done um
 		i believe that all the language is is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> read it except it's been shortened a little bit and there might be a word or two changed
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh but it's it's it's a glorious movie  um and i like as you know these these these  silly silly movies
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and i also like just some strange strange movies do you do you have any
 	
 	
 		such as
 	
 	
 		well the the one that comes immediately to mind i um is <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Cook the Thief His Wife Her Lover</ENAMEX>
 		um  but there also these various um
 		but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX> movies um i got i got hooked on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> that made me go out and watch every <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Lynch</ENAMEX> movie i could lay my hands on
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh really i haven't seen any of those
 	
 	
 		oh um well i don't i don't especially recommend i mean  you have you have to just sort of like this though you have to like did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're really good
 		huh-uh no
 	
 	
 		no so okay so if you weren't if you weren't drawn to watch that you maybe wouldn't be drawn to these movies either
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're they're just strange yeah
 	
 	
 		are they i mean is it
 		like mystery or
 	
 	
 		oh well it
 	
 	
 		suspense or
 	
 	
 		i think suspense is the right word um and and but but little bit strange and esoteric and um
 		
 
 		in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> a little bit there's some elements of the supernatural in it too
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		that that was the television show
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		um
 		there's also a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of of movies in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> called um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Walters</ENAMEX>
 		who who puts puts out even weirder movies
 		he uh his most recent ones have actually been fairly fairly mainstream like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hairspray</ENAMEX>
 		um but back in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early days</TIMEX> he he he had things um
 		um
 		what are what are the titles i can't remember the titles anymore but but some really weird ones uh with
 		quite a random <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> um it would've made you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fellini</ENAMEX> movies look normal
 	
 	
 		right so do you like um movies a lot see i don't do i don't
 	
 	
 		i i do i do like movies a lot
 	
 	
 		really see i don't do that i don't go to movies that often but just recently i've been to a couple
 	
 	
 		do do you rent them or
 	
 	
 		um no we i just go to like the dollar movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> around here generally but i don't know i just i usually fall asleep or  i get bored pretty easily so
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> does too um i mean she falls asleep  so we have to we have to pick just the right kind of movie to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">to to to</NUMEX> to appeal
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		right
 		that's exactly how
 	
 	
 		well well it was good talking to you
 	
 	
 		yeah it's good to talk to you too
 	
 	
 		take care uh-huh okay bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh bye-bye</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	