
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay you don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no we were never blessed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um we had a foster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> for a while and we're real active
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> with some of the young people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i hear i heard one of yours
 	
 	
 		oh yes yes we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>  and they range in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ages</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> until the youngest is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		so you have a considerable range of of interests and activities and so forth
 	
 	
 		right we do and when they were speaking about some of the activities that you like to participate in as a family one of our very favorite is reading we love to read read with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and to them and
 		and so far they've been they've grown up with a love for reading too and we're very glad about that
 	
 	
 		that's terrific you know that's not i've i've observed that that's not done enough these year these days
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		when we had our foster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he was um
 		uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and a half</NUMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that year</TIMEX> in there and we read every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> because we just felt like that was important to spend time
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		with him there's so little time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-on-one</NUMEX> time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> with mechanical or or the electronic uh games and and TV and so forth to draw <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> away
 	
 	
 		boy i'll say
 		right
 		boy i'll say that's right my with our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> where with all of them we start right from the time they were born and and spent time reading with them and
 		and they seem they enjoy it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will get the books and bring to us and say you know let's read a book
 	
 	
 		did they have them memorized and and know if you're skipping a page
 	
 	
 		uh yeah they do they do did you experience that too
 	
 	
 		yes it it on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> when it was already really late and i'd try to short circuit it it was no no no
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX>  and they catch on pretty quick  you mentioned TV watching
 		watching too much TV and i i feel that's a real big problem also i i think that there's just too much of that it's used too much as a babysitter and
 		and
 	
 	
 		i totally agree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just plop the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> down in front of it and
 	
 	
 		now there are some wonderful programs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and when i had our foster <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> i was babysitting i had
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> under the age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and we ended up using television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> times a day when <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX> was on
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to entertain them but also to do some learning things and then we re-enforced that then with with some of the things that we were involved in if i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> and and so forth the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> wanted to emulate everything i did
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and so and we talked about the letters and numbers and so <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> so we used it as a tool
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		but not
 		i won't say i was perfect it wasn't ever used as a babysitter while i was busy with one of the others but
 	
 	
 		oh that's right
 		that's right and then i can't say say that either but then like you say there's some good shows on it and there's some good videos also that you can rent that are
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know real helpful and  um we also like to play with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i one of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our other favorite things to do is to have
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pillow</ENAMEX> fights with them  and they really enjoy that they laugh and you know it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> here and it's hard to get outside and do a lot of
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		lot of outdoor physical type things and so
 	
 	
 		i hadn't thought about that
 	
 	
 		yeah so we we do pillow fights and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">um course</ENAMEX> just play with them play games and
 		um when you were growing up did you spend time did your family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> or or what other activities
 	
 	
 		we did we went camping and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> and i did that all through our our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> together too so it was something that carried over from both our backgrounds and into into our current life
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		your your pillow fights reminded me though that when when i was growing up um uh we we spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> and then we went from there to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and and it was even further north
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		boy i'll bet
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> used to roughhouse in the winter time with us we'd get on the floor and just you know play play play tickle games and and and hug and cuddle and that was important to do that bonding and i never thought of that till you mentioned the pillow fights
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh it is oh
 	
 	
 		but we'd get everybody involved in that well it was just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and i and we thoroughly enjoyed that that time spent with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> that we didn't get to see him very much at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		boy i'll say i'll say you do and and i think like you say the bonding and the physical you know loving and touching that's that's very important i feel like so um
 	
 	
 		do you have outside the home activities that that you do with the the family
 	
 	
 		yes we do we well like i say we the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> we live in it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> a lot of time  so we go sleigh riding and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> love that they love there's
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 	
 	
 		several hills close by that we that are kind of designated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sleigh</ENAMEX> riding hills and and we take the tubes you know the tubes and toboggans and
 		and go and do that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> um oh bike riding and
 		we go well we've we've each got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> with the little one we haven't done it this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> as much because she's just so so tiny that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we didn't get a chance but um we've got the swings and had a trampoline
 		
 		
 	