
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay what do you think of the public school system <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> off do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are in it
 	
 	
 		i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that are in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano Public School</ENAMEX> systems and i am a substitute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> at this point looking for a full-time job in the public school system  so
 	
 	
 		oh okay well then you should be a good one to know because i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are grown now i now have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> in the school system so uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i don't have first had experience right now with it so what do you think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i think the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> are doing a good job i think they have a long way to go yet but i think that um
 		they are starting to head towards more technology
 		and getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> computer literate earlier you know my kindergartners were on the were on the computers and i think that with the way the world is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that's got to be done
 		and i think that uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> now are starting to teach thinking strategies more than just giving them you know
 		skills you know you don't just add <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> plus <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> you figure out why you're adding it and what you're going to do with it once you've got it together and i think that that's something that is drastically needed because most of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> cannot think they literally cannot come in out of the rain
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you you know and that just i don't care how intelligent you are if you be cannot make it function for you that intelligence is being wasted
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh this has been one of my pet <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">peeves</ENAMEX> and probably why i went into education
 	
 	
 		correct
 	
 	
 		so i think you know they're they're trying to head into into teaching them to think and use the education that they have and i think that's very very important
 	
 	
 		yes it is i i agree with you that they're starting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so much earlier on things because
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> we have a uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grader</ENAMEX> and then we have one that's in kindergartner and and i know the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grader
 		is doing stuff that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> was doing were doing in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it's amazing to me and stuff that i didn't do until i was in junior high which of course shows my age
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah uh i tutor a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> that's in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> grade and her pre-algebra book is higher then some of my algebra <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> when i was in high school and it's like oh i going to take this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and study it before i can help you
 	
 	
 		that's kind of scary
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know so they're really they're really moving them along but yet  at the same time you know they are stopping and making them use it and function with it like they would need to do in everyday life
 		and that's what you know a lot of the things that we did in school i've never used and never will use
 	
 	
 		now
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh so i think that it's it's appropriate to teach them you know why they are learning this not just because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> says you have to learn this
 	
 	
 		correct are you finding that uh since you're doing substitute that you're wanting to do full-time um
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> that one of her complaints is she can't teach because she's so busy filling out all the forms
 	
 	
 		yes that's a
 	
 	
 		and and do are you do you find that
 	
 	
 		well filling out the forms and also all of these uh statewide and national wide testing things so that they compare and say you know you can as far as i'm concerned
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you can make a survey or test scores say anything you want it to say
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's just a matter of how you're going to interpret it
 		and you waste so much time
 		quote unquote teaching to the test to make sure that your scores are the very best they're possibly going to be you know that
 	
 	
 		be um-hum
 	
 	
 		i think it's uh i think it's crazy personally you know the first the whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first nine weeks</TIMEX> of school is is used
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		as a review but more than a review they're getting those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> primed and ready for the tests that are coming up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> so that you know your school district shines throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that's totally useless i think you know there's a place and a time for all of the tests and comparisons but i think they've taken it to the extent now that it's just ridiculous it's like bragging on your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and everybody's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that have ever hit this <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> and nobody else's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are going to ever live up to those and that's great but that's what they're doing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> and they're wasting too much time on that i think
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i i know that this again this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> uh is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano School District</ENAMEX> and she teaches uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it must uh emotionally disturbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and she says she has some <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> in there that are reading on the level of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and she says she's getting very frustrated and very depressed because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> is pressuring her to pass them on even though they're not ready but because evidently you receive a certain amount of money
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		when they're passed on or something i didn't quite understand it
 	
 	
 		yeah there's not yeah the bottom line line is always money
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		
 		
 	