
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Kate</ENAMEX> what kind of uh where do you like to eat out
 	
 	
 		well we uh we really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food you know here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and uh so we try and go around to different <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> trying them out
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and so uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tia's</ENAMEX> is probably our favorite uh restaurant there and i think they have the one of the best services that uh that we really like it
 	
 	
 		do you have you tried <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Mesquite</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		no where's that at
 	
 	
 		that's at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skillman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LBJ</ENAMEX> there is uh it's where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skillman</ENAMEX> uh curves into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Forest Lane</ENAMEX> and it's real good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food a another real good one is uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raphael</ENAMEX>'s down on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> Avenue
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they're both very good um-hum
 	
 	
 		really oh that uh no we haven't explored uh you know too many places um you know
 		a lot of the big name brand i guess uh chains uh yeah but um oh we've tried places you know down uh by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Collin Creek Mall</ENAMEX> the uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> and um gosh we tried what was across the street
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">chains uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Paso</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Chico</ENAMEX>'s or something yeah something something like that uh-huh uh-huh yeah
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Chico</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Phoenix</ENAMEX> one um-hum um-hum um-hum well i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tia</ENAMEX>'s better than i do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Chico</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">El Phoenix</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		uh much better uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Mesquite's</ENAMEX> is one of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> but then <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fajitas</ENAMEX> are one of my uh
 		i like it better than just about anything and they make very good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fajitas</ENAMEX> there in their own uh homemade flour tortillas that are just absolutely wonderful especially with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX> on them
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 		yes
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh oh i know i tell i tell you what they they are they just um they're excellent uh excellent food i wish i could make them here at home
 	
 	
 		yes yes so do i  well what else do you like
 	
 	
 		just can't make those flour tortillas but
 		well i love uh i love <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> and i notice they have like the you know The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana Purchase</ENAMEX> um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Razzoo's</ENAMEX> has opened up down you know off of um um  oh close to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">635</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes now i haven't eaten there have you eaten there
 	
 	
 		yes i have eaten there now the only problem i love the food it's a lot of cajun food and a good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> but uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> has always been so strange every time i've been in there mostly it's been at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">lunch time</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh but i hear at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> though they have uh you know the outdoor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">um bar</ENAMEX> and um uh that's it's really uh you know kind of lively so it's it's really good all their blackened grilled stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i we like uh uh for the cajun the spicy we like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atchafalaya</ENAMEX>'s out on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beltline</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> and it's a good restaurant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well that sounds great
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> for one of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is either <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent</ENAMEX>'s there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> or uh  i believe it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Rusty Scupper</ENAMEX> over on uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Dallas Parkway</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Addison</ENAMEX> which is absolutely wonderful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the service is great they have every kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> that that you could imagine you'd want and the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the atmosphere is wonderful too if you want <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX> special <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> out and fish <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> that's a good place to go
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh  well i uh i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and and work and so we uh we tend to eat a lot of fast food stuff  uh-huh
 	
 	
 		fast food oh i can understand that i can remember when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were small we lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> area at the time and we had a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> when they were first coming out i can't look a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald</ENAMEX> in the face now
 	
 	
 		yeah i know i
 		i know i i'm so sick of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> we we used to eat there we used to eat there all the time and so now we we we branch out at this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendy's</ENAMEX> or some other fast food joint
 	
 	
 		i know
 		yeah  yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taco Bueno</ENAMEX>'s good  and cheap and cheap very cheap
 	
 	
 		oh and and cheap too so yeah but but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know they they've got those expensive tastes so uh they like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tia</ENAMEX>'s so they can sit down and all that good kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		yes yes yes sounds like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i know they they they're just spoiled rotten but uh but no i uh uh we love to eat out of course it's just so much easier and simpler yeah so we uh we usually eat out generally <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times a week
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh yes
 		well it's just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i and it's either TV dinners at home or we go out to eat and i would much rather go out to eat than TV dinners
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		oh oh me too me too so i know uh i i know that i uh you know i just work and i'm just tired when i get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and i i just don't feel like cooking
 	
 	
 		oh no no
 	
 	
 		and uh you know on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> there's always things to do and uh so we like to go out to lunch on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> especially
 	
 	
 		i like breakfast out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IHOP</ENAMEX> there in Plano
 	
 	
 		yeah now i we've been there twice and and both times i just oh the food just didn't quite settle with me and i don't know what it was
 	
 	
 		oh really oh now that's surprising
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because normally they're just they're real good and i like because they they're even if they're crowded they're fast service you know i i don't have to wait <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">forever</TIMEX> for a table
 	
 	
 		yes and i love
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and we also like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owens</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		oh family restaurant uh-huh
 	
 	
 		country sausage yeah yeah we think it's good
 	
 	
 		now i haven't been there before i went to one i think in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> or or or somewhere up there but i've never been to that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> here i know it's just down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> so now have you been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applebee</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		um-hum it's good
 		yes yes and we like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Applebee</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		yes yes i i really like that too so that was uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it it's fun i like your up there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Country Steak House</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i've been i've been there twice uh-huh yeah so
 	
 	
 		have you tried it
 		we like it because it's fairly reasonable and they have we go for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> bar
 	
 	
 		salad bar yeah
 		
 		
 	