
 
     		
 	
 		i was gonna say my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern State University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aberdeen South Dakota</ENAMEX> and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Miller</ENAMEX> used to be an assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> at BYU
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so i thought that was kind of an interesting interesting coincidence
 	
 	
 		huh  so you went to what college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Northern State University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Aberdeen South Dakota</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what did you graduate in
 	
 	
 		i just in what major or what year
 	
 	
 		yeah major
 	
 	
 		uh international business
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and you
 	
 	
 		i'm going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> and i'm going into nursing
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well that sounds interesting ah how long of a program is that
 	
 	
 		forever  seems like anyways it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but it's probably gonna take me longer because i didn't decide to major in that until  uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year and a half</TIMEX> after i was already in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		you know i read a study once and it said that uh
 		like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty four</TIMEX> percent
 		of uh college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> actually graduate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a four year</TIMEX> program
 	
 	
 		oh really that sounds
 	
 	
 		it took me it took me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 		you know you just you get started and and you change your mind or you wanna pick up a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> major if you're management you you you decide i'll i'll take that marketing it's just what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> more classes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and it it just just doesn't happen that you get out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		so what is your advice to
 	
 	
 		my advice is is uh
 	
 	
 		picking a college
 	
 	
 		look for at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> ratio
 		you know if you're gonna go to a college where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student faculty</ENAMEX> ratio is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and four hundred</NUMEX> to one
 		i don't think you're gonna have as meaningful of of a college experience as if you're down to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> to one
 	
 	
 		um-hum is that what was yours more like
 	
 	
 		yeah ours was about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty six</TIMEX> to one
 	
 	
 		
 
 		really oh that's great
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		which is you know it it's interesting but it it's what i thought was nice is you could always there was always time to talk to professor
 		you know and and they knew you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you weren't just in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> you know and
 		so you could you could go talk to them in their office <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> at any time and or if you ran into them in the student <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> or whatever
 		you know you could sit down and talk to them about a problem they were always willing to help you out so
 		but our house
 		i i
 		put that against uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> where we had uh a biology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred and fifty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		wow in high school
 	
 	
 		yeah it was a biology lecture class
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and you know it it
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		it just wasn't the same you're sitting there and you're taking notes and
 		you know you got a computerized test scores with multiple choice because there's no way they could correct a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred fifty</NUMEX> point short answer test or you know a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred and three hundred and fifty</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> short answer test
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it just wasn't the same you you'd run you'd pass the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> in high school you know and even in high school you could say hi to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and
 		unless you're in that biology <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> and they just you know they'd look at you like do i know you or should i know you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah there's it's
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> here are pretty big so it's hard to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> help  it's kind of you're on your own
 	
 	
 		do you get uh a lot of tutoring or
 	
 	
 		no  very little i mean well like my for example i have i'm in a chemistry class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and there's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> in it and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TA</ENAMEX> for the whole class
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and he only has certain office <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> and
 		so there's only certain times you can talk to him and
 	
 	
 		and you could get there and his office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">hours</TIMEX> could i mean he could have like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning office hours</TIMEX> and have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> waiting to talk to him and you still wouldn't get to talk to him anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well what would be your advice to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> thinking of attending college
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i think your advice is good um let's see
 		
 
 		my advice would be to pick a major before you get into college
 	
 	
 		that's excellent advice
 	
 	
 		because i i didn't and i took ton of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> that i didn't need to and um i don't know i just feel like i'm
 		it's it's gonna take me a lot longer than and not that's always bad but it's i don't know it's frustrating i guess
 	
 	
 		well it it it does get it you know you get to the point where it's
 		i'm never gonna get done
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i i mean i was taking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> classes and
 		finally i said let me get out of here
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		but uh no that's good advice even if you don't have your major decided on have an idea of what you think you might want you know  so you don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> but you think you want business
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	