
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		last the last time i had one of these conversations i you know discovered that i
 		my tastes and and and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> were very different uh
 	
 	
 		oh well that's good
 	
 	
 		uh i  my my own uh
 	
 	
 		so where do you like to dine out
 	
 	
 		um  well sort of yuppie places i guess is probably the best way to describe them um places that are  comfortable and have sort of unusual different foods
 	
 	
 		oh i see well i like the atmosphere myself
 	
 	
 		um where where what do you find particularly good atmospherewise
 	
 	
 		well i like i like let's see well it depends on the mood i'm in also sometimes i like to go where there's quiet music and there's a piano <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> and so that we can visit or there's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		other times when i like when there's real exciting and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">place</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> where there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> on a trapeze and she
 		she goes back and forth over the bar
 	
 	
 		well that sounds different  i'd seen things like that in movies but it don't recall having ever been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> ever even close to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> where that was an option
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh well that's that's called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old San Francisco Steak House</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and she uh swings back and forth over the bar
 		it's very interesting
 	
 	
 		oh
 		uh the
 	
 	
 		she tries the ceiling is i don't know how high it is but she touches the ceiling with her toes and then her
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's kind of interesting
 	
 	
 		that that sure is now can i top that can i even come close
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		gee
 	
 	
 		but uh so you like different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		sure enough um
 	
 	
 		what kind what kind
 	
 	
 		uh what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> it's been <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> food <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days in a row</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh gee
 	
 	
 		um but normally not so  not so not so concentrated um
 		um southwestern cuisine um
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deli</ENAMEX> kinds of stuff uh you know it covers covers you know quite a range i mean the the only things i find difficulty with is is these these raw fish things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yes i can't eat that either i do like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> though we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red Lobsters</ENAMEX> out here
 	
 	
 		uh
 		how do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red Lobsters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in the middle of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i eat there quite often
 		how do we have them
 	
 	
 		yeah i would have thought they would've come out of out of the water somewhere
 	
 	
 		they're all over
 	
 	
 		crawling around on the on the
 	
 	
 		no no i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Red Lobster</ENAMEX> that's the name of the restaurant
 	
 	
 		around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 		oh oh oh i'm sorry oh i'm sorry i thought you were talking about a kind of food like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Red Lobster</ENAMEX> yes them the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> yes thank you never mind
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm talking about the restaurant
 		
 
 		what makes you go back to the same place is it the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		well it's it's um
 		it's a combination of a lot of things i mean there's sort of a value quotient i mean i i
 		you know there's no absolute dollar limit that you know is either okay or not okay but it's it's more like gee this is a really good you know you got a lot for your money either quantity or quality or interest or
 	
 	
 		oh and the service too
 	
 	
 		and service and um
 	
 	
 		right the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> means a lot to me
 	
 	
 		yes
 		um
 	
 	
 		a lot
 	
 	
 		do you prefer to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men men</ENAMEX> or womens as servers
 	
 	
 		i really prefer a man
 	
 	
 		um-hum why is that
 	
 	
 		i just i feel that they're more efficient and they
 		they just seems like they just have it uh more together
 		you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> and you won't see any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> servers
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> servers down there
 	
 	
 		yeah i've never been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> what how how how are the how is the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> compared to what we find in
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well oh how's the food different there than up here
 	
 	
 		yeah compared to what we have in this country
 	
 	
 		well it's much spicier
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and it's um it's just prepared a little bit different but it's uh it has a different flavor to it
 		and the service is good because the because they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> servers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh what do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men  waiters</ENAMEX> or women
 	
 	
 		i i i think i probably have a slight preference for for male servers but but not very great
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		um
 		you know it's the the quality of service is is important and it and it's and it's i don't think that that's i don't correlate that with genders
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i think i think it really it might actually just be that you know some some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> employ <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> than another
 		it may just be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> i go to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i just i feel like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> have it more together than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> they just i've waited on tables myself and i just could never seem to organized like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> were
 	
 	
 		how how did you like being a waiter or waitress
 	
 	
 		it's a lot of hard work
 	
 	
 		that's that's what my impression is
 	
 	
 		a lot of hard work
 	
 	
 		and and and being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chauffeur</ENAMEX> that isn't also hard work
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chauffeur</ENAMEX> yeah really hard to please people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just like waiting on tables you just can't whatever you do sometimes you just can't please them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah is this is this one of these limo services where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and want to be driven around and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	