
 
     		
 	
 		oh now we can talk about that great team
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i think we know where we're heading well
 		uh well i just heard i guess uh
 		big problem right now on the other side <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duke</ENAMEX>'s trying to sign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra</ENAMEX> you know but  apparently he's gonna sign for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> is what they're saying
 	
 	
 		you you think he's worth it
 		who could be worth that huh
 	
 	
 		well
 		i mean i don't know i think i think i'm worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty five million</NUMEX> if he is but uh uh
 		as far as
 		i mean if they're going to pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four and a half</NUMEX> million i mean yeah he's definitely worth it just because i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ryan</ENAMEX>'s only got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple good years</TIMEX> left in it where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra</ENAMEX>'s got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least another ten or fifteen years</TIMEX> but
 		i mean yeah that
 	
 	
 		i i think they'd be better off trading him off for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two million and a half</NUMEX> dollar a year <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX> they can win some twelve games each
 	
 	
 		well uh the problem is you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom House</ENAMEX> who is going to he'll blow their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> out i mean
 	
 	
 		that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra</ENAMEX> i mean those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX>
 		you got a uh they've got to resign them just to keep the credibility of this franchise i mean because if they don't resign them i mean that's pretty much going to be the last straw they've kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine Valentine</ENAMEX> way too long
 	
 	
 		i think you're right i i think that as long as they they keep that uh management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i don't think there is going to be a winner i agree with you
 	
 	
 		and it's you know i don't think i mean he's even said he he you know that probably will not not sign for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as much as</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bonilla</ENAMEX> did but i mean
 		because apparently he's he uh he's real into <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um Arabian horses</ENAMEX> and one of the minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> is a big time uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Arabian horse</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> or whatever and he's i guess there has been some he'd want he wants to stay out here and get some land and develop that because
 		i was listening to a show <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> apparently he he doesn't want to he doesn't really have the stomach to go into a large market and have to prove himself all over again but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		he's got it made if he just stays there so he'll probably stay and
 	
 	
 		well i'd stay for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five million</NUMEX> bucks a year
 	
 	
 		oh i'll stay for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million</NUMEX> but
 	
 	
 		they could twist my arm
 	
 	
 		you know if if somebody that's going to pay it i mean you might as well i you know can't blame him for taking it i mean that's
 	
 	
 		well uh well i i i don't either i i think uh you know the the whole
 		pro sports have gotten out of control and watch watch a game on TV they got so many ads to pay for the thing if i can fall asleep during a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game wake up and not have missed a missed a down for crying out
 	
 	
 		oh exactly
 	
 	
 		and that's the way <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>'s going turn into it is they they have gone up to uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seconds</TIMEX> between innings instead of a minute and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they keep escalating the salaries as they are i think they're going to wind up with as much you know advertising as they do uh playing ball and uh it's going to eventually kill the golden <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goose</ENAMEX> i i think i
 	
 	
 		i don't even think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s pastime anymore i think football  took it over i mean i was a big baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> when i was younger but
 		i still follow it and everything but it's just
 	
 	
 		oh i i enjoy i enjoy them both i
 	
 	
 		there's just
 	
 	
 		i uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refereed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> for forty yeah for forty
 	
 	
 		yeah it's the only thing going in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> but football is definitely a little bit more exciting right now but i mean you know
 	
 	
 		well i think uh amateur you know high school and college is a lot more enjoyable to watch than uh you know football than than the pros
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i agree
 	
 	
 		they're just sitting around i last <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Cowboy</ENAMEX> game i went to they were sitting around uh between plays so long uh i don't see how they can break a sweat for heaven sakes you know just waiting on edge
 	
 	
 		yeah that's one thing that's
 	
 	
 		and uh it it's too bad so
 	
 	
 		yeah the worst is when they they kick the ball off after uh when it's a commercial after they score a touchdown
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah then they got then they got another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> more commercials
 	
 	
 		then then they kick it off
 		then the commercial after that they bring them you know that's that's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> commercial i think they need to eliminate
 	
 	
 		yep but they won't they they want the money you know the
 	
 	
 		yeah someone's got to pay for it but
 	
 	
 		yeah they're they're greedy and they you know they all admit it's a business and that's what comes first and that's probably what the
 		is is a major problem with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> they make money and they don't uh as long as they make money
 		and are respectable they don't make a you know they aren't going to pay the bucks out to be a winner and lose money and that's apparently what it takes  what it what what it's taking right now
 	
 	
 		well i think they're just hoping something happens to them like happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> which is a fluke i thought anyway
 	
 	
 		tell you what i got i got to keep talking to you but i think this is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> calling on this line so we're we're we're probably almost done but hang on just
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		okay uh you got another call
 	
 	
 		good did you get
 		uh well that's that's okay hang on a minute <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> okay just a second   we'll finish this off here
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i've been waiting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five days</TIMEX> for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so he can wait <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple seconds</TIMEX> here  that's uh but anyway i i think we've probably got a
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		situation that we aren't going to see a winner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> but
 		as long as
 	
 	
 		well i i just i mean  i've been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> since i guess the uh middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seventies</ENAMEX> and uh it's just been the same thing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> i don't expect anything and
 		
 
 		i mean with the lineup they have
 		
 		
 	