
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what uh what kind of recycling have you got in your community
 	
 	
 		well in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> we recycle everything
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		oh yeah we recycle plastic we recycle aluminum we recycle paper we recycle everything
 	
 	
 		well now do you participate in all of that
 	
 	
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> does i'm not real high on it myself how about
 	
 	
 		well i think i think that's great that she does that i i'll applaud that um
 	
 	
 		do you do that
 	
 	
 		no and i i as a matter of fact i kind of cringed a little bit whenever i heard the topic because i think it's admirable and i think it's something that eventually we're we're all going to have to do it
 		uh i don't but i know the
 	
 	
 		do you realize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen</ENAMEX> that the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forbes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> pointed out that it actually costs more to recycle than it does not to recycle
 	
 	
 		uh in costs more in what way
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> for example for recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> to get rid of the ink it costs about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two</TIMEX> percent more to recycle paper than it does to have new paper
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting and i've you know i wouldn't i i mean i hadn't heard that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> and that's that's a little surprising but you know i think about the amount of of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> that i throw away in a week
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know you multiply that with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> that are that are tossing out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and it
 		i remember i i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> and i took the wrong turn and i went over into uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">State Island</ENAMEX> where the uh uh landfill is for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and of course that's not where i wanted to be so i turned around and beat it by hasty retreat but you know just the the amount of garbage that we generate uh is is staggering and i just i don't know how much longer we can continue to just dump everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it's uh it's a problem that uh is probably at the moment over emphasized because there is
 		apparently more landfill available than it's a matter of economics and economically right now uh it's more of a scare tactic it appears that we are running out of things and the facts
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in some cases are particularly paper which trees obviously by being a renewable resource and being a crop no more different than <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> in effect
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's a situation that
 		of economics where it's less expensive to have new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> than using and recycling old paper
 	
 	
 		yeah and i can i can understand that i think i think about uh you know and they say that now uh a lot of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> for instance i read an article not long ago about this uh uh new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> that they had come out
 		that they're identifying on the car those uh particular different parts uh uh that are plastic so that that whenever the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> is worn out and dismantled uh they can recycle the the plastic components
 	
 	
 		right
 		those are uh plastic is very recyclable and uh it should be
 		uh
 		that's something that just won't go away when you dispose of it and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> and and your metals are very worthwhile being recycles it's uh
 	
 	
 		it's just a matter right now of who's going to take the time uh to do it and i i mean it's something that i personally feel is it it's worthwhile i just uh
 		i haven't gotten into it and uh i i think i'm probably like a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in that uh until it gets to the point that it's kind of mandated
 		uh i don't think i'm i'm going to do it unfortunately i know
 	
 	
 		what what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> do you live in
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well in i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> and uh they have a very big recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> where uh
 		for your grass clippings for example if you don't put them in a paper sack they won't pick them up they have special pick up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> for for uh leaves and debris uh you know
 		clippings type thing and if you put it in a plastic one they won't pick it up yeah
 	
 	
 		really i saw an article i mean a a program on a TBS not too long ago that uh  they were talking about uh recycling and they uh
 		were showing  uh in a city i think it was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Portland Oregon</ENAMEX> if i remember it was either but it it was either in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX> and of course you know those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> up there are very uh uh environmentally conscious
 		and they were uh talking about the the recycling effort up there and how they've got uh uh all these different bins and containers and
 	
 	
 		that's what they're coming out with here matter of fact
 	
 	
 		really yeah
 	
 	
 		i haven't received ours yet but uh that's the plan in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> also they uh bring out these humpty  bins and you're supposed to fill it up with
 	
 	
 		i know  and you know and i'll tell you when you you know and i've been accustomed all my life to throwing everything in one bag and then uh dumping it in the dumpster it's going to be a rude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">awakening</ENAMEX> to have to uh start sorting everything
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i i frankly
 		
 		
 	