
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		did they mention our topic
 	
 	
 		yes  vacation spots
 	
 	
 		okay
 		right anything anything in the area of types of vacations you've been on lately you've really enjoyed
 	
 	
 		well i  i guess probably my favorite thing to do is to go to the beach um and my most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite</ENAMEX> place to do that is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX>
 		uh i love <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> very much but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past summer</TIMEX> we went to um  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulf Shores Alabama</ENAMEX> and had a great time there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the beach was beautiful and and that was really uh a nice place to go so that's  that's probably one of my most favorite places to go how about you
 	
 	
 		well i'm a lot the same way we uh i was raised
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX> but also <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and i spent an awful a lot of time on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia Beach</ENAMEX> area and i sort of love the water i've always loved the ocean
 		so i enjoy going to the beaches myself as far as a favorite beach
 		um probably <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX> is as as more of a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i haven't been there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i'd like to go back and see how it has changed but i enjoy
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX> i enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Padre Island</ENAMEX> right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> but i enjoy pretty much any beaches
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i've i've heard that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Myrtle Beach</ENAMEX> is wonderful i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who think that that's the best place in the world i've i've never been myself but uh you know i've heard that it's a wonderful place to go
 	
 	
 		well i haven't been right haven't been for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX> myself but
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of these days i'll go back and see how nice it is i'm sure it's just as nice as ever as a as a high schooler and a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> it was a great place to go it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the big weekend</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">place</ENAMEX> and things like that especially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> the place to go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> to get a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure
 	
 	
 		you know a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> job and to spend your dollars and uh have fun and everything
 	
 	
 		sure well also one of my i was thinking another one of my favorite places is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>
 		uh have you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe New Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		well it's wonderful
 	
 	
 		oh i'll bet it is
 	
 	
 		yeah it really is a beautiful place and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two</TIMEX> falls i've gone there i've made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> it's sort of becoming an annual thing for me uh i go by myself i go without my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and uh if
 	
 	
 		what do you do
 	
 	
 		uh pardon
 	
 	
 		what do you do while you're there
 	
 	
 		well  i basically uh
 		i love to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> there are wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> it's a real uh it's just a wonderful area and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX> i went to a fabulous uh monastery
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh that's out in the desert uh out in the hills of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe i</ENAMEX> also went to one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pueblos</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX> and that was just wonderful
 	
 	
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> would probably enjoy i mean enjoy we'd probably enjoy that also are you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm not
 	
 	
 		okay we're we're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> so we'd we'd definitely definitely enjoy all the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you'd really enjoy it then
 		well you would love it because i have a very great appreciation for uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> and all the ones i visit are <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX>  that i went to is a little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">place town</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tamayo</ENAMEX> it's out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Fe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they have there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sanctuary</ENAMEX> there there was supposed to be some uh miracle healing that occurred there
 		and it is just a fabulous place i i  i just love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamayo</ENAMEX> and it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about thirty minutes</TIMEX> north of of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Fe</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh no kidding we'll have to maybe give that a try sometime
 	
 	
 		well i'd highly recommend it particularly if you're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> i think you'd have a great appreciation for it
 	
 	
 		if you're a a water <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> still says the best vacation we ever went on with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> was
 		we went to one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Tarr Villages</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> and we went to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> located at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto</ENAMEX> Plata
 	
 	
 		did you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Puerto</ENAMEX> Plata
 	
 	
 		and you know that's the most reasonable vacation we were ever on we just opened the paper <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one morning</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or five years ago</TIMEX> and it said round trip all included <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days</TIMEX> hotel food all you could drink just every party everything it was almost like a cruise
 	
 	
 		ah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five ninety nine</NUMEX> so we said let's do it so we packed up everyone <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of us plus my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> we all went
 		and it's probably not like i said not only the most reasonable vacation we were ever on and everything was paid for it was just glorious i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> was fantastic you get they had pools they had beaches
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were so courteous the lodging was fantastic the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was just like being on a cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baked Alaska</ENAMEX> right on down and all this for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five hundred and ninety nine</NUMEX> dollars it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i mean that's unbelievable the price
 	
 	
 		oh it is unbelievable and we keep saying that one of these days our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are getting older now they're in college and uh be getting married and whatever so we doubt we'll ever have the opportunity to go back with our with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but but we're certainly going back but
 	
 	
 		with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's probably <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place that we really enjoyed
 	
 	
 		now that didn't include your airfare did it
 	
 	
 		that included everything airfare lodging every meal i mean if you were a heavy drinker you could sit there and drink <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five or thirty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drinks</ENAMEX> a day or whatever you wanted i mean just it was everything
 	
 	
 		gosh
 		good grief
 	
 	
 		and it was just a a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> type of surrounding very
 		tropical just uh entertainment <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX> i don't know if you've ever been a cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> or not but it was exactly like being on a cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've been on a cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we were on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> cruises and uh
 		
 		
 	