
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		camping um i've been to several different kinds of camping when i i've been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> camp where we slept you know in tents and there were a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and cooked over the fire and i've also
 		uh been camping in a camper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> or or on a uh with a truck and a and a camper um when i was younger
 		i really enjoyed going in the in the the trailer
 		i didn't realize until i was older how much  how much work there was involved for the for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of the camping
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um are you have what kind of camping have you participated in
 	
 	
 		uh i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scout leader</ENAMEX> so we we go camping every month
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know just you know tent camping of
 		i never really camped in you know in a motor home or a trailer
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's always been in a tent
 	
 	
 		so when you go do you go to to designated camping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> or just up in the mountains or
 	
 	
 		just no no the the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scouts</ENAMEX> have their own you know ranches
 	
 	
 		well no mountains there
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that they own and they've got park <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rangers</ENAMEX> that run them
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and that you know they've got campsites set up and latrines and water and all for the boys
 	
 	
 		oh so you you don't really have to rough it too bad huh
 	
 	
 		no we we bring our own cooking gear you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> split them up in patrols and they cook their own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh do you do you cook over an open fire or do you have the little camp stoves
 	
 	
 		uh we
 		we usually cook over an open fire we've we've got camp stoves in you know in case it's if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wood</ENAMEX> is too wet or something but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh have you ever done <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> oven cooking while you're camping
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh yes we
 		we've cooked stews and cobblers and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biscuits</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		in fact every every time i go i end up having to cook <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biscuits</ENAMEX> for breakfast in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> oven so
 	
 	
 		oh  you must be an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> huh  oh
 	
 	
 		well  just a lot of practice
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i've had um
 		we go my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> once a year goes up to the in the mountains around here it's to a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cup River</ENAMEX> and
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and also a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion type thing and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> makes uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">potatoes</ENAMEX> and onions in the in the
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> ovens and they are sure good i so i don't know how to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> that way but it's
 	
 	
 		yeah we
 	
 	
 		i've liked the things i've tasted
 	
 	
 		we do that for breakfast sometimes
 	
 	
 		oh do you set up your own you take your own tents you say and
 	
 	
 		uh yeah the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy scout troop</ENAMEX> owns enough has enough tents for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> tents one for each boy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple leaders</ENAMEX> have big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> you know sleep together in them
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and sometimes sometimes we rough it we went there's a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">lake</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake Texoma</ENAMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas Oklahoma</ENAMEX> border
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> backpacking there that they didn't have any
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> or anything and we
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		each we packed in our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tents</ENAMEX> we packed in our own groceries our own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		oh wow so you have to
 	
 	
 		and boy
 	
 	
 		take everything you need and
 		do they did you just find a place that you liked and decided to set up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> there or
 	
 	
 		it's it's a it's a state park
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we just you know had to check with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ranger</ENAMEX> and tell him where we was going we had a map and all
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		we had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> hiked in i guess <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about five miles</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and we set up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and you know spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a night</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> like that kind of better or do they like to just go where it's close and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		oh they they seem to like the roughing because they want to go again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month in December</TIMEX> oh i keep forgetting you're it's not as cold there as it is here  oh well i when i was a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> year uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no it's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl scout camper</ENAMEX> we we hiked into a spot and that was um by a lake and it was beautiful and i almost think that's you feel more rewarded when you when you do it that way than when you drive in with uh
 		other stuff it is a lot more work though
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it takes a lot more so did you camp when you were growing up or is this something you've just done as a result
 	
 	
 		uh i was in scouts as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> so you know i've gotten
 		when <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i've gotten used to it and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mississippi</ENAMEX> out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and she's
 		her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> camps they you know they spend they spend a week on a lake fishing and stuff uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		in fact <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> we
 		on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day weekend</TIMEX> we went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arbuckle Mountains</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> we camped at a different site <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh how nice
 	
 	
 		and that was enjoyable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that sounds like it sounds like it was a
 		a nice trip
 		huh i yeah i have lots of good memories when we always used to take a week in the summer my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and have lots of good memories of
 		sitting around the campfire and marshmallows and ghost stories
 		
 		
 	