
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay how did you find out about this
 	
 	
 		well uh my brother-in-law sent me the thing
 	
 	
 		from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> oh
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh and we're supposed to talk on voting is that right
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh uh why we think there's such a shortage uh low turn out
 	
 	
 		okay um  do you want to start
 	
 	
 		okay well i think there's a uh a multiple multiple reasons i think <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are fed up and they think they don't really their vote doesn't count
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> of all a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just aren't educated to you know that they should do that  they should participate
 	
 	
 		they maybe they don't realize the importance of it or something
 	
 	
 		right we had uh city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">councilman</ENAMEX> here that won by like a handful of votes you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> votes or something
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that would have made a big difference if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had turned out for his opponent
 	
 	
 		boy i'll say
 	
 	
 		and i think another reason sometimes it's inconvenient
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> especially in a presidential election i don't know why it couldn't go on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several days</TIMEX> or why we couldn't even phone in our vote you know you can you can uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> you can register over the phone i don't see why we couldn't vote over the phone you know on the computers and all
 	
 	
 		oh that's an idea
 		yeah well no we don't  not
 	
 	
 		oh you don't do that up there
 	
 	
 		yeah we have the voting but uh i never heard of
 	
 	
 		i mean you don't register for college there they doing that all over the phone now down here at the big at the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> now what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> are you in
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 		oh
 		it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mantua</ENAMEX> it's just a small small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> we probably only have like oh seventy well maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>  not very many
 	
 	
 		really oh my my that's interesting
 	
 	
 		right so when we vote it's like you say there's it's a handful of of votes makes a difference in fact this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last November</TIMEX> they had a
 		vote and i think there was only like oh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> votes within the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different
 		you know the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were running for for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> of
 	
 	
 		right
 		just a difference of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> really hm
 	
 	
 		yes yes
 		in each of them and so like you say it makes a difference but that's that's a good idea about having it the voting over the phone maybe someday it will
 	
 	
 		right yeah we could use our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> number or something there ought to be some way that they could safe guard it but
 	
 	
 		it will a come
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh especially presidential because you know sometimes you do have to stand in line for a long time
 	
 	
 		right
 		right and you know i wonder i don't know what the
 		satistics are but i wonder what age um the least has the least good turn out for the voting
 	
 	
 		oh that's a an  interesting point i have no uh no idea i wonder
 	
 	
 		i wonder if it's the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or just in the middle-aged or or who it is that doesn't turn out my guess would be the younger
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true i know a lot of them that don't vote uh because my i have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty year old</TIMEX> and i know a lot of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> don't vote
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh i go to school right now and i i've heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> say they don't vote
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh just because they don't care
 	
 	
 		i guess well they don't really read the newspaper much you know i you know at that age i can remember being in college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first the first time</TIMEX> and i was a journalism major and i hardly ever read the paper  i think i mean it's appalling when i look back but
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i think that may be part of it too they're not really informed
 	
 	
 		right and i don't know how big of a problem this is but i wonder if i've heard some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say on occasion that
 		that the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> they don't care for any of them so they don't want to you know they don't want to give their vate vote for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or</NUMEX> of other just because they
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true that's very true i've heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on talk shows say that they feel that that's a statement when they don't vote at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right right that that's some that's saying hey you know we want somebody
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		better for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> i don't know i think that's kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> out  i really do i think you ought to you know make your opinion one way or the other there i mean if you even if you don't agree with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cop</ENAMEX> out yeah i think so too
 		i know even if you're voting against somebody more than for someone which i usually am nowadays  in the national elections it seems
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		right we have
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know when when i voted for somebody with great enthusiasm it was a long time ago oh
 	
 	
 		and so this last election here in in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> they had
 		um they counted them by hand you know the ballots by hand and i know that on the bigger ones they have little it's a punch card system are you familiar with that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no you you punch it something out
 	
 	
 		right you you have with your pencil you just punch you know they have a little tray that holds the ballots
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh no i've never seen one like that
 	
 	
 		and and apparently it makes the the counting a lot easier for the
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		for those that are counting it but um  with just the small ones they just go ahead and count it
 		by hand and i really liked the the punch card one because we got the results so much sooner when it was over
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right well we have uh where you fill it in with the lead pencil and and the machine counts it it's really fast too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh oh yeah that would be they probably can turn those results in
 	
 	
 		it
 		well
 		well right like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scantron</ENAMEX> you know they call it that goes through the machine i half the tests i take in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> now are that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		it's so easy i just stick them in this machine and get the number  out you know
 	
 	
 		oh wow that's fascinating
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		oh so have you ever run for any kind of
 		
 		
 	