
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are um
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two</NUMEX> of them are back in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> but they're all grown <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX> and over
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		and how did you spend time with them when they were young
 	
 	
 		i guess like everybody else soccer games and all sorts of games and carpools and
 		traveling and um they we seem to be together enough
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> was there was always <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> here at least because um we'd never usually leave together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i usually work teach at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was here in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">daytime</TIMEX> and i mean at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and then i was here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">most of the day</TIMEX> if they were when they were here so
 		they didn't spend a lot of time by themselves
 	
 	
 		how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have oh um-hum
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and a boy
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> now so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are grown also and they live away from me so i don't see them much but
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh you are
 		well we had uh that those they were all away and now there's uh one's coming back from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and the other one has just graduated and stayed back home so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i i tried to spend a lot of time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> when they were young we spent lot of value time um creating things and
 		building things together i feel the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> watch too much TV today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh absolutely yeah that's the truth we didn't have a TV for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three and a half years</TIMEX> when they were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> early <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> for some reason and they did so much better and then we went back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you can just see it that
 	
 	
 		well i tried to put a limit on it when they were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> to so they could only watch so many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> per day of TV so
 	
 	
 		um-hum where'd your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> go to school
 	
 	
 		well we traveled we moved around quite a bit so they went to a lot of different schools
 	
 	
 		oh
 		they weren't here in north <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> huh oh
 	
 	
 		no
 		they did go a year in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Palestine</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we did move around quite a bit so
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't know that i i just uh that's that that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV</ENAMEX>'s probably one of the problems and then both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> working and
 	
 	
 		but
 		right right
 	
 	
 		uh that's a i don't think a good situation but i don't imagine it'll change
 	
 	
 		i don't think so either it takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incomes now anyway
 	
 	
 		right
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		but i feel that i didn't get to spend as much time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> as i could have
 		or as as i should have i i was a working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		you probably didn't if
 		that's right if you had to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's just almost impossible
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		especially when they get up to the age where they have so many things they want to do on their own so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i remember the things that they really liked my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he liked kites he always wanted always building kites and working on those he loved kites
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		so uh well my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of mine ran sports so we spent an
 		time lot of time with their different sports activities because they all played and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now they're all in college or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one two one</NUMEX> out and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in still in college so
 	
 	
 		well mine they were in the music end of it instead of sports they did my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> did play a little <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football and soccer</ENAMEX> but i had them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> they were playing horns in the band
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		so well we probably if they're alive and kicking we probably did did a decent job
 	
 	
 		yeah nobody's perfect all you can do is your best and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		shit absolutely
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		anyway well
 	
 	
 		well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandsons</ENAMEX> now and i one of them uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and one of them's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> and i'm gonna get to see them at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> time so
 	
 	
 		oh great yeah
 	
 	
 		i uh it's gonna i'm gonna enjoy that
 	
 	
 		i would hope so
 	
 	
 		they're all little they're little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> so but i bought little things for them to work on and to try to keep them busy um-hum
 	
 	
 		yeah that will be
 		yeah that'll
 		that'll be fun look forward to that you're gonna fly out there
 	
 	
 		no i'm going to drive to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> uh hum
 	
 	
 		oh you are
 		ooh i've done that a few times
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that's a tough drive
 	
 	
 		it's worth it to see my family
 	
 	
 		sure you just gonna try to spend spend the the
 		uh spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> somewhere
 	
 	
 		oh yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		well we always stopped at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pecos</ENAMEX> that seemed like like it was a good
 	
 	
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> so i'm gonna stop there at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well that'll be great
 		so well anyway it's good to talk to you
 	
 	
 		well the they won't be be upset with us if we hang up too soon
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know i think
 	
 	
 		i haven't done that before usually i talk and talk and talk
 	
 	
 		they usually come on and say something don't they
 	
 	
 		uh yeah when our <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> are up
 	
 	
 		well that's all right
 		how long have you been with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i'm just a temporary i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manpower</ENAMEX> there and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and uh what do you teach in
 	
 	
 		i teach history
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh that's very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are interested in that history yeah and chemistry
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		yeah there's not not many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like it but it's uh you can get them get them hooked on it if your pretty good
 	
 	
 		what are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> what are they going into they you said they were in college
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> is going
 		
 		
 	