
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		um they said to discuss the type of novels i read for enjoyment i like mysteries i i i really enjoy a good mystery i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not into the gory bloody type murder things but  i like a mystery to curl up with at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and um do you enjoy mysteries
 	
 	
 		well i do i don't read much of them i i i tend to watch movie mysteries more than read mysteries i read other types of books but who's your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> in terms of mysteries
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Holt</ENAMEX> i like you know that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that era</TIMEX> and that type of a a setting so i i that the the type of area that i read um what kind of books do you enjoy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well  my my books are a little bit more uh  different than that um i tend to um right now i i do a lot of um reading of the mystic um
 		Catholic i do a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">saints</ENAMEX> uh i do a lot of mystic um the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the ancient um writings and i've been doing a lot of that kind of reading and um so like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Francis of Assisi</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Viola</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Saint John</ENAMEX> of the cross um those kinds of of writings uh sort sort of um old spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		oh that's
 		oh that's great
 	
 	
 		it's been real fascinating and
 	
 	
 		boy it sounds fascinating
 	
 	
 		that that's been a lot of my reading for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past number of years</TIMEX> and then i read contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		who um combine religion and psychology and that's been an interest of mine and so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		right now i'm currently reading a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morton Kelsey</ENAMEX> and uh his his a book on it called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Transcend</ENAMEX> and it's a story it's about prayer and um and it sort of combines uh some of the old um with the new
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so uh i
 	
 	
 		well that's fascinating
 	
 	
 		yeah i do that kind of reading although i do do some uh casual reading my reading lately has been fairly heavy but um
 	
 	
 		that sounds heavy  in fact it
 	
 	
 		it is yes but i just read i've read <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prince</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tides</ENAMEX> have you you know that's going to be a new movie and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh yes
 	
 	
 		that's a good book if you yeah very good book
 	
 	
 		is it
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i would highly recommend it um it's not a mystery uh it it is of sorts and it's it's really it's it's fiction but it's an excellent book i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh oh that's interesting i it sounds like my my novels that i read i don't do that real often i'm like you i'm more into the self-help help and the
 		um of course child rearing i like to read about that i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and and i like religious books also and um
 		you know that that's interesting that that you read those type things are they are they hard to understand
 	
 	
 		it depends i think i've i've learned through the years
 		different books speak to different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i say you know my recommendation is for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to try it and if if they can understand it they're supposed to read it and if they can't you know then don't try
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		put it away for another time um-hum
 	
 	
 		um-hum because i really do think it depends on on where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are at the particular time as to whether or not they can read it and for me on certain books speak to me and certain books do not so you know i i it
 	
 	
 		hm
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and i just think not every book is for every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> these are not like you know best sellers so um
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i agree
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> now when you go to the do you get them from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		i tend to buy them at a place here called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Books</ENAMEX> and it has wonderful um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		wonderful books and i tend to get them there i have i have a fairly expensive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> now of
 	
 	
 		boy
 	
 	
 		of things that i have read um another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's wonderful who's more contemporary but who has recently died is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Murtin</ENAMEX> and if you've read any of he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cistercian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monk</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and his writings are wonderful and he was a prolific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and uh you'll see if you know the name you'll see it quoted often um and and he
 	
 	
 		huh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he's really quite good and i think his books are a a tad easier to read you know i think that's a good place to start
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um have you read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Peck</ENAMEX> that's another good place
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		he wrote this this is what started me on all of it was The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Road Less Traveled</ENAMEX> that was a that's been a best seller
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yes i'm familiar that now i'm familiar with the title i wasn't familiar with his with his name but
 	
 	
 		well he um
 		he's wonderful and i recommend that book to anyone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um that is a great place to start and so it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Road Less Traveled</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh i'll have to do that
 	
 	
 		wonderful book if you're into religious reading um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and psychology it he's he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">psychiatrist</ENAMEX> and he was converted late kind of late in life and it's sort of his story and it's quite good um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		huh
 		now do you um
 		when do you do your reading do you
 	
 	
 		at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> i tend to read at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> um-hum i have i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven eleven eleven</NUMEX> and fifteen so
 	
 	
 		at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 		that's when i do
 		
 
 		oh they're a little bit older
 	
 	
 		how old are your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>  so that's the only time i have to read is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late at night</TIMEX> and sometimes i'm too tired to do that  but i do love to read yes i am uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh goodness you don't have time to do anything
 		i bet
 		i bet now are you Mormon
 		okay i i just assumed that because you're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yes yes i
 		
 		
 	