
 
     		
 	
 		you feel about uh drug testing in the work place
 	
 	
 		well actually i'm all for it even though um  for instance like in the area that i work for you know there's no danger you know of someone getting hurt because of you know being on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or something but uh
 		uh  i think because of ethics involved and uh things i'm just i'm in favor of it i i realize that that's putting
 		a lot of  government control in effect or or control over people
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		i think we need something in place to uh to solve the problems i certainly uh feel that it ought to be done
 		in public safety situations you know airline <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> and flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">controllers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who run <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trains</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">buses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi cabs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh definitely
 		well it's just like uh i can't remember now where it was what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two three months ago</TIMEX> there was that there was that bad train wreck and uh one of the um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> running the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> was on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were killed in it and and yeah when it comes to safety and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being killed i definitely think it should be a requirement you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're uh you know to heck with their rights you know they're interfering with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s rights to live
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know if they're in that type of position and have that much control over people
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the issues that came up for me personally was that uh
 		we see  i've gotten involved in uh foster care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i've seen a lot of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> come into foster care as a result of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> being on drugs
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh there's probably a lot out there that could probably stand public assistance or being rescued uh which aren't identified and so uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		testing at the work place in uh in in general i think is probably a good idea to to save some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		feeling like that if you know then you can look into a situation and in case there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> involved
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i can i can understand that i i think it is
 		you know i think it's so sad these these crack <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> that are now coming into you know grade school elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> you know that are so um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you know they're so messed up themselves and you know in talking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> i have several uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>  they uh
 		um you know they're hard to control they're hard to deal with and yeah i think that would be a good idea
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		being i'm a contract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> and before i could even go to work here i had to be drug tested you know and they do a random drug testing of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh but so far
 		far um
 		they don't require everyone to do it they just go through randomly and pick someone and you know and go do it and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has an excellent um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		assistance program if you're found you know found with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they actually give you i think um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> tries
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know to to quit it or get off of it or or whatever before you're you know dismissed i mean they work with you and they they have a program uh
 		uh that you can go to that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> picks up the tab for and also it's really an excellent program i know it seems like the older ones here are in favor of it the younger ones you know course are still
 		they're either you know doing some marijuana  or something or they're very idealistic you know and uh i don't know i think sometimes the older that you get i think the more ramifications you can see of so many things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> uh testing when you're hired is a requirement
 	
 	
 		is it
 	
 	
 		and i think they have a policy of uh random testing but uh i don't know whether they've ever done it or not i kind of wish they would
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and we do have an employee assistance program that's uh good for uh drug abuse uh treatments and other psychological uh problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		stress in the work place marital problems whatever's  bothering you
 	
 	
 		yeah this this program you know encompasses everything but you know i thought you know it's not an instant dismissal if you are found to be taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> which i think you know is good and it's good on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI TI</ENAMEX>'s part as i said i think they give you three chances
 		you know to come to grips with it before you're dismissed
 	
 	
 		what
 		you know a lot of times i see problems here at work though uh i remember <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years back</TIMEX> i had a uh schematic drawing that needed to be done and i was in a hurry to get it out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i sent these drawing the rough draft over to drafting and i usually do a pretty decent drawing myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when the drawing came back uh it was was apparent that it had been done by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because the line work
 		
 		
 	