
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay um do you participate in family reunions
 	
 	
 		i did for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i don't have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> left to have them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> did you uh were they far away were they close
 	
 	
 		that's
 		well  i come from
 		a family that was very large in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bell County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> came to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bell County</ENAMEX> on a covered wagon
 	
 	
 		oh how neat
 	
 	
 		and had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and so sometimes we would have a reunion with that group
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then sometimes we would go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> where they came from and have a reunion with the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh that would be fun
 	
 	
 		yeah it was a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		yeah well we uh we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that's uh oh it started probably <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> um
 		because i remember going as a teenager before i was ever married and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i went uh while we were still dating and it's still going on and
 		it used to be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Brownwood</ENAMEX> down at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brownwood Texas</ENAMEX> but now we hold it at uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lake Texoma</ENAMEX> so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> doesn't have to drive as far
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we have had as many on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> it starts on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and goes through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and we've had as many on a uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about two hundred</NUMEX> and fifty
 	
 	
 		um now we would have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> like that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> we'd have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred and fifty or three hundred</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes and we took uh i assume you all brought in food and everything
 	
 	
 		well so many of us came from a long way that we we'd usually at a motel and we bought food there
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh uh-huh it's i know on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> we all elect now to chip in and we go get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kentucky Fried Chicken</ENAMEX> and bring out and uh but we kind of take our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		but
 		um-hum hum
 	
 	
 		now our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> are participating in it and just love that they have all this little batch of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> that they get to see once a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enthused</ENAMEX> and uh
 		with it and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know thoroughly enjoy it so it's been kind of nice it started out when i was a youngster and watching my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> now i'm to the  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was and uh i am uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> and doing more of the cooking and watching my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> you know participate  more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and everything and uh
 	
 	
 		well it's something i really miss because i had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty seven first cousins</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my word
 	
 	
 		and you know we were very close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> was enough older than i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> would be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> now
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that they're all dead and in fact many of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first cousins</ENAMEX> are dead
 	
 	
 		oh are they
 	
 	
 		and course they have their own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> and all that so
 		we really very rarely all of us get together
 	
 	
 		get together any more
 	
 	
 		and and we're a long way away and and the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> the next like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i don't know very well you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it so it's i doubt that that will come to be again but as long as my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> lived we we got together once a year
 	
 	
 		i think i do think now we have noticed a waning of interest and i think as as parents
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		get older and start dying off i think sometimes it is hard to keep the interest going
 	
 	
 		well and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> have gotten so mobile i mean like i have
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> nephews that are grown
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> who has a new marriage and a younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> one of my nephews lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nephew</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> lives here but i think it's very unlikely we'll have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion you know
 	
 	
 		yeah you probably do good just to get your immediate family together
 	
 	
 		yeah and i'm divorced and really only immediate family i have left is my my i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s really all dead
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it was great pleasure while we did it you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they're a lot of fun well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and then we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> and and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> are both married and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s not as interested in it as our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> but our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is really interested and uh
 	
 	
 		did it does it bother you if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are not interested in it
 	
 	
 		i beg you pardon
 	
 	
 		does it bother you if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are not interested in it
 	
 	
 		oh a little bit i i wish that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was you know and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> are closer to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s age and than to our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s and just totally different interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and plus and he's just he's newly married and doesn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i'm hoping that as they you know are married a little bit longer and have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that they may be more inclined to want to go
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know to it i know that
 	
 	
 		what what kinds of things do you do to try to get your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> interested to talk to them about it
 	
 	
 		well talk to them about it and you know tell them some of the things we're doing now when he was a child uh a young oh preteen you know when he was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or twelve he loved going he had another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> he was close to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we but that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> kind of quit going and as he got to be a teenager um he wasn't quite as as interested he was more interested in
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rock</ENAMEX> and roll and this is more <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> and uh just lack of interest
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	