
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		oh
 		okay what kind of music are you interested in
 	
 	
 		i'm basically into uh
 		oh just rock and roll uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh jazz i'm a little bit of everything jazz reggae rock uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm more into the i'm see i'm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty three so</TIMEX> i'm you know i used to be in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and hang around all that stuff but i'm
 	
 	
 		so
 		oh
 	
 	
 		pretty much into
 		more classic rock now probably you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clapton Lynyrd Skynyrd</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh so
 	
 	
 		but uh i'm also into you know jazz and stuff and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> so you like the hits of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you're not really interested into  do you
 	
 	
 		i'm not into uh the dance stuff but uh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh i
 	
 	
 		so what are you into right now
 	
 	
 		well
 		well one of my favorite things is is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time of the year</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> music i love <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> music  all kinds i like you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>'s songs like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Frosty the Snowman</ENAMEX> and course i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so they like that too and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i like also like the you know the religious type <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> songs and i just love the the music this time of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> and i also
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> a little bit of country you probably don't like country sounds like
 	
 	
 		uh i like some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Black</ENAMEX> some you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		do you
 	
 	
 		yeah i've gotten into that more lately <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> i i used used to just totally not even listen to it but all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are into it so you know it's just
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm pretty much handle anything you know
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> music yeah around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> sure
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah so that's
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		that's good i
 	
 	
 		it just depends but i'll probably say rock
 		you know
 	
 	
 		for your favorite
 	
 	
 		not heavy metal so much anymore but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i kind of grew grew out of that it's a little irritating now i guess i see why my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> didn't like it when i was
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		is it
 	
 	
 		in junior high but
 	
 	
 		no that's about how it goes
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they can't understand the words the heck's going on
 	
 	
 		yeah so did you do you listen to your music loud do you like it loud or
 	
 	
 		no <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just regular</TIMEX> when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> probably but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's
 		just
 		not i don't irritate anybody with it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh-huh well that's i you know when i said i liked the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i i don't like the real heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> like the you know crying all  but just the just the light country stuff and i also like
 		um
 		i like a lot of contemporary music i i like all kinds of music i even like classical i have that playing you know once in a while in the background here at home and um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		enjoy that so do you go to concerts or
 	
 	
 		yeah as a matter of fact uh
 		the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">other day</TIMEX> here i was um
 		i was downtown uh a sale call working and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Halen</ENAMEX> i don't know you might see this in the news they put on a free concert
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and out on calls and we just happened to be <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about about a mile</NUMEX> away so we went down there to the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West End District</ENAMEX> which is uh
 		real nice um
 		downtown area which is a big hang out for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> and stuff so they put it on and um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was unannounced type thing and they announced it like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> before the show and um we just happened to be down there and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh wow
 		well that's nice
 	
 	
 		it was a little riot almost broke out so it was we happened to be in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> across the street you know nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah i used to do the concert thing when i was younger but i mean it's just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now i mean you want to lose your hearing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		God i mean it's just
 		i used to go out with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and stuff in high school
 	
 	
 		and too a lot of money too  oh really
 	
 	
 		oh yeah but
 	
 	
 		oh huh
 	
 	
 		just it's not
 		i don't know i mean with the prices and you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five</TIMEX> dollar ticket and there's there's not really that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		anybody i really want to see for that much amount of money now you know
 	
 	
 		no not for them
 		that's right do you play a musical instrument
 	
 	
 		no i don't even
 		i was in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> in junior high i played baritone but
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that wasn't
 	
 	
 		you haven't haven't kept that up
 	
 	
 		that was just more or less you know for the heck of it
 	
 	
 		uh-huh oh well that's good i i played piano a little bit and i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		how to be a well well a well rounded individual i guess so
 	
 	
 		oh well i
 	
 	
 		i hadn't even thought about that since  uh
 	
 	
 		oh well if there's i guess there's still chance  but you do like to listen to music you do enjoy it and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		i do too i do too i think it's really really powerful it can make a strong a lot of lot of strong statements
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		trying to i hope my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will be interested in i'd love for them to play in a marching band i like the music from marching bands you know in parades
 		as they're going by i i enjoy the drums and the trumpets and all that kind of stuff so i guess i like all most all kinds of music and
 	
 	
 		yeah my uh ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> used to be in a a drum corp or whatever
 	
 	
 		oh did he
 	
 	
 		back in and they were from up north i guess it's real big up there
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they're from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that's one thing he he was always really into that i just remember
 		it
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting i've never heard a drum <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">corp</ENAMEX> in person did had did you hear any of hear him play at all or
 	
 	
 		uh i'd seen some
 		they have these competitions like once a year out here i know it's just drum corps that come out and i've never been to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> but i mean i know it's i guess they just have th eir uh
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 		
 	