
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right this is my opinion i i'm still a student right now and i'm actually studying in elementary education i think that there are quite a few problems with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um more than anything i just believe that as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> we're taught to learn what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> wants instead of actually um gaining a further vantage point
 		and so it's basically we're taught to be mediocre in what we learn
 	
 	
 		yeah  um i'm also an education major  i'm still in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and uh but i wanna go into teaching special ed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i think there is a lot of problems in that area a i think there is problems all over the education system whether it be
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um elementary you know or even <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> you know have their flaws but  especially in the learning disabilities because um
 		a lot of times you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> think oh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s dumb and you know they just not too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have knowledge you know about  this area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of uh
 		type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know because it's starting to become new and and they're starting to find out more research about um this type of learning
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you're right i think that's really a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a really neat field i uh work right now in a special <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> for abused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and for some of the learning disabled
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's incredible how they they can learn quickly if you just find what's right for them
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and i think like you said at least in my opinion i think they put a lot of restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> of how they can teach them you know
 	
 	
 		that's right it they're they hire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> who aren't even qualified to teach those kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they burn out so fast they don't wanna teach them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's not enough <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> who want to do that  and they're starting to find out you know oh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>  may have a learning disability they test them and find out that they do and then it's just a growing field because more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are being tested into that
 	
 	
 		i i think it's really interesting too i think along with the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who is gifted and in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> he did terrible his all his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> because there was no one who ever challenged or whoever found what exactly was what he needed in terms of learning
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i think again it kind of goes back to the same thing of you know being mediocre in everything that we do
 	
 	
 		right yeah like  everybody not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with problems um learn differently i mean
 		you know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> can go out and learn how to teach but  they only know one way and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> might have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		problems you know learning that and comprehending well what does that mean i think it's i think more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> should um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		find different ways and be creative on their teaching
 	
 	
 		well i think you're absolutely correct
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		you know i think personally like you said it it has  more to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> coming out of their shell and not being afraid to make mistakes and saying you know hey i'm i'm gonna try this If it works great if it doesn't i apologize
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		and i i found  in my own schooling that when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> made that special effort to to make the class exciting to make it different to to challenge my intellect or to to bring about a different method of teaching i was a lot more interested in learning
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		what do you think about the grading systems and and how those work
 	
 	
 		the grading system grading system um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		i think um well in a sense it's probably too easy but if it wasn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know i mean nowadays a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> they just you know don't try they don't get the grades that they could
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		i don't
 	
 	
 		do you think there's too much focus on grades grades instead of learning
 	
 	
 		i don't
 		yeah i think
 		well the field i wanna go into grades to me doesn't mean much it doesn't tell you how intelligent you are how bright you are you know um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		because i know somebody who's very bright and very intelligent but just doesn't get the grades and that's just because they have a learning disability um so yeah i think you have a good point there where they don't focus enough on them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how they learn and what they're learning you know not on the grade
 	
 	
 		hm
 		right
 		yeah and i think at least as me as a college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> i have a really hard time because you know they
 		when you go out for a job or whatever they're gonna focus on your grades and i think again that a lot of the school problems are more society problems where they're not looking at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> as much much as they are just the whole overall picture
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you know like you said i i like the point that you brought up that that you said really it it needs to be individualized and i think as that happens more that the schooling will become better
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		right and that's hard with a a large class you know with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you can't give them all your full attention but and you know i i wish there was a way i'm not sure of it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	