
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh which ones have you seen lately
 	
 	
 		oh i just  i'm sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">blanking</ENAMEX> tonight i just got done saying i just saw <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> um  fairly recently uh
 		oh i know uh uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> that take off from uh  uh across across
 		across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on a crime spree
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> yeah i haven't seen that is it good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah it really is it's it's interesting
 	
 	
 		is it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i enjoyed
 		i was gonna go see uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crystal</ENAMEX> movie also which was i'm a little bit behind i usually rent them
 	
 	
 		yeah i i'm not familiar which which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Crystal</ENAMEX> movie
 	
 	
 		oh this is the uh just the one oh gosh it was the uh City Slickers right have you seen that
 	
 	
 		oh City Slickers
 		that's a real good show yeah it's great uh it says a lot about uh uh you know i'm i'm young but it says a lot about middle life you know and uh  uh it's a really good show
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i i've heard lots of good things about it and i would have would have liked to have seen it but i was with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i figured she'd like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> better so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i'd heard it was really good too so
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		it is
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm not too familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX> uh  uh uh uh recently i i've seen uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fisher King</ENAMEX> have you seen that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no no
 	
 	
 		that's a really good show
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh has Jeff Bridges</ENAMEX> and and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Williams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh really really good
 	
 	
 		yeah there's there's been a a fair number of of pretty good movies out recently
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it kind of runs in  in batches i mean for a while sometimes they come in a whole bunch of them that just i don't even you know doesn't even sound like something i want to see you know
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what what kind of movies in general do you like to watch
 	
 	
 		um  well i like to be entertained once in a while but uh i i really enjoy watching a movie that uh  where they don't really try and attract you know the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> but rather put out a a real good movie
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		uh  always my my favorite movie of all time has been uh uh The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mission</ENAMEX> did you ever see that
 	
 	
 		no in fact i'm not even familiar with it i don't think
 	
 	
 		uh it's a a i think it's put out by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landmark Productions</ENAMEX> the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who put out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chariots of Fire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's a it's a has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert DeNiro</ENAMEX> in it uh he plays one of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> and uh it's about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jesuit</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> in uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mission</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inca Falls</ENAMEX> in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> Northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 		hm oh uh uh-huh oh no in fact i i i'll i'll look for it because i  i've been
 	
 	
 		uh really really good show
 		yeah it's it's something that you know it's it's really stirring the cinematography is just beautiful and really beautiful scenes and real good music
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		actually yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s from down in that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">region</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seven</ENAMEX> the called the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">the Seven Missions</ENAMEX> which are which are right down in this where i'm sure where it was filmed at
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm sure that that would make it worth worth her watching she my my uh my movie watching has has severely uh has has changed a lot since i got married
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah she she likes uh action movies and uh and and comedies and so anything that's has anything little is a little little bit less than sort of mainstream <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is boring to her  and so i i i i really i used to watch a fair number of foreign films i used to watch a lot of sort of the less the less popular films
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i find i don't do it anymore or else i have to watch them on my own
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm much the same way i i i i have a fiance and it it gets very difficult to uh  uh she yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		find something both of you will watch
 		yeah
 		um she it's it's funny because i mean most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aren't really sort of she's sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> type of yeah she really likes all these gory shoot them up films
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		keep her on the edge of her seat
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'll watch them you know they're kind of fun to watch in a way
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they are sometimes you're in the mood for it even
 	
 	
 		yeah  but uh  so it it it varies i don't seem to get you know as much variety <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> lately as i used to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i found when when i get when i get with my uh old college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddy</ENAMEX> we we usually rent uh good gladiator movie or two
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh prior to that i i still enjoy watching those you you can't just watch them by yourself or else it's it's just not bearable
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it's it's fun to
 	
 	
 		well yeah on the other hand you you know given that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> likes those i i  i occasionally like to watch them and and so uh you know so it's you can always count on her to watch something like that and she'll even watch things like karate movies and stuff  which
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know which most most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> won't won't come within <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> feet of
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's that's
 		the ones where they dub in dub in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the the all the all the   all the sounds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">karate chops</ENAMEX> flying through the air  but uh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's great
 		uh  on on foreign films did uh did you did you watch are you uh fluent in another language or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">echo</ENAMEX>
 		i speak yeah i speak several uh but i i don't mind watching subtitle movies uh no i i i don't
 	
 	
 		oh you don't
 		i i don't either i i feel foolish sometimes because i i don't speak another language fluently but i do enjoy watching you know subtitles
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean for some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that's just you know that's out of the question you know if you give it subtitled they won't watch it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	