
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what do you like to read
 	
 	
 		uh i read about just anything that i can get my hands on
 	
 	
 		you sound like me
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		if it's printed i'll read it
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah it's amazing to me the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that uh i've i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> that uh like whenever i go to visit them i'll always have to be sure and carry a book with me because there's nothing to read in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and i go crazy
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i i pretty much carry my own reading material too i mean i'll uh i'll be walking to work i mean walking to the elevator to work and i'll be reading a book on the way up in the elevator and everybody laughs at me
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah well i i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> looking around and i found this uh new book by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PJ O'Rourke</ENAMEX> called uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horrors</ENAMEX> and it's about uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a  humorous humorous attence attempts to explain the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and it's really cute
 		
 
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		but anyway he wrote for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolling Stone magazine</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> i think he still does
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> is it a is it a satire or
 	
 	
 		it is very much a satire
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i like i said i i i gosh i can't remember the last book i bought but i've read so many and any book my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> usually has a stack at her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so i'll go and pick up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> over there and
 		or several actually and just get through them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by one mostly i like i don't know
 		i suppose
 		uh mystery or history true history
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that type of thing
 	
 	
 		most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> do like mysteries a lot i have i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> too is a voracious history buff she just she reads one history
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		book after another and and i was telling her about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> that has uh one particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> that has all of the mysteries arranged in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area uh
 		and then another one that while they're not arranged in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> area they do they have question marks on the covers to indicate that they're mysteries and she said oh that sounds like heaven to her so she wouldn't have to have to look for them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		that's true
 		no i can't say that i've been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> lately i've found quite a bit i mean i'm either reading a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> or like i said anything i can get my hands on
 	
 	
 		yeah the only problem that i've got now  is that uh i take a daily paper and then i've got oh i don't know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> coming in and then of course i've always usually i'm in the middle of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> different books at the same time
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and i've found lately that uh that i i feel  God for some reason i feel kind of bad about it but i'm not able to get through the newspaper i mean and i and and then if i'm not finished with it i don't want to throw it away and then all of a sudden it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> and then it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh uh-hum
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> counter is covered with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines newspapers</ENAMEX> so i finally just you know make a run to the dumpster
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		i uh i well i end up just picking out key sections and reading those and the rest of it if i get to it fine if not
 	
 	
 		hm yeah
 		yeah the only really the only the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only day</TIMEX> that i just uh devour it cover to cover is on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> but that's sort of a ritual with me get the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bran muffin</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the turn on the stereo and i'm just i'm i'm set for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> is that all
 	
 	
 		well maybe a little more at least an hour at least an hour
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> gets both i mean he gets the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> here and he he sits down for at least about
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> so me i don't know i don't i don't sit specifically sit down on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> to read the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> sometimes i don't get to it till like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah well that's the good thing about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> paper though they have so many articles that aren't necessarily uh you know you don't feel like they're
 	
 	
 		but eventually
 	
 	
 		old if you don't get to them that on that one day
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		well i uh i don't know i had bought books for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and uh the last time i moved when i was transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> i uh filled up
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> with books because where i live now doesn't have a bookshelf doesn't have doesn't have the book shelves that i had in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> where i moved from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't know see i've i've just i've got such so many books and moving them was such a pain that i've really
 		stopped buying so many and i started going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> again which uh i hadn't done in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen years</TIMEX> you know and it was kind of like an awakening i thought you know gosh this is free it's amazing so but i've enjoyed it  and i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		it's it's really a much better idea it's a bit inconvenient for me but i've i've always told myself i'd do that because
 		i don't know i get the books and then after i read them if i really like them i'll keep them but if if not you know it's it's wasted space for me so i end up giving them away
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah but um i've got
 		i'm kind of sort of surrounded i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> that are within oh i don't know it's uh  i guess the furthest one away is maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> miles one of them's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only about a half mile</NUMEX> away the other one's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a mile and a half</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		and it and one in particular stays open until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">uh nine o'clock</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> so it's you know it's great and that makes it it it you know if they were just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">regular hours</TIMEX> then it would be difficult because i'm
 		usually work pretty late at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> but um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		anyway that uh i still like to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bookstores</ENAMEX> and browse around but uh
 	
 	
 		well i'll i'll read the reviews
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if they end
 		
 		
 	