
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX>  did they tell you our topic
 	
 	
 		uh no somebody else answered the phone and put my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> in uh what is the topic
 	
 	
 		okay it's uh the topic is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> will you buy next and what kind of decision you know do you
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		think about getting the you know to pick that car out and uh and why
 	
 	
 		okay uh my next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> to buy probably would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> i've had uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		well i'm on my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one and i'm not real sure that i'd be in the market for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for quite a while
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm the same way i was uh i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillacs i</ENAMEX> went to my first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> this last time i travel and uh
 		my grandfather
 		worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Motor Company</ENAMEX> so he always said why don't you drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> or don't you try a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> so i finally tried one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		my
 	
 	
 		after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX> and uh
 		i've had i guess i guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillacs</ENAMEX> and and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Suburban</ENAMEX> in my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">last five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> but i bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> and i like it
 	
 	
 		my
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> has been a uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Lincoln</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but i've always been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i'm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auto parts business</ENAMEX> myself
 	
 	
 		oh are you
 	
 	
 		and uh the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac i</ENAMEX> bought was an Allante
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i just love it to death i'm not sure i'd ever get rid of it
 	
 	
 		well i'm a i'm a traveling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">salesman</ENAMEX> i travel on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> so i like a little heavier <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so that's
 	
 	
 		i used to do that quite a bit myself
 	
 	
 		so that's why i
 		choose you know to drive a heavier <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and more luxury <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but i tell you what i will probably get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> the next time quite honestly yeah because i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		really
 	
 	
 		there's just something about that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> that whether it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMC</ENAMEX> product or whatever seems they handle better and
 	
 	
 		they seem to put they seem to be put together a little bit better
 	
 	
 		i think so too
 	
 	
 		and you know the buttons on the controls and things like that are a little easier to get to than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> products
 		and i think that's one of the things that makes me shy away from uh imports
 		is they put so much you know gadgetry
 		on the dash and and the the buttons are so small to push and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to do that i kind of like that feature
 	
 	
 		yeah they really do
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		you know i'm a i'm a funny <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">duck</ENAMEX> that came that comes to the simple things like front end alignments i have never had to have a front end alignment on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know why why whether i just seem to drive them better or what but i've never had to have a front end alignment on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> they always appear to hold well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i've uh i had an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eldorado</ENAMEX> was my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one was an eighty and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about sixty thousand miles</NUMEX> i finally had it lined up and i had them do all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> wheels
 	
 	
 		did you
 		and the only thing i miss about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> is
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fleetwood Brougham</ENAMEX> was my last <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and i traded it in traded it in on my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> and they're just not as large as before i do miss that
 	
 	
 		that's true yeah but what is big today
 	
 	
 		well you're right
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> still as big as it always has been but
 	
 	
 		yeah it's big but the trunk space for me uh what i usually do is i usually take the backseat out of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and that's where i put my <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">samples</ENAMEX> because trunks just aren't big enough
 	
 	
 		you know a car i ran across recently that has a tremendously large trunk is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Continental</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah now i have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Towncar</ENAMEX> and it's it's a deep trunk but not as broad as the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Towncar i</ENAMEX> noticed uh or with the with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> uh i was rented <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we could uh put golf <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> in them
 	
 	
 		oh good and it went all it went all the way down
 	
 	
 		you know straight across i mean front to back not going from side to side
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		and we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> full sets in there and still had room for luggage
 	
 	
 		yeah i sell sporting goods uh hunting related items i sell <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns gun</ENAMEX> cases and things like that and i need to you know it's about the same size as a golf club they need to samples need to stretch out and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> cases and things like that and
 	
 	
 		i see yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know if you've ever looked at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		nope
 	
 	
 		it's not as peppy as a as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Towncar</ENAMEX> because it's a V-6
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but it uh i took i drove it from here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX> and i really enjoyed driving that car if i was going to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> product that's what i would buy
 	
 	
 		yeah i drove <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks ago</TIMEX> to our one of our big national sales meetings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> i usually fly i drove it with another one of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that worked for me we drove it's you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten hours</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nashville</ENAMEX> and it
 		it handled real well but my main thing is space so if a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental i</ENAMEX> might consider it the next time a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Continental</ENAMEX> has more trunk space you bet
 	
 	
 		you might take a look at them they they had a a lot more space trunk space as a matter of fact they had
 		more trunk space than my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sedan de Ville</ENAMEX> had
 	
 	
 		you always have leather interiors on your Cadillacs
 	
 	
 		um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of mine have had leather interiors yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i like leather interiors also
 	
 	
 		uh i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eighty Eldorado</ENAMEX> which was leather leather and uh then my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty six</NUMEX> was a touring <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">sedan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it had the gray leather package in it
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allante</ENAMEX> has um i guess saddle saddle colored
 	
 	
 		that's a nice car
 	
 	
 		type thing
 	
 	
 		you bet and i'll and i will say one thing about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> versus
 		
 		
 	