
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> would you like to buy next
 	
 	
 		well i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> i guess that's kind of everybody's dream
 	
 	
 		huh why would that be a
 	
 	
 		oh i guess it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> product and i like
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> because they're made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and uh we've had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and have always had real good luck with them
 	
 	
 		okay well that's good if you had uh no financial requirements if you could buy any <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in the entire world no matter what it cost what would you buy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh  um i think i'd still go with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> i don't i don't care about a big fancy fancy
 	
 	
 		say what
 		which type of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is your favorite
 	
 	
 		oh i don't know i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX> probably or yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seville</ENAMEX> that's a sharp looking <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that really is it it always has been though
 	
 	
 		yeah they have been
 	
 	
 		you know it doesn't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Coup de Ville</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sedan de Ville</ENAMEX> squareness it never really has it's always had it's own unique look
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i've always liked that i liked the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the one year</TIMEX> they had or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the couple of years</TIMEX> they had were uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the trunk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> would look like belt buckles across the back of it
 	
 	
 		oh yeah right
 	
 	
 		i thought now that looks sharp that looks real sharp
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think the ones uh now with all of the um fancy gold lettering and all you know i think they're very pretty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and course the top now the vinyl what is it a vinyl top i think those are pretty
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh the i i've never really uh i've never ridden in one recently um but they're supposed to be just real smooth
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just a nice comfortable ride
 	
 	
 		yeah they are and uh
 		they they're just always they they look like  they're sturdy you know they look like they're very sturdy and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you don't have to worry that much about  um getting you know hurt like you would in a small one
 	
 	
 		right now they've got a uh a unique feature uh feature in them now if uh if you have a front end accident
 		at such a rate of speed the engine the engine will actually drop
 		out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> so that it doesn't come through the
 		so it does not go it doesn't go through the you know into the inside it'll go underneath the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> instead
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		so that's that's a big safety factor they've got in them now
 	
 	
 		yeah and i suppose they all have the balloons
 	
 	
 		the air bags yep
 	
 	
 		the air bags yeah
 		well
 	
 	
 		so though that's great that's great so you say you've you've always uh preferred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> products what uh
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah i do um i i go for things you know built in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> rather than foreign countries help our economy and
 	
 	
 		right
 		what kind of uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> have you had in the past
 	
 	
 		mostly Oldsmobiles
 	
 	
 		Oldsmobiles those are real nice riding <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yeah that's what i have now but of course if i had my choice i'd still have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX> but um i've been very satisfied with the with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oldsmobiles</ENAMEX> we've driven them for about probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		has that been the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Cutlass</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sierra</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninety Eight</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninety Eight</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 		so
 	
 	
 		well i don't think uh
 		let's see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninety Eight</ENAMEX> now that's got that big V <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> engine in it doesn't it doesn't it
 	
 	
 		well no now the one we have has a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six uh-huh</NUMEX> but it's a very good car it's uh
 	
 	
 		has a little V <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 		okay
 	
 	
 		a have not had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one minute</TIMEX>'s problem with it and i've had and i have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twenty three thousand miles</NUMEX> on it
 	
 	
 		it
 		oh that's great that's great that's always nice to get uh reliability
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in a product especially when you're spending you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">anywhere from fifteen</NUMEX> to twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollars</NUMEX> for for a single item
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know you just don't want any hassles with it you just you expect it to do its its job and i think a lot of
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> don't really keep that into consideration don't take that into consideration you know
 	
 	
 		um-hum there that's true
 	
 	
 		they just expect you to buy their product but
 		that's always been something that's been a key factor in me is how reliable is this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> gonna be you know price is is an issue but it's not the most important issue
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		no it really isn't because now you can get like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year</TIMEX> financing on them and so um but i i i would go with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> any time
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh well i've always been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> myself
 	
 	
 		oh really oh
 	
 	
 		yes but that's all right you know it's it's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> made too which is good um but i i've ever since i guess i was i was growing up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s always had Fords
 	
 	
 		yeah well sure
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh well i grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> so everybody has a truck
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> have just i've i've just never had problems with them i honestly think i would die before my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> would kill over on me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah well uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> yeah those are good products also um
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		doesn't seem like
 		
 		
 	