
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Jerry</ENAMEX> i guess <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>'s topic is about recycling and i'd like to tell you first of all what's happening in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> here in Plano
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		all right
 	
 	
 		right now we have a pretty nice recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> where a lot of the recyclable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> can be picked up by the by the collection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> or the the city
 		along with your garbage can uh you can put out newspaper you can put out glass you can put out aluminum cans you can put put out certain types of plastic material
 		and that's on a roll out effort right now not all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> can go ahead and uh participate right now but uh
 		that will be rolled out to everyone i hope in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next year or so</TIMEX> and those that aren't participating they have the specific drop off <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> where you can take <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and aluminum
 		and i think uh overall that's an an excellent opportunity because i hate to see our landfills being filled up and uh growing bigger and bigger and bigger
 		where they're becoming a big problem for only not only the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are living <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> but for the future also
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i was reading  my <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> that's cute i live in a place called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dye Mound</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		how about your community
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dye Mound</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dye Community</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>  not incorporated my nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about a half a mile</NUMEX> at least i can't even see their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		sounds like a place where i grew up
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean uh i'm out in i'm out in the wilderness literally
 	
 	
 		well i like it
 	
 	
 		and uh well give you an idea it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three and a half</NUMEX> miles of dirt <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> to the concrete i mean to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">asphalt</ENAMEX> we're out there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we i do some interesting recycling things
 	
 	
 		well good
 	
 	
 		i'm building our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and i'm going to incorporate into my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> area a weight activated uh crusher
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		so when i drive the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in the in the driveway in the afternoon it it'll just drive it up on a ramp that actually puts me on top of the the uh pressure side of a uh hydraulic cylinder
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the weight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> will crush what's ever in the disposer
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		hopefully hopefully it's not my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well let's hope not you can be uh get in trouble for that
 	
 	
 		well i thought i'd you know i'd use it as a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a escapement</NUMEX> type thing i don't know if you're familiar with that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> but what you do is you just build up the pressure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then you go over and release it and then it just it just drops you know
 	
 	
 		well it's quite similar to a hydraulic jack isn't it
 	
 	
 		very similar yeah
 	
 	
 		okay okay
 	
 	
 		well what what it'll be you just you drive up on the jack but you it won't go down
 	
 	
 		yes until you release it
 	
 	
 		until you pull the pin yeah
 	
 	
 		all right i think that's
 	
 	
 		anyway
 		i  i have another uh recycling method i use
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know all that junk mail you get
 	
 	
 		oh yes i sure do
 	
 	
 		the glossy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that says buy this and send off for that and you have won and all that well anytime they send me a return envelope
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i put all that stuff back in the envelope plus the other stuff that i you know happen to gather up
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because uh well like i say we live away and when you throw trash away you throw it in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> and i don't like that so i don't do that so i take it and i send and i mail it back to them
 	
 	
 		yes
 		no
 		well great that's excellent
 	
 	
 		i've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> actually stop mailing me stuff
 	
 	
 		well uh if a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did that then then we wouldn't have a lot of this junk mail that's a great idea i hadn't thought about that and we might be able to incorporate some of that one thing
 	
 	
 		yeah well i think one of the the best ways to eliminate uh or help the recycling problem is to eliminate non-reusable items
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		for instance uh i saw a thing on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nova</ENAMEX> think was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> has designed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		recyclable materials i mean recyclable items whatever he makes it's all out of the same thing
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh
 	
 	
 		see so if it's plastic it's all out of plastic if it's metal it's all out of metal it's he's a design he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> designing stuff
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well that's a great idea that's a great idea
 	
 	
 		and incorporating incorporating incorporating incorporating you know reusable <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> into your
 		uh you know your assembly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> into your actual scheme of
 	
 	
 		product
 	
 	
 		product <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> is is the only way to really do it on a on a broad scale make it financially uh attractive to recycle and somebody will find a way to make money at it
 	
 	
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yes they will exactly
 	
 	
 		well there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> that's all he does
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		he collects trash
 	
 	
 		well that's a full time job
 	
 	
 		you know
 		yeah well he's he's out for cardboard
 	
 	
 		yes well i've found out too that uh you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> we've always been recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> for the last twelve years
 		and at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time we could get a pretty good return uh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> we could take and collect the newspaper an and
 		
 		
 	