
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well um i don't know i'm  have only been um selected for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and it was sort of a a rude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">awakening</ENAMEX> to our judicial system um
 		after having served on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> and uh come to a decision
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh and</ENAMEX> and really it was a case that was cut and dry the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>  on uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> stand admitted he was guilty
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and then uh the first thing that was done was after um we we found him guilty
 		his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> jumped up and uh started going through the procedure you know routine for filing an appeal
 		which you know i i i know that that's the right uh but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> but i mean it makes you wonder why go through it one more time when you know he admitted he was guilty of the crime
 		so um i don't know that it was a little bit disgruntling to me
 	
 	
 		it
 		right i have never served on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> i have been called like only twice in my life and and uh
 		at the time i've been a legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistant</ENAMEX> and nobody wanted me on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> so i've been excused but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i uh i don't know i look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who get excused and and it's supposed to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> and i'm not sure it always is uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it is a lot it is a huge burden to put on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't know the law uh
 		you know that especially in criminal cases when you're deciding someone's life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i'm not so sure that you know
 		that that's something that is
 		that you can really really have the knowledge to do as as just a lay person
 	
 	
 		oh not
 		i agree with that and certainly um i think that uh  i know that uh
 		i have heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> being you know in on a on a criminal case and uh saying that you know and i think you've got this option  that if you want if you
 		are found guilty by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that you can choose  even before the trial begins  for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> to sentence you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and that i i think i think i'm correcting correct in that  but uh
 	
 	
 		well a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> can set i mean they do set the penalty you know the the
 		judgment  at once it's rendered guilty you know the sentencing is done by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>  in in a lot of the cases um some cases it is up to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you know you're told if you find them guilty then this is the choices that they have to make it's either life or death you know
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't i don't know it just
 		it it seems like in some of these cases i don't know that you could really have an impartial
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX> because of the media given
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i don't you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s age of television the coverage like it is there's no way that you can be shielded from it
 	
 	
 		well i i understand what you're saying and at the same time  i'm afraid that there are people
 		out there that walk are walking around that have no more conception of what's going on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day in and day</TIMEX> out than if someone came down from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and and unfortunately those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who my in my book i would i would consider them to be terribly uninformed
 		might be deemed the most eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be put on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>  while like like you said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> i don't necessarily would  i don't think i'd consider them to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of my peers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so i but that's well you know one of the reasons why i hope i never have to be in a position to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> listen to what  a case of mine and i hope i never you know am in that situation
 	
 	
 		well i know when i've been you know called to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> duty they had to stand up there or stay you know until they dismissed me and i look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and the reasons that they get dismissed
 		um before they even you know the selection is is even started it is your profession you know <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">nine tenths</NUMEX> of them are your professional people
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		who are out in the world you know the rest are retired or they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">housewives</ENAMEX> or
 		uh
 		
 
 		
 		
 	