
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		surprised to get anybody this time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> but i've been i've been trying all different times and i don't get anybody at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thirty</TIMEX> i don't get anybody at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine at night</TIMEX> so i thought i'll try a really weird
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh well i'm at work and i just happened to walk back into my office i've been gone for a little while
 	
 	
 		oh  well well i go to school so i'm home certain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and um i really haven't been making many of these phone calls have you got
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i don't make i haven't ever made any i just receive them
 	
 	
 		have you have you received many
 	
 	
 		here i haven't here lately yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it it's uh well the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time we were on this it came just about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> i never had to make one they just always came
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah exactly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> must be tired of it or something well well anyway i guess we're supposed to discuss this uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		subject what do you think
 	
 	
 		well i never gave it any thought myself i was hoping you could tell me what you thought
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh well i don't have any objection to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> doing that i think it might be good for them but as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> i might be afraid of where they were sent is i'm just concerned about their safety more than because if they do good works in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> they'll probably be sent to a ghetto
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if they were sent to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> world <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i couldn't help but worry worried you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but that would be my main objection
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		i don't know i think maybe it's it should stay on a voluntary basis
 	
 	
 		i don't think it'll probably never happen but
 	
 	
 		yeah  yeah i i i think it would be good for uh everyone to do something like that but i i guess i don't feel like it should be something forced upon you
 	
 	
 		yeah well it it probably won't i don't i don't even know how we'd pay for it anyway we can't uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		seem to pay for all the things we have going now  that's another consideration
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		but uh i don't know some some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are so spoiled nowadays it might be a real eye opener you know
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		i mean sometimes my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are on the other side of town here and they just see some really tiny modest wood frame <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and then they think
 		they're just kind of shocked at that side of town you know i probably lived in one of those when my i was a little girl
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> that every time her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> starts taking things for granted she threatens to send him to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> and let him get a taste of that for a while  wouldn't it though
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that'd be an eye opener wouldn't it i mean right next to us is such a pitiful country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it is
 	
 	
 		i know sometimes i wish we'd help them out instead of going all across the world and helping some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> i never even heard of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i know it
 	
 	
 		seems to me we uh it be to our benefit to strengthen that country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right on our borders
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but what do i know right  i'm just sitting at home and and uh doing laundry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and certainly not up nobody has called me from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>  oh but um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		oh shoot
 	
 	
 		anyway how did you get on this program
 	
 	
 		i work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you do work at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> oh you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lewisville</ENAMEX> oh yeah i just went by that place we were going to a football play-off game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or so ago</TIMEX> which we lost and  we went by that's the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i'd seen it looked really nice a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> there it looked like a pretty little uh site
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		yeah
 		hang on a minute
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hm</ENAMEX> do you need a bag no i don't think so yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty</ENAMEX> might okay
 		i'm back
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		but how'd you get on it
 	
 	
 		did
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> over on uh Central uh why we're living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> i'm not so sure but he works over there and that's we did it last time
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		so  just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and i are registered this time i don't know they didn't even ask him back  that was weird wasn't it
 	
 	
 		really
 		huh
 	
 	
 		but like i said i hardly ever get any calls this time and i can never find anybody
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i don't get too many hm
 	
 	
 		i so um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i used to get calls from far away too
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 	
 	
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and but now it just seems like it's in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Fort Worth</ENAMEX> area that i get calls from
 	
 	
 		yeah i've had the same experiences all right around here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know uh i wonder if they really i don't know if they could possibly teach a machine to recognize the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all</NUMEX> different accents there's just
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there's so many within this one town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know even even in some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk a little bit different
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> says things that really sound funny to me and he doesn't pronounce them at all that way and that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		course i think everyb ody in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> sounds a little bit funny but you you know how that goes  oh God
 	
 	
 		oh i agree  oh shoot
 	
 	
 		well i'm surprised she hasn't told us to cut it off yet sometimes she says at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh our switch are are overloads so please end your conversation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		well well do you have anymore words of wisdom about the subject  you don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you wanna send over there
 	
 	
 		no i sure don't
 		no no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  oh shoot
 	
 	
 		well it is  well uh i don't know if mine would want to go live in the ghetto well one of them is real idealistic she might
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> is i'd be more suited to that than her she's just bugs
 		
 		
 	