
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		they want us to talk about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> our favorite football <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and it doesn't sound like to you yours will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> with your accent
 	
 	
 		it
 		well it is well actually it isn't actually i the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Giants</ENAMEX>  but i do like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh right
 		oh okay where are you
 	
 	
 		well i'm in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> yeah where are you
 	
 	
 		Plano i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well
 	
 	
 		well what are you doing down here you working
 	
 	
 		uh well no well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was transferred down here
 	
 	
 		oh is he is he with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		but anyway they want us to talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorite team</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Giants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes but you know they're not doing so good this year
 	
 	
 		well that's true but that happens after the anytime you're the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> it's it's hard to repeat because everybody's shooting for you
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's true but i i don't know they have basically the same team they had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i just i think the coaching stinks
 	
 	
 		you don't think that maybe their desire is not there or maybe they're a year older
 	
 	
 		well i don't know i just think uh  they got rid of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Parcells</ENAMEX> well they didn't get rid of him he quit and i just don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that's replaced him he's very conservative in his play calling
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know i think he uh he could should he could have taken more chances this year
 	
 	
 		you don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> saw the handwriting and thought he'd be better to go out as a winner
 	
 	
 		well that's possible but now i hear uh he's been talking with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tampa Bay</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		i know it but see he can only go up from there because they're so bad
 	
 	
 		exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		you know  if you go out on top and then go somewhere else it's bad well it's it's well i don't i don't know i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Simms</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Simms</ENAMEX> might have been treated badly since he got bumped aside for Hostetler
 	
 	
 		well gee i don't know it's hard to say you know you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hostetler Hostetler</ENAMEX> brought them to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> and uh i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah but do you do you think it's fair because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simms</ENAMEX> was hurt that he didn't get his job back and then if he didn't do the job put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hostetler</ENAMEX> in there
 	
 	
 		well it's a it's possible you know i who's to say i mean uh i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hostetler</ENAMEX> he'd he had his his right numbers were there i mean you know he he had pretty good numbers but um
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		it
 		it just seemed to me that everybody was just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half</NUMEX> a step off i don't know whether it was age or
 		determination or coaching or what you know because it just somehow they were almost there all the time but
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't know they're very disappointing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> was very  it didn't do anything i mean their their maybe they they i think the most they they scored in any game was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty four</NUMEX> points or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know they really had a  i don't know why because they had the same well you know they had the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> but they didn't score all that many points <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in each game but they um they have a terrific
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those things where everything just falls in place for you you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess i guess yeah well how about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> they're doing you know great
 	
 	
 		that's right but look what happened to them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well yeah but now well you know they're really on the road back you know i mean that that game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was terrific
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah that's true
 		were you out there
 	
 	
 		no no i i haven't been to a game in a long time
 	
 	
 		oh well i've had season tickets since um nineteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty seven</TIMEX> so i've seen a few games
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh that's great were you out there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> oh man
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 		so it's uh do well do you think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Taylor</ENAMEX> is about had it
 	
 	
 		i don't think so i mean i hope not anyway i mean he's so good you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i know he's uh fun to watch yeah he's great to watch and
 	
 	
 		yeah he's he's real good
 	
 	
 		yeah well you think y'all will fire your coach
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know uh you know i don't know  i think maybe they'll give him another year
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah they probably will
 	
 	
 		you know but um i was disappointed he was too conservative and he just didn't take enough chances
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um i you know i'd i'd prefer them to get somebody else i'd like to see them get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcells</ENAMEX> back
 	
 	
 		well
 		well i think he probably had to had pressure long enough and he wants to go somewhere where he can you know i can see his point it was a good time for him to leave really
 	
 	
 		yeah he left on top you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Super Bowls</ENAMEX> in uh what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> that that's pretty damn good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well what what else could you do
 	
 	
 		yeah you know he couldn't really top it so uh and now i'm sure he's making more money doing uh you know sports reporting
 	
 	
 		yeah well what do you think you all's draft choices needs are for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> or do you get into it that deep uh-huh
 	
 	
 		what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>
 		um you know i really don't i guess i guess they can um
 		i really don't know defense and offense i suppose you know i've got they've got the running backs well they could use a uh i guess they could use some more good receivers you know and
 	
 	
 		well didn't y'all lose your tight end also that uh
 	
 	
 		yes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navarro</ENAMEX> was terrific yeah they could use a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a couple</NUMEX> of really good tight ends they really they don't really have you know really you know super tight ends
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what happened
 		what happened to him did they trade him or did he go somewhere
 	
 	
 		Navarro he was uh injured and i don't know then he came back and then they released him
 	
 	
 		is that i couldn't remember what happened to him
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		because uh he was good
 	
 	
 		oh he was terrific he was like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Novacek Novacek</ENAMEX> is
 		
 		
 	