
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		this is a real easy topic for me to spend at least
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">thirty minutes</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> on i vacation
 	
 	
 		i don't think they'll let us talk that long
 	
 	
 		yeah i know it i know it you say vacation i just say where i love to go i've and i've been lucky enough i've traveled quite a bit <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rio uh Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh you've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's wonderful i'm envious
 	
 	
 		yeah i was
 		i was lucky enough uh when i was uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years old</TIMEX> back when the the dollar was really strong i mean it was you know still the keen currency i convinced my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to let me take off a month and go backpacking in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		that's memories you'll never ever have again probably
 	
 	
 		it oh not never and uh you know and i've just i went everywhere and it's you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX>
 		what was your favorite country
 	
 	
 		uh well jeez if i had to pick <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> country i guess i would have to say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i think so because uh it was just the the history was just so staggering whenever you know you walked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">coliseum</ENAMEX>
 		and uh you realized how many <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> it was you know and you could just imagine the uh the gladiators and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">lions</ENAMEX> and it was you know
 		pretty pretty staggering to think of and then of course then the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Roman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">forum</ENAMEX> that's even older than that that's just ruins and uh but the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> was good the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were nice and there was just so much to see and do
 	
 	
 		well
 		that was probably before we were the ugly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		well actually back then like i said it was this is in nineteen seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and uh  uh you know i did the whole trip uh airfare uh everything
 		for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">less than a thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh  not even sure you could get airfare
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right and i and i stayed gone a month
 	
 	
 		golly
 	
 	
 		yeah now of course that was back when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX> for uh this uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Arthur Frommer</ENAMEX> had a book out it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> a day
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so we budgeted and we said well we'll be extravagant we budgeted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars a day
 	
 	
 		i love it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and and we stuck kept in that budget and had just really perfect
 	
 	
 		wow
 		who'd you go with
 	
 	
 		i went with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine uh that i'd been in high school with actually he and i we were in college at the time and we were talking about going to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> taking a little trip uh up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> got out
 		and we started adding up you know totaling how much it was going to cost and i said hell we could go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> for that he said well why don't we and i said you know we did i'm i'm really happy that that we did do that
 	
 	
 		why don't we
 		wow i've always wanted to go like to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well and i've i've i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> several times since then um
 		and that is i could go back anytime
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		anytime
 	
 	
 		well i teach literature and at
 		the high school level and consequently i teach all about these wonderful places in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> especially and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Canterbury Cathedral</ENAMEX> and you know all of these places and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and never seen them somehow now that doesn't seem fair
 	
 	
 		well
 		well i um uh
 		had a job for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> that i traveled just an awful lot
 		and uh as a matter of fact i stayed gone more than i stayed at home yeah for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four years</TIMEX> and i built up an awful lot of mileage so i've made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> just using airfare you know airline mileage and so that's how i've been able to make make those trips
 	
 	
 		um
 		gee
 		of all the places you visited then what is your one spot
 		for a vacation that you would love to go back to
 	
 	
 		i i would go back to uh if i could go back anywhere right now i think i would go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um why is that
 	
 	
 		and
 		well because uh we i didn't go any farther north
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Edinburgh</ENAMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was over there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and he uh uh went to on a driving tour all up through the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Scottish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">highlands</ENAMEX> and just came back just raving about how wonderful it was very very scenic very
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		beautiful and it's it's a part of the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that's a little bit off the beaten path there're not as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourists</ENAMEX> that go out there and i enjoyed uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> so much but i could go back listen i could go back into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day of the week</TIMEX> and the beautiful thing about that is
 		you could take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> and head any direction it doesn't make any difference and take these fabulous day trips and anywhere you go is interesting
 		and uh
 		the last time we went we found this really uh
 		small kind of quaint <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> actually we found it over there on the trip before but stayed in it the last time that was reasonable reasonable and uh just used that as a base and then took day trips on the trains the train system is wonderful which makes me
 		wonder when we'll ever get our act together here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and have a and have a decent um uh transportation system but we'd just take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> trips and that was that was a nice way to do it
 	
 	
 		isn't that the truth
 		did you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Germany</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have been yeah we went the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i went over there i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX> and stayed right across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from one of the original medieval beer halls
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		
 		
 	