
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right i i like keep forgetting to make these calls i've been on this list for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> and i think i've made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> calls
 	
 	
 		oh really i just
 		oh i just got <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and i haven't started yet because i wanted to get one first see how it worked
 	
 	
 		right
 		well they do have some kind of nice prizes and it's worth doing and i'm so mad i think i've had this for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX>
 		and like i've said i've made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> calls and lot of times we don't answer the phone probably when i get mine <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the evening</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		really yeah
 	
 	
 		well we're supposed to talk about movies have you been to any lately
 	
 	
 		i have i was trying to think of the one i went to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of weeks ago</TIMEX> but i forgot it already
 	
 	
 		uh i really haven't seen one since probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> because uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every weekend</TIMEX> in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> we go to our high school <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football game</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> then we go out with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> after and that's kind of the
 	
 	
 		oh
 		that's your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> yeah really
 	
 	
 		our social  for the but oh i saw uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> which i didn't care for
 	
 	
 		really i didn't see that because i didn't think i would care for it
 	
 	
 		no and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> dragged me to it i like i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX>'s a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> and he's nice looking but he just to me is not a very dynamic actor
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah i think that's why a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go to see him though  right right
 	
 	
 		i guess because he is good looking i don't know oh i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Slickers</ENAMEX> did you see that was a that's the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> i saw i think
 	
 	
 		yes i did see that and i really enjoyed that
 	
 	
 		i did too i thought that was so cute and
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought that was appropriate just for everyone yeah that was great
 	
 	
 		oh i do too oh i i really enjoyed that
 	
 	
 		yeah and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> went to see that one too so it was fine for her
 	
 	
 		and
 		right which most of them probably aren't  i don't know what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> see any more my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> so they've probably seen about everything at this point
 	
 	
 		so yeah
 		right well that's right
 		probably they have them my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> is twelve
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and we had a sleep over <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> they wanted to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> which i have and i was hesitant and they all had seen it anyway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh i know it that's the way it is
 	
 	
 		and they're all twelve so
 	
 	
 		we can see some pretty raunchy stuff on on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just regular</TIMEX> TV without cable or even you know there's no way to protect them any more
 	
 	
 		yes they do yes they do
 		right but i i love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Roberts</ENAMEX>'s movies but i didn't think they were great for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 		no right it'll teach a great lesson because she ended up so in so well  but it was a fun movie to watch
 	
 	
 		no
 		really really
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">i love Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> and then i like that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after that where oh what was it it was like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX> thing yeah
 	
 	
 		oh the scary one oh yeah i didn't see that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Predator</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't remember the name of it but that was so good
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		that was really excellent
 	
 	
 		oh i like scary ones that are realistic
 	
 	
 		yeah that that was  that was
 	
 	
 		they say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cape Fear</ENAMEX> is really frightening too <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cape</ENAMEX> Fear the new one that came out
 	
 	
 		what was
 		oh i don't know
 	
 	
 		they say it's really horrifyingly scary but uh i'd never get my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> to that he doesn't like to be scared
 	
 	
 		really
 		oh  the last scary thing i saw was Misery
 	
 	
 		oh and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> both saw that they liked it
 	
 	
 		i that scared me to death and i watched it at a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> on video and i was just oh yes it was horrible it was so awful
 	
 	
 		it was still scary oh my gosh
 		i know that one sounded gross i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> wouldn't have stood for that he means he likes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Poppins</ENAMEX> and things yeah
 	
 	
 		really
 		i like that too i like funny movies and i like scary movies
 	
 	
 		i do too i really i really like a variety
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		where you from
 	
 	
 		i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i was gonna say well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and we lived there for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> when we <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got married and so it sound kind of nice so was familiar  your accent
 	
 	
 		is he really
 		oh
 		yeah yes it's so close because i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Long Island</ENAMEX> so that's close you know that's more related to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> than it is to like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester New York</ENAMEX> those that kind of thing
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right
 		i don't know they talk up there
 	
 	
 		yeah different it's it's different yeah i guess
 	
 	
 		just uh different um-hum
 		well see the accents up there fascinated me because even in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> alone there were several different accents the way they would pronounce words differently
 	
 	
 		oh
 		really
 	
 	
 		and and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> they lived in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> there most of them were <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty or so</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		really and they were all from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> hum
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum and they lived you know they never moved into <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> when they were young they always stayed at home until they got married it seemed to be the custom up there or they went in the service and so they were together for all that time
 	
 	
 		really yeah
 	
 	
 		but they still had the accents differed a little in the family
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		so and it
 	
 	
 		when did you live there
 	
 	
 		uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> i finally i finally
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX>  yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really i converted him to being a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> i i just thought life would be i knew it was easier back here
 	
 	
 		are you from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well sort of i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> brat but i was real familiar with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas i</ENAMEX> went to college here and everything
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and i just thought you know we could probably get a better <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and life is a little slower a little easier and he loves it he he really would never want to leave so it worked out
 	
 	
 		it is it is yeah
 		i'm used to it now so i like
 	
 	
 		probably hard when you first came
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		was it hard when you first came
 	
 	
 		oh yes it was because we're here eighteen years
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		and you can imagine what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plano</ENAMEX> was like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i know oh compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> oh yes
 	
 	
 		it was very difficult
 		yeah it was very very difficult i didn't even want to talk
 	
 	
 		you all transferred
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX>'s from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and they were he got a
 		
 		
 	