
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		my TV down
 		okay i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> invasions of privacy um what most annoys me are all sorts of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		phone calls trying to to sell me things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all all sorts of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> calling and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		especially with it being that i want investment advice that i want this service or that service or the other thing
 	
 	
 		yes and i hate those  canned messages they put on my recorder
 	
 	
 		um
 		my sense is that something may just have been done about it by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">congress</ENAMEX> and not clear
 		just what went into the
 		even the final will i think it does something about the random dialers that just dial phone numbers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i guess in some cases they just consider pickup your
 		your phone and and and not let you use your phone for a while whether you hang up on them or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um  but i thought i saw something about having some kind of provision that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could specify that their phones were
 		not for commercial use and and uh and uh people <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> would be prohibited uh from calling for purposes for purposes of of selling you things i'm sure that's true
 	
 	
 		i have through the phone company um  no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine hundred</NUMEX> numbers can be dialed  from my phone or received
 	
 	
 		ah  something i probably should do too i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> can do that now is that right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh especially with with possibly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> around um that could could be useful protection
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yes and i don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> around but i just don't like those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine hundred</NUMEX> numbers
 		so i've excluded those
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		but isn't it does not stop you from the uh dialing services
 	
 	
 		i should do that
 		what are dialing services
 	
 	
 		where they uh intend to sell you things
 	
 	
 		oh oh where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just  just call you
 	
 	
 		um-hum um-hum and leave again that canned message on the
 	
 	
 		um yes
 		what another problem that has been eliminated those problems used to be when i used a credit card
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they'd want to have my phone number
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i did not like giving it out or even give out my work number
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but i think i'm not sure if it's by law or just
 		otherwise i think the practice has basically been eliminated of asking for a phone number
 	
 	
 		well that's the thing i hated too about uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Shack</ENAMEX>
 		if you go in and buy anything they want your phone number
 	
 	
 		how did <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio Shack</ENAMEX> work
 	
 	
 		and i don't think they're gonna call me and ask me how it's functioning
 		and and i don't give that out i have an unlisted number so i don't
 	
 	
 		yes that's that's that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> solution but you you you nonetheless often get get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> calling you
 	
 	
 		sir
 	
 	
 		despite the fact that your number is unlisted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you believe they actually have your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> or are they just calling a number that happens to be yours
 	
 	
 		well  anything that you buy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		you can you may get put on a a uh
 		preferred list that is purchased
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> can purchase this list and what that is is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who buy from the mail
 	
 	
 		yeah and they so whole list of addresses and list of phone numbers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i don't particularly mind the addresses
 		um
 		is there anything you can do about that
 		like give out a phony phone number
 	
 	
 		uh not
 		not really
 		um no uh  that unfortunately is legal
 		so
 		they can't stop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from uh uh advertising
 		and that and that's what it falls under it falls under the guise of advertising
 		so i don't care for it but
 		it is a legal uh uh solution
 		for some companies
 		so
 		but that's the way things are
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i don't know i think it's gotten much worse the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe that's just because i've gotten on more lists
 	
 	
 		well they you know that's that's the telephone is not the only invasion of privacy you've got the holy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rollers</ENAMEX> and you've got uh all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> knocking on your door
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		um
 		who want to uh
 		either direct you to the right path or or or want to uh sell you uh paper routes uh whatever
 		so um you know it's not just the phone telephone
 	
 	
 		yeah sell you magazines
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i guess for whatever reason i guess we just don't get
 		
 		
 	