
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay we're on uh recycling and uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i am not real well informed on exactly what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> does i know that we uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they ask us to bundle our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and we do that and we recycle our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> pop cans and stuff
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		but now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> has quite an elaborate system don't they
 	
 	
 		yeah they do uh it started out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years ago</TIMEX> when they put these uh collection sites
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they uh near a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> near a the football <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> and the like
 		and they just couldn't believe how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were going out of their way to fill these things up these huge dumpsters were being filled up in a in a matter of a week
 		so they knew that there was something going on here so they started looking into programs
 		and what we have now it they changed the whole way that they do garbage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> instead of collecting plastic bags of garbage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> a week
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they make a collection on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> for yard waste
 		and the yard waste has to be put in the special bag that's a decomposable paper sack
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a pretty good size it's maybe the size of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX>
 		um grocery bags
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and we put that out by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and they collect those on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and then on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
 		we put out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> containers that they gave us one container's a huge green monstrous thing that a uh a special truck comes by and hooks onto the side of it and flips the container into the
 		back of the garbage <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> so and that's where you put your regular
 		um garbage and trash
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and then also that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">same day</TIMEX> you put out a small tub
 		uh it's maybe <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two feet</NUMEX> high and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three feet by two feet</NUMEX> wide
 		and you put just throw in your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> and your milk jugs
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> and then they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and then they recycle they separate it
 	
 	
 		exactly they have a big truck that has like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> uh not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> big doors on the side of it they throw the different stuff in the different doors
 	
 	
 		oh that's a neat system
 	
 	
 		yeah it is and apparently it's you know it it went off pretty much without a hitch the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> the special <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> door <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> were a little tough in getting because of something to do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> war
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> were being the engines or something were being shipped over there for something or other
 		but it it does work pretty well
 	
 	
 		well i know our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and daughter-in-law live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> and i know they have commented on the system i don't know that they know that it worked that way but they have the two separate containers and stuff
 	
 	
 		oh yes uh-huh i noticed something interesting the last time i guess <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two Wednesdays ago</TIMEX> when they were picking up i happened to be out there in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 		when they were picking up the that tub stuff and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who was doing the separating when he was done emptying the tub he took a little electronic reader device off of his belt
 		and he read the bar code that was on the side of the tub
 		so they must be collecting information about who does it and how often
 	
 	
 		oh that is interesting does i wonder if that means that if you don't do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you suppose they will  come and knock on your door and
 	
 	
 		i i don't know but i think that's a really interesting question
 	
 	
 		that that is interesting you know will you be penalized if you don't will you you know uh
 	
 	
 		yeah that that seems far-fetched only because
 		it it it there's no law that says you have to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> or pop cans or milk jugs so there there's it's possible that there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> that doesn't buy any of those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> things
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and therefore wouldn't have
 	
 	
 		that's true except that it's hard to match and you know when you have uh cans you know from the the market and uh you know vegetable cans and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 		no they won't take vegetable cans just just the aluminum pop cans
 	
 	
 		oh they don't take vegetable cans this is just their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> cans well then yes it is possible that's interesting i wonder uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		yeah what they're doing with that
 	
 	
 		wouldn't you really like to know
 	
 	
 		i would someday i'm sure we'll find out
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i'm sure you know if nothing else call the sanitation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> say okay what are you doing reading you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum so tell me what your feelings on recycling is it do you think this is a good thing or silly
 	
 	
 		i think it's a very good thing i think that uh
 		i think it helps that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> is giving you a nudge
 		to do it because i think there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't do it and i can't say that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i are real real conscientious we got started on the aluminum cans because our uh
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandson</ENAMEX> was collecting them uh to raise money and uh stuff for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> he was in so we started collecting them and now he's through so we've we've just we've kept on
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yes
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's interesting too that we have to drive we drive to Plano up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano Road</ENAMEX>
 		to uh just inside your city limits to
 		you know turn them in to dump them in i sure there's bound to be some here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> but we just haven't really seen them advertised or you know something and
 	
 	
 		dump them off yeah and that is interesting
 		right
 		yeah well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each day</TIMEX> in fact has a a little list of all the recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> for all the different things they publish it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every single day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's interesting
 	
 	
 		yeah and phone numbers and and that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i haven't noticed uh i haven't noticed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> you know making that big a deal
 		
 		
 	