
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what do you uh  how do you feel about your uh
 		job benefits
 	
 	
 		well i'm a contract <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and uh so i don't have a lot of benefits and uh
 		uh i do think they're very important my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has medical insurance and he has a life insurance policy his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> does not really have a retirement plan and i think that's something that's very important
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i believe medical insurance and retirement are probably the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> strongest
 	
 	
 		yeah well i um  i worked for a
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most important
 	
 	
 		a large oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and then resigned in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> and went into business for myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and what i discovered
 		at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after i had resigned it was kind of amazing i had never really thought about that corporate umbrella
 	
 	
 		yes  right
 	
 	
 		while while it was there and after i resigned and i walked out from under it i really felt exposed and it was something that i had been completely you know you grow accustomed to having that behind you or or or over you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah you sort of take it for granted
 	
 	
 		absolutely and it was i'll i'll tell you i was absolutely amazed at how at at the difference and then  plus whenever i had to start paying for my own health insurance
 	
 	
 		oh i know isn't that a shock
 	
 	
 		and and life insurance  believe me it was it was a rude awakening  so anyway i was in business for myself for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX> and then i have gone back to work uh since uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> nineteen ninety i'm back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> with another oil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> so i'm back under that corporate umbrella and i will tell you i am glad to have the coverage again
 	
 	
 		well we uh kind of discovered it when uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was with
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> was in real estate and he had some nice benefits with it and all of a sudden when the market dropped out up here of course then you know everything kind of went downhill
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		and then he went with a steel company
 		and they they folded but he was still under the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COBRA</ENAMEX> plan on the medical insurance
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then all of a sudden the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that had taken it over went bankrupt well that ended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COBRA</ENAMEX> plan plan and everything and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then we discovered and our medical insurance for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months</TIMEX> was running us uh
 		i think it was nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		holy-moly
 	
 	
 		you know our age and uh i had some <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">arthritis</ENAMEX> and stuff and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they socked it to us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know course now fortunately we we're back we have some medical insurance
 	
 	
 		well
 		well i feel like i'm i'm the luckiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in the world on in several ways number one i had the opportunity to get out whenever i left um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Houston</ENAMEX> in uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> and resigned i had the opportunity to get out and do all those things that i thought would be so glamorous and exciting wording working for myself
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they were and they were for a while and then i found out that it was just as much work to do that as it is going into an office you know getting on a plane and flying around and all that kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		what did you do consulting work
 	
 	
 		well no actually i was uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and i had a architectural design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> we did uh retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> finish out all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and it was
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know very successful and a lot of fun and more work than i've ever done in my life and at the same time i got all of that out of my system and it is so it's so wonderful now and i'm so appreciative too of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">and</ENAMEX> and i know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		now i think so much better than some of my coworkers what it means
 		to and have somebody that's providing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some of this stuff for you and uh you know i'm real lucky my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has good uh health benefits and dental
 	
 	
 		benefits um-hum
 	
 	
 		and also uh retirement plan on a contributory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">thrift</ENAMEX> plan that i'm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was just thinking about that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> i need to up my contribution to that if i can force myself to save a little bit more
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i know that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> he's with now has excellent uh hospitalization and prescription card and dental insurance but they have no retirement
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		benefits and you know we definitely you know miss this i grew up in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that had their own business you cannot pay me enough money
 		to go into business for myself and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>  has watched my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i don't believe you could pay him enough
 	
 	
 		yeah well i tell you until you've done it you don't know what it's like you you it's on your mind <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty four hours a day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven days a week</TIMEX> and i'm i literally drove myself nearly insane i was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> i'd get up at
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum um-hum you're always
 	
 	
 		i'd get up at i'd be sitting around at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at nine nine o'clock at night</TIMEX> and get up and go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and work until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one o'clock</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you you know and
 	
 	
 		well and you think you know okay  you know are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> going to get paid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>  you know are we going to meet our and i
 	
 	
 		precisely precisely and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> get paid and you don't
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right i can remember my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> saying somebody saying they wished you know <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX> wasn't so high you know they could only afford <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> said if someone doesn't buy some beef i'm not gonna be able to afford the chicken
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and uh
 	
 	
 		well i'll tell you i'll tell you the odds are definitely stacked against the small business person
 	
 	
 		they they really are they really are cold um
 	
 	
 		uh the problem that we ran into is that you know we we  got beyond just being a real time
 		
 		
 	