
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um i guess when i think of camping i think of going out and setting up a tent and
 		and uh cooking out and that kind of thing what do you think of it as
 	
 	
 		well yeah that's exactly what i think of too when
 		that's the way i think of camping in a tent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not comfortably
 	
 	
 		well i know we used to do that when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were younger and uh we could uh
 		we even had it fixed up where we could setup a tent and have a have supper ready in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about thirty minutes</TIMEX>
 		so it worked out real well for us then have you ever done that
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's great well when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> had all different kinds of travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		whatever he liked he had a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> and he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Winnebago</ENAMEX> and he had a truck <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">camper</ENAMEX> and
 		he was always buying new things like that and i hated it i i hated going camping and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		when when i got older i liked things like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caesar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Palace</ENAMEX> you know that's where i like to stay and and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah  and oh okay you can't you're gonna <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> out at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Caesar's Palace</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		uh right exactly so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boyfriend</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		and he loves to go camping and he said let's go camping and i went
 		and i loved it  and so my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> couldn't believe it you went camping  but it was nice it's peaceful and quiet and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		different perspective
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was just nice and i sat there and thought what do i have at home that i need that i don't have here  and i couldn't really think of anything so
 	
 	
 		right
 		now where did what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> did you go camping in
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> in the mountains
 	
 	
 		oh yeah now that's so peaceful
 	
 	
 		it was just beautiful and um it wasn't very crowded it was during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> and it was just wonderful
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so that was nice  so i guess i do like camping
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i think it depends on probably as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> you didn't feel that you left your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> at home and you didn't like there's much to do
 	
 	
 		right that's exactly right boring to me
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		what kind of places did your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> go to when they camped in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh they went all over
 	
 	
 		just uh various <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean they they even moved they did they went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> like um well we lived on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and things like that you know not far away and then to the extreme um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they sold everything and bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> trailer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh moved
 		to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>  and pulled it behind us and that was really funny because i mean it's funny now it wasn't funny then an all these very strange things happened i mean it was just really
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		no
 		hm
 		well let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wildwood</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> did you go there
 	
 	
 		i think they said
 		yes yes we did  that's exactly where we went
 	
 	
 		aha
 		i thought you might i understand that's a very popular place if you live in that area
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah lots of uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh some of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> had always talked about and what got me they never went anywhere on vacation but to Wildwood
 	
 	
 		and did they camp out probably
 	
 	
 		i
 		i'm you know i'm they'd go to the go to the shore go to the shore and we said you know really there are other places in the world
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah i wouldn't like to go to the same place all the time
 	
 	
 		but
 		hum-um but they we have these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> he went to high school with that they go to the same place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and have for the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's boring to me too
 	
 	
 		well
 		i you know i guess it's fine if they like it but i like to move around a little bit
 	
 	
 		well there's so many places to go you if you went to a different one every time you couldn't see them all so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's true and they each have their own special beauty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		have you ever been um up to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Lake Texoma</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		that's pretty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they have a a park up there uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower Park</ENAMEX> have you been there
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah i have it's been a long long time though
 	
 	
 		now that's where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> used to like to go
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now they like to go out and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">fish</ENAMEX> and things like that and course they go and do their own thing since they're grown but
 		they uh
 		they still talk about our camping trips so maybe they didn't dislike them so much
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure
 	
 	
 		but uh are you planning to go on any more camping trips
 	
 	
 		well i don't know
 	
 	
 		well if you get invited huh
 	
 	
 		if i get invited maybe yeah
 	
 	
 		all right
 		that sounds good
 	
 	
 		if i find time
 	
 	
 		yeah you stay pretty busy here then
 	
 	
 		that's the hard part
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		what's about your ideal time when you go camping how long do you have like to go
 	
 	
 		how long to go for
 	
 	
 		no how many how many how many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week a two weeks a few days</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		um i i don't know we've only gone that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five</NUMEX>
 		
 		
 	