
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		do you have any do you have any uh major preferences as far as television
 	
 	
 		TV um
 		trying to think i was trying to think of some while they were calling you um
 		i like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> what is it is it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> shows i think it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		all the um the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with the two little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> in it what's it called
 	
 	
 		yeah uh oh uh
 	
 	
 		or three little girls
 	
 	
 		yeah the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> play the
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> play that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the the youngest girl
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		right i really like that what's it called
 		i trying
 	
 	
 		um
 		i don't know all i can think of is the name of all of them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> but that's not it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Full</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah there you go yeah i really like that show
 	
 	
 		yeah that is good i i like uh we have cable i really like watching the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nick at Nite</ENAMEX> shows you know where you get to watch <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dragnet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mister Ed</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh we we can watch those <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">all night</TIMEX> sometimes and  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Reed</ENAMEX>  yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh really
 		um lately i've been getting into talk shows and  yeah just you know controversy and
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		which which which one do which ones do you like
 	
 	
 		just really whatever just as long it depends on the subject actually where where it's more interesting some of them get pretty boring but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah uh  there's that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i think it's out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> his name is um
 		oh i wish i could remember his name
 	
 	
 		is he one of the talk show guys
 	
 	
 		yeah he's he's black and yeah no he's black and has a bald <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name starts with an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maury Povich</ENAMEX>
 		hum let's see
 	
 	
 		oh it's like his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlo Marlo or Marlin</ENAMEX>
 		i can't remember his name anyway he always has like really strange shows like uh
 		uh  male strippers or female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strippers</ENAMEX> or  really sensationalistic you know uh like what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldo</ENAMEX> used to be
 	
 	
 		yeah it something
 		yeah see i don't i don't like those i like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't either it'd
 	
 	
 		more controversial subjects i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i mean
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah do you watch cartoons a lot
 	
 	
 		no  i'm
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i don't watch TV that much uh anymore anymore it seems like uh i'm going to school right now so
 	
 	
 		oh yeah where you going to school
 	
 	
 		BYU
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah so and i'm working too so everything keeps me pretty busy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh i'm going to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTD</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 		oh really my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> taught there for a while yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really what did he teach
 	
 	
 		um speech pathology
 	
 	
 		that's what i'm majoring in i'm a graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in speech
 	
 	
 		oh wow no way how long have you been there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah uh this is my first semester
 	
 	
 		oh okay so you wouldn't know him he
 	
 	
 		yeah who
 		who who who who what when did he teach
 	
 	
 		hum
 		um he taught <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a year ago</TIMEX> he used to work at um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">um University of Texas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> what no
 		um oh shoot i can't remember what it's even called now but um he worked there for like fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and then part time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTD</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and and then they stopped funding the program there
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and so now he's at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Women's University</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh is he teaching speech pathology there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay what's his name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Bird</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> B I R D
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		yeah he published a paper uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple of years ago</TIMEX> i think didn't he well well one that i read does he publish a little quite a bit
 	
 	
 		um some what and he has he has some like different programs out like
 		i don't know what they're called but they're like in he has little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals stuffed animals</ENAMEX> with him and like little cards and stuff i don't know exactly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah okay i yeah he has a test he has a testing yeah a testing battery he uses real yeah i remember i remember yeah well that's interesting
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh what are you studying
 	
 	
 		um i was i am studying nursing but i'm thinking about changing right now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i just i don't know and it's really tough to get into the program down here so if i don't do that if i decide to stay in nursing i'll probably come and go to TWU
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TWU</ENAMEX> dorm across from Collier uh yeah and all
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> used to teach at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Collier</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's that's where the speech program is in uh i'm living in that dorm and there all those nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> i i tell you what that's that's a tough that's a tough uh
 		field though nursing is i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i have a lot of respect for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean they spend a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> studying
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you're at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baylor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>  yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		oh okay <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young</ENAMEX> i see all right
 	
 	
 		so but i get to come home and on the nineteenth and i'm so excited  so homesick
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		do you do you do you like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt</ENAMEX> it's it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		it's in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Provo</ENAMEX> actually but yeah i really i really like it out here but i've been i i've been away too long
 	
 	
 		oh it
 		do you
 		um-hum i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> so i i've been away from there too long
 	
 	
 		um huh how
 		
 		
 	