
 
     		
 	
 		now we're ready  yeah i had a
 	
 	
 		
  
 		there we go
 		okay
 	
 	
 		a family reunion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year first time</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many many years</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i had uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> there with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and we all got together in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gatlinburg Tennessee</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh great
 		oh
 	
 	
 		spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> there up in the mountains and rented a little little house little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		how nice
 	
 	
 		sort of visited and got to know each other we hadn't been been around each other for quite a while over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> so it really was sort of nice
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well that is nice was it was it awkward at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> or did it work out fairly fairly good
 	
 	
 		well it worked out fairly well you know as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i don't know about yourself but we used to have big reunions and it was so nice and
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		you know it's just something that you don't do anymore and uh we had such a good time that
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that we're already deciding to have one in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> say in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney World</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">somewhere</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> just get together and
 	
 	
 		oh great uh-huh
 	
 	
 		just something you need to make time for
 	
 	
 		now are you from from quite a ways away from each other so that you don't see each other real often
 	
 	
 		yes we are  we're sort of uh we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and i have
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sisters</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina West Virginia Virginia Florida</ENAMEX> everywhere  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		so we don't get to see each other very often
 	
 	
 		oh yes okay well we have um
 		several different reunions
 		when i was like you say when i was growing up we had a lot of family reunions and they were the extent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> and you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">great-aunts</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncles</ENAMEX> and
 		um those have dwindled down to just we go to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> we have one at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas time</TIMEX> and it's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		sure
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		yes it is and it and these are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that we see you know just once maybe twice a year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we get together then and have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> party and
 		and you know have a dinner and a program and renew acquaintances and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we we go camping up in up in the mountains like you mentioned yes it is it's fun
 	
 	
 		well that's neat
 		which you in a great area for it
 	
 	
 		yes we are there's lots of lots of nice places to go and i know some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> have a real formal type thing where they send out
 		the letters and um  assignments and have parts on the programs and quilt drawings and stuff we we don't do anything that big you know
 	
 	
 		uh i admire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do that but we're just not that well organized and you know everyone's heading different directions so it's very hard to get together
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 		yes that is in fact i in a in a magazine i'd read an article about different ways to plan a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> reunion and
 		you know if you had a real big like you say a real big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> and a lot of
 		a lot of planning went into it that would that would be great but we tend to stick to the
 		call each other and you know that we plan on those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that i mentioned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> for sure but
 	
 	
 		sure that's the important thing just the important thing is to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and that's great
 	
 	
 		that's right because you you do you forget
 		the the cousins i have uh they grow up and change and you know you wouldn't even recognize them sometimes other than these these times that you get together
 	
 	
 		oh you bet
 	
 	
 		so do you have any with your extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or is it mostly your your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		mostly my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> right now but as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> we we haven't done that like i said before it's God in just forever i don't know how we'd ever get all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cousins</ENAMEX> together you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's like it's like high school reunion high school and college reunions uh i didn't go i'm i just turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years old</TIMEX> recently and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		didn't go to many reunions until i hit my twentieth i believe and of course i haven't missed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> since then because it's just so enjoyable
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you get to see all your old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and what's going on and it's just a it's a neat deal i look i look forward to them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		boy i'll say yeah so do you when you have your when you got together with your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> did was there a lot of catching up to do
 	
 	
 		oh yes
 	
 	
 		a lot of changes that had happened since the last time
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids kids</ENAMEX> getting older getting married and graduating high school and college and whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		just lots of things to catch up on and and we spent that time to do that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> did you get take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with you or was it the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no this was this was just for the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> just for the parents
 	
 	
 		oh how fun oh that's fun
 	
 	
 		it was sort of neat though in fact we uh we had a little rule that we would we would not take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with us this time but all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are a little older so
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 		that that makes a big difference
 	
 	
 		yes all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are in a middle and high school and college so and married so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		so we just all got together and it was sort of neat
 	
 	
 		that is that is that's it's a fun thing to do and i think it's important that we keep doing that because everybody is so busy you lose you lose
 		you lose touch and you lose ties
 	
 	
 		you bet because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> both were there so it really paid off
 	
 	
 		oh were they
 	
 	
 		yeah it was neat and and and her <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were there and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> so it worked out real well
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i'll say yes i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> are scattered all around too and that's you know
 	
 	
 		are they
 	
 	
 		yes they're  they're all over the place
 		
 		
 	