
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay um well actually i don't really cook  um i'm i'm still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> in college and um
 	
 	
 		you don't
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i'm fortunate to have my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom  cook</ENAMEX> dinners for me so i'm not not very experienced because um
 	
 	
 		okay i'm i'm a single <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> so i i guess i have to do a lot of cooking for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh yeah
 		hm well i have cooked like small dinners like just <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hamburgers</ENAMEX> and things like that and canned <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> that you just heat up nothing great though so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		okay well i was born in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisiana</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was Italian so i can
 		i'm familiar with you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cajun</ENAMEX> food <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian Portuguese</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cajun</ENAMEX> food's really good i've had that before in uh Mississippi
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> that's it
 		yeah i've i've had all kinds of different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">foods</ENAMEX> i travel a lot but  never cooked it myself so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		you all have some pretty good cheese up there don't you
 	
 	
 		pardon me
 	
 	
 		say y'all have a lot of good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheeses</ENAMEX> up there though
 	
 	
 		cheeses oh yeah  yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i kind of miss that up <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh i said
 		there <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Portuguese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> in me and i kind of miss the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheeses</ENAMEX>  because in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> only get a bunch of domestic stuff you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		oh i love <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food though it's probably my favorite kind of food
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food i don't think i've ever had <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		well it's mostly they eat a lot of stews and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soups</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		what is that it's
 	
 	
 		a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> they they boil you know they boil or broil a lot of their food
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and it it's kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> except it's not quite as spicy as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		oh yeah hm
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> they though <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexicans</ENAMEX> use a lot of hot peppers where the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Portuguese</ENAMEX> use a lot of more garlic and stuff in the hot in the spicy food
 	
 	
 		a real lot
 		oh really
 		oh
 		so what do you like to make for you and your son
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh i like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> spaghetti the kind that you cook the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so it's real thick and all you know
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> make their own <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX> yeah it's really good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i don't i don't think i can go the the jar stuff  after after being spoiled by the real stuff
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son cooks</ENAMEX> a little bit he's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> he usually has supper cooked when i come home during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh that's great that's really good i wished i would've  cooked more when i was in high school
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah we're we're both in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> we learned to you know cook out over open fire in the woods and all
 	
 	
 		oh that's great that's good to know sure it comes in handy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah and you know like to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> Cajun <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> when i when i can get the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> it's kind of expensive in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i bet yeah
 	
 	
 		but sometimes we had
 		see we went into one of the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and they had uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Cajun blackened shark</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		and i tasted it and it taste pretty good and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX> was on sale so i bought some and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i'd eaten <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX> and cooked in it turned out real good
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 		hm i've never had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">shark</ENAMEX>  and i can't see it any
 	
 	
 		
 
 		it's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time for me and i didn't know i didn't know whether i'd ever eat it but i sampled it and it was it was all right uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's good i like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> but i hardly ever have it i haven't eaten it in a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah well you you live on campus or
 	
 	
 		um i used to i used to live in the dorm for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> but then i came back home i went to um
 		University of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison Madison</ENAMEX> so when you  eat eat in the dorms you know there's a big <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> already prepared for you
 	
 	
 		um-hum  right
 	
 	
 		so i didn't i didn't get a chance to cook much and now that i'm home my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s home so she <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		but i i do i make some things you know once in a while you know get hungry enough you're gonna cook for yourself but i'm still i'd like to learn you know i it's i like to bake i make cakes and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh you do
 	
 	
 		yeah i can do that but
 	
 	
 		okay i'm not very good at baking i'm you know good at cooking the main dishes
 	
 	
 		oh oh yeah
 		oh well i i'd like to learn how so it's one of my goals  i'm sure i will once i move out on my own
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah when i was living with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> she she tried to teach me how to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> and i wasn't interested then
 	
 	
 		see i'm not neither
 	
 	
 		yeah and then
 		once i moved out i miss her good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and i don't know how to cook it so i'm constantly looking up recipes or trying to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cook</ENAMEX> what what i remember eating when i was small and wished i'd you know i'd learned from her
 	
 	
 		yep yeah i should start doing that it it  takes a lot of time though doesn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah it it does
 		course my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> never followed recipes you know she just cooked to taste i guess most good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cooks</ENAMEX> do that anyway
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		they just add a little bit of that and a little bit of this and it comes out
 		
 		
 	