
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well let's see what have you seen lately
 	
 	
 		well uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Slickers</ENAMEX> and
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Trek Five</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 	
 	
 		yeah you only <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only five</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought i'd better see that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before i go and see <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		well nah didn't need to
 	
 	
 		no i found that out
 	
 	
 		i just saw the latest one
 	
 	
 		how about yourself
 		how is it
 	
 	
 		it was fantastic
 	
 	
 		oh i can't wait
 	
 	
 		yeah it's the the lines in there were just perfect i mean it was classic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trek</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		now does the old <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> meet the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		no it's just the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> still
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it was just a rumor that that would happen this time
 		however the rumor is is that it will happen next happen next time so
 	
 	
 		you know that i read in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> or somewhere no it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that they said they weren't gonna do anymore that was it
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah uh
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		except that the rumor is is that they still might but it may not include the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> and it will be a next generation meets this generation
 		
 
 	
 	
 		huh i'm not sure what the difference in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">light years</TIMEX> between the new generation and the the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> was
 	
 	
 		so
 		i think it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		somewhere in that range
 		considering that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spock</ENAMEX> was on an uh you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">couple weeks ago</TIMEX> and and that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the very</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> episode of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next Generation</ENAMEX> they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCoy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's right
 		is that right he was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> still
 	
 	
 		and um-hum yeah well you know he it was like a rear admiral whatever you know and he just kind of hobbled down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> real slow Vulcans age a lot better
 	
 	
 		well yeah he didn't look too bad did he
 	
 	
 		huh no huh-uh
 		matter of fact he looks just as about as old and the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Next Generation</ENAMEX> as he does in the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX>  imagine that
 	
 	
 		yes yeah that's amazing
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> did they have some pretty good special effects
 	
 	
 		oh excellent excellent special effects
 		but i think the script was you know just incredible compared to the last one
 	
 	
 		yeah Five was the script was bad bad bad  no i don't why
 	
 	
 		well you know why
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh William Shatner</ENAMEX> wrote it
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		and even worse he directed it
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Leonard it its Nimoy</ENAMEX> he does a lot better
 	
 	
 		oh yeah he in fact uh he didn't direct this one he produced this one
 		but he directed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> Four something like that
 	
 	
 		In <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Search of Spock or no Journey Home i</ENAMEX> think that
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		are you're a real life Trekkie
 	
 	
 		well i think so
 	
 	
 		i really like them i i wouldn't go so far as being a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trekkie</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i've gone to you know one for real live <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trek Convention</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah i saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Doohan</ENAMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that plays uh Scotty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">huh</ENAMEX> did you get to talk to him
 	
 	
 		no  not in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> like that huh-uh it was like uh want an autograph wanna stand in line for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about four hours</TIMEX>   it was a pretty crowded place
 	
 	
 		it was crowded no
 		yeah wow
 		huh they have some good management <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principals</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Generation</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah i it's it's kind of funny i uh was reading in uh a book
 		uh trying to think i can't quite remember the name of the book but it was it was saying don't do <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Trek</ENAMEX> management style
 		and they were referring to you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Captain Kirk</ENAMEX> every time he left the Enterprise everything went to hell
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and and nothing got righted until he got back up on the ship
 	
 	
 		right and he kind of was a cowboy type too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he made all the decisions but uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Luke</ENAMEX> does more of a a committee type of management
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um-hum yeah um
 		it's definitely a lot better  a lot more realistic really
 	
 	
 		what other movies have you seen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> saw The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Addams Family</ENAMEX> last week
 	
 	
 		oh how was that
 	
 	
 		it was pretty good uh there were a few things different than the old series but on the on the whole it was pretty similar
 		and  a lot of fun
 	
 	
 		lots of little funny spots huh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		did they have Thing and
 	
 	
 		oh yes in fact Thing has a big much bigger role than he does in the series
 		i mean you know there is lots of areas where Thing saves <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and he runs around a lot
 	
 	
 		how did i've always wondered how he gets around
 	
 	
 		uh you know just finger hopping
 	
 	
 		but he's in a box right
 	
 	
 		no no no in fact it's funny he never did does come in out of a box i don't think and he's just kind of walking around
 	
 	
 		didn't he used to
 	
 	
 		not really he was always in the box before
 	
 	
 		oh
 		well that's yeah that's  okay yeah that's what i was thinking
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	