
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so i guess you're a Cowboy fan
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i guess we're sort of we're stuck with that down here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX> we have to be  but uh been it's been difficult suffering with them through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past few years</TIMEX> but it looks like they could be
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		you know on their way back a little bit
 	
 	
 		yeah what's what's the story with uh your quarterback though
 	
 	
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX>'s hurt right now he's gonna be out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple more weeks</TIMEX> at the very least and may miss the rest of the season
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		course if they're lucky enough to make the play-offs he may be ready for then
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		we're we're fortunate to have a
 		you know a a fairly good back up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> that's come in
 		but i tell you what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> uh
 		they love their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> i'm a i've been here since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy four</TIMEX> and uh they're quite easy to easily to get attached to
 		and uh we've got our new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX> which i we like we like what he's doing
 		they've forgotten about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Landry</ENAMEX>  he's a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">his day</TIMEX> but they've forgotten about him
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so who
 	
 	
 		yeah isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> were the tradition you know
 	
 	
 		oh yes who who's your favorite team
 	
 	
 		uh well it's kind of weird for me i'll tell you why <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all i used to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> when i grew up
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i grew up on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX> where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX> play uh i mean they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> but it's closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		uh then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> which were up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> uh but then around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty five</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> started playing really good defense and they started you know really not that i'm a fair weather fan
 		but they really started looking good you know so now i root for both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jets</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>
 		but i'm involved in this uh rotisserie league i don't know if you're familiar with those
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		well you draft <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> from different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 		so it's kind of you get points based on how many how many touch downs and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and</ENAMEX> and stuff like that that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> on all different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> uh make
 	
 	
 		well i'll be darned
 	
 	
 		so you get kind of caught up um  and now i got like you know players  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> on on like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and and i i happened to have uh your kicker
 	
 	
 		why sure
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micheal Irvin</ENAMEX> who was a great he's a great wide receiver and uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		so how how's your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> doing
 	
 	
 		so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s doing pretty good for for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i have i do have a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> um but they're not doing that much and uh i also have
 	
 	
 		well good
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> are having a sad year
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jet</ENAMEX> yeah they're not they're not looking too good um but you know it's always tough after you win a <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> i guess and
 	
 	
 		i know maybe we're maybe we're both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of the future huh
 	
 	
 		yeah and they they um they um i mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was just fantastic with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> it was just
 	
 	
 		oh we're well it was fantastic they had a hell of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a season</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah and it was such a i don't know maybe because i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> but but uh it was such a unbelievable run you know all the games were like won by field goals and stuff like that so it was
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 		they had a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> i think they're they're missing their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		most of all they're just they're in a rebuilding type of thing they've got they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX>'s down too right now so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the big thing  oops
 	
 	
 		i'm here
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		big big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>'s trying to come back hold just a second that's that's my other line
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		sorry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		that's all right
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so anyway <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>'s trying to bring them back right now i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah they got a big game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> i think if they win it they got a shot at getting into the play-offs but i don't think they're gonna win
 	
 	
 		who they play this weekend
 	
 	
 		they're playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh it's a big game yeah they play at up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no they play in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		play in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> well yeah
 		good chance there hope so
 	
 	
 		but i i don't know  <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all they don't they haven't done too well against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> lately
 	
 	
 		i think we
 		right and we just hope we just hope <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> makes it and of course all that depends on what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> does too so i don't know
 	
 	
 		and
 		
 
 		yeah i guess you got to pipe it off having the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> uh win <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> to knock out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's true because both our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> are like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are up what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		you know
 		um-hum but uh yeah i think i think i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> will make it i think that i think they're they're uh they're doing pretty well and i think that like if the season ended now they'd be in the play-offs so you just have to like win <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i hope so their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> play-off games travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> i believe and that's that'll be a tough <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on
 	
 	
 		really oh you never know i mean what's to you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> game up maybe they'll oh well they lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> already though didn't they this year yes so they can
 	
 	
 		right yeah it was there but they lost them playing there but uh still a tough game
 	
 	
 		well maybe they'll get lucky and not have to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> because that's a tough place to play lately
 	
 	
 		they
 		but you got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmett Smith</ENAMEX> versus <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Sanders it</ENAMEX> ought to be a little exciting be a good game anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> was hurt too they're all getting knocked down so maybe they have a better shot against this new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> because they haven't <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> hasn't played as well with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> as with
 	
 	
 		you bet
 	
 	
 		um i don't know i think i think his name's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kramer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and uh they used to have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney Pete</ENAMEX> who was doing really well for them and then he got hurt so
 	
 	
 		yeah he was doing well and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> they drafted from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> uh they gave all that money to
 	
 	
 		right yeah he's doing a lot
 	
 	
 		they've got a lot of high dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> i tell you
 	
 	
 		yeah well uh
 	
 	
 		what do you this is off the subject a little bit but what do you feel about the amount of money
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that are are making and uh the amount of time
 		
 		
 	