
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> my name is uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Donahue</ENAMEX> and i'm calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes how you doing did you uh press one
 	
 	
 		hi yes i did
 	
 	
 		oh guess we ought to get started i'm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay um let's see um i enjoy watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today Show</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early in the morning</TIMEX> with my first cup of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX> because everyone is still sleeping i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>  and
 		i enjoy watching the news because i probably don't have as much time as i'd like to read sit and read the paper  um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what about yourself
 	
 	
 		i like uh i would like probably like i think i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today Show</ENAMEX> on the rare occasions i get to watch it i uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one comes to mind uh without a lot of thought is uh Thirty Something which course is not on the air any more unfortunately  it was one of my favorite shows
 	
 	
 		um right
 		i
 		yeah i enjoyed that too i guess too also that was a nice one because it was  at a time when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are already in bed  um i
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh yeah and i was gonna say uh I'll Fly Away which uh
 		i think it was supposed to uh catch some of the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> as uh
 	
 	
 		uh i haven't had a chance to
 	
 	
 		we've been trying to watch that it's uh not quite as good i guess you got to get into it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		is it isn't it it set in a different era is it um was was it the fifties in the fifties or in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's uh it's about uh the civil rights struggle in the fifties
 	
 	
 		okay i didn't i've i've seen the commercials for it but it's not uh seem to be on at a good time for me  i try to stay away from horror movies i just dislike them totally
 	
 	
 		totally agree
 	
 	
 		yeah i i don't um  uh one
 	
 	
 		well i say violence and horror i just kind of lump them together
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's that's that's right and um with young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> we just really try to screen a lot of the things that they
 		they watch um we watch a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sesame Street</ENAMEX>  and a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBS</ENAMEX> and the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discover</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> or Lifetime
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah that's fantastic isn't it that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery Channel</ENAMEX> it's
 	
 	
 		yes it is it is it is wonderful and especially my  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> is just fascinated by some of the the things they have on there um
 		what else i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> enjoys watching a lot of sports which i really um don't particularly enjoy but  they're they're on you know i tolerate it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well i uh i like watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oilers</ENAMEX> and the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's about it i guess i'll watch that's about the only sports i really like to get into on TV
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and um what else is there's a lot of things that i just can't believe
 		is even on TV you watch it for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two minutes</TIMEX> and think this is so ridiculously stupid
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well one of the good things is having cable they uh
 		they uh now uh you know the choices are so
 		so  good and so uh variety variety there that you can really
 	
 	
 		you you can change it  you know what is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> too we uh subscribe to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney Channel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i think if my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were small small again we'd probably would too but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's a really nice and it they have um you know movies
 		that sometimes we'll sit and enjoy and it's it's really a very nice uh that was we dropped um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX> because there was just never anything appropriate on for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and now with renting videos so readily i mean you can just rent it if you really want to see it that badly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but
 	
 	
 		uh it's kind of a
 		toss up there whether the inconvenience of renting the video versus uh  there never seemed to be anything good on when we wanna watch it you know
 	
 	
 		that's right and then and then they repeat everything so often too and or if it's on at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> well
 		i i'm asleep by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> i don't think i could stay up that late any more  um not to start a movie anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah well that's true and uh then course they have the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pay-Per-View</ENAMEX> but our our channel uh system here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> is uh is not noted for being the greatest you know i think we kind of got the short end of the stick when uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		programming came around so
 	
 	
 		i see i see
 	
 	
 		they charge a lot that's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four dollars</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a half</NUMEX> or something like that per per view it seems a little high
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it that does that does seem high but um
 		what other there's a i guess one or two sitcoms and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> of course like to watch that new <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> show that's uh  which is pretty silly but but they
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		we used to watch uh when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would watch when the teenage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would watch that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bart Simpson</ENAMEX> that was pretty good
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah once in a while <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bryan</ENAMEX> watch that but that is more for an older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> than than the younger ones
 	
 	
 		yeah they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		you know so that that seems okay for them
 	
 	
 		i i like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Roseanne</ENAMEX> that's uh  Coach
 	
 	
 		i do too i had to try to tell my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that you know we don't really talk to each other like that i hope we don't anyway to make sure they don't think well gee mom
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		look what their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> just said said well but um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like to watch that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Doogie Howsner</ENAMEX> but that even that sometimes i have to shut it off and say and say it's an adult theme we don't need to watch that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> we'll we'll get out the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clue</ENAMEX> game or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or i'll suffer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parcheesi</ENAMEX> or something with them
 	
 	
 		at least you're exercising a little control
 		
 		
 	