
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh i haven't uh talked to anybody outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metroplex</ENAMEX> so i didn't even think of saying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington Texas</ENAMEX> this is a real first  are you at work
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 		yes i am
 	
 	
 		i i i've been trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thirty and six thirty</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> and i thought well i'm not having any luck i'll try <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the middle of the afternoon</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i'm i'm happy we got through
 	
 	
 		i am too well do you uh have any uh opinion on the subject
 	
 	
 		well i'm i'm especially interested with what what's happening in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> uh the the move to um
 		uh the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the the</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX>'s vote to uh basically to secede and set itself up independently
 	
 	
 		democracy
 		hm
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> is quite a remarkable
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		accomplishment is that is that reported in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> papers
 	
 	
 		oh sure well yeah we  we we hear a little of the news  uh God i have heard about that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last couple of days</TIMEX> how how big is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine</ENAMEX> the area do you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> as an area it's not
 	
 	
 		or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> or anything i'm really uninformed
 	
 	
 		i i'm afraid i don't have the statistics in front of me it said
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's not a tiny area um
 		if i was looking at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> map i would say it was sort of reminds me of of a uh
 		well it's not as big as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> proportionately maybe
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but but but it's it's more significant  in the sense of it's a great agricultural region
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i see oh i i didn't really know that i know a lot of their
 		oh their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that they had overtaken or wanted to be independent or several of them right and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estonia</ENAMEX> what about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Estonia</ENAMEX> are they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		they're they're completely out now
 	
 	
 		right i thought they were
 	
 	
 		yeah the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Baltic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">uh republics</ENAMEX> got out as quickly as they could
 	
 	
 		but but the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ukraine Ukraine</ENAMEX> is especially significant because it of the agriculture
 	
 	
 		right it's it's very important for the economics of the whole of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um so they would have a probably really fight to keep it in if they could
 	
 	
 		right right um except they can't fight  it's done done democratically um
 	
 	
 		no they don't
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has already given his  opinion on it right didn't i read that
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so now uh not that they may that may matter i don't know anymore  i um fear for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> from what i read you know i wonder how they're gonna get through the winter
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foodwise</ENAMEX> or any wise sounds to me like they'll start rioting soon or not that that would do any good but i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do that when they're desperate
 	
 	
 		that that's true uh
 		hasn't happened here for a while but it um
 	
 	
 		well that's true since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> i guess when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterans</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and well you know with war riots of course
 		let's let's hope we don't get to that point  things are not so good in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> jobwise
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		no i've i've heard they're i hear you have some problems
 	
 	
 		well we do we have lots and lots of uh layoffs here lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> folding lot of layoffs and it's pretty scary
 	
 	
 		do you do you do you blame the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> for this
 	
 	
 		well i don't understand economics that well i don't know i i  i know that we have a terrible situation with foreign trade and that other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> put a lot of restrictions that we don't
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and so i assume that that has some effect
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or a great effect and i do uh i mean they said during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan Reagan Bush</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> the rich got richer the poor got poorer the statistics prove that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um  i i guess
 	
 	
 		so i mean you think it's it's you think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> have done this or is it just coincidence it was during this period
 	
 	
 		well i really don't know i think maybe they uh  maybe they contributed to it maybe they should pay more attention to these trade  or you know to the more equalization of the trade
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course if somebody in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China China</ENAMEX> can make something for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> cents and we have to make it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten</TIMEX> dollars because we have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> well i don't know what's gonna happen then
 	
 	
 		oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> use <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">slave</ENAMEX> labor too that's that's one of the ways they get away with it
 	
 	
 		right
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> labor right well i don't know what do you think has caused our horrible situation
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um i don't think there's any <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> simple answer to the whole thing i mean it's that's very complicated
 	
 	
 		one thing
 		right well they say too that having a democratic congress
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> is not good the i mean i've read that is a theory
 	
 	
 		so which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> are we gonna throw out
 	
 	
 		well i hate to say it but i i'm tending to go stray back into my original democratic party  i i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas Texas</ENAMEX> used to be a democratic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> didn't it
 	
 	
 		oh i know it used to right well you don't run into too many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democrats</ENAMEX> anymore for a while i kind of deserted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> but
 		now it it's looking better to me
 	
 	
 		i like your governor
 	
 	
 		oh do you oh i'm glad to hear that well i think so too i i just admire her her a lot
 	
 	
 		she's an impressive woman
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i hope i really hope she does well but she's uh
 		know  you know probably more popular out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> than she is here although she did manage to win but look who she was running against you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well yeah anybody could beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Claytie</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he shot himself in the foot so many times oh how did you get on this <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> thing
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh i i know some of the people
 		
 		
 	