
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay well have you bought anything recently and uh
 		if so do you find it to your liking do you think it's worth the money
 	
 	
 		i bought i haven't returned it but i bought a i went down to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coach Store</ENAMEX> and bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> handbag
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i've had it now for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> and i have owned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Coach</ENAMEX> products before that's why i love them so much
 		and uh i am going to have to take this back to have it repaired after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months</TIMEX> i am so peeved
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		yeah i can imagine
 	
 	
 		i
 		i think it's
 	
 	
 		because they're not cheap
 	
 	
 		no they're not not even at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five percent</TIMEX> off so um
 		i just uh and i've owned many before i'm just really not a bit happy with it i don't know if they've gotten too big or too popular or
 		or
 		what but you expect when you
 	
 	
 		well i know that in going out and and looking at clothes
 		uh even going to expensive stores
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the clothes look to me so sleazy  any more i don't know whether it's the type of materials they're using
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		is it you know is it supposed to be you know crepe or what and or if it's a case now i've seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dillard's</ENAMEX> in an area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they hadn't even they'd hung the clothes out but they hadn't even pressed them so they didn't look good to begin with and uh you know and they looked cheap and they were you know they weren't cheap they were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty nine hundred hundred</TIMEX> and fifty
 	
 	
 		i saw that um-hum
 	
 	
 		you know you don't buy find cheap dresses any more even at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penney</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		especially at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penney</ENAMEX>'s they've upgraded considerably
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and uh the only thing that i know that we have uh
 		uh
 		televisions
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we have have gotten real good televisions we have had real good luck with televisions
 		and i just wanna i think that their
 		i think their quality is better
 	
 	
 		but to see you can buy you could you could you pay the same price for a new television as you do for a new suit a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s suit you know
 	
 	
 		well that's true that's true that's true you do you you can buy a portable cheaper than you can buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s suit
 	
 	
 		oh you exactly i was
 		uh i had i bought something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> and i thought well i've been wanting this new whatever and i did this this is my new brand i know what it was i was wanting this new television and this is
 		this is my new TV and it was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> pairs of shoes and a you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i've gone to the outlet to buy the shoes so so
 	
 	
 		i know well i know that uh
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> we usually for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> we will give him a suit and we try to you know stay around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and something on them we you can't find a suit any more for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		huh
 		even even at uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Men's Warehouse</ENAMEX> and things like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		you know i could you know for what some of the suits cost they had just moved into a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i could buy them a
 		a small new refrigerator almost as cheap as what the suits are
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		and that's utterly ridiculous clothing has just gotten totally out of sight and i hate to spend you know a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollars for a dress that's made in Taiwan
 	
 	
 		that the you have to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> to have cleaned every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> times you wear it or something and
 	
 	
 		yes yes yes very definitely so uh
 	
 	
 		i just
 	
 	
 		you know i i other than the TV's uh TV's i i do think here are made pretty good uh but i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> are made that well any more
 	
 	
 		hum
 		i am real happy with my car
 	
 	
 		now what is it what <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> do you a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i i think everything's it's oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four and a half years old</TIMEX> and everything works on it and nothing's fallen off or broken i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chryslers</ENAMEX> that haven't had that luck and
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		Toyotas that haven't had that luck and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh no i think i think you're right the electronics seem to be of decent quality
 	
 	
 		um-hum i don't know whether competition is so stiff between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> or i don't know what it is but you know the electronics seem to be you know pretty good value for their money
 	
 	
 		and going down in price too
 	
 	
 		yes yes definitely because i know the price of the big screen TV's you know they're going down you know compared to what they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		and
 		i bought a little camera <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six years ago</TIMEX> that i just thought was the the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bee</ENAMEX>'s knees or whatever it just i mean just wonderful and now i can get it for fifty dollars less the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> and for the same price i can get one that does a lot more
 	
 	
 		
 
 		same model um-hum um-hum
 		the only thing i'm not seeing going go down that much is the camcorders the video tape recorders things
 	
 	
 		oh well not a lot no
 	
 	
 		uh uh they've gone down a little bit we just bought one we kept thinking they would get much cheaper you know like somewhere around <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six hundred dollars</NUMEX> but they're still right up there around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine eight</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nine hundred dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know which kind of surprised me because the how long have they been out now almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> has an old one
 	
 	
 		you know uh-huh and uh so uh
 	
 	
 		they've gotten smaller though and
 	
 	
 		that's true and maybe that's what it is maybe they're just coming you know they're constantly working on them
 		and so therefore they keep changing and they don't have any reason yet to
 		
 		
 	