
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh well i i kind of feel like we pay um
 		um maybe uh little uh too much actually i mean like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five thirty</TIMEX> percent of our income the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yes absolutely
 	
 	
 		and it just seems uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and yet you have big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> that that manage uh just because the way the laws are written not to pay anything at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all year after year</TIMEX> after year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh-huh yeah no i i agree with you there um i've gone to other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> where there's no food tax you know some things there aren't taxed at all and i think that that's really nice i think they that's what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> needed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to do also is to discriminate as to uh which should be taxed and what shouldn't be taxed so
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i don't i've never been any place that didn't have it we went from here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> for a while and and they had a food tax there so i guess i'm just kind of
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh see we don't they don't tax food here do they
 	
 	
 		no they do they do uh-huh yeah but i have lived in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in which they don't uh tax uh food uh clothing items personal things like that
 	
 	
 		they do tax
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um so that was that was really neat but i guess the way that they get around it though is that there's no quote state
 		income tax but then you pay  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> fifteen percent taxes um you know i know they say it's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only eight and a quarter</TIMEX> or whatever it is but uh but yeah i really think that it's it's way too much
 	
 	
 		no state income tax right
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh whenever you buy an item especially a large purchase item it it's it's something in which you're you're paying and you've always got to add in that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about ten</NUMEX> percent tax
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh what do you feel about do you feel like um
 		how do you feel about for what we get back in the way of services and things
 	
 	
 		in the last what
 	
 	
 		in in the way of services for for the money that we pay
 	
 	
 		oh in the money that we pay um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well  now for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> um i really like the the things that they offer here
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too
 	
 	
 		um i and i can't say that for for all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> or all of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> um but for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano i</ENAMEX> do i really think that i get my my money's worth they always seem to be ahead of any other um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and in the things such as uh you know separating out your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> and your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> now and and uh having the great big you know gallon drums uh uh keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> beautiful and and i think that they really do a good job at it too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah well we participate in a lot of the recreational you know we use the recreational facilities
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		where we came from in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> i mean it was a nice area but we didn't have any the mean the
 		the recreational recreational <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> they have here are just
 		unbelievable so i think that we get a good deal in the way that goes
 	
 	
 		right
 		um-hum um-hum well and i think you get spoiled and you expect it whenever you go to any place else and it's just not quite up to standard or par and it's just like oh gee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whiz</ENAMEX> you know it makes you really appreciate i think uh you know that your city
 		and uh what it has to offer now as for the state you know i uh uh you know i guess the the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> outside of what metropolitan <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> are okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know i haven't i haven't been much i haven't been much outside well yeah i used to travel when i was here and they seem to be okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah and the outside i mean the your state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highways</ENAMEX> i i think you know are are pretty adequate uh adequate but gosh you get into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and you might as well forget it um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah now we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> for a while in the  and in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> was pretty pretty pretty rough in places
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right yeah so um i i don't know i'm uh i'm really glad that they didn't go to the um the the state income tax um i'm hoping the lottery is going to uh take care of it uh i know there's a lot of religious issues and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um but i i'm hoping that uh in a way <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can can see that as a contribution then to the state
 		um i did live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> and i know that's how they kind of got around um you know having to uh taxes or increase in taxes was was by the lottery
 	
 	
 		is that right yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and and i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are concerned that it's only gonna be the the lower you know income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are actually going to you know be the the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> in this um
 	
 	
 		yeah so some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> probably say you're taxing them anyway then if you're dangling a lottery out there in front of them yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah yeah absolutely absolutely and um i only saw it as being you know really positive and of course it you know was just a fluke if you won
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know because i really never expected to win and and i never did the big big lottery we're talking about uh but you know every once in a while i'd come up with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three dollars</NUMEX> or something but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i felt good in the sense that i was really putting my money the way i felt it was back into uh the taxes uh and it went actually most of it went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and uh to school reforms things like this so uh yeah i i saw it really as a positive thing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah how do you feel about um federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> and things
 	
 	
 		you you know i was yeah
 	
 	
 		what are what are the federal services what what do we i mean i know we got a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> and and you know uh
 		i guess i guess they have matching federal funds for a lot of our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> and local projects
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right well because i was looking at some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> that i actually use now i did um uh way back when i did use government um things such as uh uh
 		food stamp
 		
 		
 	