
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 		all right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		okay what uh what was your name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX> and yours is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charley</ENAMEX> right yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia okay Charley</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		well i i listen to the radio whenever i can i watch TV TV news at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> but i'm really a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> so i read that paper from front to back but i don't think either of the papers i get here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metroplex</ENAMEX> are that great
 	
 	
 		oh yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Telegram</ENAMEX> i get that one it's it's not the highest  quality i don't think and i get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> and it's kind of fading no not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> i get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> what do you get
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um i read the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> we we've moved here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six month</TIMEX> or no <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		i think
 		oh where'd you move from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so i tried the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times Herald</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and then i tried the tried them both and i ended up back with the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i think it's the better of the papers
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i don't and i pretty well read it uh i kind of i mean i go through the whole paper i don't read every
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> would you not roll around here please run on run on from out here
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh i don't uh i i pretty well look at it all the way through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> and then i listen to i listen on i have a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty five minute</TIMEX> drive so i listen to the news on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too
 		oh yeah i love that i think that's so good once you've listen to that you can't believe the regular radio news
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and they have a lot of um early breaking stories before before anyone else does so i kind of like that
 	
 	
 		huh it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i like i like that too
 	
 	
 		yeah and i guess uh i'm getting used to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Morning News</ENAMEX> i didn't like it as much as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that from where we moved but uh
 	
 	
 		oh i don't think any of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> in the area are great papers you might have had a really excellent one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but you know you have to get a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> or you won't know what's going on that's why i get the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> one which i didn't do for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before we moved over here but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's the only way i could find out what was going on in my own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> so i had to subscribe to it finally
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		we used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> and we got that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that was like a number of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and i liked it i of course uh that was probably fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		oh
 		yeah well the editorial page is pretty good of course they you know it's all things they get from other places
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i'm not really thrilled with with the paper
 	
 	
 		do you listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX> do you listen you say listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i listen to that quite a bit when i can
 	
 	
 		yeah i listen to it i guess uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> on the way in and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> on the way home
 	
 	
 		yeah you really get a whole story you know the news on television is probably i think the worst source
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because it's like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight minutes</TIMEX> of top news out of the whole <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half hour</TIMEX> by the time you take all those you know the ads and the sports and the features and the the cute little talk you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i don't know i guess um i used to watch TV news but i don't hardly ever watch it any more uh
 	
 	
 		uh i'll catch the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten o'clock</TIMEX> sometimes or if there's a story that i'm really interested in i'll i'll try to
 	
 	
 		yeah i'll turn it on if there's a how about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline</ENAMEX> do you ever watch any programs like that
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">i love Nightline</ENAMEX> yeah i like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i like that too but it's it's hard sometimes to stay up for me that late
 	
 	
 		yeah it really is if you have to do something early where do you work do you work at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> No you don't work at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> do you
 	
 	
 		no i work for a mechanical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractor</ENAMEX> um
 	
 	
 		where where where do you have to drive to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Farmers Branch</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> so takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about forty five minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah you go against all that traffic i guess on LBJ or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well no i go kind of a back way but it still it takes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">forty five or fifty minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> drives from here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arlington</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>  well yeah he listens to a lot of news  but
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's a good drive
 		yeah well do you read any uh do you do read any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> or anything like that
 	
 	
 		yeah um well just <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> as far as news i mean we get a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> but that that's the only news one that i get
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah do you read it pretty regular
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh uh well i didn't like it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> it was just all about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and i don't don't care that much about  uh did you get it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i don't we don't take we don't take many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> occasionally i'll i'll see one somewhere and look at it but um i don't uh seems like it takes too much time or something
 	
 	
 		the whole issue's is oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that's true no we do get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and um i i read it pretty well you know i especially read the political news uh um i like to keep up with that but um
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like you said i think the best source of all is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Radio</ENAMEX>  and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nightline well Nightline</ENAMEX>'s great especially when something exciting is going on you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then i then i'll really make a point well you know it used to come on at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten thirty</TIMEX> which was better but then they put that silly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Entertainment Tonight</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah so it comes on at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> now yeah so i'm still used to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> time it was um oh it was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> up there i think
 	
 	
 		right
 		oh was it
 	
 	
 		yeah but that's still that's awful late
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i know i wish it would come on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> but obviously the sitcoms make more money or they you know or they wouldn't have it on at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>  but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well i guess we've exhausted that subject  well who do you think's going to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> next year since you're up on all your news
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		guess we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> again but
 	
 	
 		yeah uh i don't know who's going to run on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> side um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Buchanan</ENAMEX> supposedly was thinking of running against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> or he just announced today
 	
 	
 		is that right
 	
 	
 		i don't know if he's announced or he's thinking about it but it was on the news
 	
 	
 		huh
 		well that's kind of a futile effort probably wouldn't wouldn't you think yeah
 	
 	
 		well i would think but it
 		uh it might scare <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> a little
 		
 		
 	