
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what kind of car uh are you thinking of buying next
 	
 	
 		uh more than likely it's going to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> products do you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LeBaron</ENAMEX> yeah it it won't be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> i've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Mustang</ENAMEX> now and i hate it
 	
 	
 		do you really what year is it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		and why don't you like the Mustang
 	
 	
 		it's um i've had one problem with it after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other the the</TIMEX> the paint the paint's peeling off of it and there's no reason for it you know and
 	
 	
 		i'll be darned
 		well you know the old sayings about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fords</ENAMEX> what they stand for
 	
 	
 		fix or repair <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daily</ENAMEX> or find on read road dead
 	
 	
 		there you go
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that uh i it's it's my electrical system shorted out like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times and it's been torn up since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> and i and
 	
 	
 		well uh
 	
 	
 		luckily everything was under warranty so it's only costing like a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred and forty dollars</NUMEX> to get it fixed it would have been like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well we've always uh we've always had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oldsmobiles</ENAMEX> and uh been very uh happy with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobiles</ENAMEX> but uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> thought she wanted to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford Mustang</ENAMEX> and then she kind of changed her mind and thinks her next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> ought to be one of those uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi</ENAMEX> Eclipses
 		she really
 	
 	
 		those those are nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she likes uh likes those uh she has a sister that lives in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX> that has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and uh really uh enjoys it
 		well what uh what things do you consider when you buy a car
 	
 	
 		um the gas mileage for one thing and i've uh
 		i've always had like stick shifts i want this next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i want to get i want it to be automatic
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		because i'm  i'm i hate driving anyway and then
 		and changing gears at stop lights and stuff is really getting on my nerves now
 	
 	
 		yeah well especially when you're in high traffic areas and have to mess with that all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and you know when you work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight to five</NUMEX> and you're  in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">rush hour</TIMEX> traffic to and from work unfortunately
 	
 	
 		that makes it very frustrating
 	
 	
 		and i look ah and that one of the things with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> right now is is their the warranties that they have and
 		i've i feel like there's everybody everybody i've talked to that owns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> is is is is been real pleased with it hm i like those uh those
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">driver</ENAMEX>'s air bag i like that
 	
 	
 		now this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LeBaron</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah well all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> products has it in there but i is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">LeBaron</ENAMEX> would be the next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i get yeah
 	
 	
 		i sure like the uh convertible those ragtop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LeBarons</ENAMEX> they really look sporty
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i like i like that too huh but i couldn't i couldn't afford the insurance on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well uh we always  this last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX> we bought uh it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an eighty seven</NUMEX> but we bought it in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eighty eight</TIMEX> you know right at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the year</TIMEX> when they were trying to get rid of them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we found that uh we found a real good interest rate you know when they're trying to get rid of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at the end of the year</TIMEX> like that they really come down on their prices and uh
 		um you know we looked around at used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and we really couldn't uh afford the payments on a used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because uh if you go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> and try to get a loan they want to charge twelve thirteen percent you know
 		and we ended up i think with like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four and a half</NUMEX> percent interest rate on a brand new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and our payments
 	
 	
 		well that's that's what i'm paying on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> now i i had to get like a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s always co-signed on on my my loans or whatever and this is one i've  that whenever i got my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mustang</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this time</TIMEX>
 		was by myself because i was out my own or whatever and um
 		i had said that they they said it had to be like a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or whatever and
 		they're charging me unreasonable about interest but
 		i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> more payments and it's paid for
 	
 	
 		well that's great
 	
 	
 		but i got it when i got it when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">eighty eights</ENAMEX> first came out
 		so it's it's it's a good car
 		i mean i got in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> i guess in like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were younger we really wanted a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> door our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seventy seven</TIMEX> it was a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> door <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cutlass Supreme</ENAMEX>
 		and um it just happened that when we looked for our
 		our new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> they had a thing going with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX> and if you'd buy a a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oldsmobile</ENAMEX> they'd give you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollar</NUMEX> rebate because it was their seventy <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> anniversary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i believe it yeah seventy <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> anniversary so in addition to everything else we got off the car all we had to do is show them our
 		uh papers on our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and they gave us another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollars</NUMEX> off on it so we we got a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door this time and i sort of went more for the uh
 		the comfort factor and uh i like the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> but i'm a bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and i i really like comfort you know driving along the road and stuff
 	
 	
 		well that's another big factor of mine next next <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i get's gonna be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a four</NUMEX> door too something with some room
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		because i  my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mustang's a</ENAMEX> is is
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> door with bucket seats and when you buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">groceries</ENAMEX> and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		and if you try to take anybody uh you know go to the show or go out for supper and you go as a foursome
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	