
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		okay do we just go ahead okay um well we're supposed to talk about vacations and uh i'm trying to think of the ones that i've been on that i liked the most and
 	
 	
 		uh-huh do you want to start
 		right
 	
 	
 		probably the one i liked most was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh did you get to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> yeah we went there for our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty fifth wedding anniversary</TIMEX> it's lovely isn't it
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes we went uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> after we were married
 	
 	
 		uh huh
 	
 	
 		and we just went to um <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> islands
 	
 	
 		what islands did you go to
 	
 	
 		we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oahu</ENAMEX> and Kauai
 	
 	
 		Kauai uh-huh we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kauai</ENAMEX> and then we also hit <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maui</ENAMEX> and then of course uh uh the big one uh-huh with uh the big one i thought was very commercialized
 	
 	
 		the big one
 		oh
 		oh yeah it was
 	
 	
 		but the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> were just lovely
 	
 	
 		yes i enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kauai</ENAMEX> better too
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it was quiet and restful and and so beautiful it wasn't commercialized
 	
 	
 		oh it was rainy  rainy but you know we don't like to spend the money to go over there and sit on the beach anyway so
 	
 	
 		yeah was it
 		that's right well it wasn't real rainy we had some a few showers but uh nothing that really got in the way with anything and just very brief ones and and when uh now we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> liked it better than he did <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really oh
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah he really did i don't know why you know he didn't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oahu</ENAMEX> at all he thought he thought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honolulu</ENAMEX> was just horrible  you know although we went to that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Polynesian Village</ENAMEX> did you go there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's that was wonderful now we both enjoyed that very much um-hum
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah that was that was nice you know i've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Nassau</ENAMEX> too i went on a cruise
 	
 	
 		have you
 		oh neat
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and um to tell you the truth i I think i'd rather just go to the island
 	
 	
 		yeah uh
 		our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and daughter-in-law just uh they got married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last January</TIMEX> and they won a cruise and i know they didn't like it now we have several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that uh have been on and just love them but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> and i like i don't know i think we would get bored on the boat all the time
 	
 	
 		well i  got sick yeah i did <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first night</TIMEX> i went with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> just um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple years ago</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 		ooh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and we both the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> just had to leave dinner i it was bad but and then after that it was it got better we just it was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four day</TIMEX> and we we were both ready to get off the boat yeah
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		were you well you know well i think if we ever go it will only be for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three day</TIMEX> now we've been real lucky we've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> twice
 	
 	
 		oh have you
 	
 	
 		yeah we went <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London Paris</ENAMEX> and touched a little bit of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich Germany</ENAMEX> and were there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> and loved <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		is just absolutely gorgeous with the mountains and we were there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> before the snows you know started and it was wonderful it uh it was just it was marvelous and we would love to go back there and we'd love to go back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'll bet it is
 		oh
 		you haven't been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> oh i was born there yes  um just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten months</TIMEX> yeah so
 	
 	
 		no have not been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>
 		were you how old were you when you left
 		oh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten months</TIMEX> uh-huh have you ever got to go back
 	
 	
 		no no and i would like to yeah
 	
 	
 		would you my uh  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> we went with them to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> and uh she would like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX> i'm not sure whether i would like to or not
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh i would like to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would you now now i don't know if i'd like to go there just from the the problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well uh the the unrest there is uh-huh is is a little scary but i would still like to see it i'd like to see uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Italy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that would be nice
 	
 	
 		i would love to go there and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">course</ENAMEX> there's a lot of places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> i still want to come you know go to
 	
 	
 		now have you been to Yellowstone
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		Yellowstone have you
 	
 	
 		uh yes yes we have been there we i was there as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and then we we went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> and came back through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yellowstone</ENAMEX> with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they loved it i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> when i was a uh youngster
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so uh you know i've touched on that and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah now i'm just about oh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a half hour</TIMEX> um north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> so um it's at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> works in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake</ENAMEX> so we're real close and yeah we
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		now that's a pretty city
 	
 	
 		yes we we like it yeah it is
 	
 	
 		very clean you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s a pretty state from what i remember of it
 	
 	
 		well we kind of like it  well do you like to camp those kind of trips
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		we no we used to we used to camp a lot with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and uh but now we like things like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regency Hyatt</ENAMEX> we're we like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> yes
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh you like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">motels</ENAMEX> oh oh well
 	
 	
 		we have we've gone past the camping stage we lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chattanooga Tennessee</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and we did a lot of camping out there in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smokeys</ENAMEX> and it was beautiful and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> loved it and everything and then we moved to uh
 	
 	
 		oh did you
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area and uh it's hot down here and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camping</ENAMEX>'s not near as much fun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh so and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were getting older and and uh were involved in activities so the camping sort of went by the wayside
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and uh although our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> loves to fish and uh and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> are talking now about starting camping with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> now that they have gotten older
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	