
 
     		
 	
 		well what's your favorite baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i suppose i supposed to say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> right  is that what i is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the million million dollar</NUMEX> question here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well this isn't a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a true false or right or wrong test here
 	
 	
 		yeah uh um you know i would like to say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> but  unfortunately they're not i was from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> and my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubbies</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		no no my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> was but i turned out to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		well that's all right how do you expect them to do this year
 	
 	
 		lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> yeah they did pretty well
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		what'd you think the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Series</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		i'll tell you i just uh
 		moved down from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
 		and uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Minnesota Twins</ENAMEX> are the closest
 		professional sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> to where i was living
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so everybody was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and i was  kind of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> didn't have much interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> you know it was it was kind of pathetic i mean we only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> radio stations
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them broadcast every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> game live you know  and the other one was country
 	
 	
 		so you didn't really have a lot of choice did you
 	
 	
 		so that's right it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> there or you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skip Williams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or country
 		yeah oh uh and i was routing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX>
 		myself because uh they a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ranger</ENAMEX> players that i had
 		watched when we first moved here uh went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> and we used to tease about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and i used to have a bet going
 		because about some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> that had moved from here to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> but it was interesting it certainly was an exciting series anyway
 	
 	
 		it sure was it sure was
 	
 	
 		what do you think's gonna happen to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> how can we predict
 	
 	
 		well i would
 		i would like to assume assume assume that they're gonna do do better this whole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this coming year</TIMEX> i would sure hope so anyway when we moved down
 		uh i was able to go to my first you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		thought this is great this is incredible so i i became a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> fan
 		i i didn't really have one in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Dakota</ENAMEX> so i adopted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> or rather they adopted me i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it was just exciting you know you can watch <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> on TV and they hit the long ball and it looks like wow they really hit that ball
 		but when you go to the ballpark it's really not all that far
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		you know and it's so much more exciting watching a ball come at you and
 	
 	
 		oh isn't it though you know but oh i i think going to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX> it really really makes it because then you watch it on TV you feel like you're more a part of it too
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right
 	
 	
 		you know well i'm a great sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enthusiast</ENAMEX> so i love
 		you know baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> and they in fact on the news tonight <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX> was on there he was being he was put in the which i'd never knew exist the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant Hall of Fame</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant Hall</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> inducted him tonight
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and
 		he uh says he's coming back you know and he doesn't know how many years i mean to pitch he'll be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> more and he said he's been saying one more and it's been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> might be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> more  he likes it
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's right and he's still doing great still doing excellent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right you know and he said i get a kick out of it uh you know he's he's such a nice man
 	
 	
 		well didn't he just sign a twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> contract with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah and he you know when he quits at being active he will go into you know being a managing and yeah you know being a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> i'm sure
 	
 	
 		management
 		right
 	
 	
 		but he's uh he certainly is a good example uh for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		you know you like to have someone like that you could point to to say see what a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that he is
 	
 	
 		you know some of the
 		like uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Rodriguez</ENAMEX> wasn't even born when when uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Ryan</ENAMEX> started pitching
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and it's just incredible to think that there's uh there are players
 		who are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ballplayers</ENAMEX> that used to play against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan</ENAMEX> or with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and now their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> are
 	
 	
 		oh he's been a legend for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so many years</TIMEX> you know and i don't know were you here
 		had you moved here yet when he did the exhibition at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> with his son his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> pitched for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UT</ENAMEX> and he pitched for an exhibition <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">game</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh-uh i wasn't
 	
 	
 		yeah it was a i think it was a a little early part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		was it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan</ENAMEX> against uh oh it it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan</ENAMEX> against
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> yeah his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> pitched for UT
 	
 	
 		well that is neat
 	
 	
 		and uh only uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> didn't want too much publicity on it because he didn't want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> getting too nervous about this whole thing game is a game you know well the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really uh
 		knocked the socks off of them which you would expect you know anyway but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan</ENAMEX> i think took himself out after a couple of innings or something
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know of the game to let
 		
 		
 	