
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh do you have young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i have got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two one</NUMEX> is uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> and the other one's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and um this is my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first year</TIMEX> of staying home i've always had them in child care
 	
 	
 		oh well then you are familiar with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i uh i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandchildren</ENAMEX> and i know uh one has gone to a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two</NUMEX> of them have gone to preschool and i know what the experience my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> has faced with that why don't you tell me what you have found
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well um it was our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sitter</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one didn't quite work out um there were some things going on that i wasn't really happy with and so i felt that
 		that i need to move on with them and so i found another babysitter and she was wonderful except i thought that there were too many in the home
 		and it just seemed like it was so hard to find uh really good child care she was wonderful it's just that i felt that there were too many in the home it was in home child care
 	
 	
 		okay so you
 		okay so it was in home child care you took them to someone's home
 	
 	
 		uh-huh all right
 	
 	
 		well both times
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		and then i worked in in a child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> and i wasn't really happy with the particular one that i was working in
 		so i just always had a fear about you know child care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> so that's why i put him in a in a in home day care
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		um-hum  and then i just decided that i was just missing a lot of their time whether they were so little and and i couldn't get off of work as often as i wanted to when they were ill
 		so i just decided it was probably best just to stay home for a while until they were a little more
 		uh independent and uh i could go back to work
 	
 	
 		i know that in raising my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		i was fortunate i
 		didn't have to work we didn't necessarily have a lot of things  but uh i didn't and know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> because she has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah  that's how it's going now
 	
 	
 		to have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in day care you know even though one of them's in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> full time one of them's you know in kindergarten
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that is a lot of money i mean it's so expensive you have to really make a lot of money and i'm glad that she gets to stay home so that she can then participate with what's going on in their life
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> don't always seem to understand getting off to go to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> programs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the day</TIMEX> or something and
 	
 	
 		oh no yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and i know that one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> cares and it's a a well-known chain
 		um she was not at all happy with it because was there was too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> per person
 		they were just kind of left to play there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> to it and the middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandson</ENAMEX> went there as a uh
 		like a preschool thing she was wanting him actually to start getting a certain amount of of learning and training and stuff not just there you know so he went like uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think he went
 		well <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five mornings</TIMEX> a week if i remember correctly and um
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		you know and it was supposed to be a basic you know starting to learn the colors and and learning to associate with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so that when he went to you know a school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and stuff and uh she was most unhappy with it  there was no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> there was nothing to it  you know and uh she pulled him out of that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and put him in a another one that was excellent it was it was like a little kindergarten
 	
 	
 		hm
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		uh they had hot lunches and and they had classes that you know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> they'd do art they even familiarized the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> with computers uh it was just it was really a very excellent one
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and how old is he
 	
 	
 		he's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">now five and a half</TIMEX> he's in kindergarten this was last year
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh so you know it helped him and and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one uh
 		he went to a uh church preschool that was very good the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX> the big one and it was a excellent they very good it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		yes my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> goes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist um</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> um-hum i'm real happy with that one
 	
 	
 		oh does he
 		yeah they uh the church ones church ones seem to be very well run
 	
 	
 		i
 		well i've i've heard that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist</ENAMEX> ones are excellent even uh-huh
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		even the  even their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Day Out</ENAMEX> programs i heard are really good
 	
 	
 		oh i had uh i just assumed that most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">churches</ENAMEX> going by you know experience there that you know that they were good i i didn't know that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i'm not that familiar i just know that you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First United Methodist</ENAMEX> there at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richardson</ENAMEX> was just a great program
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah because this is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First United Methodist</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> that he goes to and i'm real happy with that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah it's a pretty good size church too isn't it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well that a claim
 	
 	
 		so
 		well are you enjoying staying home
 	
 	
 		yes i am  uh i taught for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richardson School District</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh i taught early childhood and uh i really enjoyed it but it was just it was taking a lot of my time and i noticed i was spending less and less time with them and it just seemed like they were sick more often and i just couldn't get the time off to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well isn't it very hard to teach young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and then come home and deal with young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and have enthusiasm
 	
 	
 		yeah it is it really is yeah it really is and i felt
 		
 		
 	