
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		now what was your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> okay
 		uh how how do you feel about uh gun control Bob
 	
 	
 		it's it's kind of like abortion it's kind of a touchy subject but um i i feel that
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is uh has the right to be armed but i don't think they should have an arsenal
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't believe in uh automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> i don't believe in in uh having antitank <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> and
 		um i i
 		there's just there's just too many uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh i kind of i agree i guess i don't i don't think that we need uh
 		um these these automatic or semiautomatic rifles even i mean i don't really even care that the i don't know if you hunt or not but i don't even care that some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hunters</ENAMEX> say they they like them i mean
 	
 	
 		no i'm i'm not
 	
 	
 		that you know uh maybe they use them for legitimate purposes but they're all you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> are getting them and using them for not so legitimate to say the least
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no
 	
 	
 		purposes what do you feel about uh um how do you feel about a waiting period
 	
 	
 		i yeah i think that's a a good thing in
 		in the sense that it um it stops someone that is acting on a impulse however
 		uh anyone that has a revenge factor in mind is is going to weight that out
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		um most um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> has if you read in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> recently um the um
 		uh murder ratio in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> i think per day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and ninety somewhat percent of these know
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">perpetrator</ENAMEX> it's it's not it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> that are going out and killing people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> that are that are shooting other people
 	
 	
 		yeah it's probably not someone that's running down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and buying one either is it probably someone who's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> already yeah
 	
 	
 		no someone that's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and and and for some reason whatever um they became
 		uh enraged or
 		you know it uh
 		some of these are somebody's dating somebody's uh girl <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ex-wife</ENAMEX> or
 		um
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> that they know and and
 		it's it's again something that you know it's it's a uh
 		it's a decision of uh emotion
 		not um
 		it's not something you can really control usually i don't think you can
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think you can regulate it
 		if they don't use a gun maybe they'll use a knife
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah
 		yeah i mean yeah i don't know if i mean yeah if someone wants to do someone in they're gonna do it whether they have a gun or not uh what do you think about that um that uh
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		deal with the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> evidently evidently um i guess they speculate that it was teenagers
 		that that somehow got a hold of a gun
 	
 	
 		well yeah yeah
 		yeah and and you look at the you know drive by shootings and things like that with with young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uh people</ENAMEX> involved it's it's
 		it's a very volatile situation it's a funny world that we live in
 	
 	
 		yeah i i we just moved here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight or nine months ago</TIMEX> from from uh a little <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we have lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX> before and and in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> for a while so we we're you know we're accustomed to the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> weren't in in the age they are now they're in uh high school and junior middle school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the middle the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> around here um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man police</ENAMEX> have come in and and uh you know they got they raid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and take out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> revolvers you know i mean it's just uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure
 	
 	
 		so it seems like
 		um you know it seems like and no and that's not a case of someone flipping out and running down and buying one so a waiting period isn't gonna help that but it seems like that there ought to be something that could be done  to
 		at least make it harder for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to get their hands on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that that's parental control
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and that's you know that extends beyond <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> that extends to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and everything else that that is bad in our society and and we don't have the
 		we don't have the parental control that that we need
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		that's that's a there's there's there's no deterrent um there really isn't and and you're not going to stop uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> from being on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>
 		again if they don't use a gun they'll use something else
 		and and then you take away the fact that uh
 		somebody has a right to protect their property
 		
 		
 	