
 
     		
 	
 		some of the political trends that have started up uh i guess in the other side of the ocean as it were some of the uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">revolutions</ENAMEX> and desires for change that's going on over there when that first started going on there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> i don't even remember his name but uh
 		he made a a not so widely publicized comment that said just wait awhile and see how much <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> aid ends up going that way
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		his and he thought or predicted that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> would be one of the first ones to start seeing uh both in forms of debt forgiven and uh actual dollar values given over to them
 		and they took a little while but sure enough some of that stuff is coming about uh
 		so i don't know if that's going to be an ongoing trend that we're going to start helping this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and breaking our own backs as it were
 		what do you think
 	
 	
 		well i think that's uh a you know valid observation that uh anytime that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> appears to be uh moving in the same direction that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> thinks is the right direction that they tend to get more you know more uh more aid from from our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> then they would have before or the other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> do
 		um i suppose that's a
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as valid a way of determining who gets aid is as anything although i'm not sure that uh
 		us giving aid is the right uh right thing for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to be doing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i i think it's kind of ironic that
 		from my you know from my observation anyway that that we're uh rewarding other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> for becoming more democratic in following more capitalistic approaches
 		whereas in our own economy the trend seems to be more towards social programs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know away from the capitalistic approach so it's kind of like you know we're moving in the in a kind of a direction toward each other
 	
 	
 		yeah that's interesting
 	
 	
 		uh you know i i mean that's my own observation anyway
 	
 	
 		yeah i think you're right i think over the well goodness i guess you could go back as
 		
 
 		far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> and say that the social programs have certainly gone up and only economics have caused a few cutbacks but still the desire seems to be that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> say
 	
 	
 		right
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		or the norm has become that they would desire that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> say yeah that we deserve this so you will provide this
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		this is part of the old happiness aspect
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's a that's an interesting thought that they're headed to be a socialist and they're headed to be democratic and maybe we're capitalist and maybe the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> will meet in the middle and and
 		and agree i i don't know
 	
 	
 		and i'm not sure that uh that i would even think at this point that somewhere in the middle would even be desirable because uh i mean if there's if there's something
 		uh if what we wind up with is more socialistic than what we have now
 		then i'm not sure that it's the right thing it's there i think we have too much too many social programs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		it's a social programs without the corresponding responsibility
 		i guess is
 	
 	
 		right that does seem to be a problem that even the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Poles</ENAMEX> faced when uh i think they're one of the earliest experimenters in in trying to get a capitalist uh economy going and
 		some of the things that showed up is um i hate the term worth it work ethic but that seems to be the one that's tied to it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Poles</ENAMEX> just didn't know what it meant to get up in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> and you know be there and put in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few extra hours</TIMEX> if it needed it or you know a little bit of work here and work there do what it takes instead of just stamp the clock stamp the clock and forget about it give me my paycheck
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		um though there are jobs of course that exist that way here uh they don't
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they don't they're not labeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>  you know they're they're uh assembly line type jobs and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they didn't have that worth it ec ethic and here we're headed towards socializing to the extent that there's a whole welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> that doesn't have it
 	
 	
 		right oh i
 	
 	
 		so but that's an interesting uh
 		merging as it were of the two ideas we're going one way and they're going the other
 	
 	
 		i noticed in uh an article in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> where i didn't read the whole article but you know the headlines anyway indicated that there's a a seems to be a consensus among small and medium size business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX>
 		that the uh the output of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> is on the decline you know pretty severely but uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the output's really suffering and i think that's
 		you know that's another indication that
 		that we're headed in the wrong direction
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh you know and i think uh i think rewards for a job well done are are
 		are necessary and i i think that we
 		i guess we have a tendency to
 		as you know as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> they have a tendency to try to get as much out of the employee
 		as they can
 		and not give as much as they can
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know in return i
 		uh i i think that that there there needs to be some give and take in both you know on both sides of the
 		of the picture there
 	
 	
 		i don't know if it'd be a political trend or not to
 		to uh  consider the problem of the
 		well i guess it it is a matter of uh at least the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s causing it there's there's so much more paperwork in most every job i mean the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> can't get their jobs done for the reports and the things that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> requires and
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh the whole defense industry issue of having so many layers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> just to handle the paperwork and
 	
 	
 		well uh you know even the police uh have a lot of paperwork to do uh i observed a uh i didn't actually see the accident but uh the  the aftermath of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> car accident <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richardson</ENAMEX>
 		and i was going into the public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> and apparently the accident had just you know recently happened then but there was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> there <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policewoman</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		taking down the information and i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> and came back out and she was still sitting in the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> there you know the accident
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> were gone but she was sitting there filling out paperwork you know so you know it took her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> plus to to handle one traffic accident
 	
 	
 		hum
 		yep the more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> the merrier the paperwork
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		right
 		
 
 		and you know i think that's uh just a a kind of an indication the paperwork the the amount of information that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> wants
 		even about a traffic accident you know is so much that uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know we get bogged down and things like that
 	
 	
 		i wonder if they waive that when uh some of these horrendously large pileups occur in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> like you hear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these twenty</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> pile
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> couldn't you imagine doing the paperwork on that'd take an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> just to do the paperwork
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		correct yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay well that just sounds like i got another phone call trying to come in so anyway it's been interesting thank you
 	
 	
 		all righty i'll let you go then
 		um bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	