
 
     		
 	
 		here we go
 	
 	
 		okay um now we're supposed to talk about social activities right
 	
 	
 		well the changes that's occurred like it how was it maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten twenty thirty years ago</TIMEX> as opposed to what it is today
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how we're living socially in comparison to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">maybe</NUMEX> from that time period from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> or whatever you remember it to be
 	
 	
 		i think um well i guess it would be like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> compared to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> i think your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> is um what do i say uh
 		uh they're they're they're polite they have more respect for other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just in in general i think and just just towards
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and property and um i i guess they would would be more conservative some of them i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah we are uh somewhat conservative but as far as the
 		uh socially our crime rate has increased and although it's more publicized as opposed to what it used to be it seems like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		violent crime is on the increase from what i've seen and um our prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> has significantly increased i would say
 		um our economy too
 		is really it's just not what it used to be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> or even fifties from history from what i've read and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh even the well it started
 		spiraling down i suppose in the seventies
 		and uh our recovery
 		uh economically has not been like it used to be
 		to me also our nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is is not the same because more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are living together that aren't married uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know if uh can't make any judgments of that nature but uh
 		i don't really want to either  because i have no problems about it either way
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are i i suppose have been raised by single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> more than they ever used to
 	
 	
 		yes i agree with
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are more on the rise too so far as getting their careers established and uh they don't no longer feel dependent upon men
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well
 		well do you think that that maybe i mean uh i've heard different you know like um
 		like i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and like other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ladies</ENAMEX> they complain because they think that um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> now are too busy with their own personal life and career that they really don't have time for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's probably true i mean they they are a lot of them that have to
 		put their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> into day care or having more with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby sitters</ENAMEX> and especially if they don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy friends</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX> and uh i guess that's why you always hear these stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> being neglected
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		in fact uh there was one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> in this area she was caught going to work and leaving her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh just a baby
 	
 	
 		not a baby uh she was old enough to
 		uh i would say she was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five to eight years old</TIMEX> somewhere along that range but that's just an extreme example i would imagine you know the situations are out there
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		well as
 		um well i think the education like our education has um increased dramatically but then i think also that we're forgetting like basic things like we should know
 	
 	
 		i agree there
 	
 	
 		like i i think well um in the morals and values of like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> for the most for most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are totally different
 		from the morals and valleys um values of like per se your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> but i think as we get older it gets to your you know what i mean i think
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> now are are i would say louder now until after they reach like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five</TIMEX> and then i think they really have a strong decline and start to settle down and realize things
 	
 	
 		yeah um i could agree with that because used to conservatism was inherent at a much younger age
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah because i think we're given more now whereas you had to work for everything and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> nowadays are just given so much that they really don't have to work and you know and they they don't have any intent to go working until they have to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's an agreeable
 		topic there
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um what else considering beside family economics
 		um our transportation system has changed for us i mean we can it we can now travel around the world in no time
 		it's just a hop skip and a jump to get into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> to go from the east to the west coast and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i i think what's happened too is just our technology is just advancing so rapidly that and there's so much information available out there that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> out there just have a hard time keeping up
 		aside from just going through their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> routine of living to get from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> to day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and to keep abreast of the
 		knowledge out there we got to constantly read go to school
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> TV watching has sure hasn't gone too much out the door because TV
 		is still well the cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">system</ENAMEX> and the satellite dishes has made it to where a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can just leave <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">regular</TIMEX> TV programming
 		and watch a lot of other a variety of programs out there as well as use of the VCR
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so that i don't know if it really hampers or it helps our education system
 	
 	
 		i don't know because i know i don't watch while i'm up here at school i don't watch hardly any TV like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> i like to sit down and watch a few shows but other than that
 	
 	
 		do you watch <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i don't watch that  i used to but i don't any more
 	
 	
 		i like that
 	
 	
 		but
 		all i mean there are even though there's a few up here we call them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couch potatoes</ENAMEX> they love to sit in front of the TV i i said but for the for the most part i will i will well i live in an all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> dorm but for the most part we're all between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages of eighteen</TIMEX> and like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there isn't really a lot of TV watching
 	
 	
 		well that's good at least you're hitting the books right
 	
 	
 		yeah well they're either hitting the books or something else i don't know what but i know oh well i guess they have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowds</ENAMEX> like during the soap operas you know like in between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i can't say that there's really that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that like sit in front of the TV all day
 	
 	
 		well that's a change then oh of course going to school too
 		it's different from the home environment
 	
 	
 		uh-huh but then um like i know this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> she's doing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX> teaching or she's just working like within the school
 		and um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> she was at the kindergarten and there's this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> he like didn't want to do anything and he said i'm not doing this i don't like it and he sat at his desk with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pencils in his hand and pretend like he's playing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nintendo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know so
 		uh i don't know how i mean i never really watched that a lot of TV when i was younger but my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> really didn't allow us to watch that much TV so i don't know
 	
 	
 		i agree with your parents
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		because uh TV kind of ruined me because that's that's all that we had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well not really but i mean
 		it's uh for the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">medium</ENAMEX> of entertainment
 	
 	
 		yeah well we watch a lot of i guess we watched a lot of TV in the winter time but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> like right now my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> well like she doesn't let us watch TV until like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock at night</TIMEX> you know are like
 	
 	
 		it was
 		even at your age
 	
 	
 		well like my younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> at home like when it starts getting nice outside in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> and everything she'll she makes us go outside even <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when i go home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> she makes us go outside and we're allowed to come in and watch TV until it's dark because she doesn't like the TV herself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and if it was up to her we wouldn't have one so you know she feels that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are too dependent on it also
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 		is there anything else
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		what about in our work ethics
 	
 	
 		work ethics oh  right now it's getting it's maybe getting better
 	
 	
 		i i
 	
 	
 		um
 		a little of course we're we're we're having to weather through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all the other scandalous items that well
 		the greed that overwhelmed us in the eighties
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i think i think it's going to have to have it's patchwork
 		put on us
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		because we have so much to pay for now
 		it's going to be really passed on to your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> and maybe a few others
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		including what's left of ours
 	
 	
 		well i really can't think of anything else
 	
 	
 		well it was nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> it was nice talking to you too
 	
 	
 		and uh what are majoring in
 		
 		
 	