
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay well um
 		do you believe only fifty percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> actually vote
 	
 	
 		i think it's somewhere really close to that cause i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> believe that their one little vote is not going to make that much difference
 		and they really don't listen to any of the issues anymore because they feel like so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are like crooked you know and so they figure why go out and vote you know they're going to do what they want to do they're corrupt anyway
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		and i think one of the good ways of solving that is to like everybody likes to come to a party so have a voting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and uh you know like in communities
 		and have the issues there and then everybody go vote together and then maybe come back over and have brunch or something i mean that's the only thing that i can figure out because
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i've heard so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say well i'm not going on voting on that one you know i i'm going to go fishing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> or it won't make any difference if if i don't vote  and i think it does we vote every time
 	
 	
 		well it uh there's no question it does make a difference uh so far as having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> and then all voting uh when you have different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">precincts</ENAMEX> you would have to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in every precinct
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to vote in different area
 		and uh not everyone votes at the same place uh i personally think that we need to do more along the education lines in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from the little ones on up
 		with the idea of the the value of voting and the purpose of voting and that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> vote does make a difference but
 	
 	
 		right and maybe maybe let them have some mock i mean uh you know elections and stuff and vote for different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in their classes and start really young that's a real good idea
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		absolutely
 		and and they are doing that in a number of schools however probably not enough of them uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> wide but it's going to take at least a whole generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh to
 		get across the idea of voting uh just like it's taking a whole generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to finally uh realize the harmfulness of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh hopefully to uh now with the many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programs</ENAMEX> throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> on how to resist taking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> how to say no to it and what have you that uh perhaps we'll finally get the youth
 		weaned off of it but uh
 		i know i i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty four years</TIMEX> in education here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dayton</ENAMEX> area and in nineteen fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> were telling us about the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> outside the school
 		and how they were just giving away their marijuana giving away their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">heroin</ENAMEX> and what have you to get them started
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and now that was in fifty one that's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> that it was already a problem so it's now uh
 	
 	
 		God
 	
 	
 		to the forefront and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are finally taking some action against it and to think we've we've neglected the value of voting
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh and what it really means to vote and  we also don't make the uh the issues perhaps in language that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> fully understand them
 	
 	
 		yeah well i don't know how it is up there but down here
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX> has a bad reputation for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> and all i mean i'm sure you heard about some of ours and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um people</ENAMEX> are just i mean it's like they're turned off on voting
 	
 	
 		um-hum sure right
 	
 	
 		and that's the reason i said maybe if you had something like a block party okay we're going to have a block party everybody's going to get together we're going to discuss the different issues and stuff and then we're going to go and vote you know we're going to go vote like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		maybe they could give something like uh the top neighborhood if you had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent in your neighborhood or something like that you know i mean it doesn't have to be it could be like a a sign that they would put down at the end of your block
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know or anything like that but
 		it it's really bad here i mean to me it is it seems like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just don't care anymore they say huh well it don't make any difference you know one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crook</ENAMEX> is as good as the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and they don't bother to listen to what any of them have to say
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> now we go vote every time i don't care how
 		small the ballot is i mean if there's one thing if there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> issue because the way i feel is if i don't vote then i don't have any reason to gripe
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 		to complain about it right right
 	
 	
 		right and i hear so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> saying well i wish this would change i wish that and you know but they didn't go vote
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and uh maybe if they like you said if they would start when little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and start letting them vote and learn how to vote and all
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		then uh and the importance of it because okay if you don't vote for your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> over here well your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>'s not going to have a chance
 	
 	
 		that is
 	
 	
 		he needs your vote just like he needs everybody elses you know maybe if they were brought up that a way like you said it would
 		because i know here uh until you get into high school now then they had the voting machines and you voted for like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cheerleaders</ENAMEX> and different things like that but they should start that a lot earlier
 	
 	
 		yes uh-huh
 		yeah i it's the same way with everything in education though it should begin and
 		right down in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade uh and your very best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> in my estimation should be <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first second</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 		develop good learning patterns and have some success and want to go on learning and continue learning uh and not wait until they're in high school and then it's too late to try to change them around at that point
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh everything should be started on the lower levels and uh certainly if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youngsters</ENAMEX> had that opportunity that
 		you know they they understood that the principles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> were established so that everyone would have a say and everyone would have a vote
 		and what that vote meant and uh but it but you're right from the standpoint that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do have a negative attitude towards politicians
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and perhaps it's because our campaigns have become so terribly expensive to run uh that only the most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wealthy</ENAMEX> can do so
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and they're not always the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> for the job but they have the money to be able to do it so uh so that there are a lot of problems along that line also and perhaps the government
 	
 	
 		
 
 		definitely
 		you know a good i idea for the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like that too is to have like a
 		a mock <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and okay this this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> tells you some things that are going to happen and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> tells you some things okay then this percentage of the
 	
 	
 		sure
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> they are not going to let them vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time</TIMEX> but they have to do whatever these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whichever <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> elect do if they did something like that and started <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> out real young and showed them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay now you're not going to get to vote but you're going to have to do what that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> says they would understand probably by the time they were in high school they'd be ready to vote
 	
 	
 		yes
 		right that's right and i think you know that's an excellent idea they for them to realize that that their going to have to do what someone else says even though they didn't vote for it
 		and that maybe maybe to think twice about voting now some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> object during primaries having to declare a party
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		whether <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> and you do that in the primary uh and i don't know that uh a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> vote in primaries for that very reason
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they can declare anything they want and they can actually <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> it if they really wanted to vote <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> they could go in the primary and say they were voting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> and then stack the ballot
 		for someone that perhaps the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> could beat but uh
 		it's uh it's just a sad situation and uh i do think more needs to be done along that line to help to uh
 		teach the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> uh uh everyone uh more about what is going on with voting and with non voting
 		so that uh we can make some start making some more intelligent decisions and it's going to take these young you know it's going to take the uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i think that sounds great
 	
 	
 		a whole generation of my feeling uh before that's going to be accomplished that's right
 	
 	
 		well you know they'd have to start when they're real young i mean you know it would have to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that is just coming in the school
 		because i well i'll tell you another thing too now whenever
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i voted i never voted in high school because there was never anyone that showed us how to use the voting machines now this sounds dumb but i did not know how to use those voting machines
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and nobody ever showed us or anything so i didn't vote because
 		anybody that went in there and they asked a question all the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> laughed at them they thought that was funny oh she don't even know how
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so there wasn't any way i was going to go in there and vote and it took me i mean it took such courage you wouldn't believe to go vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time</TIMEX> because i was waiting for somebody to laugh at me because i didn't know how to work the machines
 	
 	
 		and
 		sure
 		right well sure it is
 	
 	
 		now that's bad and i mean i was out of school i was a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i didn't know how to work the machine you know and it really scared me really bad because i thought all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to laugh at me because i don't know how to work this machine where if they'd if they'd had a class or something or just a short
 	
 	
 		well just the just the opportunity to try the voting machines yeah
 	
 	
 		time you know that that okay this is the way
 		right it's this is the way it's going to be and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was exactly the same way that i was and i didn't realize it until uh his senior year
 		i said asked him something about well did you who did you vote for for uh cheerleader and he said oh i didn't go vote he said uh there's no way i'm getting in that machine well then i realized it so when we went and voted the next time i asked
 		the uh lady i said i want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> to come in with me
 		and she said well uh why you know he'll have to come back out i said because i want him to know how to use one of these and i said i won't turn any of the buttons down but i want to show him how to use it so that he'll be able to vote
 	
 	
 		right
 		yes uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh so he went in and now he's a registered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voter</ENAMEX> but he would not vote before that
 	
 	
 		good
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i mean i think that's bad you know here i was and and even of course there's a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us but even with that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX> between the
 	
 	
 		sure it is absolutely
 		
 		
 	