
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay what are your feelings on crime and what can be done about it
 		i'd be interested in hearing since you are a prison guard
 	
 	
 		the problem goes all the way back to the entire criminal justice system needs to be reworked
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> that's for sure i agree there
 	
 	
 		no longer do we have a point where the crime fits the punishment we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> now with in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> anyway is what i'm talking about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with the situation we've got with prison overcrowding and everything a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> gets a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifteen year</TIMEX> sentence they're averaging serving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> assessed
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that's not
 		the punishment is not fitting the crime now
 	
 	
 		no that's for sure
 		i mean it's it's kind of sad when you have to give them more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> life sentence in order to insure that they're going to stay in for a while i mean you know
 		even that's what
 	
 	
 		i even gone have gone to the point where i don't believe in giving them a life sentence if you have to do that you might as well shoot them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it costs twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollars</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX> per year just to keep them locked up that doesn't count any medical or dental health they get
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		a bullet costs twenty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five cents</NUMEX> you tell me which one's more cost effective
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah and who's paying for it  certainly not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in there the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> in in a in the sense are paying for it
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 		right no yeah they do need to to drastically do something uh about the whole works because uh it's obvious especially with the introduction of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> now that crime is is there's
 		it's in such the uprise i mean there's so much more of it now than there was even fifteen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		as long as you've got the problem
 		a big part of the problem anyway take a look at most of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> that are in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">ninety percent</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		are practicing lawyers
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		as long as you got practicing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in politics
 		they're going to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rig</ENAMEX> the laws to where they know they're never going to run out of business
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		as far as hard line laws dealing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> we don't have them in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> anymore we have situation ethics
 	
 	
 		oh i believe that i do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">john Q Citizen</ENAMEX> goes up
 		robs the liquor store shoots the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> behind the counter
 		his his uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> is going to argue that well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> was under the influence of whatever drug he was on at the time and he wasn't really in his normal frame frame of mind
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well apparently he had enough snapping to where he got it whatever weapon he used and he was coherent enough to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> give me the money or i'm going to kill you
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if he if he had enough snap to do that he knew what he was doing the penalty assessed is death period
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i
 	
 	
 		that's too simple
 	
 	
 		i yeah i know uh that is too simple <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">well</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> keep saying well what if they you know but uh they're uh look at how long <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sit on death row
 	
 	
 		that's
 	
 	
 		before they even do i mean they've been assigned the death penalty and they don't even do it you know
 	
 	
 		well that's that's one of my biggest screams about the entire death penalty goes for
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> they just appeal it and appeal it and appeal it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has done a crime so bad that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> gives them the death penalty
 		now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> says we've got to give them one appeal okay i agree give them one appeal when that appeal fails within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty days</TIMEX> execution of sentence
 	
 	
 		okay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right but that's all
 		yes look i mean that has to be one of the biggest wasters of money is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> sit on death row i mean
 	
 	
 		i think that you know of the the uh
 		he run across a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s file that was like on death row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> before they finally got around to executing him
 	
 	
 		oh no i mean look at them
 	
 	
 		i think you keeping him on death row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> was cruel and unusual torture
 	
 	
 		oh yeah they're you know they say that they can't uh inflict cruel cruel and unusual punishment but boy what is that knowing that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> the shoe could drop i mean yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		that's it
 	
 	
 		i mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> that's incredible oh i don't know what the average is uh uh for
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> is the average wow
 	
 	
 		is the average because they'll appeal it for that many times
 	
 	
 		hum-um it should be never it should that should have a cutoff time just like uh uh statutes of limits and everything all that other stuff you know they they should have like within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX>
 		so that they'd have enough time for an appeal and uh you know get that stuff out of the way and if it's turned down the the you know after that if if <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have said it then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> is enough
 		
 
 		they shouldn't even allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to go any further
 		i think they're kind of bending the law just they just want more money is what it is i'm sorry
 	
 	
 		they want the money so they're going to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they will twist it and bend it
 	
 	
 		well uh that's kind of obvious i mean they're even carrying it to to where now uh that they advertise on TV you know
 		if your if you uh you know have done this or if you need this uh uh we'll sue for you and you don't have to pay us unless you but then what they don't tell you is that if you if they win you give them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least a third</NUMEX> of the of the thing that they win
 		so  i don't know it is uh it's getting to be more business now rather than uh actually uh dealing with the crime than with uh um
 		the uh punishment they the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are just in it for the money  i'm i'm convinced i know i i agree with you i think you're real you're very right that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> should i think they should
 		have an equal amount of you know maybe they can have a few but i think most of them should be not uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in the fact and that's way way they've gotten into politics it's because of the the law things you know the loops and everything
 		but uh
 		but no i know we it um we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and uh we have the same thing overcrowding and and uh they are letting them out i mean just the regular jail sentence thing they let them out because of they don't have any place to keep to put them
 		so somebody that could you know uh unless uh been a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> but uh uh even the piddly little stuff i mean the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that loses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is the victim
 		and whoever that may be whether it's a robbery or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or whatever else um
 		they are the ones that are going to pay and they are the one that are going to suffer
 		and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> you know if they pay if they if they
 		uh arrest them uh and uh then the you know time the law takes over uh half the time uh they either let them go or they get off with a a sentence because they've had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> that
 		you know feels that
 		that they weren't all together when they did it
 	
 	
 		things are going to come to a point it's going to probably
 		get to such an extent where the average <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> if they see a crime go down or a crime is happening against them they're not going to worry about trying to get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> they're not going to worry about it because they're going to be packing their own heat and they're going to take care of business themselves
 	
 	
 		right although you know uh  that uh it's kind of a catch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty two</TIMEX> because if you defend yourself or as there was a case where this
 		fellow in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> kept having his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> broken into uh through a vent in the ceiling in the ceiling u h the roof so he put an electric grate there well somebody tried to break in
 		got stuck and was electrocuted and he was being sued
 		because this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> was breaking into his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> he got electrocuted and was killed coming into his store
 	
 	
 		that's where if you had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> that had any backbone whatsoever they'd have thrown that out before it even got
 	
 	
 		that's right that's right you know now here's the innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that's just trying to keep in business you know he had tried <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> he tried security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he tried you know several other things the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> like they would just kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> you know so uh it's
 		it's it's wrong your right  um i
 		it it seems unfortunate and a little frustrating because it seems like we have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> the there isn't mu ch we can do um you try to hope that uh you know
 		your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> and uh are going to represent what the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want but uh uh they certainly
 		i'm not sure which way to take to shake up the system bad enough to start making some reforms sure would be nice to see it happening soon
 		because it's obvious that uh pretty soon they're not going to be able to handle you know all of the crime that there is
 		so  i don't know
 		uh
 		it must be especially frustrating to you having do you work there now or is was this uh uh was this before
 	
 	
 		i work there now
 	
 	
 		oh okay so it's just another job uh it must be especially frustrating because even your rights in there  are
 	
 	
 		when i walk through this is what's bad when i walk through the front gate
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> have more rights than i do
 	
 	
 		yeah and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> does that stink uh that's the same way here uh
 		and they have more freedom i mean i understand that i mean i'm not i mean you can't be everywhere all the time and i'm sure that they have searches and everything but i mean
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> that they make or that they get and the i mean
 		to me it'd be like walking around in a time bomb all the time even just being there you know just working there um
 		because you never know if you're going to get knifed or something uh you know as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> that it must be scary  uh
 		and yet
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> it is
 	
 	
 		yeah well they and yet did they can they do anything to them when they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> i mean surely they can
 		put them in solitary or something i mean  or is that just mythical
 	
 	
 		uh you can put a there's um any number of things you can do
 		aside from locking up in solitaire you can reduce their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> in good time have them sent to
 		a harder <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> than what they're already locked up into they've got the different security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> you've got your minimum in minimum out you've got your medium and then
 	
 	
 		oh okay i didn't know that
 		
 		
 	