
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		the public school systems
 		well everybody's known has known they've needed renovation for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but never really had a clear direction on which way to go with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the first direction that i can see
 		or i wish i would love to see them go with
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> learn at different rates and for too long they've kind of lumped everybody together you'd learn at this rate and that's the only way it's going to happen
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you've got some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that'll pick up on it in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the first three minutes</TIMEX> you're talking about it and the rest the other fifty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven minutes</TIMEX> you've been talking about a subject you've bored them
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's
 		that's very true um
 		i guess i can relate to that because i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that are opposites like that
 		uh one picks up real quick and the other one doesn't and you're right they do get bored uh really fast if they already know what you're talking about
 		what do you propose that they do what what is your suggestions
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">educators</ENAMEX> need to be a little bit more
 		open minded as well as innovative in dealing with
 		uh the various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 		to get the maximum
 		potential out of the person
 	
 	
 		uh-huh out of each child
 	
 	
 		out of each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are going to be great with mechanical stuff other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are going to be
 	
 	
 		each individual child
 	
 	
 		really into math some are really going to be heavy into reading
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		instead of
 		pushing the scales too far either direction
 		i mean it's great to be well rounded and have be exposed to all this stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		but why not hit the points the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s really interested in because if he's interested he's going to study it and he's going to learn it and he's going to remember it
 	
 	
 		that's true the only i think the only thing that they would argue about that is that you know every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> needs to learn every subject i mean that's that might be the only thing
 		but i mean i i definitely agree with you  um
 	
 	
 		they need exposure to every subject they don't need to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> of it
 	
 	
 		right right that's true
 	
 	
 		everything i learned about ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX> has has not helped me anywhere in my adult life
 	
 	
 		um
 		yes i definitely agree  there's no doubt about that
 		i uh i i mean i can relate to that because i'm i'm going to college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and i feel like i mean i'm taking this history class
 		and i mean it's so boring and i just hate it  and i think why do they make us take this stuff i mean what does this have to do with getting you know a computer science degree or whatever you know
 	
 	
 		what what type of history <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> is it that you're having to take
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">uh American History</ENAMEX>
 		we have to take um like this is like early <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen hundreds</NUMEX> through i don't know i think like mid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen hundreds</NUMEX> and then we have to take another one that's mid <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen hundreds</NUMEX> on up to basically present
 	
 	
 		well the early ones
 		they could actually combine <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two two</NUMEX> levels of it the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seventeen hundred</NUMEX> until
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		say the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> combine that into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and then from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen sixty five</NUMEX> to present and make that your <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> step because
 	
 	
 		yeah that's well that's basically what they're doing
 	
 	
 		to a point to a point the bottom you know the early parts of it you're giving the foundations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and
 		but
 		even then they're skimming over they're very trivial almost trivial with it
 	
 	
 		yeah oh yes definitely i agree
 	
 	
 		they want if i mean if they really wanted to get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> of the matter i mean there's
 	
 	
 		yeah there's
 	
 	
 		they make all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out to be oh they were great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and all this he had just as much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX> on him as anybody else if not more
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> was not a saint
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true yeah
 		any way this this um school system thing i i tell you i saw something on the news oh
 		i don't know maybe  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> and they were talking about i don't know where you're from but i'm from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area
 		and they were talking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Plano</ENAMEX> school system that they had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> school
 		that uh if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> did something wrong i mean whether it was behavioral or uh you know they weren't learning properly or something they took these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and put them basically in a closet
 		with no windows they had a a table or not a table but a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> in this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX> and they had to sit in there by themselves
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were getting really angry  about this because they said why is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> being put in this closet well how is that helping my child
 		you know and
 		uh the the thing you know they said well we're giving them isolation time and this helps them to think
 		
 
 		but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i mean if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> has
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> claustrophobia i mean that's just going to terrify him you know and
 	
 	
 		if if the isolation concept really works that good why are our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> overcrowded
 	
 	
 		uh that's true
 		that's true but no i mean they were uh i mean i definitely agree with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i think that is a very wrong way to handle uh disciplining a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> putting them in
 		i mean they were they were called they called them their quiet <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> or their isolation <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> they didn't call them closets but they showed these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> on uh you know on the news and i mean they looked like a closet to me you know with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">desk</ENAMEX> in it a real small
 		but they said that one of the solutions they came up with was to take the doors off of these isolation rooms
 		i said now what good does this i mean how is this helping i mean either way
 		you know i i definitely had to disagree with that i think that is
 		that's not the way to handle a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> you know discipline a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> by putting him in a closet
 	
 	
 		the the um
 		as a part of the revamping of the entire education system on that level the public school system i want to see changed too
 		when i was brought brought up
 		if you crossed the line and you broke a rule bad enough you were going to get spanked well then the extreme came in and now we can no longer spank them so we now isolate them
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		yep uh
 	
 	
 		okay we've swung the pendulum both ways let's find a middle ground instead of
 		there has to be some sort of discipline and there has to be some sort of punishment
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		short of physically isolating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and short of physically hitting the child
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		let's put him into a situation where okay you crossed the line you broke the rule you're going to have to pay for it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but
 		it's going to tax you physically
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		i i don't
 	
 	
 		have the i mean
 		instead instead have have them pick up around the school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> have them
 		weed a flower bed somewhere on the school <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> do something to beautify the school property
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		but you cut you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s having to give up his quote play time to
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		pay his debt for what he did wrong
 		but he's seeing something c onstructive come out of it
 	
 	
 		well
 		um i have to i think one of the positive things
 		i mean one of the things that can come out of uh
 		is not just discipline discipline okay but okay for instance one of the things they do at uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> school uh they have what they call uh caught being good slips
 		and when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">halls</ENAMEX> and stuff and if they're being really good i mean just being excellent they're not you know cutting up and so on they're just standing in line doing whatever they are supposed to they get one of these caught being good slips
 		and then when they collect them at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of each week</TIMEX> they get to go to this little what they call their caught being good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and then they get to spend these like money
 		well see to me that's positive reinforcement is much better much better than trying to find ways to discipline kids
 		because they're going to be good and try and earn those things
 		you know to get the positive part of it i mean they'd rather much rather go in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and buy something than be spanked so they're definitely going to work towards being good you know rather than trying to act up and be bad
 		you know
 	
 	
 		i think that not only applies inside the public school system but in society itself we've been too long there's been too much negative reinforcement how much
 		day like
 		the caught being good slips how about just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Q</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> out there on the street
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that's true  i think i think really though i mean that's one thing that i mean my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> definitely get spanked when they need they need to be spanked
 		but i really do try to use positive uh reinforcement with them at home also and it really helps and i mean they they don't get spanked very often but
 		they they do when they deserve it you know but uh
 		i don't think any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> should be exempt from being spanked
 		i mean i i think i wouldn't mind if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> spanked my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> but you know that's just my personal opinion and that's not going to i mean i don't think that law will ever change
 		they are never going to let a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> spank a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> again
 		but i don't think i mean some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> don't get don't get spanked at home and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> need to be spanked at home i mean don't you think
 	
 	
 		i most most most wholeheartedly agree
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i don't know
 	
 	
 		i mean there's a point of over kill but somewhere in you've got to find an even line
 	
 	
 		right right well there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that say you can deal with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> without spanking them which is true you can but there are times when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> needs to be spanked i mean they do things that they need that
 	
 	
 		need that shock effect where they equate the shock of being spanked with the actions they did to get spanked
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	