
 
     		
 	
 		child care seems to be uh a uh a topic that
 		varies i guess with where you are geographically if you're in an area where you got a lot to select from then i guess there are a lot of criterias to choose from but if you're in an area where there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> then uh you get what you can take
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i guess it'd depend on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> the needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> how long the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> has to be there if it's a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five day a week</TIMEX> deal i would certainly look a lot harder than if it was just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of days</TIMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we're in a situation where it's just one maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX> a month uh at best so we're
 	
 	
 		well that's lucky
 	
 	
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a couple of hours</TIMEX> usually what we use them for now is to transport between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> and have them wait there just long enough for me to get off work and go pick them up
 	
 	
 		yeah that's good
 	
 	
 		so it's nice to uh to just have them there for the limited time frame but the uh
 		the drawback is the pay <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> there's so many different situations that these day care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> have to get into they have a lot of the ones have just decided that
 		they will simplify their work load by saying if you get on the bus to ride between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and day care you'll pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars regardless of whether you road one way or both ways and regardless of whether you stayed there just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">half an hour</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they just averaged it all out but most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> stay until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six</TIMEX> so it will be about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars which will cover the ride and cover the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> you stay
 	
 	
 		wow
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i've got uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> getting out at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two forty five</NUMEX> and one getting out at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three thirty</TIMEX> so the one gets picked up at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two forty five</NUMEX> gets there by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i'm there a little before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four o'clock</TIMEX> to pick them up
 		so he doesn't stay there even <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> is not even there when i get there and doesn't get there until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about four</TIMEX> it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about thirty minutes</TIMEX> to do a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minute</TIMEX> ride in there little bus and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so the you know just for the doesn't really work out for us too economical to pay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> dollars for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> way bus ride for these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> we have to do it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> it just works out to where i don't get into work early enough to get off
 	
 	
 		yeah i can see that
 	
 	
 		early enough to get them but uh fortunately the other end of the deal is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some days</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		being a dental hygienist works by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">appointments</ENAMEX> so she if she has a day scheduled where she has to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> into the day care to of them take them to school and she has uh a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		an appointment say at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight thirty</TIMEX> and she has to be all the way across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> at her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight thirty</TIMEX> then she needs to have them ride the bus one way and i'll get off in time to hopefully pick both of them up and not have the day care <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in the other direction
 		but uh just a myriad of of possibilities that these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to serve so they have a myriad of pay structures but uh it it can get expensive most of them run uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four some as many as five</NUMEX> dollars <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">an hour</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> for uh what we call drop in care which is the situation we're in we're not a regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so the days</TIMEX> we do use them we pay through the nose and uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		oh i bet
 	
 	
 		and make their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> stay there we found on in the area that that is letting us pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as little as two</NUMEX> fifty an hour that's still <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five dollars</NUMEX> an hour for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and it it's uh fun we try to keep it to a minimum
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i bet yeah i you'd have to
 	
 	
 		yeah it's
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i when when i uh i i i was i was a commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost six years</TIMEX> before um we started our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and i looked into uh into child care and
 		and we were living in we were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North</ENAMEX> building at the time and we just didn't like anything we saw we really i didn't want to leave an infant
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with the child care that was in it the immediate area
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that we were we were located in so we uh we  tightened some belt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		belt loops and uh i just i decided to stay home with with her and we're we're expecting our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> any day now in fact i'm past due  well so so i just
 		so we've been real pleased that our that that i that i haven't to to use the  we haven't had to use day care but because what we found we just didn't like at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well even if you work out the economics if you get over all the other hurdles of the ratio of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and uh the uh infant worker
 		uh worker areas how well that's closed off or how not well that's closed off from the other noise
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh once you get over all the other hurdles just the economics of it uh it's not
 		as much of an impact to stay home as it were if you figure in what it would cost you to go back to work and you know the
 	
 	
 		right oh right that's exactly what it was with us it was just it was uh we all we had to do was we pay off a vehicle early
 		and then i would have just been paying for for that and and child care was my uh salary and it wasn't worth it
 	
 	
 		yep
 		that
 		that's it
 	
 	
 		so it was
 	
 	
 		of course you couldn't have known <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two to three years ago</TIMEX> when you were making this decision what the taxes were going to do now the child care what you do pay doesn't not even worth a hill of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX> on your tax return can't deduct it so what's it good for
 	
 	
 		no it's not
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so it's it's gotten it's changed a little bit over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		yeah uh it is so expensive down here for a child care because we're originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri Missouri</ENAMEX> and most and of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s still there and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> have their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in child care and it's a lot less expensive then it is down here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's um it's it's amazingly less expensive than it is
 	
 	
 		well what the market can bear and
 	
 	
 		yeah oh it oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in this this little section of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Plano</ENAMEX> that we're in we're surrounded
 		less than a mile we have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> to our at our disposal so
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		we can go north to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them or south to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of them or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just over</NUMEX> west a little bit further and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more over there there's just all around us but and we've been to everyone of them over the time
 	
 	
 		well that's lucky
 	
 	
 		but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just well we used to use them a little more than we do now that they're in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> just kind of get tired of them
 	
 	
 		that's lucky
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they get tired of the uh you know what's available to play on and uh and what's outside and and plus they they tend to just shift around in in who runs them for a while and the uh pay structure changes and
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		so we've just moved with wherever's it happens to be cheapest and they happen to want to survive at  and they want to live at this one for a while
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we found it cheaper even during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> for me to uh take off for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a day</TIMEX> since we work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a four and a half day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">work week</TIMEX> and come home on these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Thursdays</ENAMEX> that she goes to work at uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and get's off at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven thirty</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that she does that on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Thursdays</ENAMEX> and then occasional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s and i can take off on those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s and be home in time to for her to go off to work and it's cheaper for me to do that and take my vacation even if i uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all thirteen weeks of summer</TIMEX> that's less than uh right at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks full full uh full week</TIMEX>'s worth of vacation and i have you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks a year</TIMEX> i been long enough to do that
 	
 	
 		wow
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		now i always end up in a must take situation anyway so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we decided to eat it up that way and still take a week off and still have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> to for whatever <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week long weekends</TIMEX> or the like and
 		i think we're going to do that again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> like we did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> because we paid close to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">eight hundred dollars</NUMEX> just to have someone come into the home
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		at a couple a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> an hour
 		to take care of them on those Thursdays throughout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it it's hard to to find the prices i guess that does seem to be one of the major driving factors
 	
 	
 		i know oh it is it it it plus plus um when we were in in the section of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> over by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Addison</ENAMEX> there's just not hardly any day care over there at all it's surprising
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because of the when i was searching for it the best the best place i could find in the was down in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmers Branch</ENAMEX> and i worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carrollton</ENAMEX> it just and i was i was going to have to drive and drive and drive and and it was just it was just really
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there were just so many strikes against it but
 		uh like up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> there's there's a few places there's like i think there's i've seen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> up here
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and there's just really not very much
 	
 	
 		well i guess they haven't had the i don't know what the incentive would be but
 		um
 		i guess with all the ones around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Plano</ENAMEX> area and figuring that most of them drive south for their jobs maybe they maybe they've done it that way and going with that logic
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		oh yeah a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> drive into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> from here a lots of them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		it must be on what they're counting on
 	
 	
 		so
 		yeah yeah i i i assume so
 	
 	
 		hum well uh speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hollering at me so i better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on we'll
 	
 	
 		okay
 		okay well nice talking to you bye bye
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX> paths later um bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
 		
 	