
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i don't know how you feel about this but uh it's really scary to me
 	
 	
 		oh oh yeah me too
 	
 	
 		there was a thing in our we have a little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lewisville</ENAMEX> paper that just comes out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twice a week</TIMEX> and there was a thing in there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just this week</TIMEX> saying that in all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denton County Lewisville</ENAMEX> had the highest crime rate of all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denton it</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it's not surprising considering how close to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it is
 	
 	
 		i guess that's true but you know you've got to figure uh you've got to look at it like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrollton</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denton County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		you know you know and it gets kind of scary you know when you're looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lewisville</ENAMEX> you're looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denton</ENAMEX> you're looking at you know some of the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewisville</ENAMEX> had more crime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last year</TIMEX> than any of them and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's just getting it's just getting really scary and almost uh out of hand you know there's been
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i don't know if you've heard any but any of it on the news lately or not but there's been a couple of uh you know uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> there was a deal in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> where they had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> taking little girls out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> breaking into their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> windows
 	
 	
 		yes oh yes i was living up there when all that mess was happening
 	
 	
 		at that time there's been a couple of those here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lewisville</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few weeks</TIMEX> yeah and they're you know they're not sure if we're working with the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> or not but uh it's really scary you know it really is so
 	
 	
 		is there
 		yeah
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		what are things like you said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> do you live in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> too are things pretty calm up there or
 	
 	
 		yes we
 		uh oh yeah it's it's deader than a doornail up here we've only lived around my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was uh transferred up here from uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">North Building</ENAMEX> we're to um so it's we've been up here for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight six or eight months</TIMEX> an it's a lot different than <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah yeah
 		i grew up in i went to high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frisco</ENAMEX> and lived there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> so i was up you know pretty close to where you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are and and it was always
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frisco</ENAMEX> there always seemed to be a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frisco</ENAMEX> for as small a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> as it was there were a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really oh uh
 		um
 	
 	
 		but as far as major crime there didn't seem to be as you know one of those nice little small <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> and nothing ever happened and it would be nice to kind of get back into that so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i just don't know as a matter of fact i had uh one of these conversations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> where our topic was uh capital punishment and you know the death penalty and you know what you know we were talking about that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the things that we kind of got to talking about is you know what is it we can do you know what can what can be done to stop it and i'm not sure that i know the answer to that question
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i don't know that one
 	
 	
 		you know i mean one of the things that we talked about that i truly believe is you know you give somebody a you know a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> convicts somebody and they give them a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty year</TIMEX> sentence and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> going to be out in twelve or thirteen years you know
 	
 	
 		if if that long
 	
 	
 		yet they oh it's very wrong it's horrible you know i have i take a business law class um on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">instructor</ENAMEX> is a practicing criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know so he does this like everyday you know deals with this and he said you know you could pretty much if you sit on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> know right now you could be sure that they will serve just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about a quarter</NUMEX> of whatever you give them you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		why is that why is that
 	
 	
 		well they they say we don't have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> and we've got to get them out well if that's the case let's come up with some money somewhere
 	
 	
 		i know
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to build some more and keep these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in i mean there was a thing on TV <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> where they were interviewing it was it was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> and they were interviewing these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are like they asked them is this a deterrent and they all said no
 	
 	
 		of course not
 	
 	
 		i mean we're going to be out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> this is no big deal i mean this is like a little vacation we don't have to work we don't have to you know we don't have to worry about making a living you know we're fed and we're clothed and we're you know this is no big deal and
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		
 
 		don't have to do anything
 	
 	
 		and you know they were asked you know well when you get out will you commit that same crime again and they said probably you know this is how we live that's how we make our living we live by selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> we live by stealing we live by this you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so obviously the system's not working you know an uh and i don't know what to do to make it work and so you know
 	
 	
 		no no it's not
 		oh it it's it's too it's too hard to enforce the capital punishment it takes it it's all all this automatic appeal stuff it just drags it out for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and years
 	
 	
 		right
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years and years</TIMEX> that's something we talked about too you know if you
 	
 	
 		and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> forget you know they you hear oh this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s going to be put to death but you don't they don't tell you what this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> has done
 	
 	
 		what this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> had done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> the brutality of their crime exactly exactly
 	
 	
 		yeah killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or something like this and and and you don't get to hear that part
 	
 	
 		oh that kind of wears off with time and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s outrage slowly goes away and you know
 	
 	
 		mine doesn't  i know what you're saying
 	
 	
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> doesn't either but with specific yeah but with specific cases <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but you know the names aren't familiar anymore and
 	
 	
 		oh that's true that's very true
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't remember the what happened and they don't remember the outrage they felt at the time you know that oh my God look what he did you know and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they say they'll say oh he killed a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> you know who has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah they don't mention that part yeah that's exactly right there was a thing on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> about they had this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> uh her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was a police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> and was killed
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		i think brutally i mean this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> point blank just shot him in the head i mean just uh for no reason i mean he the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> pulled him over for like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">manor</ENAMEX> minor traffic thing you know and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know they she was getting ready to go through the trial you know for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> and you know they they asked her uh can you imagine they asked her if she wanted the death penalty and she said yes
 	
 	
 		oh God
 		wouldn't that be horrible
 		of course uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i do
 		
  
 		and i want to sit on the front row when it happens i want to be there i want to watch it you know and you can't blame her for feeling that vindictive you know i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no you can not
 	
 	
 		and you know it showed her trying to explain to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> is you know and it was just oh it was just
 	
 	
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		it was just horrible i mean this her little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> was like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and she was you know all of a sudden she started crying and said mommy i w ant my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> and and you know her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mommy</ENAMEX> said i know honey an oh and this little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> said uh
 	
 	
 		yeah and they just can't grasp it
 	
 	
 		said something about that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> shot my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> didn't he and the her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> said yeah honey the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> shot your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> and uh she said where did he shoot my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and it was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> said well we won't worry about that right now and she said i think he shot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX> in the face and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> said well you're right you know and she just started crying and it was just so sad you know i mean just i want to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah oh
 		um
 		and how a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year old</TIMEX> can grasp something like that is beyond is just a uh
 	
 	
 		no you
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> can't grasp something like that the enormity of it you know i mean i don't
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		i don't know and these poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are going to be fatherless forever and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> ought chances are he he'll be out he'll be walking the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and it's just doesn't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		will be out
 		or uh or you and i are going to be supporting him for the rest of his life
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that's right that's right i don't know i just i know you know i look at some of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">the millions of dollars</NUMEX> that we you know give to other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> every year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and i know some of the i know those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i i mean i know they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> too and i know they deserve to have food to eat and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to drink
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i just want to say hey you know let's straighten out you know use that money and straighten ourselves out before we go trying to heal the world you know i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes uh too much we give away way too much in my in my opinion
 	
 	
 		oh we do we do we do it we really do
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		and i guess if if we would as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> unite and sit down and and if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of letters in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> saying we're not going to take this anymore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're either you know do away with some of these laws providing this or we're going to vote you out next time maybe something would happen you know but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't get involved and don't sit down and do that so i don't know
 	
 	
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would rather hide their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		yeah and just not pay any attention to it yeah
 	
 	
 		and not venture venture out their own front door than
 	
 	
 		yeah well we're feeding starving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> overseas but we're not paying any attention to the ones that are starving next door you know it's really sad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it really is i heard something that their supposed to be starting a huge campaign in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> about um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse and stopping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> abuse and it's supposed to be like it's starting there supposed to be like a big nationwide campaign and you know so hopefully that will take off and really do something i don't know there's just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		that would be nice but you know it's like the big drug campaigns that you hear every once in a while they the big hype is at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and then it just kind of fizzles and dies
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		kind of fizzles out yeah that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		and uh it's just
 		it it's got to start at home is where it's got to start and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh it's
 		but then there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you get so many different opinions like well you shouldn't have well i shouldn't have to have to do this or i shouldn't have to do that and all this other stuff i don't want to get involved and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it just
 	
 	
 		i chased a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> down on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> we had put <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> out in the front yard for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> egg hunt for you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousins</ENAMEX> and stuff and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> came along and just started grabbing them stealing them i went running after them screaming hey you stop you stop i called the police
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		you know i mean there was <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that laughed at me they were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> then i called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> because i figured if these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Easter eggs</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's theft that is theft yes um-hum
 	
 	
 		they're going to be stealing <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen</TIMEX> and robbing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty one</TIMEX> you know if it doesn't stop
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well you've got to be held accountable for your actions no matter how old you are or what it is
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> knew that what they were doing was wrong and when i screamed at them to stop they kept running they knew what they were doing was wrong that's why i called the police
 	
 	
 		of course
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to heck with them you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> asked me if i wanted to press charges and i said no i'm not going to press charges i wanted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys parents</ENAMEX> to know what had happened and i want you to go to talk to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and i want you know their their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to be aware
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yes that
 		now that's something that sure doesn't happen anymore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> if you did something to somebody else you got trotted over to that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and and you had to apologize to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and all this other kind of stuff
 	
 	
 		well
 		this is exactly what i told my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> you know when it was all over i said if we had a decent set of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> here those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> will be back here <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX> with money to repay the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> and with a big apology and nothing
 	
 	
 		of course
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		nothing of course
 	
 	
 		nothing the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> ran i couldn't keep up with them but the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> was like carrying a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year old</TIMEX> on her back and i was able to keep up with her and follow her until the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> came you know so we would know who they were and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> called her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to come and pick them up
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> had the same attitude as she as she did they were convinced that the absolute only reason i called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> was because she was black it had nothing to do with the fact that she stole from me
 	
 	
 		oh Lord
 	
 	
 		and the little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> told me that the only reason you called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> is because i'm black and the little <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year</TIMEX> old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> she had with her she patted her on the leg and said see what happens when your black <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">honey</ENAMEX> you'll live with this your whole life
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		
  
 		and i told her i said honey this has nothing to do with you being black i'd follow white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that stole from me i mean stealing is stealing i don't care what color you are you think just because you're black you can steal and nobody's going to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> that doesn't make any sense
 	
 	
 		no ugh
 	
 	
 		you know oh it was just horrible and then the mother's attitude the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> looked at me and goes well what is it that you want do you want me to pay you for your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">eggs</ENAMEX> or what you know it was that kind of attitude you know i mean it was just bad and i thought you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> went home and you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 		
 	