
 
     		
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so who is your favorite football team
 	
 	
 		guess i bet you can't guess
 	
 	
 		well i would say the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saints</TIMEX> after
 	
 	
 		you got it
 		and i want to tell you something
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		they're going to go somewhere pretty shortly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah i think they are because they're getting better every year
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh they got a lot
 	
 	
 		can't call them the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Saints</ENAMEX> any more
 	
 	
 		i don't think so
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		we went to the play-offs
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well i'm a i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> Bills fan
 	
 	
 		yeah now i like them too
 	
 	
 		from a
 		from a long time ago so it's good to it's good to see the Bills doing so well now and
 	
 	
 		they are they are doing a whole bunch better who's their quarterback
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		who's their quarterback
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Jim Kelly</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i like to watch them too they're the i like to watch almost all the football but um of course i watch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every Saints</TIMEX> game that i can watch
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i think they're going to i think they're really going to do good because it seems like they're finally all coming together
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if they would just quit blowing it
 	
 	
 		well the it the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> draft really seems to be doing its job because got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> like
 		like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> who weren't certainly weren't a powerhouse uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> now they've been able to get some good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and come around and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> the same story and uh
 		and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denver</ENAMEX> was a powerhouse and then they uh
 		they weren't getting the draft picks and now the uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> so it seems to be uh moving around and uh to to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> benefit and uh you see how look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> now they're uh they're hurting
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		really bad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but they got so much bad publicity too and i think that hurt a lot of you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even wanting to play on their team
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah well well well yeah uh firing firing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Landry</ENAMEX> and hiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX> what what kind of uh uh
 		doesn't give you much respect for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> at all any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that that where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> would fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Landry</ENAMEX> you know is like one of the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coaches</ENAMEX> of all time
 	
 	
 		right right
 	
 	
 		and just because they had had a couple of bad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> and you can't even attribute those bad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasons</TIMEX> to bad coaching
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah because all the problems i mean if you think about those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that we had the losing season of how bad i mean his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> were constantly getting kicked off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> because of uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know messing with young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and i mean it was just one thing it seemed like right after the other
 	
 	
 		right and he always and uh had a lot of trouble with injuries too
 	
 	
 		with them
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know he'd uh never seem to be able to keep his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> healthy and then even like uh what is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Dickerson</ENAMEX> left the team you know that you're right you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were jumping ship right and left
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i don't know that sounds to to me more like the front office problem than coaching problem but then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was sold
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		but uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Johnson</ENAMEX> came in too though and he just you know when he bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and all and it just seemed like he just decided you know this is the way it's going to be and it was bad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean it really was to me it was like it's going to take them quite a while to rebuild because everything everything i mean anything that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Landry</ENAMEX> wanted or had he was going to change it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i mean it's that i mean you know that's the way i felt about it but i tell you what if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> ever gets a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> ain't nobody going to beat us
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in fact nobody going to beat us then because look how good we did without a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> this year
 	
 	
 		i know who was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> see i can't even think of who the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		well
 		they had quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> if you think about it uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arcade</ENAMEX> was for a while
 		and then um i can't remember that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s name the one that held out for the money and he was across the river
 		uh i can't think of the i can't think of his name now but really we didn't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> that was the whole problem we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that couldn't throw and we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that couldn't run
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		and it was it was just bedlam we really didn't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> it was uh defense winning winning winning all the games
 	
 	
 		did they were they able to draft anybody this year
 	
 	
 		i don't know because you know they gave away a lot of their drafts
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for you know other places
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i don't know i hadn't heard you know whether they have a new one or not
 	
 	
 		well when is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> draft hasn't has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> draft even gone yet
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		huh-uh not yet but i mean i don't know whether they have one of the first you know choices of somebody that would be real good
 	
 	
 		right
 		right well they've yeah they've
 	
 	
 		i mean yeah everybody gets in draft
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but i don't know whether they'll be far enough up where they can do any good
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		or even making the play-offs so that doesn't doesn't help you in the draft
 	
 	
 		right but we really i mean really and truly we just don't have a quarterback
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that's all there is to it but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and stuff they finally quit giving away the really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and started keeping them too because we had some you remember when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie Manning</ENAMEX> was a quarterback
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well he was good but we every time we'd get a real good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> they'd treat him bad
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course we had a different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> then too but they'd treat him bad and then he'd leave
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or either they'd trade him off to somebody else for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of these nobodies
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it was weird it was like they were trying if you were good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> let's don't have you on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> you know but um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> they had all good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> except for the quarterback
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> all of them every one that they played i think they played uh i can't remember whether we played <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> but all of them were bad i mean they were terrible they could not pitch you know they couldn't even take hand-offs it was terrible
 	
 	
 		hum
 		right
 	
 	
 		but um all the other places i mean our defense was unbelievable
 	
 	
 		oh that's one
 		it's one thing
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>'s lucky though to have uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Kelly</ENAMEX> then now he's the number one rated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> i think i'm pretty sure he was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past season</TIMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		did you get to watch any of their games
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then with uh
 		uh the defense with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Smith Bruce Smith</ENAMEX> there at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">linebacker</ENAMEX> there they've got a very well rounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and it seems that they've gotten over their bickering and their fighting as they problems they had in the past and now they're uh
 		really playing as a good good together as a team
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		um do you watch it every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 		when i can i'm a i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">musician</ENAMEX> and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> i play in uh i this is just something on the side and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX> i play in we tend to rehearse quite a bit on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> so i missed a lot of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sundays</TIMEX> during
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> did you ever get to watch any of the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> games
 	
 	
 		this
 		actually i i'd have to confess i don't really scope out the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> games per say
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX> just isn't isn't one of the areas i've lived in so many places i've lived in uh
 	
 	
 		i'm a
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> but i don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> there's
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		no love for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> but i've lived in uh
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		uh i was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX> and i lived in uh outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> and then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> now and uh so i tend to look for uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> too so i like uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost the Bills games i want to see and then i'll uh normally check out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patriots and Patriots</ENAMEX> were so depressing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last year</TIMEX> that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> in your area
 		i know it
 	
 	
 		yeah that uh i kind of gave up on them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost the Bills i even went i went to got to go to a Bills game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> which was fun it was the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bills Eagles</ENAMEX> game which appropriately enough
 	
 	
 		oh that's neat
 	
 	
 		fortunately the Bills won
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it was good weather
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		we beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buffalo</ENAMEX> in in and
 		was it <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		and it was sunny and <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">forty five degrees</NUMEX> so we couldn't have done much better than that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Buffalo</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no because usually it's snowing  <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		sure
 	
 	
 		but i tell you what if you get to watch some of these now i don't know how it will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> you know but i mean these games go right down to the wire
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was like i was sitting on the edge of my chair you know going oh no no and one uh i can't remember it was about uh it was right close to when we was going to find out if we was going to get to be in the play-offs or not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we're watching the game all right the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> got the ball and we had like no we got the ball back that's the way it was and they had to kick
 		and uh to know whether we were going to win the game or lose a game because they got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point ahead of us
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we had to sit there you know and they cut the show off and showing started showing us another <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game
 		we did not get to see the end of the game you talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> calling in it was wild i mean here everybody is sitting on the edge of their chair you know and they changed it and gave us another game in the middle of another you know one that was going on
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure</ENAMEX> and then they changed the game
 		right
 	
 	
 		cut us off right there <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few seconds</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> finally you know how they'll put the little message down at the bottom started telling everybody that they were not the ones that had cut that off that it was the national you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		right it was the network
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> and because it was funny i mean everybody was furious i was so mad i got up and went and called  you know i couldn't believe that but
 		almost every game that i watched it would come right down to the end we would be ahead you know but then at the very in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth quarter</TIMEX> they'd let them get up there either with them or you know right ahead of them
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it'd come right down to the end and either we made it or we didn't oh and it was it was something else i said this is the most if we had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we would have went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's no question about it because everybody was playing good together except the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> just didn't do anything
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's the that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that counts
 	
 	
 		yes but maybe we maybe we'll get your guy
 	
 	
 		well i
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Kelly</ENAMEX> is about to be swayed away from the Bills any time
 		
 		
 	