
 
     		
 	
 		yeah so uh what are your favorite TV shows
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that i can't find anymore which is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i haven't watched that very much is that do you like that
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		when was that on
 	
 	
 		it was usually on um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		uh
 		oh oh yeah well
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um um it may be that um it was recently replaced
 		by actually by um by what may be my favorite TV show of because sort of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Twin Peaks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was same time period yes
 	
 	
 		yeah so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> um what happened was
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Twin Peaks um</ENAMEX> went went off
 		they moved to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> for a while and then put and then put something i guess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fire</ENAMEX> on it and at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> and then they moved um
 		no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fire</ENAMEX> was on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> i think i i take that back
 		i'm not sure but anyway they moved it back and forth and that's when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peaks</ENAMEX> was back in that time slot as well
 		so i don't know
 	
 	
 		you don't know what happened to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Fire</ENAMEX> then
 	
 	
 		no i have no idea
 		i don't think
 		i don't think that was on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> anyway i don't know what happened to it though
 	
 	
 		i don't remember <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> to another i keep forgetting one station
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what's your second favorite
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's hard to say
 		i'm sort of a very big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and beyond that i just sort of watch anything that happens to be on i'm i'm
 		half the time i'm a TV <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addict</ENAMEX> and the other half the time i just ignore it
 		it's really bad yeah there's some new shows that i sort of like um
 		have you seen this <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Shannon Steel Show</ENAMEX> or uh
 		it's about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> it's one of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> shows you know they they seem to be popular these days
 		and then there's just a lot of those sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blair</ENAMEX> shows floating around
 	
 	
 		oh is he the reformed um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gambler</ENAMEX> yes yes yes
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i just i mean like i just finished watching that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes ago  um</TIMEX> and it and that that's a interesting one i i i like that because there's there are
 		i've noticed that every every major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> now has their own law show there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA Law</ENAMEX> and there's um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equal Justice</ENAMEX>
 		some other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> Law And Order or something
 		lots of lots of these things that are floating around now they seem to be popular shows do you like the law shows or
 	
 	
 		i really don't watch that much TV what i do is i tape the programs i want to watch and then on the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> i can watch i'll pick out something
 		but um
 	
 	
 		that that makes logical sense also saves a lot of time with commercials
 	
 	
 		you're not kidding do you ever watch <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Gladiators
 	
 	
 		oh i have i've i've caught i watched that late um i guess it's on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late Saturday nights</TIMEX> or something that's on during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> as well
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">midnight</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">midnight</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have you have have you seen this often
 	
 	
 		i tape it
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah i tape it because i don't stay up that late to watch it i tape it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i understand uh that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> they play it at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">normal</TIMEX> times because they don't consider that violent
 		and the reason they have it on here so late is because they consider it a violent program
 	
 	
 		really
 		i don't know that
 	
 	
 		and
 		i'm like i don't believe this
 	
 	
 		i
 		that don't it it it seems like i mean if wrestling is prime time
 		professional wrestling it seems like it's just
 		just just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> in a wrestling to me i don't i don't see any difference though
 	
 	
 		i don't either
 	
 	
 		i i don't understand it they consider it violent i have so ever i have seen it on
 		where we are i live in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rochester New York</ENAMEX>
 		and i think a
 	
 	
 		you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		where are you
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're uh everybody i speak to is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> oh
 		oh yeah but i'm i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
 		and uh we seem we seem to have um i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Gladiators</ENAMEX> is on
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoons</TIMEX> actually around here
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		as well sometimes
 		i think it's been on i think i've seen it during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 		i know i've seen it during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		when i was at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> down there
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		definitely seen it done on on during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> down there and i don't think it's a very violent show i think it's funny
 		i think it's a real good concept i think it's something completely new
 	
 	
 		i think it's great i love watching a microbiologist
 		fighting off with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policemen</ENAMEX> or something else and competition
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm going oh great you know
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		it's a it's a great role model for everybody
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so i think because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sort of get through you know um
 		i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sort of learn the importance of sort of physical
 		fitness as well as the
 		as well as you know some mental fitness and i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> sort of learn good sportsmanship and so forth
 	
 	
 		oh yes i mean when i had uh i was watching it the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time i ever saw a microbiologist on there i thought well it just goes to prove it has nothing to do with your physical capabilities
 		and uh there she was terrific she was really terrific
 	
 	
 		well don't they take <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have some sort of
 		um
 		big abilities like and and at least they used to when it when it the first ones i saw they had um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> on who was uh he played college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and almost went pro and they had a
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who was a black belt in karate and she was the uh she was in the junior <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX> or something or they seem to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have very very big sports backgrounds to have they leaned leaned away from that sort of
 	
 	
 		they hold competitions in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> in um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis Minneapolis</ENAMEX> um
 		um trying to think of i think it's in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> places around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> they hold competition and the only requirement
 		is of course your skill of passing these tests
 	
 	
 		oh that's how they do it
 	
 	
 		and that's it
 		and
 		we had a bar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> from here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area that made it there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> that uh made
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		well she called herself a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> so i'm not quite sure what she made
 		and uh she made it i mean there is no your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">occupation</ENAMEX> has nothing to do with it
 	
 	
 		yeah okay i just thought they had some
 	
 	
 		strictly your skill
 	
 	
 		yeah i thought they had some sort of i mean i thought they were just poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like us i guess not that's great
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but maybe i'll try it one day
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i will get on it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and see if i can uh
 		um what what do they win they they win money i think don't they
 	
 	
 		i think the last i heard was it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to about a hundred</NUMEX> fifty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow all that for getting tennis balls shot at you at a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundred miles an hour</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's you know just minor
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		just minor little ball here or there you know
 	
 	
 		one little ball here and there yeah and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s beating you up
 		so i don't mind the beating up part i i actually feel the tennis balls would hurt
 	
 	
 		oh well they they come out with a lot of bruises too
 	
 	
 		they look like
 		yeah they seem like a tennis ball but there also doesn't look like
 		it's almost livable
 		yeah but best it i i don't think i could i i could handle those tennis balls
 		so what else to you tape besides <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Gladiators</ENAMEX> at there anything else
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		see i tape <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Murder She Wrote</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		i like mysteries
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i like mysteries
 		i tape um <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowling</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because that's another mystery
 		and i don't have to concentrate too hard on them
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but i'm sure that's fun
 	
 	
 		um most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> programs like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law And Order</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		they're not on the times that i've got
 		that i've watched because i haven't had T got <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TV Guide</ENAMEX> around here in ages
 	
 	
 		oh okay well they seem to be on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> all always right right before the news is when i catch them
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i tend to if nothing else i tend to turn on the television at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock</TIMEX> just to watch the news
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">or or Nightline</ENAMEX> or something
 		just sort of get a good you know
 		a good a good think for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		your news is on at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 		when is yours on
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> i was just in the middle of watching it
 	
 	
 		oh gosh well i'm sorry i interrupted um
 	
 	
 		oh that's okay no problem
 	
 	
 		yeah ours is on actually it ours is on at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> it it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">um eleven o'clock now</TIMEX> here or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five now</TIMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> um i think they would they do that i think they put things on at
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">um eleven o'clock</TIMEX> here and i think they put it like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock</TIMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">um California</ENAMEX> time like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> but in the middle they sort of um like central time or mountain time they they push things back
 		so i was actually actually i'm not sure i was in i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iowa</ENAMEX> awhile ago and noticed that everything was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> earlier
 		so does your prime time start at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no well they have it at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> and they have it at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		wait no no not not even the news but do they have like um
 	
 	
 		and they have one at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		do like sort of all the regular sitcoms and so forth start at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock</TIMEX>
 		you so like you know the regular television shows that are that are very popular do they start at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or or at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm trying to think
 		both um let's see they start <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um Evening Shade at</ENAMEX>

 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and then it goes to um
 		what is it after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evening um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right because that would actually start at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock</TIMEX> here
 	
 	
 		that's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Major Dad</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> i think it is
 	
 	
 		yeah that that would all start at at um
 		that would all start at at
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">o'clock</TIMEX> here that wouldn't start at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>
 		we have um at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven o'clock</TIMEX> we just have
 		um the they'll play you know they have old reruns of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX> or something
 		from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven to seven thirty</TIMEX> and then something else from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven thirty</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> but then at
 		at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock</TIMEX> is when everything starts
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		which is
 		which is strange i mean because yours start at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and end at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> and ours start at
 		at at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at</TIMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and end at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> that's why we  i i would actually like it better if everything started at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and ended at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's stopped around here at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> and it goes into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> programs
 		at that point which could be one of you know many different <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> programs but it goes into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> programs
 		but uh do you ever watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's great
 		oh all the time
 		do you watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh yeah
 	
 	
 		there's there's it's at that was actually a big dilemma for me now because um <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cheers and Twin Peaks</ENAMEX> are now on the same time
 		
 		
 	