
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Dee</ENAMEX> are you familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> policies of late
 	
 	
 		um yeah to a point it's not my best subject
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		really yeah it's not mine either but uh i know
 		i know our policy i like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX> i'm familiar with that  because we have um some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that live on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nicaraguan</ENAMEX> border and they're they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">missionaries</ENAMEX> there and they
 		they live there and they have to travel by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat forty</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> to get to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and stuff
 		and uh i know that they helped a lot of those <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinistas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>
 		coming across the border and they housed them and stuff they've been down there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years</TIMEX> now and they lived it's kind of weird  they have bats in their roof but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bats</ENAMEX> eat the bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">spiders</ENAMEX> so they leave the bats you know so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah it's a whole whole different culture um it it's weird down there because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's all lizards and things running around that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who live there they just they take it for granted and it's like we go down there on vacation it's like oh how can these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> live with these lizards and like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bats</ENAMEX> in their house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think their policy with them that though is um i don't know i think
 		i wish we would have just i'm not that up on the policy of way i know that's kind of old but i don't know i just i'm glad that
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinistas</ENAMEX> aren't in power anymore because i think that they were  very wicked and uh probably some of the biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> that the world has probably ever seen and i feel like
 		most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> are probably you would be safe to say that they were just very very you know big into drugs
 	
 	
 		yeah their very corrupt like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Panamanians Panamanians</ENAMEX> are were very corrupt
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		the thing about it is like the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Panamanians</ENAMEX> is a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> down there a lot of a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> are involved
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because i guess there was a big big uh scam they they set all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> up and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">like a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> got caught for running a drug ring
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		so it's it's like everybody is into it it's just greed human greed interestingly about about that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honduras</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's very pro <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we have i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> used to uh be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> and she was based uh based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Honduras</ENAMEX> its very um uh pro <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> i don't know how many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uh soldiers</ENAMEX> are there but there's a lot i mean they uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and you can't the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> government you can't trust them either because you think
 		you don't know how corrupt they are i mean they keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in power like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Shah</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and things like that i mean it's the lesser of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> evils they'll probably you know say this is the lesser of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> evils
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't know how corrupt the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Honduran</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is but the
 	
 	
 		yeah i they need to have more checks and balances in their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to  get rid of the corruption but i think first though i don't know they need to i think turn these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in
 		the repentance on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> for all their uh
 		you know the atrocities that they've commit and the drug dealings and in the just in the drug crimes because i feel like a lot of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> are so engrossed in the drug crimes that until they repent or they're moved from power
 		that you know but there are so many of them that the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to come up if you just knock one off you going to have another one
 		and i know a lot of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> there's uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX> i know is like forty percent evangelical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> not just go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> but
 		you know really on fire for God and they're just surpassing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America Latin America</ENAMEX> by
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> you know it's just incomprehensible and uh so i just think that i think that God's going to honor that and that he's going to put in some good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of i believe <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX>
 		is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and he goes to no <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guatemala</ENAMEX> because he goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virgo Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guatemala City</ENAMEX> our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> is in real close relationship with him
 		and he is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guatemala</ENAMEX> he's an elder at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Virgo Church</ENAMEX> and
 		you know that that God is doing something he is raising up some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> want him back as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> bad but they have a rule in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Guatemala</ENAMEX> that he can't have another term
 		so they're the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are trying to override that i mean not just the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> but all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because they see when a righteous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is in authority the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> rejoice so yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah good see that's the thing that is going to have to that's the undoing of everything is that we have no morals i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		talk about the crime and all that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> it's just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have no morals that's the thing that will eventually you know if anyone is going to be saved it is having a good moral background
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um but it's funny you will mention <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX> because i guess they're one of the most successful and peaceful <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah i know
 	
 	
 		so i was reading an article in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Geographic</ENAMEX> and i don't know i don't think they have any more money than any of the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> they don't have <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> or anything and they don't have big tourism
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so maybe it is their faith that has enabled them to keep the crime out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX> they don't allow anybody to come in that um
 		to come in any uh what do you call what do you call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> they don't allow anything like that like i could not go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX> and live
 		as an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> they would not permit me to move there to work they wouldn't their jobs are there for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Costa Ricans</ENAMEX> they don't allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to move in like less nations you know and take the jobs
 	
 	
 		yeah they don't they don't probably don't take a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> either
 	
 	
 		no they don't take any i mean i couldn't even go there my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> couldn't we would have to receive all this special permission to go there
 		for even when some you know in in inner
 		company you know transfer or something
 		and i have another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> from uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Costa Rica</ENAMEX> that she was born there she's <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Costa Rican</ENAMEX> i guess i do know a little bit i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> one time
 		and stayed i've been there twice and stayed and that was that was just really sad but a lot of it though is their debt i think that we should not loan them anymore money that if we still want to give them money give them money
 		quit loaning it to them you're not going to get it back don't be indebted to anybody don't be the you know loaner nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">borrower</ENAMEX> and it's just not good we need to if we feel like we need to give them money then give it to them but quit loaning all the money out which i don't think we're loaning anymore now but
 		that's how we got into a problem if we got them we have sink them in the hole by us loaning them all of these <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> that common sense you could just look at it and say they're not going to be able to pay us back
 	
 	
 		yeah also uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> that we will loan the money in uh
 		a lot of the higher the higher <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were just stealing it and building these beautiful <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> and nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ranches</ENAMEX> and things so we are we're suckers
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lo Mas</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah we we are now it's like we are partly responsible for their problems by loaning them all that money
 		that was really stupid on our part to even loan it to them you don't loan money to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like that i mean if you feel like you need to give them something to help them out fine but you don't go making
 		<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> of loans in to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that you can just look at the situation and yeah and know that they are not going to be capable of paying us back and
 	
 	
 		they know they're not going to pay it back
 	
 	
 		that puts a bondage on them it makes you know pressure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and makes their inflation go up and it's just a big mess so
 	
 	
 		you
 		did you go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> uh anywhere near when the earthquake hit
 	
 	
 		no but i knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i was there before that but i knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i got a letter from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of mine that i had met there that who who the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment building</ENAMEX> was destroyed and they were living in a tent so it's kind of weird you know
 		because these were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he was on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> dive the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mexican diving Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pool</ENAMEX> he'd go watch them dive and all this so they were you know just normal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> weren't squatters or poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or anything that
 		um i did i knew all of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> there but none of them that i know of got killed in it
 		but um they're all <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> though  God really protected them see that broke out a revival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> new s and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> never told you about there's been a real revival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico City</ENAMEX> since that earthquake because there's a lot of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> there's a lot of sin in those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> and a lot lots of witchcraft a lot of witchcraft a whole lot of witchcraft
 	
 	
 		oh i could imagine
 	
 	
 		so a lot of it in the name of Christianity
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		so you know oh yeah there's a lot you know they call themselves <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> but you know they are over there doing witchcraft and stuff and
 		just a whole the lot of it generational things too like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mayans</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incas</ENAMEX> you can't find a trace of them because God totally destroyed them for how wicked they were
 		and yet they're revered and honored and almost worshipped by so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> even now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> you know everyone's all intrigued with all of these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that were totally removed from the face of the earth
 		because of how wicked they were i've been down to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX> and i've climbed to the top of the pyramid of the sun where they used to take a beating heart out of a young <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirteen year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and then hold it up to the sun God and that's pretty heavy duty you know
 	
 	
 		yeah is is there still blood stains on the altar or has it worn away all through the years
 	
 	
 		i don't think there are the little box is black on the top of the pyramid of the sun it's black so yeah you can't really tell but it is kind of weird you know you think wow there is where they did human sacrifices to false <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gods and</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is it
 		do you get spooked you feel or do you get <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">butterflies</ENAMEX> in your stomach when you go there because
 	
 	
 		um at that time i kind of did it was a very oppressed eerie just you know feeling but i wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> when i went there but uh i think that all those
 		those you know generational things i think that God did i'm praying you know that keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christians</ENAMEX> that are beginning to rise up there to be able to pray because that does affect that things you know those in your background
 		
 		
 	