
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">hi Jim the um</ENAMEX>
 		well how do you get the most of your information
 	
 	
 		uh generally the most of my information i'll get in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> with my newspaper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		periodically updated through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> i try to catch the news at least
 		once before i go to work either on TV or on the radio <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">most days</TIMEX> it's just catching it on the radio drive on the drive in to work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		do you enjoy mainly network news or like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh for world events i'll take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		but for local local coverage
 		or statewide coverage i'll take the local news
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a lot more indepth
 	
 	
 		do you um
 		do you do you get them do you feel like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> are generally biased either liberal or conservative views
 	
 	
 		i extremely so
 	
 	
 		i that's how it is here too
 		that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> is very liberal one of them is very conservative
 	
 	
 		and there's no mid ground anywhere in it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> doesn't seem to be um granted i i i read primarily the more controversial topics so i'm sure that it's easier for them to uh
 		be you know polarized more so on the topic on the
 		the news items that interest me most
 		but uh it doesn't seem like there's much middle ground
 		in either of the papers
 	
 	
 		with what i'm involved with doing is kind of a controversial job anyway
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		i work with the uh state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison system</ENAMEX> so i'm always kind of interested i look at the what the liberal view is on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> need more rights and i hear the more conservative lines that we need to get back to
 		making the punishment fit the crime but they never do go far enough
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX> with the system i've got an extreme almost an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> view on
 		get into the criminal justice system
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because what they got now sure isn't working
 	
 	
 		well i think that it's been proven since somewhere in the early nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> that rehabilitation in the forms that we have been attempting it is not realistic
 		um i can't remember the study but it was there was a quite a long-term study done in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> that uh
 		evaluated the incarceration systems that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has based their systems on and uh it's been proven
 		useless for rehabilitation uh which is
 		what a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to believe happens in a prison
 		and
 		um there are amount of reforms that could be helpful in that area are numerous and costly and would  require require a lot of task <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et</ENAMEX> cetera and um
 		there is a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that would
 		go right off the roof  um are do you work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> themselves
 	
 	
 		yes that's i'm a
 		inside guard i also work in the segregation <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> for the ones that mess up
 	
 	
 		goodness yeah
 	
 	
 		so i get the real sweethearts
 		but i get a aside aside from that i
 		i'd almost say i've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremist</ENAMEX> views on gun controls on personal crime convention uh personal crime prevention
 	
 	
 		to to which end
 	
 	
 		there was a thing recently in the paper there was a bill in front of the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">legislature</ENAMEX> that was going to allow
 		the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> to be able to pack his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		concealed or unconcealed i'm all for that
 	
 	
 		why is that do you think the average <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> has the the um
 		uh the wherewithals in order to use it
 	
 	
 		i don't know if every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> does or not but just
 		you having lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> you know what it's like out there
 	
 	
 		it's
 	
 	
 		when i go to a shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> if i
 		i feel under dressed if i'm carrying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">less than two</NUMEX> blades
 		from the training i had in the military i'd rather take somebody with a blade at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">close</NUMEX> range than i would with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pistol</ENAMEX> because i know they're going to go down i know i can keep them down
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if the if the option came up to where i could pack a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side arm</ENAMEX> in the open i i don't worry about carrying it concealed i want them to know i'm packing it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and given the option of that i would definitely
 		when i went shopping to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> i would definitely be packing all kind of power firepower
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh i
 		i lived in a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> that was uh unpleasant i lived south down in uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montrose</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisdom City</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		yeah and it was it i was um keenly aware of the the the danger in my area
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> was attacked and she got away unharmed but scared to pieces and had had all of her clothing ripped off of her um
 		and then i had another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that was also approached and got away
 		and this was in broad daylight both times so i was keenly aware of the danger in those areas but i didn't
 		i guess i didn't feel like i was
 		competent enough with any kind of weapon
 		to to carry <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or to feel
 		like carrying one would be a benefit to me rather than just having them take it  you know i mean that's i that's that's truly how i felt i felt like if i were carrying something and if i actually pulled it on somebody that was trying to attack me
 		that their chances of getting it from me would be higher than my chances of using it effectively on them
 	
 	
 		that's where the only stipulation i'd like to see tacked on to the legislation saying that there had to be some form of formal
 		firearms instruction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N R</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX> certified firearms instruction
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you can't train somebody how to shoot in a combat situation until they've been there
 		i've seen it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lebanon</ENAMEX> i was in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granada</ENAMEX> invasion in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty three</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty four</NUMEX> i'm very accustomed to knowing when i pull a piece out whether it's a full sized firearm or a handgun
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when it clears leather shot the shot's going to be fired you don't pull it out for show you pull it out to take care of business the same way with the blade it it comes out of my back pocket or it comes out of a
 		sheath on my web gear it's coming out and it's going to draw blood you don't pull it
 		trying to think is it uh
 		in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gurkha</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> had a legend that went along with their legendary side arm the
 		Khukri which is their blade
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you never drew that thing out unless it was going to draw blood
 		which is a good
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		mental training aspect for it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that that or any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side arm</ENAMEX> whether it be a blade or whether it be a handgun or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i feel that is certainly if you're going to carry one you need to be uh very comfortable with the piece and have
 		enough uh knowledge and insight for your own self on whether or not you're going to use it in that situation and not pull it unless you intend to because i i feel like that's
 		you know i mean i'm i'm i'm all for uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> having having firearms or having whatever form of protection they prefer because you know even though the odds is
 		you know the criminal ends up getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and shooting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to begin with you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that had it in the beginning but if the if if you're talking about uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if you're talking about a criminal
 		an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assailant</ENAMEX> that is coming at you with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and you don't have a gun at all well the chances are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> percent they're going to get you
 		if you if you both of you have a firearm you've at least got that fifty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">percent</NUMEX> chance
 		that you may get them first
 		and so i believe in that but
 		i i've not ever felt comfortable in it i guess it's  i'm glad i  i'm glad i um i'm that i'm married to someone who feels comfortable with them  you know it's it's one of those things um i was reared in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">t</ENAMEX> here's also a moral aspect to it a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have not
 		either mentally sat down and gone over the moral aspect can i take human life even in a life threatening situation to myself or to a loved one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when it actually comes down they don't have time to think about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in that fraction of a succeed that they're caught i don't know if i can do this
 		there's a bullet already on the way to them or there's a blade already cutting them somewhere because they
 		they had the time to react but they
 		hesitated
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's
 		impossible to
 		in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> setting explain that to somebody they've got to
 		on their own have made that decision long before they ever decided
 		to carry a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> of any type whether it be a fighting staff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		up to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">forty four</NUMEX> magnum any any of them
 		in the correct hands they're an absolutely fantastic weapon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but if you haven't made that moral decision can i take a human life even under those situations where either my life or a life of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> or a life of a family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> is threatened
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		can you do you defeated the purpose of even having the gun
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		or the or whatever the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapon</ENAMEX> is
 	
 	
 		uh i agree
 		i agree that would be something that would have to be
 		uh evaluated
 		i feel prior to ownership
 		the uh i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> hear only the sensation stories of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> being killed or
 		
 		
 	