
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		all right what do you think about it like well you can go first
 	
 	
 		well uh i guess uh i hadn't hadn't had a lot of time to think about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> but uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		wow i dropped the phone
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that was loud sorry
 	
 	
 		uh i i guess i voter apathy of course i is uh is a universal thing uh not just i don't think just <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> really i think other places have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the same problem and it's basically because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> don't really feel like that their vote really has any influence on the outcome
 		not just of the election but of the results of the election the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX> and you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislators</ENAMEX> don't really do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh most of the time what the what the their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX> uh really want them to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they do what they think is either best for the you know the the uh economy or whatever's best for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> that are paying you know part of their way
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and and i think it's you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> don't feel like they really have as much say so in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> as uh they would like to have so they they kind of drift away because of that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really i think that that's a big part of it i think that's probably the root and then also that added with all the pressures on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> today it's a real it's a real pain for us to go vote i mean
 	
 	
 		huh yeah
 	
 	
 		i remember the last time that we had to go vote it was like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> just to get up there and do it was major effort you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and we ran in there it was like right at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late</TIMEX> and i was going to go we wanted to go together to do it and take our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> but it was like we ran in and whew we were the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in there
 		and i thought you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle</ENAMEX> gets off usually about oh by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> but we live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tarrant County</ENAMEX> and he drives from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so you know it's a drive but he still had a lot more cushion to be able to go vote a lot easier than most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and because he doesn't hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> traffic and all then he might have worked <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> late it was just like ah we had so many things to do and we just couldn't get them done and i i remember thinking that
 		man it i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> and i really feel like we have a responsibility to vote but i tell you what if i wasn't a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> i would there's no way i would have gone to vote just because of the pressures
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the you know just the time factor and just the anyway and i felt like i was listening to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> and i i guess i even thought that then this morning so it's funny i got this topic because there were talking about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
 		it pays the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to make you know legislation that encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> to work outside the home because then you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you can tax and you you put both of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a higher bracket
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that it's probably not going to end anytime soon the pressure you know to work and just the pressure it puts on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> family
 		and um i  i thought about that and i said yeah that's funny you hardly have time to go vote for this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX> because you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are expected to do so much now and i just kind of laughed and i thought God i never thought of it like that you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so anyway i think that's the other side that
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's that's a good observation and and true yes uh
 	
 	
 		yeah but i agree too with what everything you said but i think the two go and then you put those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> things together and you're going to have you know no one going to vote but then um i don't know disillusion what's the solution
 	
 	
 		yeah oh what's the solution huh start over again  you know that's we've the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have talked you know about having about redoing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX> completely or changing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> a little you know to some extent
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know now  come on
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that's a you know we really ought to take a long hard look at at the system and and see if there's a way to improve it not just say that's the way it is or it's been that way for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		let's you know see if there are some some improvements uh not a not a change but some improvements i think the system itself basic system is
 	
 	
 		but i think that
 	
 	
 		is uh appropriate but i think there are some some modifications even that could be made uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		limitations on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and restrictions you know restrictions that could be put on on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> itself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to get them out of our everyday life
 	
 	
 		yeah there's
 		yeah i know they're i know you can't even spank your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> without
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know with this you know i don't know
 	
 	
 		you
 	
 	
 		we don't have we don't have a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> but i know that when you go in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> we had some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foster twins</ENAMEX> and
 		it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and it wasn't through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> but boy howdy man these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> needed a whipping sometimes not to be beaten not to be abused but to firmly be told you are not going to do that and you are not going to spit in my face i said no
 	
 	
 		yeah he
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and if you do that this is going to be the consequence but it you couldn't do that even through the state even the mother it wasn't through the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> but even though um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> really would given approval but because of the situation we just didn't think it was
 		wisdom you know you go in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and they start spitting their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> out at the table now come on but you know you couldn't do really a lot because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>'s control so that's that's a good idea there too i like that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anyway you know have you ever had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two year olds</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twins</ENAMEX> start spitting their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> at you at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luby</ENAMEX>'s you know i mean you're like going i mean yes
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh yeah i i remember our our our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i remember when she was at you know at that age and and how she was and that that's exactly of course there was only one of her it wasn't twins
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but that's exactly the you know the way it was and of course <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five years ago</TIMEX> you could you could uh you could
 	
 	
 		you could go in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luby's</ENAMEX> and take care of it
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah you could could uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i did i stood there and i did take care of it it took forever though and i think God just had some grace there because i don't think if it had been my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> i don't think that would have worked what i did in order to get them to eat that food you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but it took like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five minutes</TIMEX> but it was the whole thing was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> but i don't want to rewrite <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Constitution</ENAMEX> i just wish <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i wish it would be interpreted like the founding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> wrote it to be interpreted by
 	
 	
 		uh-huh right
 	
 	
 		and that they would begin to teach it in the
 	
 	
 		yeah i guess the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">the Constitution</ENAMEX> is not the part that needs to be changed it's the
 	
 	
 		right  our society is so messed up though it's like no wonder they interpret it wrong we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> last night and we ate dinner at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meadow Road</ENAMEX> and seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> there
 	
 	
 		it's the rest of it huh you know the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i couldn't believe it it was like this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> was like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> we were the only normal seeming human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the whole place almost
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i'm not kidding and it's like these it's this it this i told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle i</ENAMEX> said if this is reflective of our society no wonder we are in such a mess and
 	
 	
 		yeah well i t's there are some some strange things
 	
 	
 		you know these were the rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these</TIMEX> were the you know these were i mean just the things that happened we had a bulimic in front of us and she just looked crazy but yet she had money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um she was just so friendly and i asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> as we checked out i said is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> a ballerina or what and he goes he said no she's a bulimic
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		because she was so skinny and then all these other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are coming up around us and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> they went to check on their ticket and the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> at their table started taking their plates and and in fear just piling their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> on his plate and shoving it in his mouth i mean this was in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> and i was just sitting there thinking now
 	
 	
 		you're yeah you're kidding
 	
 	
 		i he did it's like said they
 	
 	
 		you mean it's that at a like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX> a total stranger
 	
 	
 		uh no he was sitting at the table with um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another couple</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh he was sitting at the table with them
 	
 	
 		right but he took their plates up and made sure they didn't see him and i think he was the one i heard him mention about the tickets were messed up so they went to take care of the tickets he took their plates and began eating his eating their food
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i'm not kidding my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was like totally freaking out he said i can't believe it look at that
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but and i you know what i mean i they were right next to us and it was obvious that they didn't know and so and he ate it all before they got back and everything and so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just thought no i don't know if there's an answer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> not going to vote when they  when our society is falling apart like it is i don't know if people
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yeah
 		maybe we don't want those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> voting
 	
 	
 		i know yeah i know and they you know these are probably some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> i can't help but think that either
 	
 	
 		yeah yes
 		yeah that's that's
 	
 	
 		is it no seriously because these were this was a nice <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dallas</ENAMEX> this was not we weren't over on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cedar Springs</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Hines</ENAMEX> or anything you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's uh
 	
 	
 		so anyway i think our society is just worse off than i realized that's what i thought
 	
 	
 		that's
 		i'm going to have to start going out to eat more often i'd i guess i would like to see some things like that
 	
 	
 		we live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Euless</ENAMEX> now we don't see that in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euless</ENAMEX> too much but you know that's what it i mean it was just absolutely maybe it was just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah a a full moon <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> or something
 	
 	
 		but i don't think so i
 		i have a feeling that's more reflective of our
 		government and everything then
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well that's our time
 	
 	
 		well there's your  another call  well i think we had a good call and so okay have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> bye
 	
 	
 		okay yeah i enjoyed it thank you uh-huh okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	