
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right what uh what kind of camping is there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well there there are quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">um parks</ENAMEX> i guess state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and there's a couple of national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> i guess that you can camp at
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um most of them have pretty good facilities
 		i don't know if the camping that i've done is really roughing it without a a whole lot of stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		so you do uh like backpacking and the like
 	
 	
 		uh done a little bit of that mainly just um
 		camping out at state <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> i've been to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and there's some real nice ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> has one of the best parks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		huh
 		is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ozarks</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah part of them are
 	
 	
 		yeah so that's probably a pretty nice place to go
 	
 	
 		yeah they've got uh real nice lake system and
 		around their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gray i</ENAMEX> think that's one of the ones we've been to it's is real nice there a bunch of lakes around it there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf course</ENAMEX> and  um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just a whole bunch of camping sites
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what about you where have you uh
 	
 	
 		oh i've been camping for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> not on a regular basis but uh i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> started camping out in the desert in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then sometimes in the mountains also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
 		and uh then i moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> and i i didn't camp for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX> and then i started to uh
 		go camping again kind of in conjunction with white <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> rafting so i'd go up somewhere and camp <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">overnight</TIMEX> and then do some rafting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then maybe camp <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">another night</TIMEX> and drive home
 		and that was uh that was pretty good so i went out and bought a whole bunch of camping gear
 		and uh
 		you know i still do it once in a while
 	
 	
 		yeah i think we've collected stuff off and on over the years
 		the more times we did it the more serious we get about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where where is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh well it's it's uh in terms of north south i would say it's uh a little a little more towards the northern border of the state and pretty much in the eastern <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of it
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so what it
 	
 	
 		so you're kind of away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Ridge Mountains</ENAMEX> that area
 	
 	
 		well it it's uh actually the the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Ridge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> are closer to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX> they're <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about three hours</TIMEX> away if you go due north
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blue Ridge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> i think are much nicer and you can pick those up going west but then you're talking about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the way it works
 		but um
 		it's a real it's a real nice place to go and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and there's some pretty decent campgrounds although i don't think <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Raleigh</ENAMEX> i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> takes
 		they probably just don't spend as much money as a lot of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> might
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s from the western part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> we've been down the parkway a lot but i didn't know how much how much camping areas there were along there
 	
 	
 		i think there's quite a few
 		i can't say i've checked them all out though
 	
 	
 		what what's it like camping in the desert and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> that seems like a challenge
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's actually kind of incredible it's really really nice
 		um
 		i like it better than almost anything i've ever done just the sky is so
 		amazing
 		you know you really can
 		probably count <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's just kind of nice i like the uh i think the desert has a rare kind of beauty
 		which um
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't realize you know they hear desert and they think of scorpions and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX> and sand and
 		being real dry and lack of water course it it has all of those qualities but it also has a certain quality of beauty that's
 		you just don't find anywhere else except in a desert
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's pretty nice the uh
 		the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Doors</ENAMEX> has some some nice desert scenes those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> all go camping out in the desert
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of course they drag a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> with them but
 		um
 		the uh the shots are are pretty nice and it's sort of like that i mean it's just almost surreal in some places it's very pleasant
 	
 	
 		hm
 		are are the temperatures real extreme there or they just
 	
 	
 		they can be yeah i mean you got to you sort of have to choose your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> carefully and know what's going to happen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what i've been i've been camping in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Death Valley</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> doesn't go in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah  true
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but it's beautiful in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> i mean it's just beautiful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> get up into the high eighties
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		huh
 	
 	
 		uh maybe the nineties but it's it's quite bearable and then the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> are reasonably warm you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixties</TIMEX> or seventies
 		it's just great it's really very nice
 	
 	
 		yeah we've talked about planning a trip up through um
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> that lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> up through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Mexico</ENAMEX> and into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX> area
 		i don't know don't know when i'm going to get a chance to do that but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that would be
 		that would be pretty nice i've been i have been camping on the south rim of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Canyon</ENAMEX>
 		that's okay a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like to go down and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> down inside i was just too lazy that trip to
 		do all that walking especially with my gear
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i'll bet
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> thing you said about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> is really true it's when you're close to a big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> the the lights kind of wash wash out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> so it's nice to
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		to get away
 		it's just amazing how how much you miss
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 		yeah it really it really is
 		i mean i don't think i ever see the Little Dipper you hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about the Little Dipper
 	
 	
 		hm um-hum
 	
 	
 		but i don't think i ever
 		see it except when i go get out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> and go camping in the desert or in in the mountains
 		otherwise it's just too faint
 	
 	
 		well i guess we've
 		talked as much as we need to on the subject
 	
 	
 		yeah i think we fulfilled our obligation well thanks for calling nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		um yeah it was good talking to you <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX> bye-bye
 	
 	
 		okay bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	