
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>  i was i was thinking about our topic for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX>  um  immigration problems  we have immigration problems and what do do you think about it
 	
 	
 		well i think it's a very very complicated and i sort of i see perspectives on all sides uh and i've really
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		have no hope for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">solutions</ENAMEX> but um i do keep myself somewhat abreast of the issue i have worked with uh uh
 		a little bit with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> uh who've come over um
 		you know to escape the genocide programs that are over there and seen you know heard about some of the problems that they've had and i'm also fairly sensitive to the issues about how open should the borders be because i
 		in general like a smaller rather than a larger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> to the land area and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		where are you
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> which has a lot of immigration probably more than any where else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> though i'm not sure if that's the case
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well we've got a lot too i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX> right outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we're getting a large  oh gosh i don't know i think there's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty six</NUMEX> different languages now that are spoken in i the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DISD Dallas Inner City School District</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		Cambodians uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asians Vietnamese</ENAMEX> we we're getting a lot of um <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican Americans</ENAMEX> you know we've had those for a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah sure well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> used to be part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX> or most of it
 	
 	
 		yes oh yes  no i'm busy right now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven  Steven</ENAMEX> wants me to do popcorn right now  okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i don't know what the solution is
 	
 	
 		i i don't either it's a really delicate uh moral issue because if if you have
 		well i guess the one thing i do see that is is that needs to be a solution is that if you do let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i do feel you have a certain obligation
 	
 	
 		to get them on their
 	
 	
 		to to get them on their feet because otherwise what you're doing is you're letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in and you're you're dooming them to being underclass people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know you're dooming them to ghetto life or whatever and i know that that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southeast Asians</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hmong</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i've done some work with uh
 		feel really quite hurt and and unsure of themselves when here because they're coming from you know from the slash and burn intercultural society you know they're coming from the middle ages basically and they're being plunked down in plunked down into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
 		many of them had been promised by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> during the war over there that because they cooperated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and they helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> out that when they came here the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> would help establish them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> of course isn't doing that and uh
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so they come here and they don't know what what the heck they're doing and they're finding themselves adrift in the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and of course there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> who would do like nothing better than to take advantage of them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they're they're incredible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> of crime and part of it is this lack of lack of basic information being dissimilated and i'm not saying it's easy to do and i know there are a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are trying but but the funding isn't there for very much work to be going on
 	
 	
 		and there's a lot of graft like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> trying to tell them oh giving them information that was free to them anyway if they just knew how to get it
 	
 	
 		uh yeah exactly yeah have i mean these are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who don't have the foggiest idea about what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">um</ENAMEX> and it's very it's i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		i couldn't really conceptualize how hard it was to understand that until i until i met with them and i realized that they some of the information that i just you know don't even realize and know is information
 		they don't have and i never thought well i guess that is something you need to know you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> getting into trouble because they come here and so they start farming on uh available land you know like the median strips on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">freeways</ENAMEX>
 		because no one's using it but then someone comes along and says you can't do that you know why can't they they have no idea why not some some of them you know the ones that have been here longer and have been in you know understand now but when they initially come over
 	
 	
 		you mean really trying to plant something that's what you're saying farming
 	
 	
 		yeah because they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> these are all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> coming over and they're being put in the middle of the city
 	
 	
 		ah
 		oh oh that's terrible
 	
 	
 		i mean they're nomadic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> you know they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who farm on the hillside and then leave the hillside to another hillside and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> on that hillside
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		these are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've never seen flat ground before and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've never seen property rights before you know these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've never seen any machines other than those used in war
 		and uh they have you know so i i i do have a lot of sympathy for them and i feel that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> could try a little bit harder to to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> adjusting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way because if they don't you're just going to produce
 		you know you're going to produce an underclass you know you're going to get a situation that i think a lot like what happened to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> being sort of led out of slavery and then
 		then many of them ended up just working the same jobs they were as slaves then and there was no real up upward movement and not being yeah um
 	
 	
 		and not being cared for yeah that's true well what did you do when you helped these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how did you what did you do through
 	
 	
 		well i i wasn't helping them i worked with them not to help them but actually for my own purposes i'm i'm a linguist and i was uh doing a language trying to learn their language a little bit
 		and i actually um i mean helped them them in the sense that they received money for working with me but i didn't i didn't i wasn't a social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> or anything like that
 	
 	
 		oh i uh-huh  uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i do have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have tried to do more social work
 		you know by explaining to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how the language and what the problems learning <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> might be and such
 		because all the models of teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> are based on teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> or to other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> language <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't realize how different some of the languages they speak are
 	
 	
 		well i'm an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESL</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> yes  i got my certification but actually they did not teach us very many things
 	
 	
 		oh you are uh-huh well you
 	
 	
 		about how really to go about helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to learn another language i mean it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't know what to say it's not step to step
 	
 	
 		that's that's been my impression
 		yeah it's it's not they're not withholding information they just don't have that information they they haven't the foggiest idea
 	
 	
 		yeah  but anyway i enjoy it they the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i've worked with so far have been <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> speaking
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and  but i'm applying for what yeah it is a lot of the words are the same or you know they just change the pronunciation a little bit but i love it i love the culture the that they  way they respect education
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> is pretty close to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> really and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX> is a lot like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">English</ENAMEX>
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> so much more than than my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you know and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i like it and what i've been thinking about doing is volunteering for this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">center</ENAMEX> that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falk</ENAMEX> has started that works with the school district and doing what
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		trying to get them set and inculturated
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		into the system i thought that would be good experience for me and i've applied at another district where many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i'm sure it would
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that would be wonderful too
 	
 	
 		yeah it would be a good experience and you'd be helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i'm sure very much and and i i mean not to put not to trivialize the problems of any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant group</ENAMEX> but i do know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are having a lot of trouble i mean and part of the problem is that
 		a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> immigration from you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades ago</TIMEX> has been very successful because they valued education and so forth they became a very successful immigrant group
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but and but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming over from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> right now coming from war torn <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are
 		are not not having the same success i think some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have just assumed well why why can't you be successful the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> were or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> were or something And it's really much more complicated
 	
 	
 		well and times were different too
 	
 	
 		yeah the times are different yeah
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> let's see is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> and he's going through the i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish League</ENAMEX> or something and helping a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that's come over from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he spends well right now he's down to like once a week but he was going over there several times a week to meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and help them with the language and he thoroughly enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah i i think it's a wonderful thing to do and there's a lot there's a lot more i guess another possible solution is since <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> aren't going to start paying more money for this and and other budgets aren't going to be cut to pay for it
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		uh more of the volunteer network service because everyone gains from it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		would be would might be really useful
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and if it's you know uh just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i think makes  makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> so much happier
 	
 	
 		uh-huh what's so sad about this is both  of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> had a degree
 		having to do with computers but their training isn't what we need in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and because they're so deficient in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> they haven't been able to get jobs
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they'll have to go back and get a degree here you know almost start all over
 	
 	
 		yes yes i've known <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with effectively worthless degrees in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i mean and they're highly educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but of course if you're educated and you don't speak <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> no one thinks anything of you
 	
 	
 		no no and this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> was um stocking the shelves in a drugstore
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		feel sorry for her
 	
 	
 		yeah i do too
 		well it's been good talking with you
 	
 	
 		well same here have a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> okay yes i do  okay bye
 	
 	
 		uh okay okay it does sound like you have some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to take care of  uh okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	