
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think maybe that we could do better with the budget if we didn't buy so much stuff overseas
 	
 	
 		well i don't know how much that would do for the budget though i mean that has helped the economy as a whole you know <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> jobs and all but
 	
 	
 		well then maybe they wouldn't have to take so many taxes out and stuff like that
 		well
 	
 	
 		yeah if we bought more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> stuff i guess that's more <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> taxes
 		well i guess you know it's like your own home budget you know you can either earn more money or you can uh
 		spend less
 		and you know just like you and i have to make choices like that i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has to do it too
 	
 	
 		well i agree i think that's what i'm trying to say
 	
 	
 		yeah the question is which which  excuse me that's my little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> which one should they do
 	
 	
 		spend less
 		i think we  well i think we give too much money away
 	
 	
 		to
 	
 	
 		other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		to other countries
 	
 	
 		we don't ever get anything from anybody when we're having to fight to get money to help us with this war we were just in
 	
 	
 		well that's that's the
 		that's because
 		we're supposed to be the rich ones with all the money to give away
 	
 	
 		right well it's not true though we're not anymore
 	
 	
 		we're still we are still the biggest ones
 		as you know as far as how much money we've got in the whole country we're still bigger than anybody else
 	
 	
 		we can't even take care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are hungry and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		yeah that's that's an important thing we've got we've got a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are getting money the from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> for this that and the other thing
 	
 	
 		uh i mean
 	
 	
 		and uh it would probably help if we could figure out how to get them to put money back into the system instead you know
 		you take someone on welfare and you give them a job and they're paying income taxes all of a sudden you've changed it around and it's going in the other direction
 	
 	
 		but see right right now we're having a hard time finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> jobs
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> you how well you know are you are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> worker yeah so am i  so we know you know that times are really tough <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> and yet we're still sending money here and there i just know it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i am
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's just crazy
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> without i have several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> without jobs now that in this last riff
 		went out looking for jobs and jobs are really hard to come by now really hard to come by
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's what i don't understand
 	
 	
 		and that's scary
 	
 	
 		yeah you wonder you know when is it going to happen to me
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		it's already happened to me once but i was lucky
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i got to stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> but you know not everybody's that lucky anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they're and i don't know the welfare system is just so abused
 	
 	
 		well i i i don't think the problem so much is abuse
 		i think the problem is is just the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is trying to do too much
 		um i mean who where does it say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s supposed to be the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to take care of all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> or hungry or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et cetera et</ENAMEX> cetera
 		and and where does it say that that if someone is short that they can go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and and get a handout
 	
 	
 		well i know but then okay but that's here but then other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are doing it to us
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		their when their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are hungry and all they're asking us for handouts so why shouldn't our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> be able to ask for a handout
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i think we should take care of our own things right here in our own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and then if we have anything left over to share with other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> then maybe we should consider sharing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i just don't i think we're and then they keep raising the taxes boy i'll tell you what i barely make ends meet and they raise taxes and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		wages aren't going up that much and it's hard
 	
 	
 		no they're not
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean you know especially if you're alone it's on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> salary it's terribly hard to pay the bills and pay your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> payment and a car payment and insurance is ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know  and
 	
 	
 		you know i think you know i've got a fairly decent job here at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> but uh when i think of you you go to the the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and you see someone working as a cashier and you think you you know how much a cashier makes and you go how do these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get by
 	
 	
 		not very much
 		they
 	
 	
 		because i know how hard it is for me to get by
 	
 	
 		yep it's hard it's really hard i
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well uh no i don't know i guess if we had the answers we'd
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we could save the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but
 	
 	
 		we could go run for office
 	
 	
 		yeah  well they all say great things when they run for office
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well the thing is um you know who's really in charge of deciding how the money gets spent
 		and and it's you know it's not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> just suggests it the ones who actually you know debate it and decide it is the is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
 		and you know what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is out for they're
 		they're going to do whatever it takes to make their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> happy which means bring more jobs and more federal spending to their little area
 		and uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and that means every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Congressman</ENAMEX> is sitting there working for money going to his area nobody's working on less money going to his area or on anybody else's area
 		and if you just if you just looked at how much <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> spends on itself it's ridiculous
 	
 	
 		yeah i know that
 		you know and then they cut their defense i i'm not sure if that was such a great idea that cut us really bad i just i hated to see that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well now the thing is
 		yeah they're cutting defense which is you know there are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there working for defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> who are losing money but i don't i don't mind because i think you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is not there to give me a job Government
 		the defense is there to defend our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and they do it for whatever you know they spend whatever money they need to to do that but i don't want them to to break the budget just so that i can have a job
 		i would rather have the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> stable
 		so that i can go get a good job with someone who's not working you know not making defense stuff
 	
 	
 		well yeah yeah i do but i still hated to see it  i mean one of the reasons i voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was because
 	
 	
 		if you know what i mean
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was so defense conscious and we were doing so well and i thought well <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is going to just carry right on  he didn't  was i surprised i uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well he didn't have much choice really
 	
 	
 		well i don't know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but but defense is not the biggest part of the federal budget either the biggest part of the budget are things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		but those are things that we we really need i hate to see the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that don't have anybody and hey you know there are  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out there that have no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or and they really depend on their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> and maybe they're in a nursing home somewhere and they cut some of this stuff and what happens to them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well you know how fast your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> medical insurance has been going up right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well just think the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s insurance bill has <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and that's been going through the roof
 		and that's why federal you know that's that's the biggest increase in federal spending right there
 	
 	
 		so what's the answer
 		
 
 	
 	
 		think we need to figure out a way to uh to make medical care cheaper
 		why is this stuff so expensive why is the cost going up so incredibly fast
 		you know because it's it's coming out of my paycheck it's coming out of your paycheck and it's coming out of our taxes too
 	
 	
 		yes yeah
 	
 	
 		why why is these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> making so much money
 	
 	
 		isn't it <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> that has it all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> run or something
 	
 	
 		oh there's a whole lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> that do that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden Denmark Norway</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		they what is it is it free to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or how do they work that
 	
 	
 		it's it's free for everybody
 		
 
 	
 	
 		in the state
 		or the country
 	
 	
 		everybody in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> like i i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denmark</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and medical care there is free you just go and say i want your help and they'll help you there's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of things though <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all it's not
 		as high a quality as we expect here because it's paid for by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> instead of by us
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> um your taxes are a lot higher
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		an awful lot higher we're talking fifty percent something like that
 	
 	
 		so they are paying for it okay well the way i you know it was talked about
 	
 	
 		they are paying for it
 		and and the and the just the quality of care is not as good either
 	
 	
 		well then that's not the answer
 	
 	
 		there has got to be a middle ground i think <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>'s got a good answer but i don't know many details about it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		what do they do
 	
 	
 		it's it's some sort of government program i've heard a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say good things about it but i just don't know the details on it
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		i don't know i don't know if anything will ever happen to to change change change things i i guess it's going to have to change
 	
 	
 		well something's going to have to change but you look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and you look how many of them get reelected and they're the one's that have got to make the changes
 		i mean i don't see anything changing because you've got the same old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in there
 	
 	
 		and the other thing that concerns me terribly is automobile insurance now i don't know how much longer i'm going to be able to afford it at all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's eating me alive because i i might be almost fifty but i'm single
 		and i don't think and this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s that just because and i own my own home and i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>  and because i'm single there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that won't take me no matter how old you are
 	
 	
 		single
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they won't take you because they say you're a risk you go out and party i said i don't even drink i mean i don't even go out but they won't take you i mean i was turned down this year
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		by an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> who represented i'm not sure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> he represented but i was told because you're single they absolutely won't take you i said that is that's prejudicial that's terrible what's going to happen if they all start doing this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		um-hum what's really terrible is they can do this to you you know and you don't really have that much of a choice as to whether or not you take it because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government government</ENAMEX> says if you're going to drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> you've got to have the insurance
 	
 	
 		but yet they're not helping us with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">companies</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they're they're not helping you uh be able to afford the insurance that they're making you buy
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		
 		
 	