
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		what's what's your most recent one that you've seen
 	
 	
 		well actually what i do i haven't been to a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> in probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight or nine months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so i haven't really seen any movies in the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> but i rent probably <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four or five</TIMEX> movies a week
 	
 	
 		really i used to do that too but i haven't been doing it lately but
 	
 	
 		we've got a good video place out here and uh uh oh gosh uh
 		i'm just trying to think of all the movies i've recently seen uh
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no see i haven't seen that one uh
 	
 	
 		have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wild</ENAMEX> Orchid
 	
 	
 		no is it good
 	
 	
 		well it depends do you like uh steamy movies
 	
 	
 		uh no not yet i know that sounds funny coming from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> but usually i don't
 	
 	
 		oh okay what type of movies do you like
 	
 	
 		um
 		um action  i i guess one of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two</NUMEX> of my favorite movies is probably like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lethal Weapon and Lethal Weapon Two</ENAMEX> and those are those are like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of my most favorite i mean they're just really good movies and i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX> on a Wire
 	
 	
 		okay
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and movies like that
 	
 	
 		do you like suspense movies or do you like uh just action or
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 		some i guess like what do you mean like like are you talking about movies like <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Die Hard Two or</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Jagged Edge Jagged Edge</ENAMEX> was a suspenseful one or uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Fatal Attraction</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay yeah i liked that
 		that was pretty good
 		um that was okay i i don't i guess i thought it was too far fetched but so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said oh no it wasn't you know but i guess
 	
 	
 		oh  well i hope i don't run across them
 	
 	
 		really that's true because i don't know i just didn't find that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to be real i i just thought it was too far fetched
 	
 	
 		what was your favorite all time movie
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh gosh
 		i don't i can't think off my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> do you know which <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> yours was
 	
 	
 		i i have to say that probably the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> movie that really threw me back the most uh that i was really the most in shock with was probably uh Star Wars
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well that's
 	
 	
 		when that first came out i really did not expect the special effects or anything like that i mean
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i guess uh out of all the movies i've i've never been as excited to go back i was ready to go back and see it again you know
 	
 	
 		really yeah yeah you're right about that but that that's really like an all time classic i mean i don't think anybody anything could ever beat that
 	
 	
 		now i i also liked uh oh Gone with the Wind or some of the classic like The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arabia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		see i've never seen that
 	
 	
 		oh you haven't
 	
 	
 		no should i rent it should i go rent it tomorrow
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		no that's uh that's a that's a real interesting movie and it's got a good historical perspective to it
 	
 	
 		that's probably something i need to see right now because i'm taking history in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>  so it'd probably be a good thing for me to see
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		actually i just saw a movie uh called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Lost</ENAMEX> Capone
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and it's about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Capone</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		primarily one of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and i won't give the the whole plot away but it's it's really a good movie uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Capone</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them was lost for many many years
 		and uh he actually he turns out to be a law man
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		yeah it's really interesting it
 	
 	
 		oh you just gave it away i guess i can't go see it no i just kidding
 	
 	
 		no that's okay i didn't give away the whole thing i just gave away just enough to get you interested
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that does sound good is it one i guess it's a rental
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		okay i may have to do that
 		go see it or go rent it
 	
 	
 		and a lot of times what i wind up doing is picking say an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> or an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and seeing like all i've seen all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Dean</ENAMEX>'s movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mae West</ENAMEX>'s movies
 		and just kind of kind of go out and uh rent all the movies and uh
 		uh you know just kind of go i guess you could do that you know get all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Carradine</ENAMEX>'s movies or uh um <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Segal</ENAMEX> to what's his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		i can't remember his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> name
 	
 	
 		it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> is it
 	
 	
 		is it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Segal</ENAMEX>
 		i don't know he was on uh on uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arsenio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i don't i don't watch that  um
 	
 	
 		just recently
 		it was really kind of interesting because <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Arsenio</ENAMEX> was asking him about uh
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		what he thought of uh one of the other action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> God i can't even remember the name he said well he wouldn't really
 		talk about it didn't want to talk about him because he didn't think he was such a uh a good action guy
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		it wasn't Stallone it was uh
 		i can't remember
 		shoot
 		i can't remember the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> name
 		but i like all the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rambo</ENAMEX> movies
 	
 	
 		oh see i didn't really care  that's that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side of the action i guess that i didn't really care for but see i don't really like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't think he's really a very good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> i know that sounds awful because so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think he's so wonderful but i just have never been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">yo Adrian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hey</ENAMEX> that's pretty good no i guess like i say i just have i don't know i just have never seen any interest in him but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no we we actually rent uh probably a good good combination of movies with the exception of horror films
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		don't watch really very many horror films at all
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't either
 	
 	
 		you know i don't know there's something about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming up through the sofa to get you or something you know it's just you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah you're right
 	
 	
 		coming out of the TV that just doesn't make my day you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well it's so i guess i'm a real i'm a realist and so when i watch movies like that it's like this can not happen so i just don't enjoy it you know because it's just like
 		come on give me a break you know i mean i just and so many of them are done so poorly
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know that it just doesn't even give you the effect i mean some of them are done good and they do scare you but um so many of them are just done real i don't know i'm not really into those
 	
 	
 		i just saw uh uh a really interesting movie called uh Flatliners
 	
 	
 		oh that was one of my favorites
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes i thought that was a very good movie
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i was really impress ed with that one i mean it was what i liked about it was that it was a new subject nobody had ever touched it before
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and it was just it was done so well you know it was just
 	
 	
 		it was just crazy enough for the you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> might try to do it
 		you know i mean and it's not like there's a lot of scientific data on it
 	
 	
 		right well that's probably true but it was a very good movie it was done real well too i mean there wasn't any part of it that you really felt like
 		no this can't happen it seemed real it seemed real you know it was really good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that that was one i mean it's not my all time favorite movie but it was good it was really good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and um i don't know
 		if you like this kind but i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> was a really good movie too
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that was a great movie
 	
 	
 		yeah i've we've seen that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> times we waited and we rented it you know but but it was really good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh have you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shrimp</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Barbie</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't i don't know if i've even heard of that one it must have uh what's his name in it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah it's got
 		no
 	
 	
 		no it doesn't
 	
 	
 		no uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogan</ENAMEX> yeah no no
 	
 	
 		really yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Hogan</ENAMEX>
 		no really i'm surprised
 	
 	
 		no it's got uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cheech Marin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really  that must be pretty good then was it good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah it is it's kind of uh kind of a poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pretty Woman</ENAMEX> in reverse
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but it was kind of cute actually did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirty Rotten Scoundrels</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes yes
 	
 	
 		i though that was a really cute movie i enjoyed that
 	
 	
 		yeah it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twins</ENAMEX> was good too  because when i thought of that i thought of  anyway um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh there was another one what's the one that just
 		oh Dances with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Wolves</ENAMEX> have you seen that yet oh you've got to see that one
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 		i hear that's the one that you really need to see at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> instead of home video
 	
 	
 		it's really
 		right that's probably true that's probably true it's it's very very good very good that's another one that i was really glad when it won all those awards because it really deserved it
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> uh has got a uh a picture from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Costner</ENAMEX> and he signed it it's from <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Dances</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Wolves yeah</ENAMEX> and he signed it he he happens to be uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of her her business associates
 	
 	
 		really
 		oh wow that's impressive
 	
 	
 		and all right not not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh neat
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> so uh uh but anyhow we got uh we got a nice uh picture and it came in an envelope that says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dances</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolves</ENAMEX> so we've got to uh try to get out there and see that one
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's really worth it i mean it's a very good movie and yes i would suggest seeing it at the theater i know that they're still playing it and they pushed it back to playing it in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> until like August
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		i think because they were they were scheduling a video release of it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and then when it won all those awards
 		uh they pushed it back to August
 		so but yeah that one is definitely worth seeing it's really good
 	
 	
 		now did you see uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Driving Miss Daisy</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah and you know i didn't think that one was near as good
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		you know i guess it was okay i mean it was all right but um when i compare like
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year and last year</TIMEX> it it just i don't know maybe it's it's not
 		
 		
 	