
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		okay now when you babysit what age group <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you sit with
 	
 	
 		well gosh all kinds um mostly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between the ages of two and ten</TIMEX>
 		um last like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few summers ago</TIMEX> i kept <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the entire summer</TIMEX> and i mean they became like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i'd think so
 	
 	
 		and um
 		and they live in an apartment <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> so we swam a lot and we played on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground</ENAMEX> a lot and
 		we would go to a movie on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Thursdays</ENAMEX> and um
 		there was always an activity you know they had their favorite TV shows and things like that that we watched and then we took naps and
 		um i don't know it it just seems like there was always something to do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are so full of energy
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and oh they were they just
 		they they just keep you going
 	
 	
 		now was this a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> family
 	
 	
 		uh one parent
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> how much time did she spend with them
 	
 	
 		yeah she's just
 		not much at all  i mean i would get there at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> usually weren't awake by then and she would get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> at like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five thirty</TIMEX> in the afternoon
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they would have dinner and then it was time for them to go to bed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um now at this particular time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> were two
 		and
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
 		but then i also i've been babysitting this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> uh for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight years</TIMEX> he's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> now and um you know i've watched him grow up and he's like a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> to me
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's changed over the over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> um
 		we get along a lot better now that he's older
 		and uh we do different things now we used to play ball a lot but now it's he likes to watch TV and he's into wrestling and um i kept him on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> we went see we went to go see a movie and um
 		things like that but i feel like i don't know when i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i want to be able to spend a lot of time with them
 	
 	
 		do you now you say your you go to school
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LSU</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and what are you studying
 	
 	
 		uh communications
 	
 	
 		well sounds like your getting a lot of experience in communicating with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i mean i love <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> um i don't know seem when i was growing up my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> stayed at home with me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> until we were in junior high
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i don't it would i think it was very beneficial to us i mean like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> we were always in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> programs reading books and we went skating a lot and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know she was just always there for us but nowadays if there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to a family the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> works just as hard as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> does and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> either stay at home and get into trouble or they're stuck in a day care
 		and i just i just don't want my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to have to be raised like that all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> they their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> worked all the time they got to stay at home by themselves and when i was younger
 		i thought they were lucky because they got to get away with things like i couldn't ride my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> but they could because they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> would never know it but now i realize that it was better because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		they have got into a lot of trouble
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because of lack of supervision
 	
 	
 		well that that certainly can happen now if you you say you're in communications uh what base of communications would you be most interested in getting in to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i'm majoring in uh public relations
 	
 	
 		public relations so so you would have a job with a company
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yes ma'am
 	
 	
 		rather than uh radio or television or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> or what have you
 	
 	
 		right uh-huh
 	
 	
 		and uh then you'd be willing to give up your job to stay home and with or stay with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i would like to uh stay at home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least the first five years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but what what i plan to do in the future is um go ahead and get my upper education as far as my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> and work on my doctorate and teach um college
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and in that case then i'll be i'll be at home when my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are at home but i'd like to stay at home with them until they get in at least into kindergarten
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where they're at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> from what <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight to three</NUMEX> or something and then i would be at my school teaching
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 	
 	
 		well that that's uh is an advantage of being in the education field i spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty four years</TIMEX> in education
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yes and so oh i started out with college and then went to high school and then i preferred the high school age level much better than i did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> because you have a closer relationship with the uh students
 	
 	
 		what grade
 		oh did you
 		what did you teach
 	
 	
 		that i taught physical education
 	
 	
 		oh oh i started out as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PE</ENAMEX> major
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		in education i wanted to be a PE teacher
 		i sure did
 	
 	
 		well i uh i found that uh it was a perfect combination from the standpoint of having vacations off at the same time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and it worked out fine from that standpoint uh plus the fact that uh when i left uh
 		usually uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was seldom home for maybe forty <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> or so and then our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> he had to get on the bus and he did get on the bus it was his responsibility and he never ever thought
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of uh not going to school he said in view of the fact that
 		he was certain i had a hot line to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because uh i uh well i i was in physical education then and i just kept getting pushed into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> wound up in administration
 	
 	
 		absolutely
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and so he thought surely that i or i would have bought a hot line to know if he ever skipped school which of course was not the case and i wouldn't have checked on him however uh there are there are points
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		both directions in that uh from the standpoint of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> working and not working
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh i listened to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> say i don't know what this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> wants i'm working <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> jobs they each have their own television they each have their own telephone they each have their own <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> they each have this they each have that
 		i'd say but what they don't have is you
 	
 	
 		that's right they need some attention
 	
 	
 		absolutely and uh acting out because that is the way of getting attention
 	
 	
 		well see whenever my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX> stayed home with us we did without a lot i mean we were it's hard to make it on one income but we did and and we lived in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trailer</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen years</TIMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		huh
 	
 	
 		you know we we only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> car we only had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> telephone you know we didn't get to eat out all the time but i i feel like that it helped me now because i appreciate the value of the dollar
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and um i also had the supervision that i needed while i was growing up and i hope that i can provide that for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		and we certainly uh we need more of that we need more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> willing to supervise though we've had such a breakdown in the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> from the standpoint of of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and school and everything along the way
 	
 	
 		oh we have
 	
 	
 		and that i think has contributed much to uh the delinquency that works grant and the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> results that we're having
 		uh that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have just not really taken enough interest in them from the very very beginning and i think
 		my feeling was that the very best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> should be in grades <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one two</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> off to a good start let them have positive um
 		uh experiences from the lower levels so they want to continue learning and uh keep going and not wait until they're they're in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tenth</NUMEX> grades it's too late then you cannot reverse that trend at that point
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it is
 		it's way too late i agree
 	
 	
 		right and uh while <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> very often will be involved with the school activities when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s in the elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and they get into the high <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> so often they seem to drop away at that point and that is just as valuable
 	
 	
 		it is
 	
 	
 		at that time as to the rush in the elementary yes right
 	
 	
 		because all the peer pressure
 		it starts in high school and the parent really needs to be there for the child
 	
 	
 		right and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> needs to take pride in the fact that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parent</ENAMEX> is doing something uh we were fortunate in view of the fact that
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> did play <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and i did keep statistics for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> did take movies of the football
 	
 	
 		oh great
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> and movies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and we tried to be a part of it but not overshadowing him or making him feel that we had to be there all the time
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so what i feel that i learned a great deal from my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 		uh with regard to
 		what their biggest complaints were with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and a thing such as uh one of the biggest complaints i well remember because i spent a lot of time with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> uh was um
 		caring their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> say when i was your age i didn't have this or that and i know i never ever said that because i knew that that was one thing that was really irritating to young people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i guess that was good that you were you were hearing it from other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes and i had to deal with their problems and i could talk about the kinds of problems which they were bringing that they had
 		just in general aspect and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> would share this and then he would have to make decisions for himself along those same types of of uh lines
 	
 	
 		well um
 	
 	
 		so that i think he benefited from my experiences
 	
 	
 		does your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		no he uh works uh for a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> yeah in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> area but when he went away to college and he was on an allowance
 		from the time he was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade and uh a small allowance and all the way through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">college</ENAMEX> and he held <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> jobs
 		while he was in college and we didn't even know it he didn't even tell us uh that he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> jobs but when he graduated he had a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five thousand dollar</NUMEX> bank account
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh we had told him that if he ever wanted to go to college he could go if he got married he was on his own if he flunked out he was on his own
 		
 		
 	