
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how are things in your area in that respect
 	
 	
 		well um
 		starting with my work um we're in a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> can and paper recycling um i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and there's a uh a lot of paper that gets thrown away here so we've started recycling our uh plain white paper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and we have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that collects it and takes care of that that for us uh in the community um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore County</ENAMEX> that i that's the county i used to live in
 		um they just started experimenting with uh trash pickup where uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day a week</TIMEX> they pick up recycled items and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another day a week</TIMEX> they pick up
 		the other trash and uh they've uh contracted with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> here that has a special truck that has different containers on the same truck you know one that holds paper one that holds plastic one that holds tin one that holds aluminum
 		and uh so they've they've started experimenting with doing it um on a very large scale also in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore City</ENAMEX> they've started doing it uh there's been a lot of awareness um
 		especially here on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">east coast</ENAMEX> because our landfills are you know so filled now that uh there's just not enough room for all the garbage that we uh that we create
 	
 	
 		i think we've all heard about the train load from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> that couldn't find a place to dump or something
 	
 	
 		that's right and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">barge</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> that went around the world and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		until the garbage all rotted or something
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> is just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and i've been very discouraged by the local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> dragging their heals about getting into a recycling program each
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> who comes up from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election</TIMEX> promises that that's going to be real high on his list of priorities but it just doesn't seem to be working out that way
 		uh one of our local city council <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who happens to be a personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of ours made the statement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that there would always be landfills and we just sort of came unglued at that point because if that's their thinking
 		then i think we're definitely in trouble here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because there just cannot always be landfills uh my
 		we have always saved aluminum just absolutely forever and uh i'm saving uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> now and glass our biggest problem is that no one will take the paper
 		it gets really difficult to find someone in fact now i'm donating it to a local church
 		and by giving it to them they take it in mass and then our junk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> gives them <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> dollars just because they've they're a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and he writes it off as a donation but it's a real problem with
 		with the paper to find that outlet for it after you've got it stacked up
 	
 	
 		yeah that's uh it's been a problem that i've noticed a lot in print that uh um once you have collected this
 		what do you do with it because there's not a whole lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that are taking it there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that want to participate and given the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> will participate and they've proven that time and time again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i was just reading some figures this morning that seventy <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">nine percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> polled considered themselves to be environmentalists
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so uh you know it looks like there's a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there who want to do it there's just not a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> out there that know what to do with it another problem that that's uh is plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> cartons
 	
 	
 		um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they've got a way to recycle them they've got places that can recycle them into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">products</ENAMEX> no problem the problem is that they can't there's no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> to get it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have the raw material the empty milk cartons
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who can do something with it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh in order for this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> to survive they've had to uh in their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> start sponsoring their own recycling centers
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		in order to get the raw goods but they you know of course they can they're limited with what they can do they can only do so much and uh
 	
 	
 		sure
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know it's it's a matter of i i don't think you know i hate to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> involved with anything because it always costs more money but um you know it's a matter of they're going to have to pass stricter laws or start making
 	
 	
 		i know i know
 		um
 	
 	
 		the garbage collection um more costly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and once they do that then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will be more interested right now it doesn't matter how much garbage you put out to the road it's a flat fee a month
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if they started billing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> by the pound things might change drastically
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		as far as well that's one way to force them to recycle is that if they bill them by the pound then they're going to save it and not not put it out to the trash
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		uh it we are in an open rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and we find more garbage on the roadsides when it starts costing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they simply take a bag and pitch
 		pitch it into a ditch someplace uh my  my biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> or one of my biggest concerns is is the tires what they're going to ever do with used tires my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> uh recently retired after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX> in a service <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> and of course
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		originally it was no big deal you could get rid of them but now there's just simply no way to get rid of these things and you see more and more of that around about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have have thrown a tire in the ditch or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> tires in the ditch and
 	
 	
 		well actually there's a gentleman down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> who has invented a process using a certain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> and he can take a tire and turn it into immediately burnable oil
 	
 	
 		will the will the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> allow this
 	
 	
 		it has less <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sulfur</ENAMEX> in it than processed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel oil</ENAMEX> for the house
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it does nothing to hurt the environment and the heat generated by the process is in turn used to run the machine so it's self-sufficient
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and very efficient i mean it it control you know it it  controls its own process it burns it reduces the amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> that's required in order to
 		get out the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> at the other end um so far they've demonstrated it on a uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX> size <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> invented they're currently looking for funding to build a larger scale and i saw this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three months</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh-hum
 		a lot of these things can be placed in your area because of the density in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> and yet they would be  just frightfully expensive to put in our area because of the scarcity of population
 	
 	
 		well if you think about it if um uh i remember that when they used to take uh they used to pay you to take the tire you know get the turn in your tire when you got your
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and your your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> probably remembers that better than i do i remember there was a time when they'd give you one or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two dollars</NUMEX> for your used tire now they charge you <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two dollars</NUMEX> for your used tire
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right  well he was at the point where if if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customer</ENAMEX> did not want to take the tire with them he charged them a dollar to dispose of them and still there wasn't really a way to dispose of them this was just to sort of encourage them to take them
 		uh at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time uh not too long ago uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> could use uh tires to start a fire burning fence rows which of course was an air pollutant and they've put a stop to any open burning of any kind and they are fining
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now i mean it used to be the law was and no one enforced it but they are enforcing it now and and i'm glad they are however <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> solution presents another problem
 		well i would like certainly like to see this you know if this is true with this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX> it sounds wonderful
 	
 	
 		yes
 		i saw it on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> news and um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> actually took the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> that came out from the process in a measuring cup turned around and poured it right back into the uh tank
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that he was using to fire the process in order to run it
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		and you actually um with this process by putting in the tires end up with more energy from the oil
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		than you put into the process so it's a way of of making a profit off the tires
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when you stop and look at the you know something like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight million</NUMEX> tires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> that are you know discarded you know there's a lot of tires out there that that could go through this process
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i you've certainly hit on the key to any of it whatever we're going to do there has to be a profit there doesn't there the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fellow</ENAMEX> who recycles the paper and the plastic and the aluminum he's got to be able to make a profit or he just isn't going to do it
 	
 	
 		there's not a profit
 		i think the the problem is that there's there's always a payoff to recycling but it's hard for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to see it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because it's hard for them it's hard to explain to someone that look it's costing us you know umpteen <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to bury this stuff in the ground
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then what is the long-term effect of us burying that in the ground if that stuff
 	
 	
 		it's costing us a lot more than money isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah it it's going to leak into our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and then we're going to have problems with our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and then it's going to cause health problems and so there is a long-term
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		effect and when you stop and think about it every just about every single thing that's produced can be recycled
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean if it's if it's uh food you know if it's stuff you scraped off your plate it can go into the compost and you know and so it's i mean
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it there's a way to recycle everything and and um if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> just retired then i've got to believe that you've got to be old enough to remember that back during the wars hey recycling was the thing to do i mean you didn't
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		we didn't throw away anything did we
 	
 	
 		that's right if you if you didn't recycle you were un-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> and and that was the bottom line
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well we have to come to that now that's all there is to it you do see a lot of positive things uh i saw a printout sheet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that i'm going to to copy and take to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> at sorority
 		
 		
 	