
 
     		
 	
 		the uh public school system system seems to be
 		getting a lot of uh criticism lately i guess over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> it's always seemed worse uh to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> that have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in there than it was when they were there so
 		uh i don't know how much of it is well a lot of it is deserved but then a lot of it's not i mean the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are coming out learning
 		uh things a lot faster uh whether or not they actually have it learned that that that yet uh remains to be seen at least in our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> case it's they're still in it but uh i know they're learning things that uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we never learned plus they have the burden of uh
 		well this is the burden they have the task of learning computers uh even in uh kindergarten they had uh a requirements that they had to meet for learning the uh
 		terms like keyboard and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitor</ENAMEX> and they wanted know what a computer was and what a disk was and
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		that's great
 	
 	
 		you know all the uh yeah it is but it's interesting that that there's that much more knowledge to be learned at this at this uh age you know not just the colors and begin on the alphabet it's
 	
 	
 		so much more complex
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		learn your colors learn your alphabet learn all your your little terms here and and learn how to uh
 		begin learning some of the reading and by the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade uh the little school system that we're in
 		they have uh really a lot of computers uh it's a very
 		wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">district</ENAMEX> as as all that fighting's going on over who gets the money and the like but they have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">great</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i've been hearing about that
 	
 	
 		they have uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty seven</NUMEX> computers for each of the little <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> and each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> serves
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> grades so the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> have their own batch of computers that they've cycled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> through and
 	
 	
 		goodness
 	
 	
 		and so there's uh well i guess <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> and they're all very nice uh computers all tied together on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAN</ENAMEX> and one server that handles all the
 		software so that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> don't have to go around to each machine and do their work they can control it from the machine the server it's it's a beautiful system but uh
 		the only bad thing it seems to do is uh not the computer necessarily but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> the school system seems to put a little bit more
 		pressure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> than uh than we had of course of course i guess with that learning comes that pressure
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we also managed to land in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that uh
 		they decided to build <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big rectangular <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> and then not have any walls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">classroom</ENAMEX> and so it gets a little noisy it's a little hard to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that quiet from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> to the next and they can't really
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		be rowdy at any one given time so they they put them outside a lot they try you know to get a lot of good breaks here and there and
 		but uh they just took bookcases and things to move around and sort of what you know sort of build a an idea of a wall
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> seem to handle it okay but it's it's got some drawbacks to it
 		and uh as if that wasn't bad enough they they also experimented with a particular size school most of the elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> were uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven hundred</NUMEX> uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in in it only goes from kindergarten up to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> grade for our elementaries and our particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> run uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> fifty right now
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 	
 	
 		so they they put a few more warm bodies in there than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> really needed to have they still have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty three to twenty five or so</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> ratio but it's still
 	
 	
 		that can be a disadvantage to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah still a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and you just can't get them in and out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> in a reasonable length of time you know traffic is a bit of a problem  i mean of all the decisions they could have made on this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they uh they located it in a
 		up against a creek and there's no street access to it except for one turn around driveway and that feeds onto a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> that is right across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> from
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>  and they all get out at the same time and it's just uh so we we spend a little time getting i get
 	
 	
 		get it
 	
 	
 		go over there to pick up uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> about two thirty
 		and he gets out at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two forty five</NUMEX> and that gives me a little bit of time to get parked and then i wait for between between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> rather than drive all the way home i wait a little while and and at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two thirty</TIMEX> i mean at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three thirty my</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> gets out
 		and we usually let them play if the weather's nice play outside until the traffic dies down and then we go home so i'm there from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two thirty</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four o'clock</TIMEX> i'm just waiting for
 	
 	
 		oh that's a good idea
 	
 	
 		to pick up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> that's how much of a chunk it takes out of the old day but uh it is better just to let them you know play outside than it is to fight the traffic so
 		and there's it's real nice <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> lands on both sides of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> they have you know climbers and stuff like that but
 	
 	
 		well great
 	
 	
 		the the school system in and of itself as far as what they're teaching um
 		they cannot keep up with the private as far as because of the ratio there's just no way plus the private tends to have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the more disciplined <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know they're not dealing with the whole gamut of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX> here they're they're private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> do not put up with
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that is uh that much of a problem like most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have to
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so you have that kind of a situation but uh by the same token you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> coming out of private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that they've spent very much time with them
 		not able to social cope socially with the other types of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the world
 	
 	
 		yeah um i remember i mean during my i went to a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> during the junior junior high <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> which was uh
 		you know really during the development development time of my life and it was a small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> we had like maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in junior high
 		i mean in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> like in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> grade we had <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> in them and whenever we moved up to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth eighth</NUMEX> grade we had like <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty or twenty five</TIMEX> in the whole <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">eighth</NUMEX> grade and we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different classes so the ratio was real good um
 		as far as the we had real good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and i learned a lot i feel like that if i had of gone to a private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> during junior high i probably wouldn't have developed such good study skills because um
 		i thought the private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> was difficult i mean it gave a lot of homework and everything and it really helped me develop
 		my skills my uh
 		my memorization i can memorize things real well now and things like that but and then whenever i got to high school it was kind of a disadvantage to me to to the fact that i was going from a class of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> to a class of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five hundred</NUMEX>
 		and uh and i do feel like that i was socially withdrawn to a certain extent because i didn't know anyone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> in high school you know and i was the peon
 		but uh it probably took i don't know maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first semester</TIMEX> to get to get to where i was really comfortable with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> because um i hadn't been in the public school system for so long and it is just it's really different
 		it uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> there are a lot a lot wilder than what i was used to i was grew i grew up in a very protective home and then whenever i got to high school things were just
 		so much different especially nowadays i mean even the high school that i went to just recently they put up these little metal detectors at each door when you walk in to make sure you don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> and things like that and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i mean it's it's gotten worse i graduated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about two years ago</TIMEX> and even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX> it's gotten i mean it's just increased the the crime and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and the violence and everything have just crime increased enormously
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		well another thing that we've noticed that's uh changed over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> and
 		uh we're not really sure exactly what we're going what we want to do with it publicly but uh
 		the teachings
 		uh the ideas that are taught uh don't always agree with what we would teach them either from a standpoint of morals or from a standpoint of how to handle a given situation
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there seems to be a a large degree of violence not necessarily taught but but ingrained in a majority of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> either from TV or from
 		uh quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like in the
 		<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade take uh karate lessons and take various uh self-defense things and it's it's it's given to them or it's proposed
 	
 	
 		golly
 	
 	
 		it seems to be socially acceptable as a self-esteem you know building building the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s confidence up and you have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graders</ENAMEX> that are uh you know when they get into a fight they they tend to use some of the the
 		maneuvers that they have and they feel a little more confident about their fighting ability they tend to get into a few more fights and several of them have ended with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> calls and and having uh broken bones down at that level of
 	
 	
 		oh goodness
 	
 	
 		of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i know more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> that has has got a uh record already just because of fighting of that that nature
 	
 	
 		oh no
 	
 	
 		and  it's it's not something that necessarily happens at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but just in their their uh relationships as they after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> times and the like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then you get into the whole area of of uh well what what i would deem the new age thinking where they have these little extra classes but they offer to come in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about fifteen to twenty minutes early in the mornings</TIMEX> and
 		all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will sit around in a little circle and they're they're asked to empty their minds and to to think about uh they have a name of a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> that they they're to uh think about that <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> and they're encouraged
 		
 		
 	