
 
     		
 	
 		and she's expecting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of this month</TIMEX> and she's the only one that lives nearby
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh well that'll be nice though
 	
 	
 		so the rest live in
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> lives near <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		but still sort of up in that general area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> so you can probably see them sometimes
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah we see them once in a while a couple of times a year at least and the ones in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pittsburgh</ENAMEX> of course we see more often
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so uh
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		i'm ready to go
 	
 	
 		well uh what kind of recycling do you have in your area
 	
 	
 		well they've been trying different things one one of the biggest problems seems to be we don't they don't have anyplace to put some of the things that need recycled
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right now
 		we've recycled <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> because we have a glass industry in our community
 	
 	
 		oh what which one is that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Owens</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh uh-huh
 	
 	
 		um
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">glass</ENAMEX> has been recycled for a long time uh we have a cycling area set up here at our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> have and they've done that for years
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> are recycling their plastic bags now you can take them back in and they have bins to collect those uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">aluminum</ENAMEX> cans
 		they try to do the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and uh they had to close their area down because they couldn't sell it they were what they were doing was shredding it and trying to sell it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> for bedding for their animals
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that type of thing and that didn't work but but somebody told me that they were charging as much for it as they did for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> which is why they couldn't sell it you know because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX> would buy the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">straw</ENAMEX> if it's a you know similar price
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		sure
 	
 	
 		
  
 		okay i think by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> it's going to be required that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Clarion</ENAMEX> which we live nearby will have mandatory recycling started
 		so
 	
 	
 		on just particular things or
 	
 	
 		uh mainly the glass the aluminum the plastics
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		well it sounds like they're doing quite a bit
 	
 	
 		well we're working hard on it because we're fighting also in our area a large hazardous waste incinerator
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		which we do not want built and uh
 		we would like industry to do more before they build these big huge incinerators
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		we we just feel they should they should offer industry some incentives to do more reducing of their
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste products</ENAMEX> and reusing them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that are doing it have save money eventually at first apparently it costs more to get started
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but once they get established then it's a money saving thing
 	
 	
 		well our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> does some things all of which i couldn't even tell you about i don't know all of them but
 	
 	
 		and what is <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		gee my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> works for
 		no not for that okay excuse me  go ahead
 	
 	
 		well i i was just curious as how you got hooked up with this this speech type of thing if
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> works in uh for the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> he's he works in a computer laboratory
 	
 	
 		oh and he
 	
 	
 		and uh it was through him that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well here at work um each <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of us has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> trash baskets in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> and one of those is designed for any kind of paper products that um they want
 		to use you know for recycling they can't deal with every type
 	
 	
 		uh maybe you could tell me what is the difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> paper waste and just like newspapers
 	
 	
 		well i guess i don't know specifically except that uh for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that they want to recycle they do not want any newspaper um and
 		things like candy wrappers or uh that type of thing let's see i have a list here um they don't want lunch sacks or brown envelopes
 		uh phone books
 		so there are you know a lot of kinds of things that they don't want but then any kind of computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> letters uh booklets they'll even take things that are bound
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and it doesn't all have to be like white they'll take colored folders and and uh even some of those can have plastic tabs on them so it's it's hard to kind of figure out
 	
 	
 		oh really
 		hum
 	
 	
 		you know which things are the right ones i mean i i'll frequently have to look at the list if it's something that i don't throw away all the time
 	
 	
 		um
 		it's neighbor
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um they do that and then we use uh different <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> and things and i know that you know they're
 		real concerned about how they take care of that sort of thing i i don't know all the details but they're really on top of that
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		right yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there probably some other things that i don't about because we're a real large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> and i just don't have contact with them but in our uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> well i live in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">suburb</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they have initiated a newspaper recycling whereby they pick it up from your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day a week</TIMEX> and all you have to do is bundle it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh all around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> there are a lot of recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX> where you can take things sometimes for money um but most of those are real far away from
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like where i live at any rate
 	
 	
 		well it would be inconvenient to in other words to
 	
 	
 		very inconvenient and um it's just you know hasn't been very practical to get into a lot of those things if they would make it something where they you know would pick it up at the curb or at least
 		make it you know down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and up the corner type of thing uh
 	
 	
 		right more areas where they would pick it up yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah that wouldn't be so bad um our grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> like yours will take the uh plastic bags and they'll also take the the paper bags back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um
 		uh you mentioned the uh glass type of stuff the reason i ask you about that is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and it it changed names somewhere along the line but
 		um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> used to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knox Glass</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Knox Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knox</ENAMEX> is just over the hill here  yes uh-huh they they no longer are you know
 	
 	
 		oh really yeah it's
 	
 	
 		active
 	
 	
 		yeah they were taken over by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glass Containers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> and but he worked for them for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty one years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh for heaven's sake
 	
 	
 		and used to travel up there to <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Knox</ENAMEX> quite a bit and and i even did once when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> you know so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh for heaven's sake well we only live probably <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about fifteen twenty miles</NUMEX> from Knox
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		yeah we i was looking through a photo album not long ago and they had had some pictures and things in there of Knox
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i'll be darn yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh i guess that's about it you know as far as what goes on that i know about
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are getting more interested and they are more concerned and we're just we're just real concerned about this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">incinerator</ENAMEX> because we really they want to put it right in uh
 		in between <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of our main <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> sheds
 		that feed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clarion River River</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh we we just we just don't want it anyplace  we feel that we that they should give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> more incentives
 		to do more recycling and more reduction and and more reuse and all those things that could be done
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we we just don't think
 		we don't think some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> are really interested in our best interests
 	
 	
 		yeah that's
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		it's it's been a real struggle and a hardship for a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our area that we have you know have been fighting against this thing in trying to have things changed to make them more more right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		well i think probably more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know would participate if they just made it a little easier and like you say make it um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		better for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to do these things get involved in it without huge cost to them because obviously no one wants to spend a lot of money just to deal with trash  you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		right
 		uh well
 		we're we're going to pay for that that whether we pay industry or pay we we've already paid industry for like these super fund that's cleaning up we paid industry for it
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		we pay all help to pay to have them haul it away from their place and where they put it now they found it's not a safe place it's leaked and now they have to clean those up
 		and it's our money that's cleaning this stuff up and now they want to put it in they burn it and that will make another hazardous dump
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and eventually they'll have to do something with that we'll pay for it again so why not pay industry this is my feeling why not pay industry a little more and reduce it you know and and not have as much of it
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		also probably look at packaging and that sort of thing we don't we don't need <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three quarters</TIMEX> of what we get
 	
 	
 		oh definitely
 		hum-um hum-um no but they think and probably the right <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> buy it
 	
 	
 		i uh that's their marketing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		and i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would be willing to do more like saving their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and that if they had a place to take them we don't have anyplace right now
 		that will take them
 	
 	
 		yeah i i'm guess our city you know in picking them up must take them somewhere else and get something for them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		probably yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't know that it's a big money
 		
 		
 	