
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		crime in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and i guess in some of the rural areas too seems to be going up i don't know it'll ever go down on any steady basis uh more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> more opportunities and
 		somewhat of a lessened uh sensitivity toward it it's almost um
 		you know it's almost expected that that's going to occur and there's not quite the shock any more especially the so-called littler
 		things where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tend to steal a little time at work or steal a few supplies or
 		uh the whole defense industry's had some problems in that realm even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>'s tend to steal a little of that here and there and uh then you get into
 		whole areas of crime like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> usage and organized crime and
 		as far as steps to reduce it uh
 		i'm not sure that there's anything that hasn't been tried we might have ought to come up with something new if we could but uh you can't keep throwing money at it and
 	
 	
 		well you mentioned one of my
 		pet
 		buzz words there which is
 		sensitivity to it and particularly violence i uh
 		really get uh
 		ticked off with uh seeing this violence so much of it on TV and so forth in the movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think that uh it does goes a lot toward uh
 		you know like you say it gives <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a
 		kind of a makes them insensitive to it and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's
 	
 	
 		it's hard to judge but uh you know just thinking back i don't seem to recall my growing up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> i'm only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty three</TIMEX> but it uh looking back on the
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that i played with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> we only played so-called war you know a few times and and then uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cowboys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> in my case
 	
 	
 		yeah that kind of a deal as opposed to to uh you know having shooting giant cannons and all the kind of warfare that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are playing with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you know they turn the stick into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cannon</ENAMEX> instead of a simple little gun
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are the answer that's uh that's where our uh
 		hopefully the cure lies if there you know is to be one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		get uh
 		get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> uh
 		corrected to to some extent
 	
 	
 		there was another uh angle that i i started seeing as uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Polish</ENAMEX> situation and some of the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as it were uh they started coming into the news and you started hearing about some of their
 		troubles and the like and some of their their crime problems
 		it made me wonder just how the
 		uh outlook of the future affects <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s decisions to either commit  crimes or how they live or whatever uh it seems like they
 		the poorer the situation or the poorer the outlook the more likely they are to commit a crime
 	
 	
 		yeah i think uh  if you got
 	
 	
 		uh that makes sense
 	
 	
 		that's of course i guess one of the root causes is uh
 		the have nots or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are  without you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well that's not
 		of course that's not the total thing but
 		that'd explain a lot of it and then uh i guess the drug
 		thing is really uh
 		become a an engine for crime here lately
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true i mean it feeds upon itself
 		not only does it make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> stagnant and not very capable of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">social</ENAMEX> progress in the realm of uh earning a living in the way that the norm is uh but it
 		you know makes for a habit that has to be supported at a rate that uh can't be supported by uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> as far as working goes i mean you can't be that much into <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and still hold down a job capable of paying for that much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's a vicious circle in and of itself
 		there's really uh i don't know a a bit of an eye-opener i guess even to see some of the the portions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">States United States</ENAMEX> that are
 		becoming depressed economically and to see that the high schoolers that are coming out of school why even for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two to three years</TIMEX>
 		uh there's nothing for them you know uh a lot of these rural areas college wasn't even a a consideration for the majority of them they kind of are confident that they could just move right on into industry
 		and industry's gone from a lot of these areas and there's nothing to go into
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so they
 		still feel trapped and feel you know they were looking forward to getting out on their own and getting away from whatever uh family problems they had and
 		so they just turned to whatever be it <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or be it crime or some way to make the money to get away from the situation they're in
 		and
 	
 	
 		yeah i'd agree with that
 	
 	
 		uh i guess that's not going to do anything but spread as as uh economic hardships spread and so will the the crimes of that age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> i guess
 		i've got a a brother-in-law that's on the police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> and and his uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> is a uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> in an emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> when they come home from work together they have the worst stories to share i mean we spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> with them down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and just the things that they have to
 		uh you know Spring break's a big deal and and uh he was telling me that he had to be on the scene of an accident where <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> all of the them  drunk uh
 		collided <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> on and every single one of them died <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> in another and
 	
 	
 		um
 		um
 	
 	
 		and uh as if that wasn't bad enough the the ones that were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> alive that they rushed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> and she got to work on and she got to see them die and uh and they just get all the world's worst situations very few rewarding situations uh and
 	
 	
 		um
 		that's got to be a a grim uh supper topic there
 	
 	
 		grim family yeah yeah and they
 		fortunately they have some some success stories to share and i try to
 		tell them to dwell on those i can't see how they can both stand uh to live that way but they don't see much uh hope for neither one of them sees any real solution to the to the problems uh
 	
 	
 		well it's got to be frustrating as hell for a
 		particularly a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> you know they uh
 		they go out and  make the arrests and
 		i guess
 		the  <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> crowded the way they are before they can get the paperwork finished huh they're releasing them or they're releasing somebody just like them you know it's a revolving door that uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		has to be uh
 		just uh
 		beat your head against the wall of frustration you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i meant to ask him the last time i was talking with him if uh if there are any circumstances under which they suspend the normal paperwork for just even a minor wreck because
 		uh numerous times there there have been just a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> incident and
 		he starts his paperwork when you know he's gets there and then by the time they all cleared out and gone he's still sitting there doing paperwork on this deal and i said
 		wonder what those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> do when they have those you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> car pileups on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">highway</ENAMEX> if it'd take a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> uh you know whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> just to do the paperwork
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah well
 	
 	
 		that's a
 	
 	
 		uh
 		i know that uh minor uh wrecks don't require uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um uh you just exchange your insurance information
 	
 	
 		right
 		it just be up up to something i guess that was big enough to
 		to call them out for well i got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> needing me so i'll
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		see if we get together again sometime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Greg</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you
 	
 	
 		nice talking to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	