
 
     		
 	
 		talk about the activities that we don't do  uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i i don't have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so but i i have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>  and i know they spend a lot of time with them  which is good
 	
 	
 		that's good to hear yeah and  i haven't uh well i've been  around a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> lately at work at my job that don't have a lot of values
 	
 	
 		you know
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so it's it's always nice to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that like each other  and like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> that get along with each other and like to do things together
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah they have a lot of values i love that  do they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> the the most valueless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> doesn't  but she's married now i i'm not quite sure why  i i think he said that he'd give her a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		she got married to him
 	
 	
 		oh that's wonderful
 	
 	
 		but  it's it's it's it's kind of weighed on me and then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the  other day</TIMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i met a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> who who're they're just gonna have their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and  they really like each other
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and they're real happy with one another and she says things like  i'm really glad when he comes home and there's not enough time to spend with him in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the evening</TIMEX> and  i'm like
 	
 	
 		oh that's neat
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		that's good you know i like to see that you know i have uh some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> joined they have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> girls <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> and the other was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brownies</ENAMEX>  and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> got involved as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> and then all of a sudden the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> was getting involved with  doing nature hikes for them and working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX> camp
 		here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and then going out to  um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Perot Camp</ENAMEX> and working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and stuff and they're gone a lot and they take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and they go away for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and  in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter time</TIMEX> even you know to do work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scouts</ENAMEX> and i think it's neat
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know they've really become very much involved in in just that one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>  which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> can use the help too  so i i wish i could see more of that you know
 	
 	
 		right
 		well on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> we just met uh a family we were thinking about getting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine Coon Cat</ENAMEX>
 		and we went over to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> that breeds them here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> and  uh her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> actually it was her she said that her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> said to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>  you need a hobby
 	
 	
 		
   
 	
 	
 		so she chose the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and you can tell it's a family hobby
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> they're all a part of it and it was really neat because they all were interested in each other and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and
 		they raise <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">champion cats</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh  those are neat <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		so they've done really well
 		yeah i've just learned about that breed
 	
 	
 		they're really nice looking <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> but they're all mongrels
 	
 	
 		well that's what we're gonna end up getting
 	
 	
 		well they're the ones that need the homes
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		you know <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> were just all um strays in the neighborhood little baby
 		kittens dropped and stuff and it just kind of built  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at a time just kind i couldn't you know one time <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them came  at once and i can't turn a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hungry cat</ENAMEX> down
 	
 	
 		oh i know
 	
 	
 		so you know and the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that i picked was here uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> brought him over and said he was injured  and it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter time</TIMEX> and i said i just cannot have another <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> i just cannot have another <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>  and i looked out there and he was just laying on my lawn just shivering and all and i said i can't stand it i brought him in so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		those are my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> we don't have very many activities  but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i know what you mean our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> hates other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and the we've tried to get her to like  other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and she just
 		uh she wants to be around human beings and she does not wanna be around other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> so our next we're gonna try it with a kitten
 		and see if her maternal instincts come out
 	
 	
 		huh lots of luck is she spayed oh yeah real maternal
 	
 	
 		yeah  we're hoping it's our last hope
 	
 	
 		she'll eventually i mean mine you know i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> and  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX> everybody's spayed everybody's neutered  and
 		we still have a scrap every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and then nothing real bad you know a slap here and there but  um they put up with each other and they will eventually  her nose will be out of joint for a while and she'll hiss and growl and  slap every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> but they'll she'll finally accept it
 		you know they really don't have any choice in my  in my household  we have a little bit of uh  a fight for who's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> mean a male <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> are are real you know real territorial and so that's the big battle here
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know uh who's who's top dog  well top <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> i guess you know but um we i don't i don't know i don't have a problem with it  i think they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		just learn to accept and i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> too and they've  slapped the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> around too  every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX>  so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		that's true they've got to keep them in line
 	
 	
 		yeah but she'll accept another <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> eventually as long as you make her feel um  like she's still loved and everything  so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maine</ENAMEX> Coon <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> were great they were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> pounds and
 	
 	
 		and they're
 	
 	
 		oh they're just gorgeous but yeah  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollars for a kitten and i think of those i think of the kittens at the pound
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh  yeah <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollars
 	
 	
 		i just
 		yeah yeah and they are lovely but
 	
 	
 		ooh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> payment  that is is a lot of money
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah and then she's saying you know you can't let them outside and you can't do all this stuff and i'm like ooh
 	
 	
 		i don't let <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> out anyway but  i let <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them out just in the back yard every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> but my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> are inside i'm afraid  you know with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neighbors</ENAMEX>
 		it people throw rocks at them and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> run over them and i i just you know i just don't
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i know so and and now they've lost the desire most of them don't even try to get you know to go out i just have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>  that drive me crazy that i let out in the back you know but i won't let them get if they start going in the front and stuff i bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">m</ENAMEX> in
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know i just worry i guess i'm too protective but  you know i see these <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> that are  wandering around the neighborhood and too they can catch diseases really easy just by touching a nose to another cat they can contact leukemia
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">feline leukemia</ENAMEX>  so we know we try try real hard to keep them healthy
 	
 	
 		uh we just bought <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a acre</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> with an acre to try to  so she'll she'll have some room to walk around and not off of a busy street we're we're choosing our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> isn't that bad
 	
 	
 		oh how neat
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do it for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i mean why not well you know why not why not
 	
 	
 		oh them too  well because i he loves she's one of those that loves outside and she doesn't go far but she just wants to be able to have that freedom
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah  well if you're off off a road you know away from a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> and you're off of the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> you said away from a road  you know and you keep an eye on her it's probably okay  i'm just real
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know i guess i'm in a neighborhood and it's  it's just real tough on <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> here you know when i every time i see one run over i just you know it makes me sick  so
 	
 	
 		yeah it gets hard
 		especially with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> oh i know
 	
 	
 		you know but  anyway we kind of got off the subject of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> except that i consider them my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah our <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> are our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or  i we we got married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX> and i'm like well why can't Ashley be at the wedding
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh no  in her little bridesmaid dress
 	
 	
 		yeah you know if i could have i would have done it  oh
 	
 	
 		well i'm sure it's been done i'm sure it has been done well they have weddings for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs</ENAMEX> now and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> and you know you they have all that  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> for them where they dress up i've seen it in
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		magazines and stuff where you dress your <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> up and take them to a party  i haven't gone that far i'm not that bonkers  you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> do not wear clothes and
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		
 
 		no
 		i i don't think they'd like to  i put a bow on her <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one night</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX> just kept saying you are the meanest person
 	
 	
 		no no
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i took a picture of her  and that was all it all it lasted for
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well do your do any of your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have have uh older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> that they do anything with do  do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or  they just all have young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah all the ones i know my brother-in-law has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> seven and on down and they they go on family vacations and
 		uh they go like to go skiing  the the middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> doesn't get a whole lot of attention but uh this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last ski</TIMEX> trip
 		they took um she had  contracted chicken pox <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>  and then she spread it to her her little younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX> and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and they got it just at the beginning of the
 	
 	
 		um no
 	
 	
 		vacation where she got better  so she not only is she the better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skier</ENAMEX> but she got all the attention because she got to go out
 		i think think she planned it she's only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> but i think she planned  and she got all the attention from her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>  wow oh yeah
 	
 	
 		love it
 		
 
 		oh say that she needed that didn't she  you know it must be hard when you have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> i
 		you know to have i was an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> was an only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> so i  you know i wasn't raised with  <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> and i always got all the attention so i wouldn't know  i think i would be extremely jealous or would have been  had there  been another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> in the family
 	
 	
 		yeah it's it's  we can see it work with her it's she's frustrated
 	
 	
 		tough
 		must be tough
 		yeah yeah oh she she's the middle one so she's never been the only one so she really doesn't even know what it is to be the only one
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah that's tough
 		you know
 		
 		
 	