
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		so what do you what's your opinion on the our policy down there
 	
 	
 		i don't think we have one
 		yeah i was going to say it's kind of hard to have have an opinion we seem to uh whoever screams the loudest
 	
 	
 		i didn't know we had one either
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		or whoever we happen to give the most money to at that particular time we seem to support
 		without regard whether there is a democracy or a anarchy or anything else
 	
 	
 		i
 		yeah the only thing that i pretty much know about is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Central American</ENAMEX> policy where you know they're just
 		trying to
 		you know military action in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> is the only thing that comes to my mind right now
 		and then
 	
 	
 		well oh yeah and then of course there was there was the uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Columbia</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drug lords</ENAMEX> but we just
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		talked a lot we didn't actually do anything
 	
 	
 		right well that's that's what i was about to say we didn't do anything
 	
 	
 		i'm actually surprised at anything in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> along with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX>
 		i'm just kind of surprised we did that
 	
 	
 		yeah that is that is pretty risky
 	
 	
 		especially after our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> gave it away anyway
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i guess they had to finally do something actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has been better at that than i thought
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he has a little more  a little more of a stand on policy than i thought he would
 		i always considered him kind of a wimp
 	
 	
 		he takes more risks
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> is kind of mush mush mouth
 	
 	
 		yeah he was
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but but i guess most of the policy that we're using now is uh a combination of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carter</ENAMEX>
 		neither  much as you know policy makers
 	
 	
 		yeah it seems that the the policies of pretty much anywhere not just in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> has now is is you know more action than just words than just rhetoric
 		but you know i  we we back up what we say what we say with actions
 	
 	
 		uh yeah we have so far but we we really really haven't of course we really haven't taken on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drug lords</ENAMEX> yet
 	
 	
 		i don't know how long it's going to last
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i'd be interested to see if we do that
 	
 	
 		well i don't think it's possible because even though you know we're against them i don't think we can go into another country
 		and do something about the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s problem
 	
 	
 		well we did in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> we did in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah but no but see the thing when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> was uh the that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noriega</ENAMEX> was uh
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		was was uh was wanted for either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and therefore they had a reason but to go in and take out the whole drug <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">kingdom</ENAMEX> would be something totally different
 	
 	
 		it could be an interesting
 	
 	
 		because
 	
 	
 		interesting problem i
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i don't know if they could do it or not did you read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Clear and Present Danger</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh no i didn't
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i think you need to pick that up and read it it's quite uh it's it's quite interesting it addresses the problem
 	
 	
 		oh the drug problem um-hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		actually he he wrote that prior to the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Medellin</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Medellin Cartel</ENAMEX> being exposed
 		it was on the stands prior to that time it it's quite timely
 		and either he knows somebody or he has a real good a real good imagination because its it hits pretty close to home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i don't think we're going to have much of a choice in either either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't think uh i don't think the the uh problem about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> is going to be safe any time soon i mean
 		you know it it i think it pretty much got sidetracked with uh
 		with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Panama</ENAMEX> and and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Central</ENAMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> problems things that that are important take precedent precedence over
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> i think
 		i think i think the big thing is trying to stop here on the home front and before you know it it'll take a little bit of time before they'll realize that this is failing so they're going to have to go to the source
 	
 	
 		um yeah i think we realize it's failed we just don't we just  don't nobody wants to make the nobody wants to make the uh unpopular decision of going in and invading
 	
 	
 		don't admit it yet
 		right
 	
 	
 		we still there's still there's there's still too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> and  and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Udalls</ENAMEX> all up there
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		there's too many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liberals</ENAMEX> in control they can't agree on anything
 		and they have blinders on as far as the policy goes
 		as long as somebody's getting killed as long as nobody knows about it it's okay but but the minute it hit hits the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> then of course the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> and the  and the Udalls
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dawes</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> all stand up and scream and yell about what a horrible thing it is
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		of course these are the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that also drown  the  and stuff like that you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i guess it automatic i guess it's automatic respective
 	
 	
 		depends on how much power you have and who you know
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have a right to know except about what it about what concerns them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and these are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that make the foreign policy and it it's probably basically uh
 		i would not be surprised if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy Foundation</ENAMEX> or some of those don't have a lot of uh financial holdings in in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		probably
 	
 	
 		considering the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> made all their money off bootleg <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">whiskey</ENAMEX> anyway
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		every time you drink <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotch</ENAMEX> you're paying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't drink <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotch</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		good don't ever drink <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scotch</ENAMEX> it's terrible
 		i quit drinking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Scotch</ENAMEX> when i found out about that
 		but anyway but uh as far as as far as you know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> we our policy pretty much uh
 		it depends on who we're what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> we're buying down there at the particular time
 	
 	
 		yeah i think we're trying to stay uh stay friendly with uh the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Brazilian</ENAMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Argentinean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> because they're producing so much uh agricultural exports
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we don't want to piss them off and have them over produce and then because then our economy would be pretty bad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		although we do need to do something about you know of course in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nicaragua</ENAMEX> and around there with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sandinistas</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contras</ENAMEX> that's been going on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but then hell it's probably still be going on long after we're dead it'll still be the same thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down there don't really
 	
 	
 		i think it's going to have to get worse before it gets better you know the same old cliche
 	
 	
 		well i think basically they can't figure out what they want down there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		if you give everybody what they wanted there  is a complete democracy those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wouldn't know how to react because they have no education
 	
 	
 		right
 		and they'll just pick crooked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> again
 		and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> the the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will just fight their way up to the top again and it'll all
 		be for nothing
 	
 	
 		it's all tradition it's all traditional they have to
 		you have the ruling class and you have everybody else
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i guess that's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about five minutes</TIMEX>
 		appreciate talking to you
 	
 	
 		alrighty
 	
 	
 		what was that book that you were saying to read again
 	
 	
 		well talk to you later <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Clancy</ENAMEX> it's called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Clear and Present Danger</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Clear and Present Danger</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		he wrote he's the one who wrote uh Red <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red October</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay all right
 	
 	
 		and i think if if you read that i think you'll get a real kick out of it
 	
 	
 		all right thanks a lot all right bye
 	
 	
 		all right bye-bye
 		
 		
 	