
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well what's your thoughts on it
 	
 	
 		okay i i think what happened with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> is uh is what everyone says is they they made a lot of uh
 		of not well secured loans on real estate and when uh the bottom fell out of the real estate market the bottom fell out of their loans
 	
 	
 		um that's it that's that's the primary that and the loosening of the restrictions letting them ease up on their cash reserves and uh like you say all these bad real estate loans and energy loans
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um you know i i it's hard to say what caused it i mean you know if if the regulations hadn't been uh
 		hadn't been relaxed maybe it wouldn't have happened but i somehow think it still would have
 		you go in you start making massive investments in those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> areas and you're you're just playing the market you know they were just gambling with their their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savers</ENAMEX>' money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		then of course then of course there was the fraud but you're going to have that anywhere so
 	
 	
 		yeah i think
 		right  yeah that seemed to play a pretty big role i think because i don't know i get the feeling that the regulations probably needed to be a little a little more stringent
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well so are they are they handling it right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gee</ENAMEX> who knows
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		i don't don't even know if they know
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah it certainly has has uh the magnitude of the crisis it seems
 		i don't know it it seems much greater than i would have thought it really just seems out of proportion talking they're talking <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five hundred billion dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i that that's the part of it i couldn't understand i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i wonder if there's not a little bit of overzealousness there uh you know they say well this one went under because of bad energy loans bad real estate loans and then they go around classifying everybody as bad when in fact there are some very good
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		loans out there i mean not all real estate loans are bad you know the greatest majority of them are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who own their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> so you know those aren't exactly what you'd call bad  i
 	
 	
 		right no i think that a a typically bad loan is is that the ones that just took place massively in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> when they put up these huge office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> and spent
 	
 	
 		uh-huh yeah that exactly
 	
 	
 		very large amounts of money and then could simply simply could not rent them out they couldn't even rent them out for expenses it was cheaper to keep them empty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah the
 	
 	
 		than to rent them at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> percent occupancy
 	
 	
 		yeah and and that's nothing more than speculation i mean they they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it it seems that there should have been something in the regulations saying they couldn't do that i know <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> can't do it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh back when i used to play the commodities market i i tried to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> to get a loan to buy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">silver</ENAMEX> futures and they wouldn't let me
 	
 	
 		well i mean just for me to mortgage my
 		to to get a mortgage on my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> i mean they invest investigated me personally to the point where i was insulted and i was putting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand dollars</NUMEX> down on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and sixty thousand</NUMEX> dollar house
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i mean i would have thought gosh we're happy to do it just sign here you know but
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		i mean they had <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand dollars</NUMEX> in equity and i mean they just wanted to see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> of income tax returns and all that bullshit which really sort of disturbed me
 	
 	
 		and the and
 		and then it
 		yeah
 		yeah and then and then some some rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">yo-yo</ENAMEX> walks in there who's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buddies</ENAMEX> with the bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> saying look i want to borrow
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven hundred thousand</NUMEX> dollars so i can invest in this oil well they say oh sure no problem you're a good customer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah i i uh i run i run a little business on the side out of my home and i tried to uh get set up with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you would think i was asking for an appointment with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> you know and basically what it came down to is they weren't going to let me have it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		um
 	
 	
 		um they frown on home business they uh they they insist that you have a storefront
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and that's just ludicrous i mean i mean the way things are going <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are more and more working out of their homes i know a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who do <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers doctors</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects consultants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they they work in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> there's no reason for them to have an office they they have very little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer contact</ENAMEX> and when they do they go to the customer
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i mean  you know what's the story on them you know are you going to let them have it well of course they're going to get it you know all you've got to do is have a nice big bank account balance and they'll give it to you
 	
 	
 		yeah i uh i also run a little business out of my home on the side what's the nature of yours
 	
 	
 		uh mail order primarily
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		me and my uh me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roomie</ENAMEX> who's also my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> um
 		well we lump everything under this business i mean we do just about everything he's into the computer end of things he does consulting and graphics design and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh systems design i mean you name it he does that and then i handle the mail order and whatever else we do we do <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> breeding  i mean yeah it's all lumped under the business
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX> breeding huh uh
 	
 	
 		um yeah  make a few bucks here and there on that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but um we're we're there's several ways of getting set up to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MasterCard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> uh there's several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> out there the smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> who are trying to break into the market
 		and they will take the risk on a home business um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there's i made i made a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">contacts</ENAMEX> through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CompuServe</ENAMEX> um talking about you know hey we're <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> for these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> you know it you don't pay us anything the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> pays us and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of course what you're dealing with is some somewhat higher costs
 		like a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and fifty dollar nonrefundable application fee
 	
 	
 		right
 		uh wow
 	
 	
 		so if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> turns you down well that's it you're out <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and fifty bucks
 	
 	
 		that's not too great
 	
 	
 		no i i'm i'm i'm leery of it i know that's the way it works um
 		but and as long as you can meet their requirements there there's very little chance they'll turn you down and they do have some requirements like you have to be registered with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> and you have to have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		a business address and you have to have a business phone line and then you have to have a separate line for their equipment that kind of stuff uh but if meet all those chances are they'll approve you so we're looking at that
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so we're looking at that it's just it's just hard to give somebody <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> and fifty bucks on a chance you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i would i would find that uh a little bit disarming
 	
 	
 		yeah what what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> do you do
 	
 	
 		it's a computer business
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah my uh my roomie is down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> right now he's got an internship down at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> has sort of come to a standstill
 	
 	
 		i see where does does he go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		yeah he's at uh he's at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NC State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see okay what's what's his name i might know him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Floro</ENAMEX> Chrisostimo
 	
 	
 		uh-huh okay i guess i don't
 	
 	
 		do you by are you by any chance out at the campus
 	
 	
 		uh no huh-uh
 	
 	
 		oh okay because the last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i talked to was out on the campus
 	
 	
 		i see ha
 	
 	
 		it was how did how did you get involved in this
 	
 	
 		um i've got a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who's in the business who just gave me this application
 	
 	
 		yeah he he picked this thing up from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and brought it home and i said yeah sure i'll do it why not
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and he signed up for it and then of course he moved off to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Charlotte</ENAMEX> so now i'm stuck making his calls too
 		
  
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		
 
 		gosh i don't know what i got roped into
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ha</ENAMEX>
 		so uh oh well whatever it's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> bucks a shot what the heck
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah what the heck i'm surely not going to count this as business income
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah um really well speaking of that i think we've probably given them their money's worth
 	
 	
 		oh yeah no doubt about it i i usually go until the the recording comes on
 	
 	
 		oh i see i've never gone that long that's
 	
 	
 		have you yeah that it it'll cut you in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about ten minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		uh they used to it used to say you have exceeded the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minute</TIMEX> recording limit but now they just say uh we're sorry our recording capacity is limited <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> you know a nicer way of saying you talked too long
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but anyway if you need to get going we'll we'll terminate
 		okay
 		well good talking to you
 		maybe we'll maybe we'll chat again
 	
 	
 		all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		all right later on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	