
 
     		
 	
 		well do you like to do your yard work
 	
 	
 		yeah this is actually a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">duplex</ENAMEX> that we're in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">so</TIMEX> and it's rented
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we're looking into buying a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> but um the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> is supposed to do the yard work although he doesn't do it any frequency every once in a while he comes around so in the meantime we have our own lawn mower and we probably do it a little more than him
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but we don't do a whole lot since it's a rental property we've added a few things like around the patio and i've tried to get a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">shrubs</ENAMEX> to grow around here but
 		since it's you know rental we haven't spent a whole lot of time and effort in trying to do landscaping we just kind of maintain what's here and mow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grass</ENAMEX> and trim and that kind of stuff when it's needed
 	
 	
 		oh great what kind of lawn do you have
 	
 	
 		you mean the type of grass um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what kind of a grass we have  oh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Augustine</ENAMEX> yeah it's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> in the back it's the kind that has those you know grows sideways yeah that stuff
 	
 	
 		oh
 		it grows in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX> right right
 		i just love that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the middle of the summer</TIMEX> when that gets real thick that's so nice to walk on isn't it
 	
 	
 		well the problem has been in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter</TIMEX> of um
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two winters</TIMEX> ago
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight nine</NUMEX> yeah a lot of it got zapped and it's it's slow coming back like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> didn't really replant any <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> a lot of front lawn look looks pretty bad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and he didn't redo anything so it's it's coming back a little bit now this year
 	
 	
 		well you know you know mine did and it was late at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this time last year</TIMEX> i held out no hope for it but i watered and fertilized the hell out of it and i by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> it was as strong and thick as it had ever been
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and uh and of course <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> it never really died out that much i mean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> here it is only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> and it's looking good yeah we had we had a mild <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> we you know everybody in my neighborhood hires their yard work done and i think i think the fun of owning a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is doing the yard work
 	
 	
 		it was very mild mild <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		and i mean i thought so i've owned a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">um twenty five of the</TIMEX> of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX> that i've been here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> and i just enjoy it so much and uh and and particularly the lawn i love it dark i love to see it get a deep dark green
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i love to uh i i love to mow it i don't like weeding the flower beds around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>'s supposed to do that but pretty every once and a while they get ahead of him  so i end up doing that for him and and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> sometimes takes care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and so between us we got all our own little things to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and we got we got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> off in college they don't do anything but uh i uh and i love to be out in the summertime i love to be out when the sun is really nice and hot and just go out there and sweat a bit mowing the lawn
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i just love it in fact i uh mow my lawn but there's a gigantic vacant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX> in back of us uh that belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland College</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and everybody that we have that backs up to it mows about uh oh maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">fifteen or twenty yards</NUMEX> into the vacant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">weeds</ENAMEX> from growing and coming over and seeding in your yard
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so so we all even get more uh get more lawn to mow that way but uh it's fun
 	
 	
 		do you back up to it on the south side or the east side
 	
 	
 		uh i am on the east side of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland</ENAMEX> in fact so <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland's</ENAMEX> on my west side when i look out my back door to see the sun set i look across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">field</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		because we had one of our uh a person similar similar stature to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gahouli</ENAMEX> from the legal department <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel</ENAMEX> Sharp he lives around in that area too he lives on Whiteman Place i think
 	
 	
 		okay i i live on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Wharton Drive</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wharton</ENAMEX> intersects uh uh it dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ends</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">into Chimney Hill</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah okay
 	
 	
 		and then it it dead ends just dead ends up here where i live  it runs uh it runs north and south from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Chimney Hill</ENAMEX> north
 	
 	
 		okay
 		um
 	
 	
 		uh anyway i love to do that and the other thing that i love is that i am a distance runner by hobby
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and some <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> i'll come home from work like i did <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> and with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> in the forecast and the lawn was getting pretty high i said i got to mow the lawn but i want to go out and run now which do i do first
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i'm sitting around thinking well if i go out and run now because i messed around until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost seven uh six thirty or so</TIMEX> if i go out and run now
 		i'm going to get back and i'm going to be mowing the lawn and it's going to get dark and i'm going to have to guess where where the line is to mow
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so if i mow now then i'll go out and run afterwards and what the mowing does it limbers you up
 		so that you go out and have a good run i finished up right at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about dark</TIMEX> and then i went out and ran <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four and a half</NUMEX> miles and it was great just because the mowing it i i don't i didn't i don't have to do any stretching before running if i've been pushing the lawn mower around for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour and ten minutes</TIMEX> or so
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so that's just you know i just i i i just really enjoy it and i hate to here see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> gripe and moan about doing uh yard work what about <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> do you have any <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> around
 	
 	
 		we got a couple of big trees out front um i guess right along our street there used to be one of the um lines i guess there was fields here many <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years ago</TIMEX> cotton fields or something and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		you bet and i remember that
 	
 	
 		yeah well we have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> that that go across our front <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yards</ENAMEX> that are very old that must have been like where the line was in between the fields so we have couple of huge <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> out front that's pretty nice no trees really in the back
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		where the fence was or something yeah yeah
 		how how how long have you live there <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> oh okay
 	
 	
 		no not yet we've only been married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay okay because you've got a a excellent elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> over there uh our middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> went over there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one year</TIMEX> while ours was being built here and uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Richland Park</ENAMEX> is just a super neat school
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and they got a lot of neat programs the uh uh how often do you when when the when the uh growing season's good how often do you have to mow your lawn
 	
 	
 		uh nearly every week
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i got i got so carried away with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> and fertilizer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June July</TIMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> i was mowing every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four days</TIMEX>  and i talked to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> i'm from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX> originally
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i talked to my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> on the phone i said you know we <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texans</ENAMEX> are a funny breed we we water we water we spend
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">dollars</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> during the dry part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July August</TIMEX> watering our lawn we go out and spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollars</NUMEX> a whack on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fertilizer</ENAMEX> and then we bitch and gripe about having to mow it so often
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we said because we <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Massachusetters</ENAMEX> weren't like that we never did anything to it except mow it and and it always looked nice
 	
 	
 		yeah that's right we never did this watering stuff everybody waters
 	
 	
 		yeah we didn't do all that stuff here but they get more natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> than we do you know we get so much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> and then we go sometimes entire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June July</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> without any so i guess we're where are you from originally
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Philadelphia</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		oh okay so you've been in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> how long
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well you're you're almost a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> i've been here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's a long time
 	
 	
 		yeah <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty two years</TIMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> so of course naturally my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> but they still think i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankee</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and i was never called that until i came here
 	
 	
 		yeah isn't that funny i wasn't either i have uh
 	
 	
 		and i i was just taken aback by that
 	
 	
 		yeah when i got here my uh uh best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who was my office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> when i <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got here in nineteen fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> said the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> he could ever stand wore pinstripes suits and played baseball
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> weren't as mobile then as they are now i mean i will bet <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> of your neighborhood or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three quarters</TIMEX> of it and i know it's true with ours is not from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is not even from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i keep reminding these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that it's good thing we came down here and got some changes made like
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		shopping on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> i said it's a little hard to do everything on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> no pass no play uh kind of thing i said you know we had that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah huh
 		
 
 		yeah
 		uh i yeah that's true that's true we did we did and uh do you all do you all uh do you all have to water a lot over there
 	
 	
 		uh pretty much and our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">landlord</ENAMEX> always asks us to uh continue doing that even though we pay for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> because of you know foundation problems around here
 	
 	
 		oh yeah because of the foundation problem you know that's an interesting thing i've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> overseas assignments with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI uh i</ENAMEX> was in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> eighty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one eighty two eighty three and eighty four</NUMEX> and i was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> eighty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five eighty six</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> and i had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one kept the inside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> nice this is a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> story <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> and uh uh they only lived in the downstairs because he was divorced and had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and they only visited him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one weekend</TIMEX> a month
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		um
 	
 	
 		and that was the only time the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> was so the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">upstairs</ENAMEX> looked as new as we left uh they only lived downstairs uh and and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">interior decorator</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was just kept
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		very nice you know i've i've heard horror stories from other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">TIers</ENAMEX> that have had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tenants</ENAMEX> but he didn't like yard work and what happened was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Augustine</ENAMEX> grew up you know if you don't watch it and keep it trimmed back it will totally take over your flower beds
 	
 	
 		um
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		well when we came back what used to be our flower beds were solid <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Augustine</ENAMEX>  we had to we had to dig it out  and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> when we went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philippines</ENAMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> he had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> little girls
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so they lived throughout the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> he also had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> that i didn't know about and so our carpeting was in bad shape when i got back but uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard</ENAMEX> was immaculate he did a great job on the yard so you so i guess you can't have everything
 	
 	
 		um
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but but you're right and i guess that's very important because of this black <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">earth</ENAMEX> with have here that cracks terribly uh and it shifts badly in the summertime that uh if you don't water around the foundation you're going to lose it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> i'll tell you you've really got to have a conscientious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tenant</ENAMEX> and it's hard for him to be conscientious when he's thinking of paying a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">hundred dollar</NUMEX> water bill uh every uh uh i you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every month</TIMEX> when you get into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June July</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> time period
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and how how big is your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">duplex</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um each side has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">baths</ENAMEX> living room and then a big uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> that has uh dining <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> in it
 	
 	
 		oh okay they're they're fairly big
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		so each side is like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">seventeen hundred square feet</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah well where uh where did you go to school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Ohio State</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh you went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ohio State</ENAMEX> oh you're uh up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Hays</ENAMEX> country huh
 	
 	
 		right and i was i was going to school in his prime back when we had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie Griffin</ENAMEX> and we were winning all the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Heisman</ENAMEX> trophies and going to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Rose Bowl</ENAMEX> that was when i was going to school there
 	
 	
 		uh yeah yeah yeah
 		yeah we were really excited about the we're
 		
 		
 	