
 
     		
 	
 		i like everything but jazz
 	
 	
 		you like everything but jazz what don't you like about jazz
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i just don't the the beat the tempo the whatever it is that makes it jazz just grates on my nerves i just
 	
 	
 		so do you like do you like rhythm and blues
 	
 	
 		yes i like rhythm and blues and i like country western and i like yeah Waylon
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i like country western it's my favorite
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie Willie Waylon</ENAMEX> and the boys
 	
 	
 		in fact we bought uh The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> uh on a cassette tape i think The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX>'s even the name of the tape  before it became the the song of the war
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so yes
 	
 	
 		do you like um any rock and roll at all
 	
 	
 		i like some uh art course we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> who loves hard rock and i'm not
 	
 	
 		right i can't stand that
 	
 	
 		no i'm not that much on hard rock but he does have a lot of cassettes of uh CDs that i like the i guess you'd have to call it soft rock i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Stewart</ENAMEX> and and some of the things he does
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in fact uh when our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> was stolen of a little over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Stewart</ENAMEX> tape in there that i was thinking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> that i ought to replace because i really kind of miss that music but
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah some of my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and uh
 		oh some of the i guess what what you could call softer rock <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> they were the bigger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> in the seventies and  till all the heavy metal and all that came in and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's too much isn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't care for that at all
 	
 	
 		it's it's so loud and the so many of the lyrics are so offensive and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		gosh we don't need that
 	
 	
 		no i got away from all that rock and roll stuff probably <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX> and just started listening to the country
 	
 	
 		when you matured  i like some classical to and
 	
 	
 		yeah  i guess so
 		i like some classical some of that stuff grates on my nerves too like you were saying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> about the other i just stir up but there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> that are really pretty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		um-hum i think we hear more crap classical music than we think we do because of how much of it's used in commercials
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">right</TIMEX> commercials and cartoons and things like that
 	
 	
 		um-hum they slipped that in on us when we're not looking
 	
 	
 		uh-huh  try to give it to us subliminally
 	
 	
 		that's cheating isn't it  well i think we like the same kind of music  nice chatting with you
 	
 	
 		
 
 		that's right
 		i think so
 		same here
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	