
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay what uh go ahead and tell me about your home
 	
 	
 		well my my home at the moment is an apartment
 	
 	
 		oh is that right
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		i work here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germantown</ENAMEX> but i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola Florida</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh that's interesting
 	
 	
 		so i own a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX>
 		and uh let's see we are to compare homes correct
 	
 	
 		okay yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is well is typical for the area i live in a development uh it's a relatively i would say
 		oh well God it sounds like  sounds like i'm bragging
 	
 	
 		no that's okay
 	
 	
 		no it's upper middle class uh kind of an environment it's a
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		two
 		story
 		colonial which my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i designed
 	
 	
 		oh that's neat
 	
 	
 		uh it has <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around thirty two hundred square feet</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow that's large
 	
 	
 		
 
 		uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> and so forth and so on
 		and it is i would imagine in terms of
 		of size and so forth it's relatively typical for the area it might be
 		i would say it's probably midsized for the area there are some smaller and there are several you know several larger
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		but in
 		based you know in terms of you know in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX> in that area of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>
 		it uh
 		it's what now it is uh
 		probably
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh well that's not too bad that's still fairly new
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and so it's
 		in terms of cost and and and size and so forth it uh
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> you know housing there is extremely affordable and uh compared to other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> you know let's say compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 		that same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> here would probably cost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three quarters</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a million dollars</NUMEX> but
 	
 	
 		well
 		oh you're kidding
 		well do you mind if i ask what it's worth down there i mean what it's
 	
 	
 		i really haven't i really haven't uh
 		when we built it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>
 		it was it ran around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so i i would have really i haven't really priced you know in the market so i
 	
 	
 		huh
 		it it sounds like i mean from the way you described it a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> like that here would be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least two hundred and fifty thousand</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is a very marked up area although right now it's a lot lower  um because of all the layoffs and everything the economy around here is real poor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i thought that was on the upswing again now
 	
 	
 		well no not really
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> itself uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth Dallas</ENAMEX> area um has
 		become become kind of depressed because there's been so many layoffs with big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX>  um there's been tremendous amounts of of uh layoffs
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so really housing is real bad the economy itself around here is not too terribly bad but housing is still real bad
 	
 	
 		um-hum well <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX> has
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's really is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>'s market there now and it isn't because of the well there is been a lot of speculative building
 	
 	
 		yeah this is
 		oh
 	
 	
 		uh i don't know perhaps not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> but uh i'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in uh you know in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX> and so forth would be knowledgeable about it uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and home porting was a possibility <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		they were expecting an influx of
 		something on the order of fifty <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or more from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>  a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX> was coming in and uh
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		the uh attendant uh support vessels well that's no longer
 	
 	
 		so do you think it was overdeveloped then
 	
 	
 		the case
 		oh it's it is i mean the the number of single family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">units</ENAMEX> on sale
 		is phenomenal compared to the population
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and so uh overbuilding is it it has been a real problem there
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		so you can still get a get a a good good <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for a very very reasonable price and i mean good i would let's say typical
 		say three <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half baths</TIMEX>
 		on <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a half acre</NUMEX> or so of land uh
 		reasonable construction would probably run you uh
 		right now anywhere between
 		somewhere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between a hundred and a hundred</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		um  yeah that's
 	
 	
 		and probably perhaps cheaper depending upon the neighborhood so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what about your home
 	
 	
 		that's well  right now we're just renting but  it is a home um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom home</ENAMEX> it has about i guess <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eighteen hundred square feet</NUMEX> it's on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> floor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh we have no basement  i don't know if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pensacopla</ENAMEX> okay  i wasn't sure most of the ones you know know up north and everything do but  um anyway
 	
 	
 		no nor nor do we but
 		
 
 		um
 	
 	
 		it's uh it's pretty also pretty typical for the area most of this area was developed uh this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> was built in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seventy four</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so most of the it's almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years old</TIMEX> and most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> around here were built pretty much the same style uh we have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that lives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> blocks over and his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> is almost identical to us except his is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> and ours is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but otherwise the layout is pretty much the same so i i think most of them are
 		there was it like most areas that are built um there were probably like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two or three</NUMEX> styles you could choose from
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and and uh that's pretty much all the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> in the area
 		uh for probably
 		<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a square mile</NUMEX> i'd say at least maybe even a little bit more than that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">w</ENAMEX> ell the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">housing</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> is just atrocious and in in the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> area i'm i'm only about uh
 		<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">twelve miles</NUMEX> or so from the
 		uh border of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX>
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery County Maryland</ENAMEX> is probably one of the most expensive
 	
 	
 		where are you in relation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sevren</ENAMEX> are you close to Sevren
 	
 	
 		places to
 		no we are west <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sevren</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX> near the Eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shore</ENAMEX> if i had
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 		well i just my i have a sister that used to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sevren</ENAMEX> and they bought their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in i i want to say like around
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nineteen seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or something like that and they paid like they they had it built from you know they they designed it and everything
 		and to have it built they only paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty thousand</NUMEX> for it and when they left the area they sold it for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred and twenty thousand</NUMEX> so i
 	
 	
 		oh that's not unusual yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah so i just wondered you know if the whole area was like that or
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well that's that area over there is not as expensive as in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the immediate</TIMEX> you know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> area
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so we uh
 		i was just looking for example there is a uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominium complex</ENAMEX> next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment complex</ENAMEX> where i live and i was over there recently looking at the possibility of buying a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom condominium</ENAMEX>
 		and
 		ninety <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two thousand dollars</NUMEX>
 		for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> which is essentially a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX> apartment
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		now it was very nicely done
 	
 	
 		yeah sounds like a lot of money though
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes i i can't i can't envision spending that much money uh and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		for
 	
 	
 		on on something along those lines so you know it's you i guess you pay the piper but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		plus the the the phenomenal taxes around here are phenomenally high uh
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh for the</ENAMEX> and so you on that it's not unusual for example for somewhere around here on a on an on a
 		what we would you know what you described as your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and what i would describe as my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> say for example in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pensacola Florida</ENAMEX> on that house
 		with the homestead exemption and so forth and so on
 		might pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four hundred dollars</NUMEX> a year taxes maybe maybe you know maybe a little bit higher than that now
 	
 	
 		wow yeah
 		that's
 	
 	
 		but that same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> here you'd pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">almost six thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year taxes on it
 	
 	
 		wow  wow that's pretty
 	
 	
 		
 
 		so it's uh
 		so the question of whether to buy here or move to another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">county</ENAMEX> say drive
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more miles</NUMEX> north buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">condominium</ENAMEX> for approximately uh the same price maybe a little lower
 		but the taxes would be you know
 		perhaps maybe <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one third</NUMEX> uh of
 	
 	
 		really
 		that much of a difference uh wow
 	
 	
 		oh absolutely
 		you know so
 	
 	
 		that's
 	
 	
 		it's it's really sad
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		this is one this is one of the most highly taxed areas in the country
 	
 	
 		wow why is that do you know i mean
 	
 	
 		well they it uh
 		the their they do have an extremely good such things as extremely good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> for example it has one of the best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school systems</ENAMEX> in the country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and because the cost of living around here is so high public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> make great salaries around here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh
 		well
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i was reading just recently where the typical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery County</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Schools</ENAMEX> makes
 		and and and i'm not this is uh the figure he makes eighty <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year
 	
 	
 		my goodness  wow
 	
 	
 		that's and i by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> i i think i mean i they didn't they did not define it but for example a curriculum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisor</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> or
 		someone you know in that uh in that range
 		
 		
 	