
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		all right
 	
 	
 		um
 		there was a crime here in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKinney</ENAMEX> uh a rather heinous murder there was no um remorse shown by uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> and yet for whatever reason um his crime was not considered a capital crime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		an and quite honestly i i feel very strongly that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> has the has no redeeming social values and if if and when he comes gets free again
 		he will have no compunction but to complete that that same kind of
 		lifestyle i mean continue that same kind of lifestyle and perhaps do the same thing again so it really bothers me that there's not a way of getting him out of the way forever
 	
 	
 		really i think that i don't know i don't i don't think our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison system</ENAMEX> isn't set up where we um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		rehabilitate or you know restore anybody i think it'll only make them worse but i i believe that God can come in and change a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s heart
 		and genuinely change it but that doesn't negate that you do reap what you sow and if you do kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> and it is
 		you know you're found to be guilty i believe God establishes the authority of our court system and i believe that you know that i do believe that capital punishment is uh
 		alternative even you know God can still change your heart but that doesn't mean like the alcoholic that charges up all the
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> on the credit card or the shopaholic you know you get your life right with God but you still have to pay your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Visa</ENAMEX> bill you still have to
 	
 	
 		that's that's right
 	
 	
 		you know so but God sent us his grace and they give pardons but i believe if it's a genuine conversion there's a genuine and those prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know they know a genuine
 		turnaround in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> they see that and i i worked in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fort Worth</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but yeah
 		did you
 	
 	
 		yeah i have a degree in social work you see it you know the ones that have a genuine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> change it is obvious and they know that they're they're not going to pardon someone from the governor
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know what i'm saying they're not going to go without going through every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX> of authority in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> so i feel like you know that's is there is occasions where there are they do spare lives and you know i leave that with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> who
 		of course is going to go through every <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> because they want to be be reelected so
 	
 	
 		yes but my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of all that not all all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">persons</ENAMEX> who i think should be receiving capital
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh whatever capital uh that uh that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum punishment thank you i'm sorry i just got home from work and i'm just kind of spaced out a little bit uh that not all of them are being um
 	
 	
 		punishment uh-huh
 		no that's okay
 	
 	
 		convicted of it that that the the they're not even being charged with that appropriate i agree with you that that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s heart can be changed
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but the same God that can work that miracle also established the laws that said um for certain kinds of sin certain kinds of
 		sins certain kinds of of uh breaking of the law there would be a capital
 		punishment right then it was it was uh
 		almost immediate as soon as as the trial was over then it was stoning we don't have a speedy trial we don't have speedy um punishment and so it kind of loses its meaning if you sit on death row for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and years
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right but in in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old Testament</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and so forth
 	
 	
 		right
 		we don't well yeah we definitely have lost the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Judeo-Christian</ENAMEX> ethic of the judicial system for sure but the base the base is still there the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX> is still there though
 		but of the system but i know what you're saying uh but also they're under a law because we haven't been removed from the law we've just been taken out from under under a law because under the law if your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> mocked back talked you he would be stoned
 	
 	
 		that's correct
 	
 	
 		yeah under the law he would be stoned so we've been removed from the law of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">under</NUMEX> from being under the law but we're still you know we're still accountable to it we don't need to back talk but
 		you know it's like God changes your heart to not do that he changes your heart not to look upon a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> in lust because in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Old Testament</ENAMEX> they could look all they wanted just couldn't do it
 		but in the new he's looking at your heart and so i guess that's what what i mean by their character changes and you know what i mean it's like looking beyond what they're doing and looking at a heart and seeing what is the heart what's the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> showing me here and
 		those and then any of if i don't think see if i don't believe that there's not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> change and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> agree that this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> needs to be excused i believe for murder uh rape i even believe incest things
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that will permanently damage uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> i believe crimes against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> should be punished but by by death i believe
 	
 	
 		i tend to agree on that very strongly
 	
 	
 		sexual crimes unless there's a true change of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> and that's where we just have to to trust the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> and they're not going to excuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> if it was was run like that i don't there would probably be very few exceptions to
 		that and if it was done quickly and done swiftly and but it's not because the judicial system has rejected they've rejected the answer to all these problems they have pretty much
 	
 	
 		plus the all the judicial system is overloaded with all kinds of um problems and crimes and so forth and then all of the um civil things that clog the courts
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and having sat on both uh uh criminal and a civil uh jury  some of what goes through our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courts</ENAMEX> is a total waste of time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because we're suit happy but but back to the to the capital situation sounds like you and i have a lot of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of uh common ground at least as <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">as far as as</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		capital punishment is concerned i would like to see some some kind of reform or some kind of streamlining so that if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> is um convicted
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and sentenced to to death that that automatic appeal which goes in could be more quickly dealt with
 	
 	
 		uh-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		and and go ahead and get the punishment phase out of the way because it doesn't do the criminal or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> or or any of us the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayer</ENAMEX> any good to have him sitting around for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> and years
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		anybody yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		an an but him could be a her
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but you see
 	
 	
 		i know in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> uh it think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> i think it's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jamaica</ENAMEX> i know that they have you know crimes punishable by death and i'm sure they hit a few every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and then</TIMEX> and i wouldn't want to be one of them that are not guilty
 		but i know that they have like uh their crime rate it's not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jamaica</ENAMEX> i don't think i can't remember which it's uh one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean Islands</ENAMEX> and and they
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> is it like that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s going <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> and they don't have a lot of the crime because there is a law and the law is enforced and that's what what when you have lawlessness
 		i mean the law's not being enforced and all that does is lawlessness we were we went on a mission trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>
 		and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> and stuff <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> and all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were up on there getting arrested for crack and everyone was out uh we were across from
 		that big bus <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">station</ENAMEX> i forget what you call it but anyway and everyone they had like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fifteen people</ENAMEX> lined up on the fence and within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> there were fifteen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> sitting there doing the same thing
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and you'd see the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> who were back out there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		that's sad
 	
 	
 		because there's no the answer is not being given to them in the court system and i think initially when our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> was set up it was set up with God and it was really <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">an integral part</ENAMEX> and no you can't
 		you can't force <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are hurting and they're out doing crack sitting on the street they were the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i think mostly we would want to receive it if it was presented to see i don't know i guess i'm kind of frustrated that
 		you know we've gotten away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> basis that our court system was founded upon i mean it reeks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> just the whole thing the whole system and so i feel like if that was presented
 		more openly and not just relying upon and para <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> ministr y to come in and do it but that the system itself you know you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i feel like that might be better if it was run on a more scriptural basis which would include you know you know and expediting the penalties and just getting it over with
 	
 	
 		however certain uh very liberal minded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> who do not um subscribe to the same ethical system that you and i do such as the uh civil liberties <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> and so forth
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		will lobby against that and hold that out as long as they have breath which is most unfortunate because we all lose out when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go so far out to the extreme on either side
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because too too often they're can be extremism that that hurts from from any direction regardless of whatever whatever you're arguing or concerned about and
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		we all lose out
 	
 	
 		yeah i know you're right they would lobby that and and i see that and that's why you know i'm like
 		okay what's my role in this thing  you know what's my part because i don't think the system is going to get fixed i think it's crippled
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 		
 	