
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay
 	
 	
 		so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jan</ENAMEX> how do they recycle in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i the biggest uh way it's going right now uh lot most of the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		have got uh things set up so where you can bring in your uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and your cans and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and then they've just got different barrels
 		sitting out  i shouldn't say barrels like big <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Doors</ENAMEX> or whatever they're called Gondolas  um they've got them set outside and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		is it is it all voluntary
 	
 	
 		yes it's all voluntary now they do have some places where you can take
 		things and get cash but i think the lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't really want the cash you know they just want to uh help recycle which is what we do you know we
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		probably the only thing sometimes we'll take cash or the cans in and we let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get the money for that but uh for
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		there's a a lot of projects where the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> and things and that will collect your cans and it's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund raiser</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right right
 		yeah that's true but but that's really the the biggest thing around here is the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> participating you know but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i guess i you see i guess it depends on your landfill space
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know i we're in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> but my i from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> how are forced recycling
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		uh yeah all plastic they have all plastic has to go into a recycling bin all cans have to be recycled all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have to be recycled
 	
 	
 		oh wow
 	
 	
 		because they're um they're just running out of space and landfills uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania Ohio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> are some of the uh they're using their landfills up faster than they can get new ones
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so it's really uh it's uh really hard on them now up here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> though we're just just in a voluntary recycling stage right now so
 		uh so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i you know we save our bottles and we save our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and we save all of our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastic</ENAMEX> and all of our tin cans and just like you say we go to uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> area where they have it set up and we dump them off there
 	
 	
 		so it's all about you say it is all voluntary do they
 	
 	
 		yeah it's still voluntary
 		though i think i think we're supposed to have something impeme implemented by nineteen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety three</NUMEX> though
 	
 	
 		will it be mandatory
 	
 	
 		where some aspects will be mandatory um-hum
 	
 	
 		is it all um is there any place at all where you do get cash for this stuff or is it all
 	
 	
 		mostly just the cans
 	
 	
 		okay yeah that's
 	
 	
 		and i and most of the time like i said that's that's a sort of like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund raiser</ENAMEX> things that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> do or that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boy Scouts</ENAMEX> do or whatever
 	
 	
 		right
 		right yeah that's true that's true
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		um-hum cans are the only thing i think you really get money for
 	
 	
 		well they do have places around here where you can get money for your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> and stuff like that but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like i said are more concerned with you know right now you know the aspects of saving the earth  um
 	
 	
 		right um-hum
 		yeah and i think that's mostly well you know we even before as soon as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> said you know we're going to put up bins for recycling you know we automatically
 	
 	
 		um-hum right
 	
 	
 		started doing it it was it's one of those things you know and just going and taking the time to go and read the signs and the brochures on what they accept and how it should be separated you know that's
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i tell you it's kind of funny now at even even at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i don't do you work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		no hum-um
 	
 	
 		um at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> they're doing recycling i mean for a long time they didn't do this but now they're they're recycling cans and paper we have separate bins
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh separate wastebaskets  in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX> for paper
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and they i mean it's tremendous how much money they have saved and even saving all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and you know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's really i can't believe that you know because they've got it all posted all over the place how much they're saving and how well yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		how much how well they're doing yeah we do i um i i work in a uh speech interface <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> at a at a at a college
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and we do basically the same thing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> has lost asked all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colleges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and some of the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> you know if they would definitely recycle their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> paper
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the same thing you know every almost every college in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> is recycling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office paper</ENAMEX> but you know in the giant bins around and it's surprising how much
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you never realize because that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">janitor</ENAMEX> comes around and empties your garbage can every <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right yep so you don't think about it
 	
 	
 		you don't notice until you start leaving yeah they don't pick up your recycling until it's full and you just can't believe how much paper that you uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		i know
 	
 	
 		reams of paper come out of an office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> they just asked me to recycle
 	
 	
 		yep
 		yeah well you think about the waste even i mean you know cost wise and and you know like you saving saving <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> and stuff like that i mean it's just amazing you know the difference
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah so i think hopefully if you know i guess a lot of the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> did they advertise on television how successful they are
 	
 	
 		no i haven't seen anything uh but that doesn't mean that they don't i don't watch much TV but i haven't really seen anything advertised publicly
 	
 	
 		some
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean like i said they do a lot of internal advertising on that kind of stuff but i haven't seen anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">internal</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		see i don't see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> advertisements on TV anyway i think they advertise more um other places where they're not located
 	
 	
 		right yeah that would probably be true
 	
 	
 		you know so so i don't see a lot of advertisements for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah because i know that some of the large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">industries</ENAMEX> here will advertise on television you know they'll just come up and say you know they'll show you they'll to encourage to encourage recycling
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they'll say and here those of us at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalmarva Power</ENAMEX> which is our power <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> you know we now recycle forty <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">five percent</NUMEX> of our solid waste and they
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and uh we do this for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> they put those on so i so i think you know we're probably reaching a successful stage and and just with voluntary i think
 	
 	
 		right well even i mean in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> i mean they do things to try and recycle and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> um like if they see litter on the ground they pick it up and say oh look at that somebody is not saving the earth you know so i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i mean they're really trying to educate all ages you know and it's good to start the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> real young
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		yeah i think so too yeah
 	
 	
 		and stuff like that because i mean when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> they never did stuff like that i mean it's like nobody was concerned about it you know and it's like
 	
 	
 		right yeah we weren't concerned yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		you know it's like all of a sudden when there's noticeable things saying hey you know we're ruining the earth you know and now everybody is doing something about which is good
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but how come we weren't doing this say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years ago</TIMEX>  you know
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think really probably what hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s you know i know that here in the up in the uh
 		uh the the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX> area and also in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania Ohio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> the just run all of a sudden we're out of landfill
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then they're saying we we estimate this landfill will be over will be full in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> unless we cut back
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and even then you know we're really running out of space so i think that that became that all of a sudden really hit home that there's no longer landfill space in some of the more crowded states
 	
 	
 		well
 		yeah this is
 	
 	
 		so what you know and no no other state i'm sure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas</ENAMEX> probably still has some landfill space they're not going to voluntarily say hey ship your garbage here
 	
 	
 		right  yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		so you know realistically you know we had we really had to start we have to start recycling in some some uh geographic areas it's really tough
 	
 	
 		i think that it it really surprises me because of the cost savings i mean this is such a tremendous amount of cost savings i mean why
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't understand why nobody saw that before i mean even even not
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		even the aspects of not saving the earth i mean it's so cost you know
 	
 	
 		right yeah though well
 		well in some ways i guess it it doesn't become really cost savings until you have an industry around it you know because i know that like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well yeah
 	
 	
 		they require them to um put their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> for recycling but
 		the deinking process that they have to they use to take the ink out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> so it can be reused
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> is very expensive and also it waste it produces a a waste a um a liquid waste that they don't know what to do with yet
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh
 		i see okay
 	
 	
 		so even some aspects of recycling
 	
 	
 		is not real cost efficient oh okay okay oh i understand that though
 	
 	
 		still have cost yeah cost efficient yet yeah
 		so but others you know like tin cans and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plastics</ENAMEX> are are really uh efficient you know they uh they melt they melt on quickly and can be you know just because of the heating and things yeah and glass yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		and glass right um-hum
 	
 	
 		so yeah it really is surprising that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> haven't noticed it before
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true and even i i noticed that a lot of gas <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> are telling you to recycle your oil
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i mean that kind of surprises me  i mean you know because once <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> gets so you know thick and yucky you'd wonder how they could you know clean that up enough to use it again but they can
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i don't know how cost efficient that would be i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i don't know either that's i know that though i even all those petroleum products though are so terrible for your um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> table you know they really pollute quickly and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know one i was what reading some place that the brake fluid you put brake fluid normally comes in just small little pint containers
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> pint of brake fluid can contaminate so many <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gallons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> you know like <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hundreds of gallons</NUMEX> of water
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		so it's one of those things that they really um and you wonder you know with all these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> spills
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how how terrible that is yeah how terrible that is so we'll have to we'll have to keep our eyes on all that i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah i know
 		really i know i really i don't know i i think that i mean i think that they really are doing a good thing now and i hope it keeps it well i'm sure it'll keep up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i agree
 	
 	
 		you know i think it's really catching on you know i i think that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure if it i don't know i think it's a good idea to make it mandatory
 	
 	
 		i do too
 	
 	
 		um  because like we were asking some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that live in um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> are you saving your you know are you recycling and they said well we're not forced to do it yet so no
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know so i mean i don't know i think that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are forced if the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not forced to do it they may not you know i mean i don't know i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> still still still will but
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 		well you know if they're forced to do it becomes sort of a habit
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i know that it's really funny my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are forced to do it and they
 		
 		
 	