
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 		well what's your views on it
 	
 	
 		i think it's uh a good idea um i grew up uh my teenage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> were spent during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> graduating uh high school in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty eight</TIMEX>
 		um i remember when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> first came about and i thought it was a very good idea at the time i was one of those uh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> if you know what i mean and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right now i see a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who get out of school have no idea what they want to do
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and there's a lot of things out there that we could do uh for our own <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> let alone other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and i think that we've got the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> power to do it it's just uh we need
 	
 	
 		sure
 		sure
 	
 	
 		to channel it and focus it on some things that that need some fixing up um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		some examples are this uh some of the things like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX>'s been involved in uh a little program to you know fix up housing for people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there's a lot of housing ah i know in the area that i live in that's run down and beat up but it could be fixed up and used and it's just you know sitting there wasting away
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah we're not too far  behind i graduated in seventy one so i'm i'm same generation
 		i i'm it's going to be a short conversation because i agree with you i i think uh  i don't i don't even think it ought to be uh voluntary i think it ought to be mandatory
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to either either do military service or public service one of the two uh a lot of reasons for that not not just because i'm a i'm a hard ass or anything it's just that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like you say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are getting out of high school not knowing what in the heck they're going to do
 		and either the military or public service <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> can give them a lot of focus
 		and i think that it might stop us some problems later on i mean you know you these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will get their their heads on straight and and figure out what they want to do instead of hanging around <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street corners</ENAMEX> selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> or something
 		uh it's i think it would be good for them uh it helps mature them a little bit and helps them understand the world the way it really is
 	
 	
 		yeah i think a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> grow up with uh with uh preconceived notions like what the world's about
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		a lot of it has to do from too much TV
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know it's there's there's a heck of a lot of difference between you know the intake that you get from TV and and movies and what you hear in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and then what reality is
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh i remember uh i've i've worked since i was well i started delivering papers when i was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> and i had a real job when i was thirteen so i've you know worked most of my life but i remember when i got out of high school
 		all through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> was boy i can't wait to get out of high school i can't wait to get out of high school and i wanted to go to college and i had the grades to go to college and i got accepted to college but when i got out of high school i kind of said
 		you know what am i going to do now you know it's like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know when i actually started working full time and i i got married shortly after getting out of high school i uh thought i was smart ran away and got married
 		and uh i remember there was a time and within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first year</TIMEX> of marriage i said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> wouldn't i give to get be back in school
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and just have to do homework and and go work my part time job because life and the reality of working for a living and trying to make ends meet is just so overwhelming to someone
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if they aren't prepared for it
 	
 	
 		and and most of them aren't i mean you look you look at the number of marriages that are occurring right out i mean even in high school
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and you know you you wonder where are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> in all of this
 		you know why isn't somebody stepping in and and stop putting a stop to this
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in high school are just too young to be married they have they have no idea what the world is like they don't how tough it is out there to make a living
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah a
 	
 	
 		uh i mean i was in the same boat when i left high school i my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> wanted me to go straight to college and i didn't
 		you know i was ready i was ready i had wanderlust i wanted to get out and see some things
 		so i joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> and ended up staying there for thirteen years
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		um but i had lived in my own little bubble up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time</TIMEX> and and after traveling around the world a few times i realized that things ain't the way they seem
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i i did a lot of growing up there uh
 	
 	
 		yeah i think once once <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> get out and see how
 		other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really live and know how bad off some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> really are and how good they've got it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that's right
 	
 	
 		and what it takes to have that good life and if you're willing to work for it then they're probably be more inclined to work for it
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well you know it's just like you say there's so much stuff that needs to be done here in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and uh you know if if you could have a thought of something like uh
 		like a uh uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> sort of organization i mean this would be so useful just in uh for instance just helping old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh exactly
 	
 	
 		you know they you know they need help they don't have anybody to depend on and it would be nice to have somebody come over and cut their yard or paint their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> or do minor repairs or something like that
 		and
 	
 	
 		you know i've i've so i my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">their late sixties now</TIMEX> and um so many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that live around them are unable to do those things for themselves anymore
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and it's
 		it's really hard on them and the you know the thought that i i see the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> rats you know walking around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> nothing better to do than just walk around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mall</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all day long</TIMEX> when they could be doing something to help someone
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know you there's a uh a nice warm feeling i remember getting out of doing things like that when i was younger i mean i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Boy Scout</ENAMEX> and the whole bit and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s in the same position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late sixties</TIMEX> and and it got to the got to the point where i mean me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> both were were gone
 		and she couldn't maintain the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> without large expenditures of money you know it finally got to a point where she just had to sell it and move into an apartment
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		i i'm not i'm not saying that that wouldn't have happened anyway but it would have been nice if there had been somebody to come around and take care of the little things
 		you know like the like the yard work and little repairs and
 		painting and stuff like that
 	
 	
 		yeah i think there'd there'd be a you know a uh economic benefit for you know everyone concerned those doing the work and those receiving the the uh the services
 	
 	
 		oh yeah sure
 		sure i mean i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who would be giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> are going to get a lot more out of it than just money you know that i i remember when i was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> i used to do little little things for the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> around the neighborhood and uh i know how it made me feel
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know you so
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people people</ENAMEX> just don't help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> anymore they're they're out for themselves
 	
 	
 		yeah i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> covered that in his uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State of the Union</ENAMEX> address <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> when he said that you know it's time for
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> to start thinking about what they can do to help each other out instead of counting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to do everything
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's that's the that's the point we've gotten to you know every time somebody wants something they always turn to the government
 		and you the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s going to be limited i where are they going to get the money they're going to get it from us and we can do it a lot more efficiently than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> we don't need to add <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> layers of bureaucracy to a program
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		um the thing that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> works on uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Habitat For Humanity i</ENAMEX> was involved in that was uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomery</ENAMEX> before i came up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and u h it was it was a pretty neat little program we'd just go out and they would buy a plot of land and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX> and everybody else would donate their their time
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX> were at cost and we'd put up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and that was kind that was kind of neat
 		i uh in a way i think it's a little bit inefficient but but it's better than nothing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and and at least i had the opportunity of seeing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> move into decent housing
 		um course on the other hand i can start complaining very loudly about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on public assistance who are quite capable of doing something for themselves but just won't
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		because it's far more advantageous for them to sit there and just draw uh welfare money than it is to work
 		uh we did a uh a cost comparison in one of my courses
 		and we took all the benefits that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> that a a married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> would get under welfare and what they would be making at minimum wage and they came out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four thousand dollars</NUMEX> better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> by taking welfare
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so there's no incentive for them to do anything
 		far better for them to sit on their butts and draw the money
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah one of the things they tried to push through in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> and uh weren't very successful was that if you were an able bodied <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> on welfare
 	
 	
 		you had to do something
 	
 	
 		you had to do some work and
 	
 	
 		yeah and and and that's been tried that was tried in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> too and it got shot down
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't and i don't understand the reasoning for it i really don't it it seems perfectly logical that if somebody's going to take public money
 		then they should return something to the public i mean if nothing else go out along an interstate and pick up garbage
 	
 	
 		that's exactly what they were trying to get them to do
 	
 	
 		yeah what do they what do they do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> do they use highway <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> or do they use prisoners
 	
 	
 		um both
 	
 	
 		yeah that that's the way they did it in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah they use both
 	
 	
 		usually usually you'd see these big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain gangs</ENAMEX> out there  picking up trash
 	
 	
 		uh they have a they have another program in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> that's called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Adopt-A-Highway</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh uh</ENAMEX>-huh yeah we have that here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	