
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		there we go
 	
 	
 		all right
 	
 	
 		well actually i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> from way back um
 	
 	
 		oh  how way back i mean
 	
 	
 		like um late <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifties early sixties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wally Moon</ENAMEX> moon shots and all that
 	
 	
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		yeah uh coliseum <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wally Moon</ENAMEX> and all that okay yeah it's uh um
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		i i'm i'm living in  <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just</NUMEX> west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> and uh  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX> um which is also just west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> has a minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and uh
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wally Moon</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of them  yeah so he's still kicking around
 	
 	
 		is that right
 		that's interesting
 		yeah i i also lived uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX> before going to uh going away to college
 		and i used to go watch the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Toledo Mud Hens</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i saw them i went i i was out there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> i saw saw a game <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ned Skeldon</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		is that the stadium
 	
 	
 		uh i couldn't tell you for sure it's been a long time
 	
 	
 		oh okay so um it used to be a uh race track
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah um it was that was impression i got when i was there so i almost okay
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah so had a lot of fun actually i mean i like minor league <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> a lot it it's cheaper  for one thing
 	
 	
 		yep
 		well that's that's true uh i've become i've kind of become a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> over the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> since i've been here
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh they've led the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> in batting fielding and pitching but they've never been able to do more than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those in any any given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		and i uh
 		think they're in in for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">odd year this year</TIMEX> actually um
 		they um
 		i i don't understand why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Incaviglia</ENAMEX> got released
 	
 	
 		i don't either i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty twenty five</TIMEX> home runs maybe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> eighty some RBIs
 	
 	
 		i mean he you know he can't field and you know he strikes out a lot but i mean he's done that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> why get rid of him now
 	
 	
 		really i mean he really has become a a very decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fielder</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh he has okay i hadn't
 	
 	
 		yeah he he's he's not a the liability that he was that he used to be
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		oh he fits right in with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i mean with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> you know bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> that hit home runs and strike out a lot
 	
 	
 		yeah of course you know get a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecil Fielder</ENAMEX> uh you know if if he strikes out a lot so what
 	
 	
 		yeah well is that i mean with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> i mean they can get away with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> like that i mean if i if i were like if i were running <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX> i would start building the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fielder</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		but that doesn't mean get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> who hit all they can do is hit home runs and strike out you know which they did  so
 	
 	
 		right
 		yep
 		well i think the key for for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orel Hershiser</ENAMEX> can come back
 	
 	
 		i think their pitching's deep enough that it doesn't matter um
 	
 	
 		it may be
 	
 	
 		i uh i like them a lot i i think they're going to go all the way um
 		and and i i mean by saying i like them i like their chances i i actually don't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> i'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>  from from way back
 	
 	
 		right right well picking up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darrell Strawberry</ENAMEX> didn't hurt
 	
 	
 		no  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brett Butler</ENAMEX> didn't hurt either um and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Ojeda</ENAMEX> didn't hurt and  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Ojeda</ENAMEX> they got him from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hubie Brooks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh who was the last one
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		um he's uh he's pretty decent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> he's
 	
 	
 		yes he is
 	
 	
 		um okay you know who he is then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX>  and uh that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> Offerman the short stop is gonna be good
 	
 	
 		yep
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		well it should be an interesting year
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm looking i've  i've already been to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> game and in fact i should have been to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> but
 	
 	
 		are you you are you an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> fan
 	
 	
 		um  the the team i live and die with actually is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> mostly die uh but um i i go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> since they're here and i you know i do enjoy them um i was out at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">opening day</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 		yeah
 		yeah you know i kind of wish that they had interleague play like they do in all the other sports so i could see some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> here once in a while
 	
 	
 		how far is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three hundred miles</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		ooh okay keep forgetting how big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> are out there sometimes
 	
 	
 		yeah it is it's it's incredible
 	
 	
 		yeah i um
 		yeah we're we're pretty lucky because if if i wanna see a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National League</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> i can usually go up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		there you go
 	
 	
 		and um you know saw you know saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cardinals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubs</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX> before
 	
 	
 		boy you are a baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> aren't you
 	
 	
 		oh  uh yeah
 	
 	
 		interesting
 	
 	
 		um i try to see whatever i can i mean i've been to like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX> games <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">each of the last few years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		yeah hoping they'll do it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> because um uh um having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> so it's like well  well so much for going to lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> games
 	
 	
 		all right
 		yeah so so uh do it while you can
 	
 	
 		yeah seriously
 	
 	
 		sure well it's been good talking with you sure enjoyed it
 	
 	
 		yep good talking with you and uh and uh you know you'll be happy i think in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodgers</ENAMEX> win
 	
 	
 		i wouldn't mind
 	
 	
 		yeah i'll be i'll be upset probably even though my prediction will be right
 	
 	
 		yeah well God bless and uh good talking with you
 	
 	
 		good talking with you take care bye
 	
 	
 		bye-bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	