
 
     		
 	
 		well there's been a lot of publicity lately about that new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> book out by uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kitty Kelly</ENAMEX> the unauthorized biography are you interested in that at all
 	
 	
 		not really i'm not much of a fan of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> so i i don't particularly read um biographies or autobiographies
 	
 	
 		no
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i haven't read too many i i'm more of a fiction and nonfiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> that not not of that nature though so
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i the reason why i was thinking about looking at it is because
 		it's supposed to i'm not a fan of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Reagan</ENAMEX> and so it's supposed to have a lot of unflattering things in it and i thought just purely for entertainment i might enjoy that but i i wouldn't want to go out and buy it like you know the hard back copy of it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i might check
 	
 	
 		if they if they had it i don't even know that i'd probably read it even if it was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX> though you know i i just you know i'm just not really interested in reading about other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives to that degree you know unless maybe they lived a long long time ago
 	
 	
 		really
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		for me it would be interesting to find out what life was that life you know in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that period</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		not not really interested no
 	
 	
 		in biographies well i uh i have read some biographies i prefer to read
 		if i read a biography it's
 		mostly because maybe i
 		have to uh you know back when i was in school i had to have information about that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> or um preparing some kind of lesson and i need to have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		more information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but i i do like to read some biographies but that one just sounded like gossipy and i wouldn't want to sit down and just read it cover to cover but flip through just for just to get a good laugh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think the last biography that i read i'm not i think it was
 		was um on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lady Randolph Churchill Churchill</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and that was excellent
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		was it
 	
 	
 		uh yeah it was it's in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> parts i think the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one is called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jenny</ENAMEX> or something like that uh because that was her name and um i only got to read <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> part of it and i've been looking for
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> but didn't read the i read the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> where she was in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later years</TIMEX> and it was absolutely excellent and it was very descriptive of of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with money back then and uh affluents in in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> uh
 		uh that you know were associated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX> and all and it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it was really pretty fascinating and i  and that was actually <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's it's been a while since i've read any biographies
 	
 	
 		well
 	
 	
 		but i love to read i mean i'm constantly reading i read i like uh mysteries and i like
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> as far as improving myself uh i haven't read any lately but i was reading
 		classical works that i hadn't read before you know that you might have needed to read in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> but that i just didn't read for some reason or another another or that you know that you can only
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		read so many in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> that they make a requirement of and yet there are so many out there
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that uh
 		that you you know you never get a chance to read and so i said well i think it was because i read um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Tale</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cities</ENAMEX> and i just
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean that even when i read it now it still makes me cry the ending of it and i couldn't believe i i could not believe that it took me so long to read such a good book i'd read some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickens</ENAMEX> before but i hadn't read that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i i was like i thought to myself
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know what other things are out there that are that are classics you know that have withstood time and that are just excellent something's excellent about them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		whether it's the way they were written or whether it was the material they were written you know that was written about and um
 		so i started reading i had this like you know
 		i had a binge of  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> uh i was living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bermuda</ENAMEX> at the time with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> but my uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> sent me you know like booklet you know uh boxes full of different books
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and uh she just would get them real cheap and stuff and send them over but she she is quite familiar with
 		i guess because it seems like uh older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have much better
 		um
 		in their schooling they they got more of the classics than i did you know and she knows so much more of them than i do i wouldn't even know you know to go look for that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> or that book
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah so
 	
 	
 		well i like the classics too uh i think that there's a lot of
 		books out now that are kind of garbage  books and i well i don't prefer to read a lot of the things like you might find at uh
 		well like at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Target</ENAMEX> or a supermarket or something where they have a bunch of books out paperback type books usually i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm going to the book <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> for a particular reason um
 	
 	
 		uh-hum probably you read a book review or something some kind of review on it
 	
 	
 		yes
 		yes and and uh i buy some of the
 		not self-improvement books but uh
 		self-help books like we just bought a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> so i bought a couple of books about how to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> and what to look for you know and or how to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		repair this or repair that in your own home i bought that for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>  and or how to how to do something books you know for reference and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and those are really helpful i think in helping um well you know like some
 		what symptoms medical symptoms like when how do you know when to take your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> or not
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		type books which i have use as reference and have been real handy but purely just for enjoyment i
 		i had a major in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> and linguistics and so i have have a lot of
 		books in my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> that i can read from the classics
 		and i do enjoy those quite a bit and um so i tend to
 		for reading
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just day</TIMEX> to day uh you know i have a particular book i'm looking for or i just enjoy uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> magazine
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it's handy
 	
 	
 		well what i do is i usually have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> books at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time i have a classic which i have to work on basically you know what uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		just depending well some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> i can just you know basically drink in but others i really do have to work at them and then um whether you know they're a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um or if it's their style or or just understanding the material and then i
 		you know it some of those it's like i said it's like school you have to work at it but to me it's worthwhile in the end i feel good about it and i usually remember those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time later</TIMEX> and then i have the books that i read just
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		purely for enjoyment you know i mean just light reading that i particularly like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Francis</ENAMEX> books and just some of the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> that are uh for mysteries just you know just
 	
 	
 		light reading
 	
 	
 		uh purely for entertainment you know that's it i'm not really expecting to get anything out of it except to be momentarily pleased you know because i don't i can never remember the plots or anything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		later on those books
 	
 	
 		well i think that's good because you do have to use your mind and imagine up the circumstances and things it's not like
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh most television where you you know you just you can sit there and not even pay attention very much but still understand what was going on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh yeah that television it gives you everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's  basically mindless i mean all your you the only really thing you are having to use is connecting the things that they give you you know what you're hearing and your your sight uh your sight but they give you everything else
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's usually the television that we see nowadays seems like that it's
 		it it doesn't even have some of the underlying
 		uh
 		things to it you know that maybe the old movies and things had you know the underlying themes and stuff that maybe you had to kind of figure out or you know like with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hitchcock</ENAMEX> or something where you're you're you're expecting something or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i i don't know it just i don't really care much for TV at all i just i mean i sometimes get hooked into it
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but i really i really get mad at myself when i do because i realize i realize fully there's no really redeeming value for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T</ENAMEX> TV no
 	
 	
 		not too much
 		not too much well that's right well i think it is good to
 		to read books and and  because even if it's like you say it's light reading you are still getting some
 		mental exercise
 	
 	
 		yeah you're developing your imagination which
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know when you develop your imagination that can take you into a lot of other areas because you've developed uh your your your mind in in seeing things you know even if it's your own set way
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know it's you're you're taking words and developing a picture in your mind
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so i mean
 	
 	
 		that's good
 	
 	
 		and
 		it's it's excellent i i'm we haven't got <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> yet but i hope to
 		uh set an example for ours that you know that reading is can it can be your best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> basically i mean even if you haven't got a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">a</NUMEX> a human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> around you can pick pick up a book and and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		and be with somebody basically
 	
 	
 		uh-huh i think so well i guess i'd better close now so i can
 	
 	
 		oh it sounds like your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are doing stuff so are are you a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> i gathered you might be a teacher
 	
 	
 		uh
 		well i i was i'm home now full time but uh so yeah we're we think books are important around here well you have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good day</TIMEX> stay out of the rain okay bye-bye
 	
 	
 		oh okay uh-huh
 		yeah
 		okay okay you too take care bye bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	