
 
     		
 	
 		so how do you feel about our policy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh i'm all in favor of it yeah  No i uh i think we've been doing a pretty good job you know not uh
 		not taking advantage of our you know of the financial dependence that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> have on us you know uh i mean we could direct the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> even more than we have been i don't think we've been doing too bad
 	
 	
 		yeah well do you think that's do you think that's right
 		do you think we should direct the government
 	
 	
 		um
 		well i think that uh as a whole that the being that the drug problem the drug industry can uh bring so much money to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> i think that if it wasn't for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> Government matching that the government
 		the drug uh cartels or whatever would control most the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		just that uh money is power and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> that's uh his descendants his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">descendants</ENAMEX> are from um
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">uh Nicaragua</ENAMEX> and  uh very i mean it's like his mother his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> came over and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		he you know i just as far as feelings
 		uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that
 		their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> came from there and how they feel about you know our intervention and their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and stuff like that and he he was all for it because it's just like you say uh there's so many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there that that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that get the kind of control that's bad you know and that their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> can become so corrupt and it's like well uh you know i use to feel like
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well they they should work their way they you know they should should be able to work their self out of it or you know why why why intervene in another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s you know problems and things like that why why should we be the ones that have to do it and things like that
 		but
 		i think just a lot of times if we don't then then it will then that influence will affect our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> too for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
 		you know that it does help i mean you know i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> do want our help the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are you know under conditions that are you know not favorable to this their rights
 	
 	
 		right exactly yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		but uh
 	
 	
 		but
 		um i wish we didn't have to i mean i i'd rather even if a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> chooses a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that's not you know exactly the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that we have you know or or is in complete
 		opposition to it at least it's their choice as as long as long it's one that's
 		that that makes sense so to speak you know this is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> that stays in power that can stay in power but it seems like most of them don't
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know
 	
 	
 		well sometimes that's that's <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> doing that too you know we
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		we fall out of uh agreements with certain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> and then amazingly enough the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> starts turning against our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> you know  it's uh
 	
 	
 		so you think like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> influence and our money over there
 	
 	
 		that and uh that and yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> starts talking then about removing bases and and whatnot and stuff like that and people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		or or government aids and stuff
 	
 	
 		right
 		yeah i think that has a lot of things to did with uh um
 	
 	
 		well then how can you how can you say as far as like in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">um Europe</ENAMEX> as far as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the toppling</TIMEX> of those kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>
 		you know like
 	
 	
 		yeah that was uh i'm i'm really wondering whether that's going it settle down or not because
 	
 	
 		i mean
 	
 	
 		on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand you have you know that the you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Government</ENAMEX> of course mistreating a lot of the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Slovak</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and then on the other hand you have
 		well they they were feeding us  you know so uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know really what's going to happen
 	
 	
 		but we don't we're not intervening in that or do you think that we are to the degree that we are causing
 	
 	
 		oh yeah i think we're getting quite a
 		put it this way i think no i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are revolting themselves and we're
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		allowing it to happen
 	
 	
 		see i i agree with that yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i i agree that that the communication uh that now that communication has become
 		so much more widespread and you know so worldwide that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are realizing hey we don't have it so good and let's stand up
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		for you know uh well that this is ridiculous we're living with these kind of conditions in a world that's advancing as fast as it is that uh i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are just saying no way we don't want any more of this
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i think uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX> has always been one of those places where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are more passive
 		you know where it's always the minority that are
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		are trying to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> better
 	
 	
 		yeah well i mean
 		i don't mean to well i guess i do in a way sometimes i think a religion has a lot to do with that i think that that uh because of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries countries</ENAMEX> a lot you know where such <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> influence and i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> religion itself
 		was was such a dominant factor as far as keeping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down
 		so to speak
 	
 	
 		i thought it was the other way around they were always having to meet in the catacombs and all this so all the persecution that they're sort of use to it it's been sort of like you know
 	
 	
 		but but see there but i don't agree with that because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> religion as far as through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the ages</TIMEX> has been the rule so to speak
 		you know they are the ones that set the rules set a lot of the rules and they are the ones that do keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> down i mean when you a religion that most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> and they don't understand when anything is being said yet they're
 		yet they're expected to bow down to it i think that keeps <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a sort of line you know
 	
 	
 		i don't quite understand that
 		do they even understand what's being said
 	
 	
 		well when when it use to be <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> i'm just saying saying that
 	
 	
 		oh yeah the old church
 	
 	
 		uh
 		the old church
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah which it's not that way now but i think that there is just that i think that it's just <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are slower in coming around
 	
 	
 		well they actually understood it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> where it was hard  <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is very very very close to <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um they still didn't understand it though i don't think
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because i i descend from that and i you know i don't can't i don't understand <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		and i'm of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> descent so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um
 		i i just think that has something to do with why <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latinos</ENAMEX> are tend to be
 		you know the meek the more meek you know they tend to be more
 		not stand up for their rights as much they're not really sure of what they are
 		i don't think
 	
 	
 		uh i never really thought of in that way
 	
 	
 		well i mean how can you contrast the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europeans</ENAMEX> and their vocalism on their rights to to say the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> i mean why are they
 		why are they not as vocal or why do they not you know stand up so to speak for their rights
 	
 	
 		i don't know could be the t he economic still You know the there's the poverty level is certainly uh you know much worse in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
 		i mean you can say that about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> too i think it has something to do with the poverty level because <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> is certainly not a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> and yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and yet you know they have the same problem where you know where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">kings</ENAMEX> and such
 	
 	
 		um i don't agree with that i don't agree because i think that they are pretty vocal about it
 		in in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
 		i think the y've made a lot more changes
 		hey they've their very vocal
 	
 	
 		well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> yeah
 		well in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> yeah In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> i think they are but yet you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Idi Amin</ENAMEX> was you know in power for so long
 	
 	
 		well so what's the difference
 		yeah
 		so what makes the difference between say <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> and the rest of i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX> and it is rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh racial i think
 		or like you say maybe communication of knowing that hey up in other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">colonies</ENAMEX> or previous <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">English</ENAMEX> colonies everything is equal and yet down there it's not you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i think communication does have a lot to do with it
 		you know in education maybe i don't know about education because the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> is still not very educated down there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think it is communication it's just oopsy
 	
 	
 		i think it maybe has to do with a lot uh a lot to do with education because you look at the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
 		i think they are they do tend to be more educated much more educated than
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		than <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true You know that i don't know whether uh actually i i've always wondered whether how the education system works in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Republics</ENAMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		um-hum well i know that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> they're they're comparably more educated better educated than we are in our country
 	
 	
 		really that's good
 		in a way  You know uh something we compete with
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		and i've been sort of disappointed how that they they say literacy rate has gone down you know
 		that's sort of upsetting
 		to think that we're richer and yet everybody is intellectually poorer
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh in our country
 	
 	
 		in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that is really upsetting and and considering it's free you know
 		i mean good education is really still free
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's just it though good education
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		is it good education it may be free but is it good education and that's just it are we willing to pay for it you know
 	
 	
 		yeah uh-huh
 	
 	
 		i mean a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> bitch and moan about the taxes and all but are so are they willing to pay for you know
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		quality education you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you know and yet they yet <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> get very frightened when they see the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> moving in and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> moving in certain areas of technology you know that we use to dominate and it's like well you know
 		they're educating their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to higher degrees than we do so you're going to have to expect it so what you are you willing are you willing to compromise a little and and pay pay some take some of that money out of your pocket and pay for good quality education
 		so i don't know  but  i i
 	
 	
 		uh
 		
 		
 	