
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brent</ENAMEX> i've been um
 		i kind of gave up my career <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about three years ago</TIMEX> to stay home with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because i thought uh if it it's only going to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">another year</TIMEX> until the youngest is in school
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and i thought it was a good sacrifice to make
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because um it was important to me to to spend some time with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> i know that when i was in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and getting my degree at the same time my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> was it was really hard on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> because i would
 		he would come home and i would leave and then when i would come home and he would leave and um
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		so i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> said you know someone came home and they said well when is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> leaving or something it was like that they thought that's the way life was that you didn't have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> at home at the same time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and so i think um it's become real important to me that we try to spend time together as a family
 		so there's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one or two nights a week</TIMEX> we have a on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nights</TIMEX> we set aside time where it's called uh family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> and we stay home <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that evening</TIMEX> all of us and we do things together
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you must be LES
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		so am i yes what a coincidence
 	
 	
 		oh you are
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yes and
 	
 	
 		yeah i know what family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>'s all about
 	
 	
 		so you do that and right and then we try to do a family activity on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> usually in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right and then the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> too
 	
 	
 		right and then you know sometimes we try to do our lesson on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and then our activity or something on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> but
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		we're it's real important to us to spend time together
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 		um how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have
 	
 	
 		i have two
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> what what do you have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> he's in kindergarten and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> she'll be in kindergarten next year
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five and four</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		my oldest is uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> and my youngest is about to turn three
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> girls
 		and they are a handful
 	
 	
 		they are a handful
 	
 	
 		yes we we've my uh well when we <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> got married my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> worked for a year
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		then we decided to have kids
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh she she got pregnant and then
 		we decided she would stay home with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 		we would make that sacrifice it is a financial sacrifice to make because we go from two incomes down to one
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh we made that decision
 		and uh so she after she had the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> she stayed home
 		and and we had a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> and she's still at home
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		and so uh
 		you know at work a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are you know i think well this is not a normal situation anymore in our in our
 		world we live in most of them uh continue to work if they have have kids
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i know in my in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> here that works where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> stays home
 		and that's because of religious values as well they're <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baptists</ENAMEX> and they and they think that's important
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but everybody else works and they drop their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> off at day care and and leave them and
 		i don't know i just don't want i just don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strangers</ENAMEX> raising my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well no and it's it's just not um it's not as stable for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they everybody decided to come over and talk to me right now but uh it's yeah
 	
 	
 		right
 		that's how it is at our <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> when you're on the phone oh it's open
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		anything goes when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX>'s on the phone
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well it's also important i think um for my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> i i try to go out of my way to to plan things that he can do with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		since i am home with them and so i get a lot of time with them he needs to have um some time with them so he when he comes home he um
 		you know it's his job at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> he puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to bed and he reads
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		to them and he he spends <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about an hour</TIMEX> doing that and that's that's pretty good quality time with them and um but it's hard for him on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturdays</TIMEX> he he wants
 	
 	
 		right
 		with all the yard work and things like that
 	
 	
 		right he wants to run out and get things done and so
 		um i try to say well why don't you go fly kites or why don't you do something and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		if i have something in mind then he he remembers that that's what he wants to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right we feel that you know just spending time together
 		you don't necessarily have to be doing anything you know that costs money
 		or or you know that requires you to go a great distance or anything like that it's just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> like to being together as a family
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX> we went had some errands to run and so we took the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and
 		and we went by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmers Market</ENAMEX> down in in down there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they had a blast running around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmers Market</ENAMEX> looking at all the you know the food and tasting all the free samples
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they were giving out and they had a little pen there with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in they could pet you know and they liked that and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		then on the way <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> we drove by the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">high school</ENAMEX> and there happened to be an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FA FAA Future Farmers FA Future Farmers of America</ENAMEX> FFA
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		going on there and they had all kinds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">goats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX> and everything you know all out in this in the in this schoolyard there so we just said hey let's stop and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> got to go around and you know see <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and things like that and
 		and for them that's wonderful you know they they they thought it was the greatest fun you know and it didn't cost any money
 		and uh you don't have quite as much money when when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> doesn't work
 	
 	
 		well that's right
 		but i do think um you know like the current trends are that um the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unit</ENAMEX> is devaluated it's not nearly as important we find that
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know back just even fifty <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> had had financial problems the fir st place they went to was their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> took care of themselves and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but now you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> don't they don't support each other that way
 	
 	
 		right
 		right oh definitely motherhood is devalued in this society society if you're stay home and you're a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> it's like
 		what a waste <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think you know you should be fulfilling yourself and and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> isn't an important
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		that's right and
 	
 	
 		important thing as as having a career and and that should be <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> second but
 		they don't have kind of an what we call an internal perspective of things  that
 	
 	
 		right right right and it's not an easy sacrifice for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> to make because you know i you know i have interests
 	
 	
 		no
 		right
 	
 	
 		that too and it is hard to make uh those interests not be as a major part of my life
 	
 	
 		uh at this point it's not to say that some day you won't go back to work my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s a school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and when when we started uh having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> she had to work for a little while but then she just started substituting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so she would just substitute once or twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week</TIMEX> you know just for that little extra money
 		when we were in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> then we would just come home and just be you know go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for an hour then she'd be home but she wouldn't do that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		but now that my
 		my uh youngest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>'s at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> now and so they have no one at home she's back teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> full time now again
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so if you know it's not it's just a temporary thing
 	
 	
 		it is temporary it in the middle of it it seems like a long time but you're right it is temporary
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i see that we both share the same belief here that it's important that we spend time with our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and and in spite of
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah you it's it's hard sometimes at work because you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say oh we're taking a cruise we're going here we're going there you know because they have a lot more money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and a lot of them decide just not to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> it's it's amazing they either have one or none
 	
 	
 		yes
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> i know that has one they they feel guilty she has this continual guilt trip that she's not doing the right thing and so
 		on uh on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> she would you know
 		spend all of their time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and spend lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lots</ENAMEX> and lots of money basically i think they they really spoil the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> to try to overcompensate for their guilt feelings
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and and they don't want to have anymore <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> because they just don't think you know
 		that she doesn't think she could be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> at home that's not her bag so she just doesn't think she could
 		you know the guilt feelings she can't deal with with it anymore so
 	
 	
 		yes
 		well it is the hardest thing i've ever done as much as you'd go out
 	
 	
 		you know
 		um-hum yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 		and
 	
 	
 		likes staying home
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh she works at home some though
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the place she works with worked with before um worked out an arrangement with her where she can work at home
 	
 	
 		well that's good
 	
 	
 		part time
 		and so uh that it's kind of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seasonal</TIMEX> thing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> she's really busy doing certain things based on that kind of business but the rest of the time she's free
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		she likes to sew and do crafts and things like that
 		so she enjoys staying at home but uh the money part of it is not as rewarding obviously but
 	
 	
 		no
 	
 	
 		there's different rewards you know different kinds of rewards
 	
 	
 		yeah i think so i think it's an investment in your future even if it's purely not
 		not religious you can at least say that it's important to our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> unit stays strong
 	
 	
 		right right right and you really have to make a quite a bit of money the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> doesn't make it worth it with the cost of day care
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes
 	
 	
 		i know there's you know
 		when you adjust your income for what you put out for day care you know you're only making like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>
 		
 		
 	