
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		all set do you want to start
 	
 	
 		i can go ahead and start uh
 	
 	
 		sure go ahead
 	
 	
 		in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> there's definitely a crime problem i know it's you know worse in the larger <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> um it's kind of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> for me in fact at the moment i'm thinking of possibly moving to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> and uh it's
 		i am single and female you definitely are going to worry about the location and uh
 	
 	
 		oh God
 	
 	
 		you know accessibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to be able to break in i live on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> now but i you know i'm real concerned that i i don't want to be on a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floor</ENAMEX> where you can have problems with things like that and
 	
 	
 		do they have many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> that have security there
 	
 	
 		the um
 		some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> do it depends on the location the area i live in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX> is is real good as far as crime rate is concerned and we don't have
 		anything at all no burglar alarms no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> some some places do have guard gates that you have to get through or electronic access gates and things like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah well i i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> um when i worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Abilene</ENAMEX> and uh i i'm a little familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> area <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Forest Lane</ENAMEX> and you know through that off off the freeway
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it didn't seem like it was that congested in that that part you know because to me where we live out here in the north east it it's there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX> very close to each other
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> are very populated with tenement housing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> in a house
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		and with with the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are coming into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> not knowing the language and uh they're they're going to the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> it makes it very difficult
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it really does and and i i've seen the same thing that you're talking about uh much more crime than ever before <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> of course uh a big part of it i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i don't know a lot of younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> you know into more violent crimes
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		that that that's really sad you know you got young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> that at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> or twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years old</TIMEX> that are committing murders and no remorse what so ever
 	
 	
 		um-hum there's a lot of that going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		it's really sad
 	
 	
 		it is and and i don't know if it's uh the family you know thing where they're not bonding anymore where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are working all the time and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> aren't getting the attention that they need or the television
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i i really think that we're we're falling by the wayside with not incarcerating these people
 	
 	
 		oh i agree i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are getting off too easy they're getting they're getting paroled too easily they're just getting uh put on probation or something because the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX> don't have enough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> so they get they get
 	
 	
 		i uh
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		they get lighter sentences and some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> they don't deserve to be let loose
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		exactly
 		and and you know they had uh in fact on the news last night we were watching this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who lost his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 		he ran out to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> and he had left her home alone she now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years old</TIMEX> she's old enough to be alone for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> you know
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and while he was gone he had looked went looking for a job and stopped at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> that's what it was
 		and uh someone who was in the neighborhood cleaning carpets these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> went in raped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> murdered her
 	
 	
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		and the whole bit and one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> got uh i think it was seventeen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and the other one was in for uh life imprisonment
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> that was in for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the seventeen years</TIMEX> actually served <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and he's out
 	
 	
 		uh
 		that's terrible but
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> said that you know if if it weren't for the fact that he would go to jail that he would eliminate this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> himself and then go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> and have a hamburger and not thing a thing think a thing about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i mean i think that what this is going to lead to is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will take things into their own hands
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and that innocent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i i shouldn't say innocent because i mean actually actually if they commit a crime that they're in the same circumstances but
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the reasons that they're doing it compared to the reason someone else is in jail for it you know it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> different things
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		sometimes when you lose someone that you really love you do some crazy things
 	
 	
 		right
 		it's a little more understandable under the circumstances i guess
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		i i like the idea
 		that uh if someone is from a foreign country
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they come to this country
 		and uh commit a crime i think that irregardless of whether they have already become a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX> or anything they should be immediately deported
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		especially if they're found guilty of the crime
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know once they they have been arrested and if they know beyond a shadow of a doubt these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are guilty that's it we don't take care of them we don't support them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		nothing i mean they go right back where they came from
 	
 	
 		right we have enough enough problems with overcrowding in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jails</ENAMEX> as it is so let let their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> take care of it we don't have i guess too much trouble in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> with well i guess i guess we do have a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> come in from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		and
 	
 	
 		that cause problems but uh
 	
 	
 		but that's uh they're they're so close i i don't consider <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the same category with uh especially like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who come from cultures that don't have the same uh kind of moral upbringing that we have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		like you take <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> or uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Eastern</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>
 		where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> are like in the foreground uh in the background and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are in the foreground and it's like you know um they live back in where where we came from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two hundred years ago</TIMEX> you know we've we've advanced beyond that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that their uh mentality as far as the way they treat them and that kind of thing you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		um-hum it was amazing i went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Far East</ENAMEX> uh back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> to do some training for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> and i uh
 	
 	
 		it's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> were so safe it was unreal <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> is very supposed to be very safe and in fact <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> and i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> would be dangerous being such a huge large <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> with so many people
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but they at at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> there i said is there any area i should avoid and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> said let me ask another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> here and he turned and asked this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and said
 		can you think o f any place where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana</ENAMEX> shouldn't go by herself or anything and she she thought for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> and she said no and he said is there any place you wouldn't go by yourself she said no

 		and they said it is so safe there that you can leave your purse on the subway
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		and somebody will turn it in and the and nothing will be missing they said they can just about guarantee that there uh that that would happen if you did that i thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>  in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> if you left a purse on a subway you would never see it again
 	
 	
 		wow
 		you better believe it if you wouldn't even have to leave it i mean it would get snatched right off your arm
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		that's true but i was thinking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> if somebody asked me if there were places you wouldn't go by yourself at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> i'd have to set them down for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about five</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> to list all the places out i mean
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		i couldn't believe that she couldn't think of any place they said the crime apparently the crime is just uh
 	
 	
 		that's amazing well what's what's the difference there do you know
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure what it is there now i know what it is in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Singapore</ENAMEX> is they have the death penalty and they really enforce it like for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
  
 		oh i i believe in the death penalty i really do
 	
 	
 		for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> they they enforce the death penalty for that uh they're just very very tough and i guess maybe that's the way <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> is too or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is too they're just very tough on criminals
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i think that we're too easy uh and we take the the uh civil liberties uh stuff too far
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that are in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> i mean we didn't put them there they put themselves in that situation and as far as like them uh entertaining the rights that they should have
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean we educate them we feed them we take care of them and they no sooner get out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> and they're back in again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i'm not saying they're all bad but i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who are guilty of really serious heinous crimes do not deserve to be cared for for the rest of their lives
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think that they should be put away
 	
 	
 		and if they're overcrowded well you know
 		they shouldn't have gotten theirself there in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place
 	
 	
 		get rid of them
 		exactly i i really i i think that that's the whole key here this plea bargaining baloney
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where uh you know they plead to a lesser crime or uh they plead guilty in or you know tell about someone else and they they get less time
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or if they're in there and they've got seventeen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and they're on good behavior they get for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> they're in they get so many less
 		you know that they don't serve the full penalty
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i i really think we're going to far overboard with all of this
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		i agree because it's not fair to those of us that that deserve a safe you know life to have to
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		same with drunk drivers
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i think it's too easy for them
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that if the the laws and and uh were were harsher and were enforced
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i mean you have to set an example you have to start somewhere
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i think that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> know that they're going to get a slap on the wrist they might serve a little bit of time and that they'll be out on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> again
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		an i and i feel bad for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> because he's out there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every day</TIMEX> facing these people
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		right
 	
 	
 		this this craziness you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with uh automatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> and uh all this other stuff and trying to do a job and let's face it what do they get paid
 	
 	
 		right not much
 	
 	
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">thousand dollars</NUMEX> a year if they're lucky i wouldn't do it for that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">hum-um</ENAMEX> and especially not in some of these big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> like in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> i mean they've had they're up in the top top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> i think of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> that are getting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policeman</ENAMEX> killed on on in the line of duty and that's really sad
 	
 	
 		it is it really is and i mean they're the first ones that take the brunt of everything
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know and uh i'm not saying that they're all good either because there's good and bad in everything but they they're already uh have strikes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> strikes against them when they're out there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because they'll arrest someone and you know go through all that paperwork and writing a report and all this and having all kinds of evidence and you have to even be careful how you arrest them how you talk to them uh you know what they say
 	
 	
 		right
 		
 		
 	