
 
     		
 	
 		uh i don't know i'm not a real uh great football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">follower</ENAMEX> i guess there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> basic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> that i seem to follow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> one is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> and the other is the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> Sooners
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> being a a native <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Okie</ENAMEX> i uh i like to keep up with what the homeboys are doing uh
 	
 	
 		i see so you make it uh to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Longhorns Sooners</ENAMEX> game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no it's funny uh i got out and got my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s degree in uh seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and uh never went to a game there and have never gone to a game since
 	
 	
 		how about that
 	
 	
 		but i always enjoyed watching them i just growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> there it was always the home <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> kind of like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> is around here
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		and there's always been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">an interest there</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well it's kind of same for me i i grew up in southern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> and the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> and they were like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> miles right up the river
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i'm still pretty much an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> i guess
 	
 	
 		i guess you keep those things you grew up with i worked in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> for a while and uh i was probably the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in the room several times when we were watching <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> on TV when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> were playing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saint Louis Cardinals</ENAMEX> and i was rooting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		but they were kind of closer to home when when i struck up with them i really don't know what's going to take place with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> uh everybody keeps talking about the reconstruction they're going through
 		and new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> and how <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> is going to be even bigger and better than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the previous year</TIMEX>
 		in a way that happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past season</TIMEX> and i think there's quite a bit of optimism around here that still there's a chance that maybe uh
 		these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are right maybe they will come through and and do something <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> i look for it to be a pretty good year
 	
 	
 		boy they uh they sure did have a big turn around from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		they did uh they got rid of a lot of familiar names and got a lot of names in that we weren't weren't familiar with
 		some of them turned out to be pretty good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> uh some of them didn't and you know maybe the stuff that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Jones</ENAMEX> is talking about the construction and redefining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and maybe the effort might be starting to pay off at least we hope it will
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm i keep waiting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> to get over the hump they make it to the play-offs it seems for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last few years</TIMEX> but they just have done absolutely nothing when they got there
 		and you know they've got a lot of the tools to do it but doggone if they can't just put it together uh you know they have got the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> there in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randal Cunningham</ENAMEX> who's just you know phenomenal but he he's too streaky it seems
 	
 	
 		yeah but they have always been a really strong team
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and with without a whole lot of big name <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> they have got a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offense</ENAMEX> and defense and you know they they've managed with those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> and
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		once the pressure gets turned on they they seem to loose it see that's the typical trait of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> and and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> Sooners it's funny over the years
 	
 	
 		i guess yeah
 		yeah
 		i guess since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Staubach</ENAMEX> left they haven't been able to keep it going yeah
 	
 	
 		it's it's been a rough tow a rough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> to hoe ever since he left i don't know why it's so hard to find uh a good quarterback these days
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well that that says a lot for the for his ability though i think for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staubach</ENAMEX>'s i mean you know
 	
 	
 		well yeah you know he was one of the few who've come through in history that can really perform uh
 		we hope every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> hopes their current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> is going to pull them through in a way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aikman</ENAMEX> has done some of that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> winds up getting hurt every other game
 	
 	
 		yeah i i tell you it's difficult in that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s position coming into that because there he was just so highly touted by the press and everybody expected so many big things you know
 	
 	
 		yeah they did they put a lot of pressure on him from the outside and from the inside uh it's funny watching them them play he's probably like a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterbacks</ENAMEX> uh
 		when the pressure is really on when it's down to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few minutes</TIMEX> of the game for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the season</TIMEX> is when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> seem to really do their best
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i haven't quite figured that out if they figure they have got it won or if there's no real hurry because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three quarters</TIMEX>
 		or uh if uh if something happens that that adrenaline starts flowing they say hey we got to do something now and then start playing the game the way the game should be played toward <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last few minutes</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i don't know i'm looking for for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good year</TIMEX> i guess we're always looking for a good year
 	
 	
 		so obviously though do you think they're going to do anything in the play-offs to make it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> or who do you who do you like to do that this year
 	
 	
 		uh no i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> have got a chance i think they will probably win <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one or two</NUMEX> more games than they did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and they'll get close to it they'll probably get everybody's hopes up and blow it toward the end
 	
 	
 		so who's going to beat them who are they going to blow it to
 	
 	
 		uh that's a good question uh i'm figuring either one either the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> or possibly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX> i'm not real sure
 	
 	
 		boy they'd some big changes speaking of them
 	
 	
 		they did so i don't know how these changes are going to help or hinder the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> sometimes it brings in new motivation and all you can do is get out of the way because here they come
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm sure you know my sentimental favorite would have to be <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> but i i sure am scared of them <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giants</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well that's true
 	
 	
 		those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> are tough
 	
 	
 		they are tough and they're big they're mean and they are going to come right through you if you don't do something
 	
 	
 		yeah now that that sure was a fun <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX> to watch this year i mean i wasn't pulling for either <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> but that was just a good <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> game
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 		no no
 		and it's funny you know You like to pull for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">underdog</ENAMEX> and for a long time i was pulling for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh Marino</ENAMEX> makes me just crazy mad sometimes because of some of the stupid stuff he does but he's a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> he's got a good <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> sometimes it's too good because he throws too hard
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> you mean
 	
 	
 		i mean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LA</ENAMEX> sorry
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> on another subject i've been up there like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last three four weeks</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah we've trying get this new DNB <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two thousand</NUMEX> printer up and running
 	
 	
 		had been uh
 		snowing up there
 	
 	
 		oh boy i was just up there i just got back last night around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty or so</TIMEX> and it was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about seven inches</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snow</ENAMEX> on the ground and it snowed all day
 	
 	
 		wow
 		well that will make the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skiers</ENAMEX> happy
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah if if it snowed that much in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX> you know they got that much up in the mountains you know just west of there
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh you bet oh yeah up around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keystone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Copper Mountain</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">those guys</ENAMEX> will love that
 		well good to talk to you
 	
 	
 		yeah enjoyed it Bob
 	
 	
 		you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> have a good time keep those printers coming
 	
 	
 		hey we'll do it
 	
 	
 		all right bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	