
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well what's your views on it
 	
 	
 		i personally feel like as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> exists it's going to be a threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		sure an anybody that's got that much military might is going to be a threat
 	
 	
 		that's right and i
 		i think that we've made a lot of strides in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last several years</TIMEX> with them but i don't feel like that we can ever turn our back on them and
 	
 	
 		not yet
 	
 	
 		no i i just think that
 	
 	
 		course we're in a good position they're they're quite dependent on us right now
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but that doesn't necessarily mean anything but
 		i don't know the i
 	
 	
 		and i i have to wonder sometimes how much of their dependence is
 		um you  know if it's it's sort of a false dependence just to while they're building their own
 		uh way of doing things that they're making us think that they depend that much on us so that we don't watch them more closely
 		you know i'm very suspicious of them
 	
 	
 		well i don't know i
 		yeah i mean <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and foremost i mean everybody loves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorby</ENAMEX> but you know that the one thing they have to keep in mind he's a communist and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX> have their own little ideology about the way things are going to be
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		i think i think they're in pretty bad shape right now i i think their i think their reliance on us is is probably real
 		course that's not to say that once we get them on their feet again things won't go back the way they were
 	
 	
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		so
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		and i don't know you know they they want to know what it would take to convince us that they aren't a threat
 		and i don't know that there's anything that can be done to convince us of that because
 		you know we just see how if if you let your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> down in any situation how you know how quickly that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX> situation arose
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um i don't
 		i i don't think that that we can ever be convinced as a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that that they're going to change or you know not be a threat
 	
 	
 		well only unless they change their form of government
 	
 	
 		yeah and even even the strides that were made toward that though uh you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorbachev</ENAMEX> seems to have
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		he seems to have lost his steam in in that direction and
 		you know he seems to be repressing his own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> again and i don't think that
 		i think that a lot of the
 		the forward progress that was made came to a halt you know in the middle of that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Grulf Gulf</ENAMEX> crisis
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well it's going to be interesting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few years</TIMEX> to see what happens because there's quite a strong democratic um um
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> over there
 	
 	
 		yeah see so many of them have gotten a taste of of democracy and
 		
 
 		they're kind of in between right now they're they're not
 		uh they're not getting the benefits of being a democratic place but they they know what they are and uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> tells them that you know this is what it's like to be a democracy and they're still hurting
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so you know they're getting i guess the worst of all worlds right now
 	
 	
 		um yeah
 		well there was a interesting cartoon in the editorial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX> it was a
 		there was a picture of a shop <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">keeper</ENAMEX> with this really mean look on his face and empty shelves in back of him and a little <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rat</ENAMEX> and a couple of spider webs and
 	
 	
 		uh
 	
 	
 		a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> walk in and look at it and say well we have the worst of both worlds communism and capitalism
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		
 
 		but you know i i i think that i think or at least i hope that they understood that's what was going to happen now you can't go from a a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> economy to a democratic <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and expect things to be great overnight
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		it's just like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Germany</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Germany</ENAMEX> i mean the the only saving grace for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Germany</ENAMEX> is that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Germany</ENAMEX> had lots of money
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		and uh they're bailing them out on everything but even even now the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Germans</ENAMEX> are grumbling
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know which i
 		i would hope they had thought about that while they were busily engaged in tearing down the wall i mean they talk about unification unification and now they're unified and now all they can do is gripe
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		oh well i don't know
 	
 	
 		it's one of those things that all looks good on paper but putting it into reality is a whole different ball game
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah i know we we've shoveled so much aid to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Poland</ENAMEX> and
 		i don't know of course you don't hear hear the bad things out of there like you used to but it doesn't mean they're not going on it just means the press decided to cover something else
 	
 	
 		that's true
 		that's right
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		of course you know you always wonder about the information you're getting anyway
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		i you know that's another thing the news media in the in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>
 		i wouldn't trust them either you know i wouldn't trust them to send to send a story about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> correctly
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">huh-uh huh-uh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 	
 	
 		there has been a lot more openness
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		um we can only hope that that continues
 		it's a precursor of things to come
 	
 	
 		i think our next biggest threat is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese Japanese</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> economic battle we've ever been involved in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's like our <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> industry and it would have it would it would have gone under a long time ago if it hadn't have been for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> helping us out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i guess they they feel a bit ashamed they've done so well
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well here's the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> they helped us get on our feet so let's help them
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		it's amazing
 		we got a lot of problems here too i do mean
 	
 	
 		yeah and and and i have a real problem with the government you know giving away things to the the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that have as as much ability to to do harm to us as anyone
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and you know like giving them plans plans for the some of the uh top secret <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> that we have and things like that i mean that's ridiculous that is only asking for trouble
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well it's like it's like <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Saddam</ENAMEX> you know we're going to build them up and then have to go in there and take care of them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		that's  exactly right
 	
 	
 		well
 		gosh i can't think of anything else
 	
 	
 		nope me either
 	
 	
 		well i guess that'll about do it
 	
 	
 		okay  same here have a good weekend bye-bye
 	
 	
 		good talking to you
 		you too bye-bye
 		
 
 		
 		
 	