
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> do you drive now
 	
 	
 		i drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Prelude</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		do you i drive a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Accord</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i bought <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> so i'm not buying a car any time soon
 	
 	
 		yeah me either i just bought mine uh it'll be a year in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i love it though i love <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hondas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it
 	
 	
 		i think i found my car
 	
 	
 		well i i like where all the controls are
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		they're they're in good spots and i i have an automatic i can't drive a standard
 	
 	
 		oh really i have a standard
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		but um i it's and it's
 		supposedly real reliable the only thing i've ever heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hondas</ENAMEX> is that the breaks go out first yeah
 	
 	
 		oh really i hadn't heard that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		what did you have before you bought that
 	
 	
 		i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Regal</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		did you
 	
 	
 		
  
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
  
 		i had uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda RX</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> before that and that was the worse car i've ever driven in my life
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX> was was great it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years old</TIMEX> and and it was still going strong the only
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		problems i had had with it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years</TIMEX> that i owned it i had to replace the compressor when it was about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years old</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and
 		that was the only major problem that i had i mean i had little piddly things like i had to replace the muffler and i had replaced the tires and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> seems like it had a radiator leak once but i never had any major anything other than the compressor
 	
 	
 		right
 		i never really had anything major with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> but it was a standard also and the clutch went out on it toward the end i had it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
 		and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year or last two years</TIMEX> it seemed to go out really easily i think it went out twice in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and that's that's a lot it shouldn't go out that much
 	
 	
 		no hm
 	
 	
 		and so i went ahead and bought another standard when i bought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> but i don't think i'm going to do that again i think i'm going back to automatic now
 	
 	
 		well i never well well i kind of know how to drive standard but i've never owned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> so i hadn't i don't drive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> a lot so i don't feel feel comfortable in traffic with it
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		and for everything i've heard it's a lot easier to sell an automatic
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and resale value is really important to me
 	
 	
 		yeah it is me too that's why i got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hondas</ENAMEX> have great resale value
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> definitely did not  not at all
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they're worse than <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> i think or just as bad as far as resale goes
 	
 	
 		really
 		i did pretty well with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Regal</ENAMEX> because it was in really good shape but it still looked real nice the the interior was still really nice there what'n cracks all over the dash <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and stuff and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		right
 	
 	
 		and it had some some nice features so i ended up okay with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		good
 	
 	
 		and i anticipate the same thing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> whenever i decide to sell it course i may never sell it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i may drive it till it's dead but
 	
 	
 		yeah that's what i did with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> drive it till the till the clutch went out and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> fell off so probably what i'll do again
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i really like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hondas</ENAMEX> i like foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> a lot
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i looked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi Galant i</ENAMEX> was looking for a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> door car having driven the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RX</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> so long and it was so small
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's really impractical so i wanted something with a real trunk and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> doors something easy to get in and out of and i looked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galant</ENAMEX> and those were really nice and you can get them for a great price
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but i found it hard to deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> i was going through so that's how i ended up with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 		hm i wasn't even looking for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> when i bought this car i uh
 		i was thinking about buying a Prelude from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> who was moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> or something so
 		and she was gonna sell her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> because she didn't need it anymore and it was only like a year old
 		and i had never driven uh a Prelude so i went to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> because they had like uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same year</TIMEX> and same model of Prelude on their used car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lot</ENAMEX> and i went and i test drove it
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and you know i just fell in love with this brand new white Prelude
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you know <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">liter SI</ENAMEX> with the the sun roof and the moon roof and i i bought it loaded
 	
 	
 		they're nice i think
 		oh yeah
 		oh yeah i have to have them loaded i i love all those little things that you don't need but they're so wonderful
 	
 	
 		i mean
 		yeah
 		yeah i went there looking at a used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days later</TIMEX> i bought this car i i felt i felt like
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		that was the worst impulse that was that was the largest impulse buy i had ever made the other the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other things that i've bought on impulse are VCR and a washer and dryer i go for the big stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i would say
 		
 
 		yeah i noticed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		mine was definitely not impulse i really needed a new car <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mine</ENAMEX> was just it's getting worn out i guess from being a sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> i drove it kind of hard
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i got it right after high school so
 		by the time i traded it in it was ready ready to go
 	
 	
 		yeah i got
 		i got my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX> as a high school graduation gift
 	
 	
 		did you
 	
 	
 		yeah but i i guess this what'n really an impulse i mean buying it right then and you know right quickly was kind of impulsive but i'd been thinking about buying a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> and i was just scared to
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		i was scared to start taking on payments because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buick</ENAMEX> was long since paid for
 	
 	
 		right that's same with me would you ever buy a used <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> for yourself
 	
 	
 		buy a  buy a buy a used car sure
 	
 	
 		like
 		right
 		i i was going to buy one once and i just i worry about who's driven them and what they've been through and
 		the warranties and things like that just i can't seem to get over that that just bothers me i don't know why
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well um like on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Hondas</ENAMEX>
 		they supposedly the maintenance records are supposed to be registered with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> or whatever and you can request whatever maintenance records exist on <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> and you can have them checked out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mechanics</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 	
 	
 		mean they can't stop you from doing it so
 	
 	
 		hoping that they do go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dealership</ENAMEX> to get them serviced
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well and even if they didn't you can still get a good idea from a if you can get a good mechanic to check it over real carefully and check the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">blocks</ENAMEX> and everything
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		so
 	
 	
 		well
 		i guess that's all
 	
 	
 		okay well i enjoyed talking to you
 	
 	
 		i enjoyed talking to you bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
  
 		bye-bye
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	