
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay um what baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> are you familiar with
 	
 	
 		well i'm only a little bit familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Sox</ENAMEX> because i lived up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX> for a while
 	
 	
 		really
 	
 	
 		and um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh now come on no <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		after that if you asked me that i wouldn't have been able to tell you if that was football or  baseball
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 
 		really i guess they paired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> together on this call for a reason which is something we can think about later but um i understand a little bit about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX> i know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> threw out the first pitch <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> and it bounced off the ground
 		and that um that i heard a joke on the radio <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that
 		in regard that he didn't design the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patriot</ENAMEX> missile system and uh the which was kind of cruel i mean think the the shame that must have been on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> to bounce the first pitch off the ground i mean golly
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		how humiliating for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to do that any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> i don't care if you're <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah but at the same time i don't know it's pretty far to throw that far  i couldn't do it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		i know but he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> come on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> know how to do that right
 	
 	
 		right he's supposed to be able to do that
 	
 	
 		i know so i felt kind of sorry for him i said oh no that must have been hard on him because he's just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> but um i know his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> is a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		oh really i didn't know that
 	
 	
 		yeah he's like i thought he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> but it turns out my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> said that he's part <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> but he must own the biggest chunk because that's all you hear about is
 		if you know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neal Bush</ENAMEX> i think is his name see i even know his name because he's on the news a lot and i never hardly watch the news not you know not like some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hour and a half a day</TIMEX> or anything
 	
 	
 		I have
 		yeah and i've been watching uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and so if i've been watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> news when i watch it it's incentive speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> we're going to get a little off topic but speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> they that had
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		a story where he went to visit some little uh elementary school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and stuff did you see that where he the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> asked him for proof of who he was and he showed his license
 	
 	
 		oh i saw that
 		yeah i want to see your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>'s i i i don't i you're not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i know and i want to see a credit card
 	
 	
 		i know and he pulled that out that is so funny i heard it on the radio i heard the audio portion on the radio in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but i didn't see it but
 	
 	
 		it was so funny to see it was a really cute little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		that's about my extent of um about <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> i don't know that much about it
 	
 	
 		well i can tell you that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> opened i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two days ago</TIMEX> because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> was supposed to go to the opening game and i couldn't tell you who pitched but they won the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mets</ENAMEX> won but yeah not my a lot and then somebody else lost
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		
 
 		did they
 		
 
 	
 	
 		maybe it was the other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> which is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> but i don't even know if they're still <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Yankees</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's so stupid that you all have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>
 		that's really stupid
 	
 	
 		well but it then then they can have them play against each other
 	
 	
 		yeah i know
 	
 	
 		i think it's still the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Yankees</ENAMEX> you know for some reason i thought they were moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX>  this is how much i know about baseball
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX> they they lost i think
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i know that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we did go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we got free tickets because someone at our church one of the deacons at church um parks <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mansion</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle Creek</ENAMEX> which is like one of the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">places</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and he's their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head chauffeur</ENAMEX> is this funny as they're parking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> the valet service
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		yeah he makes good money too doing that you'd be shocked i was shocked but anyway someone gave an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> a tip of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> tickets last year
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> couldn't he didn't want them so he gave them to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dad</ENAMEX> had plans that night so they gave them to us so he decided that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wealthy man</ENAMEX> tipped this <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		with <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> tickets
 	
 	
 		valet with <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> tickets and we ended up with them right and so we were walking up and i looked at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i said you know what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kyle</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah it's pretty funny
 	
 	
 		this is The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mansion</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle Creek</ENAMEX> a tip i bet these are really good seats and so we ended up on <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> base right down there on the floor and you know we just they called us at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> and the game started at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> so we just threw everything together ran over and got the tickets and
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		left and so we took <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with us and nobody brings <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in these seats you know because
 	
 	
 		because they're fancy seats and stuff
 	
 	
 		yeah and you just sit down and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> were all dressed up and all this you know i just was there you know like i made it i'm here you know and uh it was just kind of funny because
 		you know but we got to sit by <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> base if they'd hit a ball i would have been afraid it would have knocked my face in you know
 	
 	
 		i know i'm always scared of that whenever i go to a game i rarely go but we went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> because
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> is impossible when um he does football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX> and all kinds of stuff and if there's a game on he's watching it i mean that's all there is to it and he's like glued at the TV
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		really
 		oh i'm glad my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s not like that
 	
 	
 		oh i'm glad my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s not like that either i'd kill him  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s like that and um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		see he goes to a lot of games not a real lot but he tries to go then my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> got us some tickets so my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and i went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> we wanted to show my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> what a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game was because you know being a non <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you want to see what a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game is like and he describes it as you sit there in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> and it was nice weather and stuff it wasn't a real problem but you sit there in a crowd
 		and you're waiting and waiting and waiting and you eat these lousy the hot <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dogs  um</ENAMEX> because we made him try a hot dog you know and things like that and um
 	
 	
 		that's funny
 	
 	
 		and um so you sit there and you wait for the longest time really bored and then all of a sudden something happens but you happen to look the other way during the time yeah and so you're basically you sit there and wait for something exciting to happen and when it happened he missed it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		you miss the whole thing
 		that's funny
 	
 	
 		and didn't understand it and it
 	
 	
 		where is he from in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um he grew up out well he grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Le Ren</ENAMEX> which is the sort of um oh <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip</ENAMEX> east to west eastern part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">France</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah i have a i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> in college from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Strasbourg</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah he's not that far he was sort of in between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Strasbourg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh-huh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX> and she's lived there for like oh off and on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh is she still there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh huh Saint Claude</ENAMEX> is that sound familiar yeah
 	
 	
 		because
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saint Claude</ENAMEX> yeah we used to that's one of the um entrances to the periphery to get in and out of the city
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and it it it it sits right at the limit
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know exactly where she is but um
 	
 	
 		that's neat yeah she does and they have twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we we met in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> oh my God the poor woman
 	
 	
 		she has twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> she looks gorgeous no she's gorgeous a nd she just liked having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and she's thin and i mean all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> or more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are thin i mean i'm not kidding you
 	
 	
 		were any of them twins
 		you probably can't afford to eat if you have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than two</NUMEX> of them
 	
 	
 		no you have i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> now that has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> and um and they're all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and under
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> and under they're all real young they're just really feel like that's what God's told them to do but they're not condemning you if you we only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> you know they don't say they don't put airs on about it or anything which is good because it would be easy i'm sure for them to do that
 		you know you get a conviction like that and you think everyone should have it and so i'm real proud of them because they're aren't really they don't do that at all you go in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> tooth brushes in there and i always give her a hard time i go now come on who's toothbrush did you really use this morning
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		but how do they afford to even have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> uh we're expecting our <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> almost any day
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		they live lean for one thing and they tithe and they really believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tithe</ENAMEX> puts it puts a hole in your money bag we don't honor God with the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> portion and so they i think that helps a lot i think that's the key
 	
 	
 		and
 	
 	
 		and he like his sales <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> he just works a normal job he probably has an income of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty five thousand</TIMEX> but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> he made <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> sale that got him a bonus of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty five thousand</TIMEX> which allowed him to pay cash for a full size van
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it's God i mean it was the biggest thing that any one in this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> had ever done and he got to do it and so God just really blesses him in ways like that just trust God because i don't know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are a blessing and and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we think of blessings as
 	
 	
 		wow
 	
 	
 		nice furniture and things like that but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are just as much of a blessing as all these material things but it's a different kind and a lot times <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think oh well i'm not blessed i have an old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> but you've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> you know you're just as blessed probably more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		because if you follow this there's a good book called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What the Bible Has to Say About Child Training</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Fugate</ENAMEX> and he's you know a lot of wisdom in it and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> talk about anything but training and training is different
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		than anything else in in psychology doesn't address it a lot of the psychology stuff the good stuff that's in psychology it just comes out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> and they don't quote you the proverb out of it but
 		the things that work in psychology other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> that they've proven to work they just come out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> and so this book it just really ties in all these things and how to train the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> so they're not going to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curse</ENAMEX> to you when they're thirteen
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know what i mean how to train them so they're going to be a blessing and so you know they do that and they they just live lean pretty much they don't she doesn't shop at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foley</ENAMEX>'s you know and stuff like that
 		but a lot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foley</ENAMEX>'s so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foley</ENAMEX>'s it's like a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Macy</ENAMEX>'s kind of store it's pretty nice and everything's pretty expensive and you know you just can't do that and you don't go to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> games as much or you get pictures like we did you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		i don't i don't know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foley</ENAMEX>'s is
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you do these fun things you know in other kinds of ways and i know <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>'s real expensive but um it's kind of a different situation because you're probably living in an <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah well that makes a really big difference but but still it's just as hard as having that but well he can your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> could have a baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> with twelve kids
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> state softball <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leagues</ENAMEX> so they're not all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right now we don't have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> because i'm the one that's supposed to start <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and i just haven't gotten around to doing it i keep saying we need to have one they go okay then start one but everybody wants to do it but you know God's sitting on my heart and i just hadn't gotten around to doing it
 		anyway so they could really only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> on the team i think they only have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> i don't even think they have but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> old enough to play yet
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but um they you wouldn't believe it though her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are the they are so good i'm not kidding you but she does work with them and it's a commitment and that that's what they're called to do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i have a most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i admire someone that can do that you know i really can
 	
 	
 		i know i do too i most of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and they feel like you know that's really all that God wants for them and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> use birth control and some of them don't i had my tubes tied so you
 		
 		
 	