
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		
  
 		do you want to start
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm trying to think what i've seen lately i mean well well we just finished watching uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles</ENAMEX> on tape you know
 	
 	
 		
 
 		did you watch <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> did you see the movie
 	
 	
 		yeah we we've seen that yeah
 	
 	
 		did you like it
 	
 	
 		yeah it was great have you seen it
 	
 	
 		i thought it was very well done
 	
 	
 		yeah i um
 	
 	
 		how about Ghost
 	
 	
 		we we saw an we liked it but you know i didn't think it was as good as all the uh hype was about it
 	
 	
 		right i feel the same way about that too it was okay
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't i i couldn't see it
 		worth getting a nomination for uh best picture
 	
 	
 		no no and uh what let's see uh the
 		most recent ones that i've seen are those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ghost and uh Dances With Wolves</ENAMEX> but i rent uh uh videos do you
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah and so we just uh it depends um you know it depends on what
 	
 	
 		you you watch many
 		do you like the classics like uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gone With the Wind</ENAMEX> and uh you know the older movies
 	
 	
 		i'd like to see those i keep you know um you know there's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> movies that i i keep telling myself that i should see one of these you know some day that i haven't seen you know that that are classics you know because i've never seen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen Kane</ENAMEX> and never seen
 	
 	
 		yeah that was good
 	
 	
 		i've never seen <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Casablanca</ENAMEX> and never seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Gone With The Wind</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think i've seen most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humphrey Bogart</ENAMEX>'s movies but in in you know a long time ago and uh like the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Maltese Falcon</ENAMEX> and all those uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh i i definitely we saw part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The African Queen</ENAMEX> on on TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years ago</TIMEX> and i've i've always i've been wanting to see all of it but we just you know we walk into the video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> and we're like well why don't we go see this now  so
 	
 	
 		uh
 		yeah that was good yeah
 		yeah yeah it's true
 	
 	
 		but um i think one of the movies we saw recently we saw uh Misery
 	
 	
 		oh i didn't see that one
 	
 	
 		that was good um oh it was great and it you think you know for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX> you know it because it was by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen King</ENAMEX> it would be really gory but there's only one well there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a couple</NUMEX> scenes
 	
 	
 		really
 		
 
 	
 	
 		at at the end there's there is you know some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> and everything and there's one really bad scene where it's i mean there's not blood but it's pretty graphic  but it's um it's a really good movie um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		really is that the one where uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> gets captured by that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> okay yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and um she's his biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> and she's also
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 	
 	
 		a little a little on the nutso side
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> did you see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Heights</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no we haven't um
 	
 	
 		i saw that one that one wasn't that great either well i didn't think so no
 	
 	
 		oh it wasn't
 		okay i i got i heard like mixed reviews um of that we saw
 	
 	
 		how about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silence</ENAMEX> of the Lambs
 	
 	
 		that's that's on our list of things to see
 	
 	
 		i know i i wanted to see i i was curious if you had seen it and that uh
 	
 	
 		no our big thing is um you know movie movie prices up here i think it's like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> bucks now in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> and you know so it's like you know a lot of things we try to catch like at the dollar theater or matinees and then a lot of other stuff we just wait until it comes out on tape
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's us too yeah yeah true i know it's too bad that they've gotten so expensive
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> movie we saw in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last couple of months</TIMEX> that we really enjoyed was uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Scissorhands</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah have you seen that oh it was great  yeah it was
 	
 	
 		no
 		really
 		i thought it was kind of maybe for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no no it's um
 		it's an odd film and it's really interesting that i like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> a lot um a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Burton</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		did you ever see the movie Beetlejuice
 	
 	
 		uh part of it i
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		i never really watched the whole thing
 	
 	
 		oh see yeah well if you if you liked Beetlejuice you'll probably like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Scissorhands</ENAMEX> if you didn't like Beetlejuice you'll probably won't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Scissorhands</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		yeah it's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">um</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burton</ENAMEX>'s kind of uh
 		he he he's a very odd odd <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> but he's i think he's very interesting and uh i liked those two movies of his a lot he did <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Batman</ENAMEX> also which you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that was pretty good though really
 	
 	
 		it was good but i mean he was
 		um
 	
 	
 		when you think of what it takes to make some of those kind of movies you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you see it for uh you know <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of hours</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX> and it really there's a lot in it when you look at the scenery and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh yeah oh
 	
 	
 		and all the different stuff like that you know
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		whose your favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um don't really know i like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Costner</ENAMEX> a lot but uh i'm a big i'm a big baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> so you know after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bull Durham</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field of Dreams</ENAMEX> you know um although you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah that was good i saw that movie too that was very good
 	
 	
 		which one
 	
 	
 		Field <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">of Dreams</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Field of Dreams</ENAMEX> was good um and i i think i liked the other movies he's done <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Way Out</ENAMEX> was really good and did you ever see Silverado
 	
 	
 		oh yeah yeah
 		Silverado uh
 		who who was that with
 	
 	
 		um let's see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Glover Scott Glen Kevin Kline um Brian Dennehe Jeff Goldblum</ENAMEX>'s in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Clease</ENAMEX> is in it if you don't blink
 	
 	
 		that the name the the title sounds familiar i'm trying to think
 	
 	
 		it was it was a big western i mean i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roseanne Arquett</ENAMEX> was in it too another one that if you blink you'd miss her uh it was and i think it was like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three hour</TIMEX> movie or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two and a half hours</TIMEX> and and it was one of those ones that could have been <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four hours</TIMEX> if they hadn't cut a lot out
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		um but it was it was really good  um
 	
 	
 		i i might have seen part of that because the name sounds familiar
 		although i would i would remember i think in with him in it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how about <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Revenge</ENAMEX> did you see that with him
 	
 	
 		no i didn't is that any good
 	
 	
 		with uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Quinn</ENAMEX> i thought it was i like everything he's done so far
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		you know it's uh one of those movies that it's not a great movie but it was okay
 	
 	
 		yeah we were in the video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> today and somebody was recommending it to somebody you know the the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who run the video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> was recommending it to somebody else
 	
 	
 		yeah it was it was not a bad movie
 	
 	
 		huh well i'll have to catch it one of these days you say you you said you seen <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">No Way Out</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that was excellent
 	
 	
 		yeah that was very good um he was in The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Untouchables</ENAMEX> too
 	
 	
 		now that's another one i wanted to see that in fact that was advertised not too long ago
 	
 	
 		he
 		yeah it was on um it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no it was on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> i think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		okay i know i saw yeah something about it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>
 		yeah i um i wish i i mean i'd seen it when when you know it was originally in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> and um
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i saw it you know i saw part of it again i mean i like you know i like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costner i</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Connery</ENAMEX> and uh there's this one there's this one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> it's really silly that i enjoy him a lot but i i've really enjoyed him in everything i've seen him in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Martin Smith</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know him
 	
 	
 		um you've probably seen him and just an you know oh that's who the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> is do you remember did you ever see <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> Graffiti
 	
 	
 		
 
 		no i i don't think so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		did you ever see the movie <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Star Man</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		okay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Star Man</ENAMEX> he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> chasing after
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um Jeff Bridges</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Allen</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Allen</ENAMEX> you know with short nerdy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> with glasses he's
 	
 	
 		okay okay
 		yeah yeah
 	
 	
 		he's just i i don't know why but he's always a lot of fun in every movie he's in he was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Untouchables</ENAMEX> he was the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh oh i know who you mean he was in uh uh <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Honey Don't Shrink the Kids</ENAMEX> wasn't he
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		no no you're thinking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Moranis</ENAMEX>
 		he looks like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Moranis</ENAMEX> but he's not
 	
 	
 		oh okay  see all right yeah that's the one i was thinking of
 		but i have i've seen quite a few movies i i enjoy them i think that uh it's it's kind of like uh good entertainment an uh an escape type of thing
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		how about some of the ads do you go by the ads when you look at them or the reviews do they influence you a lot
 	
 	
 		uh a little of
 		a review usually won't make me go see a movie i hadn't already wanted to see
 	
 	
 		yeah did you see Goodfellas
 	
 	
 		no it's oh uh i want to see it
 	
 	
 		that was that was pretty good um and
 	
 	
 		um we want to see <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Godfather Part Three</ENAMEX> also but my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s seen part <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and part two although she saw them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> but i've never seen either of the first you know
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		of the of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> movies so we're probably going to like rent those some time and then try to see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX> Part Three somewhere
 	
 	
 		i was just going to say that you should see those first uh first if you can
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		if you if you read the book it's uh even better the book was excellent
 	
 	
 		oh okay i haven't
 	
 	
 		yeah and uh i was a little disappointed in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one it's <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Godfather Three</ENAMEX> it was not bad but i expected more i think
 	
 	
 		never read it
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		we just rented um <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple weeks ago</TIMEX> a movie called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Freshmen</ENAMEX> with um it's got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Broderick</ENAMEX> in it and um uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlon Brando And Brando</ENAMEX> like does a parody of the character he played in The Godfather
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		um yeah it's it's one of the reasons why you know The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godfather</ENAMEX>'s been on our minds lately um but uh there's a bunch of scenes from uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Godfather</ENAMEX> that's used because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Broderick</ENAMEX>'s going to film <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and uh in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> they're using there's a bunch they're running a bunch of scenes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Godfather</ENAMEX> and then he's running into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marlon Brando</ENAMEX> who is playing you know this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX> you know this uh organized crime head
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so it's um it was it was a fun movie
 	
 	
 		how about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Cruise</ENAMEX> do you like his stuff
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cocktails</ENAMEX> or uh
 		what
 	
 	
 		i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rainman</ENAMEX> i thought i thought it was interesting that he was doing something
 	
 	
 		oh yeah that was good i liked <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Rainman too</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i'm being from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> of course i'm a big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barry Levinson</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> since uh he he's you know he's done a bunch of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> movies
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um no i don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Levinson</ENAMEX> did um <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tinman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Avalon</ENAMEX> which are all set in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah they sound familiar i probably saw parts of those you know a lot of times i'll watch i'll start watching a movie and i'm tired and it next thing you know it's it's especially if there's commercial in it
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then the titles might sound familiar but i really don't know what they're all about
 	
 	
 		yeah well
 		yeah of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diner</ENAMEX>'s probably the best i mean they're they're all pretty good but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diner</ENAMEX> is really worth seeing
 	
 	
 		is that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set in the fifties or sixties
 	
 	
 		uh late fifties yeah
 	
 	
 		late fifties yeah i think i saw that one
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay</ENAMEX> and uh yeah
 	
 	
 		how about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meryl Streep</ENAMEX>
 		
 		
 	