
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um what is your experience been with like do you have elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> that live with you or have lived with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		no um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> in a nursing home and that has been a real mess to say the least
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh they keep seem to keep moving her in and out of different ones
 		that they had just got done moving her uh into another one because the one she was in they gave her some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> she was definitely allergic to and almost killed her
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		and and and it was posted you know above her bed not to give her penicillin
 	
 	
 		and they gave gave it to her anyway
 	
 	
 		but but they gave it to her anyway and just she just about died
 	
 	
 		we had my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's Alzheimer's disease</ENAMEX> and  my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> kept him at home as long as she could
 	
 	
 		hm
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> who tried to convince them to go into like an old age <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX> where he could have gotten care
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and she could've had help with somebody cleaning and things like that and she refused she she just didn't want to do it she felt i i don't know maybe too much guilt or something
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah i i i don't i don't feel he uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> is that bad off and they they offered you know to get to hire you know an a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">roommate</ENAMEX> or uh or a part time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> and she just wouldn't have it at all
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		and so eventually they were forced to put her
 	
 	
 		they they were forced to put her in a nursing home
 	
 	
 		yes well my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> he eventually completely lost
 	
 	
 		yeah um-hum
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">control</ENAMEX> type of things i i mean i don't know if he ever really got violent but they put him in a nursing home and actually the problem
 		that they had with him was more with the hospital the the nursing home you know some day he had a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">fever</ENAMEX> or something so they sent him to a hospital which is what they think to routinely do which i think is ridiculous too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know because they might not be really be sick and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> they um did an electrocardiogram
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and decided that he had a heart problem and you know here he was
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		very old he had <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX> he'd been like a vegetable for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> said oh we have to put in a pacemaker and you know wanted to prove approval for it and all this sort of stuff and eventually
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		you know the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> is in an uproar discussing it and some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> said well they yeah they should do it and others you know said it's ridiculous this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> finally wants to die just let him die and um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yes
 	
 	
 		eventually the at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> they said no to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> and they found out it wasn't even his electrocardiogram that there was some other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> you know by the time he'd been sent back to the nursing home and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh my gosh
 	
 	
 		under care there
 	
 	
 		it tears apart <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> it really it it it just the biggest fights
 	
 	
 		but
 		oh
 	
 	
 		just it it it's because of that i mean that that will divide you divide <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sisters</ENAMEX> quicker than anything its
 	
 	
 		it's horrible
 		sometimes you just can't keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> at home they're just  know
 	
 	
 		oh that's true but but the the nursing home situation is such a is such a pitiful situation
 		i mean if you just if you go every time we go visit her it's just it's just gut wrenching to me
 	
 	
 		oh i felt went to visit my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time in the nursing home and i said never again i said i just can't go
 	
 	
 		i i can't i i i can't hardly handle it myself
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh it's it's
 	
 	
 		but i had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> of mine that was in a different nursing home which was sort of nicer you know and until really close to the end she was able to go out and take walks and things and they took her outside and in some ways i think it might have even
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		been better or i i say say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>'s like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX>  but i had been really close to her and in some ways i think for her might have even been better because she used to live in
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh yeah</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		an area that when she moved down there was mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly people</ENAMEX>  well not
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		you know it was like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> that
 		were mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX> when she moved there she might have been like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty</TIMEX> it wasn't you know ancient but you know older and then that community for some reason started getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartments</ENAMEX> were fairly low income i guess
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and started being bought out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> and things and she started having fewer and fewer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just she she she she used to say to me when at when she was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety two</NUMEX> or something at the time say
 	
 	
 		oh my
 	
 	
 		um you know i just i all my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> have died off i have nothing to do i'm bored you know i walk over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> i walk back someone comes and picks me up and brings me to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> and so when she went to a nursing home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		in the beginning i think she kind of liked it she did art work there she did it was almost a progressive type nursing home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well if you're not in real bad shape it's it's you know a retirement a retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> is is is a good idea for somebody like that but uh if you've got a lot of health problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		yeah then you just can't get better
 	
 	
 		it it it's just it's a mess it's just a big huge mess because because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> has a lot of health problems
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh
 		and his like his other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents grandparents</ENAMEX> on his other side both were in a nursing home and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> his other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> finally went into a coma and she was in a coma for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost two years</TIMEX> in a nursing before before she passed away and that that was awful
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i'm sure
 	
 	
 		and and um
 	
 	
 		does the medical care in nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> is typically less than
 	
 	
 		pitiful it it it's it's
 	
 	
 		in but are they supposed to give as much
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well well well what what they do is is they're supposed to monitor them but they don't monitor them very well at all
 	
 	
 		home care you know
 	
 	
 		i mean that that's the problem uh his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> that's in it now she had a stroke and they didn't catch it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX> if you can imagine such a thing
 	
 	
 		jeez
 	
 	
 		so that so then that she that was when she got moved from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one  where she was given penicillin
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one
 	
 	
 		at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one an d now she's at the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one  so it's it it it it's been a really bad situation but i have but that's all i hear about nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> is bad situations
 	
 	
 		oh gosh
 		that's horrible
 		had they checked into these nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> much before they put her in it or they just sort of i mean i it's something that's hard to even get places in there you're lucky if you get a spot
 	
 	
 		well that yes that that's true but um
 		they're in a smaller small area and our and in fact they're over up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">and and</ENAMEX> and what i would you would really consider a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">area</ENAMEX> and where there's like one nursing home per town
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		no so you probably don't have too much choice
 	
 	
 		yes oh no no no there's there is not a whole lot of choice so they've they've moved through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so um
 	
 	
 		but really it's pitiful
 	
 	
 		it is and it the regulations i don't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> the government regulations are the place i i don't think are are adequate either because they just don't the ones i've been in just don't aren't real real clean
 		uh you know they do they do a halfway decent job but i it seems like they're they're they tend to be kind of slack
 	
 	
 		often times i've gone into nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> where
 		you know they have like a central area where they take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to and all you do is to just sort of sit there like
 	
 	
 		leave them
 		yes
 	
 	
 		you know almost like they're mentally retarded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> or something and some of them you know they're just sitting in the wheelchair and sleeping or whatever and it's just it's heart breaking you know and and i i feel like you know what have i moved into and and they're
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>
 		uh-hum
 		i know
 		i know it's
 	
 	
 		some of them i think just needs stimulation
 	
 	
 		yeah i mean it's almost like a mental hospital atmosphere instead of a nursing home
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well i've never been to a mental hospital  but we
 	
 	
 		well me neither but but it just seems like that's what it would be like
 	
 	
 		right like you expect expect from the movies of mental hospitals
 	
 	
 		like uh  <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> went and uh i went i didn't go with him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> was sitting there and she said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">hall</ENAMEX> is naked and he was he was sitting in his wheelchair stark naked
 	
 	
 		
  
 		
  
 		oh gosh
 	
 	
 		he had he'd got himself undressed and and he just he just like to sit in his wheelchair naked  that's not funny but it was funny at the time
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah but the the i mean the poor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> too  he could get really cold he could
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah It was in the it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">at at</TIMEX> at the time but you think they would pay more attention to what was going on that they'd see this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had taken off his clothes
 	
 	
 		that's crazy but i think they're under stress i mean i can't imagine working in a nursing home like that either because it must be so depressing
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh no
 		oh i couldn't do it i just absolutely couldn't do it
 	
 	
 		but you know when i see them i don't know that i could  when i think of my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> who fortunately shouldn't be close to getting there yet but i don't  think of
 	
 	
 		i know
 	
 	
 		having to make the decision as to put them into a place like that or not
 	
 	
 		me too that that is what scares me to death having to be in a  in the position like that but you think you think there could be something better than that
 	
 	
 		horrible
 		i guess i would try and have somebody at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> as long as they were healthy enough but sometimes they're
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		not i i don't know  where have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> gone where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just sort of died of something in their family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> and they're you know
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are stabbed but it's not this torture
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i've been i've been real fortunate my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s never had anybody anybody anybody like in in in a nursing home but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> really has has has
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		that's it's it's interesting because it's my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s parents
 		well actually my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> both of them
 		sort of you know they just died of something um but the my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s case which is very sad she fell she came into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> to visit and she fell at the airport going down some steps and spent you know <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> but it is was still it it was it wasn't
 	
 	
 		yeah so yeah
 		oh how awful
 		oh
 	
 	
 		you know the same as a nursing home type of thing
 	
 	
 		right but still that's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah no that was that that that was horrible it was  and she she never even got to see her family that she came in to visit
 	
 	
 		oh how aweful
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		they they never come to see they never came to see her
 	
 	
 		no they came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> but i mean she came in
 	
 	
 		yeah but then she didn't get to go there oh i see
 	
 	
 		you you know she came in for a pleasurable visit and
 	
 	
 		oh how awful
 	
 	
 		fell and cracked cracked her skull open and that was sort of it but just terrible
 	
 	
 		oh
 		oh how awful
 	
 	
 		but um
 		my it was really just my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandfather</ENAMEX> i guess and this one elderly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cousin</ENAMEX> of mine that went into nursing homes
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but it's just a scary thought every time i certainly don't want to be like that someday
 	
 	
 		science medical science has prolonged life but they have they haven't really prolonged the quality of it that that's i think that's really the problem they can bring you back bring bring you out of death but they can't
 	
 	
 		yes
 		
 		
 	