
 
     		
 	
 		okay what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> are you thinking about buying next
 	
 	
 		well what a what what do we currently have i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Subaru uh G O X T</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		what year
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh okay well i have a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ninety</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic</ENAMEX> and i'm ready to get rid of it  actually no well
 	
 	
 		oh yeah it's not pretty old
 	
 	
 		i had i had an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX> that i really liked then it got wrecked and so i bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">ninety um</ENAMEX> because i i really liked my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty eight</NUMEX> and i've had a lot of problems with this one  so
 	
 	
 		so you think their quality control's going down over there uh kind of
 	
 	
 		well you it's it's kind of funny um i know a lot
 	
 	
 		well i i i think we're going to see that i think uh that the quality that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> carmakers had is slipping a little bit while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carmakers</ENAMEX> are trying to get their butt together so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		it's it's true it's definitely true because
 	
 	
 		but but that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason i uh i've had no problems with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subaru</ENAMEX> that's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> reason i went with it because i <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subaru</ENAMEX> had a good reputation uh for you know low maintenance so
 	
 	
 		yeah well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> does too  that's why i was really
 	
 	
 		well no there's there's no question but you have a nineteen i mean i've got to see i mean i've seen and i've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> that have uh like uh eighty one or eighty uh Celicas
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and those things just keep ticking i mean they just it can rack up a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> fifty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> on them and they're still beating on them
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's true
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		and it's just amazing and i mean they got and you know they're not making them like that now   you know so but they're still they're still a lot i think definitely better than the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">carmaker</ENAMEX> and stuff
 	
 	
 		no not at all
 		oh i i definitely agree with you there  because i had uh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">uh Ford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">T Bird</ENAMEX> before i got my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> and it was the worst car i've ever owned  and um that's why i mean i was so tickled with my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> it was just a wonderful <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> and then it got wrecked
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you know i wouldn't even look at another car  i just went and bought a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> i mean i didn't even i didn't look around or anything i just said that this is what i want  and i really have had a lot of problems with it  but
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		well maybe you need to unload it on somebody else
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 		well i'll probably hold on to it since it's still under warranty but
 		in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first twelve months</TIMEX> that i owned it it was in the shop an average of about once a month  it was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> about twelve times the first twelve <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>  yeah it was i was really
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a lot
 	
 	
 		disappointed because i was you know so hyped up on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honda</ENAMEX> so yeah
 	
 	
 		oh well
 		anyway so what's your next purchase supposed to be
 	
 	
 		well  i know this
 	
 	
 		oh really if you had a choice of your car what would you get
 	
 	
 		well it's this is going to sound really strange  but i really like to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">MPV</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX>  i really like those and i have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  so
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure i'm real familiar with the body style on that
 	
 	
 		they're a lot i don't like the new style like of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toyota</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lumina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">van</ENAMEX> i don't like those styles um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPV</ENAMEX> is more of uh uh just uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh-huh</ENAMEX> that's
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know what you normal  i don't know how to explain more of an old fashioned type
 		i i'm not sure how to explain it i mean it looks i guess kind of like uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aerostar</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arrow</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Astro Astro</ENAMEX> i guess is what it something like that but i used to really like the looks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MPV</ENAMEX> because it looks more like a minivan rather than i think
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah
 		do you have uh do you have a family okay well that's probably influenced maybe a little bit
 	
 	
 		yeah i have a couple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>  so
 		oh yeah  definitely but i know that it's got to have a radio
 		it's got to have air conditioning  i'm sure you can relate to air conditioning
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		um living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX> but and cruise control and tinted windows that's about it  i mean it's got to have those things otherwise i don't care
 	
 	
 		yeah well when i bought my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> it was right out of college and uh you know i always been looking for something sporty and i ended up getting you know basically something that i could
 		you know afford
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the only gripe i have
 		is performance i i probably uh a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> that i've gone out with i've had uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">RX</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven</TIMEX>'s and stuff and they're they're pretty fun to drive so
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so i think that's what uh i i'm going to have to get next time around i keep i keep holding holding off i mean i could i could upgrade now if i wanted to but i just i it's just such a huge expense and
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		and uh i i'm just going to keep holding off but i'm definitely going to look for something uh in the you know nice performance you know yeah
 	
 	
 		sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>  i'd like to have a sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> too but it's not practical for me  but
 	
 	
 		yeah  i'm in are you still there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		whoops
 		there's some kind of problems hello
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		are you still there this is something's wrong i don't know it sounds funny though doesn't it
 	
 	
 		wonder what happened
 		hum anyway
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		um but i'll probably um
 		it just depends i know that's what i want but i don't know if i'll get myself to
 		spend that kind of money you're looking at you know for a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RX</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supra</ENAMEX> or something you're looking at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX> or something like that so
 	
 	
 		oh at least yeah
 	
 	
 		anyway but
 	
 	
 		i know well new <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> aren't cheap anyway  but
 	
 	
 		anyway my ultimate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> though the the one that i really want is uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five sixty</TIMEX> or so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX> so maybe someday
 	
 	
 		huh  yeah we have we all have those kind of dreams too don't we  what i'd really like to have
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		that's the only one that i you know i see you know i see uh you know early on that that that says  it says you there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		this is strange
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX> i think something's wrong with this i hope it's recording
 	
 	
 		i hope it's not my  you there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		it may be my phone um anyway it's the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> that says you know sporty and class uh so
 	
 	
 		yeah you're right  yep
 	
 	
 		uh kind of what i'm but it's at the other one my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>'s got a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miata</ENAMEX> and those are fun
 	
 	
 		oh those are nice yeah they're they're cute <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i
 		yeah well he did he had a a red  Miata
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh he actually they came out with a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> racing green
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Miata</ENAMEX> that's a limited edition they're only going to make like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three or four thousand</NUMEX> so he went out and he traded <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">the other one</NUMEX> in and got this one and i'm like um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		wow i haven't seen those
 	
 	
 		but uh i haven't seen one yet either but supposedly they have some real wood built in to like the clutch and all this and the steering wheel so it's it's very authentic and there only is supposed to be limited edition so it may be may be a good investment
 	
 	
 		wow
 		oh yeah definitely if it's a limited edition usually no matter what it is if it's a limited edition it's usually worth something later on
 	
 	
 		if it
 		yeah
 		uh-huh but uh i think
 	
 	
 		huh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">hello</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		okay yeah i got off my pace or my cordless phone anyway uh hope it's not going bad it's going to bum me out um but he i think he he only spent you know the low <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenties</TIMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 		really
 	
 	
 		i don't know
 	
 	
 		now see i would have never figured that i would have figured that to be a lot more than that  for something that's limited edition
 	
 	
 		well i don't know i think the demands gone uh down a little bit i think you can the prices aren't as high you know and the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miata Miata</ENAMEX> was first introduced uh
 	
 	
 		and well they weren't really that bad though when they were introduced were they
 	
 	
 		what yeah the demand is so high that uh you know they were going to retail them around like <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> you know
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thirteen</ENAMEX> standard you know and you get your options you're looking at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fifteen</NUMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixteen fifteen</TIMEX> but there were you know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were buying them for nineteen and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah that's true
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um
 		they they may have gone down a little bit but i they're still pretty much in demand
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		i think there's another car coming in it's supposed to come out and compete with that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miata</ENAMEX> and i can't remember what i read about that but so that's interesting i mean i would think somebody would try to compete with that because it is very popular so
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah it really is have you seen the new uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dodge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stealth</ENAMEX> the the real nice one  yeah yeah the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi</ENAMEX> is real nice looking too now those are nice
 	
 	
 		but
 		oh yeah yeah and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">GT</ENAMEX> is the same same
 		yeah well that's that's that's the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> and stuff so they just market them but uh yeah those are and those are supposed to be
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 	
 	
 		very performance power i mean they're there is yeah big time
 	
 	
 		the expensive ones they have a cheaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> too that you can get for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about seventeen thousand</NUMEX> but those are pretty stripped and there's nothing there's really that one's just more for looks you know it doesn't have any really the performance that the expensive one does
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know but i've seen one of those and it's not that great i mean because they really
 	
 	
 		i think they're they're only around uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah the like i mean they have um better it's not quite as nice for a little bit less
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah they're not really that bad but i don't know  like i said it's it's still not practical for me  i have a hard time looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> like that because i think now there's no way i can do that
 	
 	
 		yeah i'm being
 		single and no other responsibilities for yourself i guess you know it's i can i can i've been pretty happy i've i've haven't tried to upgrade myself right now that's uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know i could i could have you know get something nice and upgrade but i just uh i'm consulting right now so
 	
 	
 		oh really
 	
 	
 		i just made my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> job hop <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about eight months ago</TIMEX> so uh
 	
 	
 		uh what
 		
 		
 	