
 
     		
 	
 		okay well i have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> actually they're <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years old</TIMEX> and uh <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five and a half</TIMEX> actually almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six now</TIMEX> and they're in kindergarten and uh <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> grade how about yourself
 	
 	
 		there we go uh how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> do you have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie</ENAMEX>
 		a uh oh we've got we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> but they're they're kind of older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> now uh we've got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty three</TIMEX> that's a senior in college a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter nineteen</ENAMEX> who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> in college and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son seventeen</ENAMEX> who's a senior in high school
 	
 	
 		okay
 		oh my
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		i see
 	
 	
 		what what kind of activities do you do with them
 	
 	
 		well you now they're especially the older <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> uh they they're into their sports and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> a lot you know the younger one's getting into it more uh what we enjoy doing with them which we started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> was um
 		we go on fishing you know day time trips with them the younger <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> especially is really good at it  he enjoys fishing
 		um they like to go to a place here called uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chuckie Cheese</ENAMEX> which is really like a crazy arcade type of thing has a lot of games um and we you know we like to do outdoors types of things with them um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i just got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX> myself because i'm hoping you know eventually maybe you know for hikes or you know going out along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canal area</ENAMEX> or whatever to ride <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bikes</ENAMEX> with them
 	
 	
 		oh sure
 	
 	
 		and um you know we enjoy um we enjoy doing more things outdoor playing ball with them my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> likes to play freeze tag with them and and i think as <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> we probably we spend more
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> than is typical i think uh with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and part of that is that they're demanding of it you know they they want our time
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> enjoys you know doing those things with them he spends a lot of time with them and it seems to me anyway from observing other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> in the neighborhood that he spends a lot more time
 		i'd say on the average than um a lot of the dads do here and i think that's good i think it's real important
 	
 	
 		i think i think uh i think that is and and we we got involved really in in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> ways uh my oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>
 		i guess when she went uh was in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade brought home a note saying uh we're getting up a soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and we're getting a chance to play soccer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh so gee you know this was nineteen seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> and none of us had ever seen a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX> game so then so then we go out and watch it and she enjoys it and they play the fall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> season so she played <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two seasons</TIMEX> in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade and
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		was pretty good at it and then in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grade they said uh oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> moved away uh call all the parents and say well who's going to uh coach well no gee you know well we really don't have enough time for that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		uh oh
 	
 	
 		then about the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> call they said we want to know we're going to refund the contracts and the money for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because nobody's going to coach and think that's terrible so at that point you know you come forward
 		well that started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about a fifteen year</TIMEX> career of coaching uh coaching administering programs and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and i in addition to coaching i think when we finally finished up we were managing
 	
 	
 		oh my goodness
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> as our volunteer time managing a program with seventy <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> in it from grades uh kindergarten through twelfth grade and year around <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball softball soccer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i well i think that's really good though because i'm sure those are memories they'll always keep
 	
 	
 		oh they are are and and and you know my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty three year old</TIMEX> she's a senior in college and she comes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> and she just loves to pick out the picture book we took a lot of pictures at the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> do you remember that <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> grade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> we had that year <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> God we were great weren't we
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 		that's right i and i really uh i really think it's very important and i'm very sensitive to it because i always felt that my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> are more  uh old school and they were older parents
 		and they didn't do a lot of things with us that way and i always felt that i missed out that way and so i want to make sure
 		that we spend a lot of time doing activities with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i think a lot of times the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> have fun as well and uh you know now that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>'s coming of course i'm sure in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> it's already hot but up here
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		i'll say
 	
 	
 		well we've had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> we had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighty seven</NUMEX> which was extraordinarily hot for now but now we're back down to about fifty and it's raining here but um
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh you know soon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next end of next month</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pools</ENAMEX> are open the outdoor pools only open over the summer
 	
 	
 		yeah oh sure that'll help yeah
 	
 	
 		and that's an activity that i you know take up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and we're starting to hit some tennis balls around uh but as as they're getting more fun for us as well and i find that
 		starting to doing more of those types of things as they get a little bit older um but
 		yeah i was going to say what do you feel in general do you feel that um <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> are spending spending enough time with their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> or what changes do you
 	
 	
 		well now i i think that they're not uh uh i see too many uh you i recognize that yes a a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> need <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> incomes in fact my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>'s working as we the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> all start college and we're looking forward to the prospect of having <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> in there uh they they have to
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh both work but another activity that i found very rewarding and i don't know whether you've got it up there are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Guides</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> programs
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		popular in that area okay well what this is is it's it's really sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Y</ENAMEX> but it's nonsectarian uh is that it's the concept was
 	
 	
 		no no i haven't heard of that
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that i think it originally started with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian Guides</ENAMEX> and uh the idea was that dads are off working all the time and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> are left to raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		so uh uh it it it is a program that requires uh dads and just and it started out with with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		where they get together in what they call <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tribes</ENAMEX> which is a neighborhood with probably <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five or six maybe up to eight</NUMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father son</ENAMEX> combinations and they get together and and meet at each other's home uh maybe uh twice a month
 	
 	
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh to uh uh have uh uh games and uh work on crafts and work on projects and and refreshments and you take <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> names and wear headbands and act like in and uh learn a little about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh things but then uh the highlight is that you go camping twice <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> like you go out to some uh camping spot and live outdoors uh in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the spring</TIMEX> and you like you go out on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and come back on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> and it is uh it's to force
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 		oh that's nice
 	
 	
 		uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> for a little a little bit and it's even to the point where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host family</ENAMEX> at the meetings at each other's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> have to provide uh uh have to provide refreshments and they've got to be cooked by you and you can't say <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> make some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cookies</ENAMEX> for us
 	
 	
 		oh i see
 	
 	
 		so part of the thing is when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> are hosting this meeting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> they have to plan it together what they're going to do when they're the host
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		
  
 	
 	
 		and what was interesting i got started in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Princesses</ENAMEX> now an offshoot to this was i think this program went on maybe for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years or so</TIMEX> and somebody got to thinking well it's even more important
 	
 	
 		i see
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		it's even more important for dads and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		to get involved in something like this because a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> think well you know i i i'll bring up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son mom</ENAMEX> and you bring up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they don't notice the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX> until they're <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX> or fifteen and start getting into trouble so uh uh because my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> one i really got into it with both of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> first
 	
 	
 		right yeah
 		i see
 	
 	
 		and uh we just had a ton of fun and i i look back now as i say the the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> are both in college but when they're here and we're we're talking about and we're digging out the old pictures books and my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty</TIMEX> we took a lot of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">eight millimeter</NUMEX> movies
 	
 	
 		oh that's good
 	
 	
 		of uh of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> camp and my uh uh my my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty three year old</TIMEX> has has hoarded all the movies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now and and</TIMEX> and just sets up the projector in her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and watches them every once in a while uh going back to things like that and
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		boy those these are so many
 		precious things that you can't ever buy back and and to answer your question
 	
 	
 		that's right
 		that's right
 	
 	
 		yeah i i don't see it we've got a lot of younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fa</ENAMEX> milies in our neighborhood and everybody's so busy out there making a living uh you can see why the well i know uh
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> who's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freshman</ENAMEX> in college <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year her last couple of years</TIMEX> in high school she made money money <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> sitting and you can tell by the number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that would have her come and and spend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh my goodness she went out on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> job she was only seventeen i can't believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lady</ENAMEX> gave it to her she said she interviewed nineteen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and she was the one she hired this was uh a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three week</TIMEX> old
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		oh boy
 	
 	
 		she went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> and and both these uh uh there were there was an only child
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were professional uh they were professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> i mean he was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> and she was a computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">programmer</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but she went to work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight o'clock in the morning</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX>'d get there at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven thirty</TIMEX> and have complete charge of this then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three week old</TIMEX> until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> came home at uh at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four or four thirty</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh my
 		yeah
 		right right yeah i think and i think that's uh uh part of the problem now i was uh uh i was in engineering myself um right now i'm taking uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> off but uh
 		it was it's very difficult even when i worked i insisted on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">working thirty hours</TIMEX> not forty so i was really considered
 		part time and that was kind of difficult because that concept when you get into professions like that isn't really there yet  so i really had to hound them for that i was a civil engineer
 	
 	
 		what what kind of engineering were you in
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		and it was really important for me to be able to be out in time to swing by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> and pick my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and of course the younger <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> was in day care but you find even working <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six hours a day</TIMEX> and not <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eight hours</TIMEX> or whatever that
 		it cuts into your time so much and what happens really is that even though i had the time with them in the evenings all the things that
 		you you you know normally you can get done during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> um you save up for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> so your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">whole weekend</TIMEX> that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> really want your attention
 		but you're saying oh can you go play now or whatever because you have so many things to catch up on
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and i think that's what you know i think it really uh that's what makes it very makes it difficult and uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s much more relaxed
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know and um a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said they've seen
 		very big changes in my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> for the better you know and um i think that you know i've i've done both sides and it's it's no matter what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say it it is too difficult
 		
 		
 	