
 
     		
 	
 		what do you think about the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> or public service commitment
 	
 	
 		uh that's the first i've ever heard of it i haven't heard of it
 		anything too much about it um
 	
 	
 		well i think it was uh thought up when there was so much controversy about reviving a draft and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> said well they uh young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were drafted have to
 		provide military service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> but there are an awful lot of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who would
 		benefit from um some sort of public service like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservation Corps</ENAMEX> back in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirties</TIMEX> or
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh various other things of that sort and it seems to me that it's it's not a totally bad idea but i don't quite see how they'd make it work
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		how would they decide who goes into uh building fire breaks in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Yosemite National Park</ENAMEX> and who goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		right yeah i the my first impression was um it would be very very good i think it would be good for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to serve but
 		i don't know if it should be an option it would be great to have some of those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> like you mentioned that were during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> or coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Depression</ENAMEX> available for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and i think there are some
 		available now where they are able to work but making it a mandatory thing
 	
 	
 		yeah the the difficulty would be in whether it's voluntary or involuntary and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who were proposing it said that it should be involuntary that it should be like a draft
 	
 	
 		kind of
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would get military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">service</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> would get civilian uh service like working in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> this i assume it's the kinds of things that they had conscientious objectors do
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were drafted and they refused to serve in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> they were allowed to do hospital service or uh things like that and if they refuse or farm work in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War One</ENAMEX> i remember
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh reading about and and i suppose that there is uh justification for taking everybody if you take anybody
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i just really think that the difficulties involved in paying them uh sorting them out assigning them training them would be insurmountable
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		it seems like you'd have a lot more conscientious conscientious objectors if they had that choice
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well  it's a possibility
 	
 	
 		yeah you know i'd i'd much rather work in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> than than to go to war and i'm sure most young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would and so uh
 	
 	
 		well i think that in the in the cases that like that uh they had to be
 		uh pretty thoroughly examined to prove that they had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pacifist</ENAMEX> and religious beliefs and so forth and that this wasn't something new just to keep out of going to war it was
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh something that was a fundamental part of their philosophy of life
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well that makes sense and then you run into again to um
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX> in running it you know how you going to cover that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because we've got a lot more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> now than we did then
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">sure</ENAMEX> and in addition to that we have the cost because you have to pay something
 	
 	
 		so
 		right
 	
 	
 		for their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> and then you have to pay them some kind of a stipend uh even if it's like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> where they don't get most of it until they come home you have to have to pay them something
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		plus the training involved yeah that would be expensive in most cases
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 		yeah now i had a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> uh back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid sixties</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		because
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it really did seem to be a worthwhile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> but on the other hand i'm not sure what the permanent value of it was i don't know what we got for all the money
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		we had an awful lot of idealistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who went off to uh what was then <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">East Pakistan</ENAMEX> is now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bangladesh</ENAMEX> and to uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX> and to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Asia</ENAMEX> and lots of uh out of the way places but i don't know if they really had significant effects in the places where they went in teaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> how to cope with their lives better
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well i know in i personally took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year and a half</TIMEX> and went as a missionary and taught Christianity in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i was living such a stringent lifestyle that it was very beneficial to me it taught me not to be so self-centered and it you know to think of others
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't know if i was doing it
 		in different situation you know not a really religious background if if i would get a lot out of it you know i think i did because it you know it emphasized that sort of thing you know a lot of
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		self
 	
 	
 		and it was definitely voluntary too they were not drafting you and sending you against your will
 	
 	
 		evaluation but
 		right
 		right and that i'm sure that would make a big difference too
 	
 	
 		yeah well what about a voluntary program do you think that would be a good idea
 	
 	
 		you know we've got
 		um well like i say i know that there are some type of programs that they have available for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> to go
 		and do um work in the national <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX> and work in uh neighborhoods to do um clean up and that sort of thing but i don't know
 		what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> it's under i don't know if it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> run or if it's a private
 	
 	
 		i don't either
 	
 	
 		charity that's put it together but i know that that helps a lot with training and um
 	
 	
 		yeah out here in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> there's a program like that for uh juvenile <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delinquents</ENAMEX> the the ones that are not dangerous and they don't have to be locked up go to these uh camps
 	
 	
 		a lot of
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and they do forestry work they maintain <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">trails</ENAMEX> and they uh put up signs and they do fire prevention work and certainly things of that sort
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that i know is run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> but there may be other things i'm not so sure what kind of uh training that is for the future for those <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah how much benefit it'll do them in the long run
 	
 	
 		it's probably a a very good way to keep them off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> and out of trouble but whether it's something that they can put to to economic use later on is a different subject
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right especially in you know if you take a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> that's from the inner city and then put them in the a middle of a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> if they go back to the inner city they may not see <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> for a while much less be able to take care of them
 	
 	
 		that's true  good point
 		
 
 	
 	
 		so that's yeah so that may not may not benefit them in the long run
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah yeah i'm sorry i'm going to have to go but my other line is blinking but it was good to talk to you
 	
 	
 		but
 		okay well thank you you too bye-bye
 	
 	
 		bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	