
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		okay do you go camping very much
 	
 	
 		no i've haven't gone camping in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> but it's something that i've done in the past how about you
 	
 	
 		uh we try to go once maybe twice a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		well that that's pretty avid to me
 	
 	
 		we uh just you know for like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a short weekend</TIMEX> or something we don't go for the long you know week long thing
 	
 	
 		uh-hum
 	
 	
 		but uh we usually go to uh a lake area you know where the campsites are and do that uh
 	
 	
 		right
 		do you tent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> or do you have a camper
 	
 	
 		oh no no no a tent
 	
 	
 		that's what i i you know that's how i camp too that's how i define camping  the rest of the rest of that is really really not the same as a matter of fact my my my
 	
 	
 		me me too  you're really roughing it
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know the majority of the amount of camping i've done has been really roughing it um as a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> i'd go with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and we went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Boundary Waters</ENAMEX> area in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minnesota</ENAMEX> so
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		that's that's really wild
 	
 	
 		yeah are you here in local <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> i mean
 	
 	
 		yes i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> where are you
 	
 	
 		i'm in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Garland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		right outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> so we um we have a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five year old</TIMEX> and we started taking her she was pretty young when we started uh camping with her
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		oh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> love they they just love it it's wonderful for them to be outside
 	
 	
 		i know i know
 		i know and then they and they you know there's no TV and they don't have all these modern toys and they have to use sticks and rocks and stuff like that to play with
 	
 	
 		exactly yes
 	
 	
 		and i like that it's pretty fun
 	
 	
 		well how it really is a good a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> thing to do yeah  and
 	
 	
 		um-hum yeah we we try to uh go with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> that have
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> also and uh that makes it a lot more enjoyable plus you know we don't have to go out and buy all the equipment and stuff you know we kind of split it up uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		good planning
 	
 	
 		yeah  because it gets it really does get expensive if you if if you don't want to rough it all the way
 	
 	
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		you know even with sleeping bags those are running you know good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX> dollars a pop and so we've built that up but no want one bad do you
 	
 	
 		you're right you're right do you have a boat no
 		oh i well actually i would you know what i would love i would absolutely love a sail <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> that doesn't go along with camping but now that that that's what i would like to have
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		yes i would too
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		would too we usually uh like i said we try to go to a lake my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> and this uh other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> that we go with her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> um they like to um
 		is it scuba dive and so we'll go to a lake and uh  where they can go do that we're close enough so they can do that and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> can play on the beach area  okay
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		and i wanna play on the beach area too that's what i would do you know  i'm just sitting here listening listening to your accent and thinking what a good time the computer's going to have with that
 	
 	
 		yes yes that's fun
 		really  am i pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you're pretty <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> yes but you know you know what's really funny um i've had <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> tell me that i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> accent and i mean there just is no way i've not picked one up
 	
 	
 		no you don't you don't sound like it to me
 	
 	
 		i've only lived here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about six years</TIMEX> so if if if i have one it must be very very slight but  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> can hear it
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yes yes oh well that's true that's true i see i don't think i do but um
 		but a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do say i sound like i guess i have i guess more of a twang to my voice but sure am i've lived here all my life but anyway uh
 	
 	
 		um-hum are you a a native <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Texan</ENAMEX> oh well good for you
 		have you ever been to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yes yes we went <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> actually
 	
 	
 		there how was i'm wondering i'm really not that familiar i know there're some good places to go camping along the uh the lakes
 	
 	
 		oh is there okay well we didn't go camping we just uh we did like um
 		we drove down to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and went went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Galveston</ENAMEX> and uh to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and then up to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austin</ENAMEX> and and kind of uh you know doing the sight seeing type
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		stuff so we didn't go camping that would be fun though to go that's one thing my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> wanted to do was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>'s vacation was to go and camp wherever we went
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		and i said well i'd love that but
 	
 	
 		it takes a lot more planning
 	
 	
 		it does and and ever once you know on my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer vacation</TIMEX> you know my week long vacation i want to be a little bit pampered you know by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX> or whatever
 	
 	
 		um-hum right exactly exactly yeah
 	
 	
 		so we're hoping to do like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three day</TIMEX> weekend
 		there's um a thing called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pfeiffer Rim</ENAMEX> i don't know if you've ever heard of it
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		it's uh there's a town called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glenrose i</ENAMEX> think it's around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> from here and uh it's got it has like <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX> tracks
 	
 	
 		oh that sounds
 	
 	
 		and stuff like that and it's got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of those wildlife parks
 	
 	
 		that sounds great
 	
 	
 		yeah i think that'll be fun so we're going to try to do that like on a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three day</TIMEX> weekend go there and
 	
 	
 		have you ever camped out of state
 	
 	
 		no i haven't
 	
 	
 		you know where you should try sometime is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Colorado</ENAMEX> it is beautiful absolutely beautiful
 	
 	
 		where
 		is it
 		i've just been up there skiing and well we've driven through you know but but not you know camping or anything but i would love to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in the mountains
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Estes State Park</ENAMEX> is fantastic
 	
 	
 		that's what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX> says yes she loves that place she loves that she says that's where we need to go sometime
 	
 	
 		well see you need to go there
 		it is it's you know it's it's high canyon and uh and there's this little mountain lakes and it's very peaceful and um in in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early fall</TIMEX> time um
 	
 	
 		oh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i can't remember what type of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX> they are but they all the leaves turn yellow and it's just brilliant and yes you would you'd like it very much i know you would
 	
 	
 		oh i love that
 		that's neat that's neat
 		well i used to go camping all the time as a a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Girl Scout</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i was too
 	
 	
 		all the time i got real used to it then i felt like we roughed it then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		uh well we did well we did you know we really did i mean i just don't understand these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that think taking an <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">RV</ENAMEX> and parking it and sitting inside and watching TV and having your microwave it's not camping
 	
 	
 		right
 		yes
 		exactly i mean we had to make the fires and dig latrines and everything
 	
 	
 		exactly right right i mean that is it
 	
 	
 		you have to get poison ivy and all that good stuff to really be camping  yeah well do you you haven't say you haven't been in years
 	
 	
 		right  oh
 		no i haven't i'm um i'm a struggling single <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> and um yeah thank you um it's you know time is precious money's precious <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">um</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh gosh bless your heart
 		
 
 		yes
 	
 	
 		it it it it i just haven't haven't been able to do it and you know what that was one of the things i really
 		thought i'd like to do with my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> you know again and the i'm a little bit fearful of trying that just <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> you know i i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		i don't blame you i don't blame you at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all years ago</TIMEX> it would have been fine but
 	
 	
 		yeah and i i really now now now i i have gone on one little vacation just the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> and i we drove down to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Port Aransas</ENAMEX> and rented a little efficiency you know and and had a marvelous like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two nights</TIMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		that was great and even at that it it was like the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time that i ventured you know out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> by myself and and you know i i stayed in a nice place but it's still it's real different not to have another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> with you
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yes i know i can imagine  no i don't blame you not nowadays
 	
 	
 		you know i'm just a chicken i know lots of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> would do it all the time but i haven't i haven't quite adjusted you know
 	
 	
 		yeah now are you with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> down there
 	
 	
 		well i i was with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> i uh i left <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> hoping to strike out and find a job where i could make some money
 	
 	
 		good
 	
 	
 		so well it it was a it it was a good plan but i haven't yet  i got into sales and i'm selling um telephone systems
 	
 	
 		have you
 		okay
 		oh
 		oh that's neat
 	
 	
 		and it's it's fun and it's interesting but it also um pretty challenging and i haven't i haven't started making money yet
 	
 	
 		hum it's hard isn't it
 	
 	
 		so yeah it's it's hard so
 	
 	
 		now how old are your girls
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fourteen</NUMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh goodness they're
 	
 	
 		yeah so i'm old  oh
 	
 	
 		oh you're not old  you're not old at all
 	
 	
 		well excuse me just second  honey i'll be with yeah go ahead
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some one</NUMEX> at the door so well i'm i'm going to listen we always
 	
 	
 		oh okay do you need to go
 	
 	
 		check and see if we should answer the door at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> so yeah so well i've enjoyed this and uh
 	
 	
 		yeah well that's very smart
 		yeah me too and good luck how many have you made so far calls
 	
 	
 		i i haven't made any i've been just a recipient
 	
 	
 		oh have you oh well this is only about my <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> one i've ever made i've been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipient</ENAMEX> on the others how many have you had so far do you know
 	
 	
 		i think i've had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about four</NUMEX> yeah yeah yeah it's  well you know when i had to set huh this is my my Gemini nature you know it's like what are you interested in and it's like virtually anything i'll talk about anything with anybody
 	
 	
 		<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> that's good very good
 		yes
 		yeah i don't
 	
 	
 		and it's it's been real interesting the different personalities that i that i run across
 	
 	
 		you bet you bet
 		i know
 		yes i always try to find out where they're from you know because it because it is neat neat it really is well then i guess i'll let you go so you can go get the door and
 	
 	
 		exactly
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well thank you and um i enjoyed talking with you you have a good time camping when you go next time think of me  all right bye-bye
 	
 	
 		you me too
 		thank you okay thank you bye-bye
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	