
 
     		
 	
 		
  
 	
 	
 		well this is a good subject isn't it it it's something that you can really talk about um i don't know what we're going to do about it but it's certainly something that has a lot of things to talk about
 	
 	
 		yeah it is
 		yeah
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um
 		you know when they say the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> it's such a big area and there's so many different problems there
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		um what do you want to concentrate on
 	
 	
 		it doesn't matter to me
 	
 	
 		well um i'll tell you something um i i have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and and they're really quite um
 		arrogant about it all they they believe that they they belong there and they've belonged there forever and
 		the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arabs</ENAMEX> are
 		um more or less they they they consider them <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> class
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		so they're really quite arrogant about it i don't uh
 		i don't know if that contributes to the problem
 	
 	
 		well how did they feel about the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> intervening intervening with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Patriot</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> did did they
 	
 	
 		oh uh i'm sure i'm sure it this is the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> time that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> are really happy to have their big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i didn't really talk about that with her she um um my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister-in-law</ENAMEX> now lives in um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		but um when they were living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> it was
 		it was the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX> they they come in
 		and they're they're nothing but really <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> for them and and they really treat them like <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> class citizens
 		they they don't really want them around but they like them around because they do all the menial labor and such but they they really do they look down on them and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i don't know being i i live in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vermont</ENAMEX> and being up here we pretty much treat everybody
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know as someone that has merit even if they are poor or if they're <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> or if they're Black we give everybody pretty much the benefit of the doubt
 		because we don't see all the crime and all the hurt in the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> you know if
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh if i lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">DC</ENAMEX> i think i'd have a different attitude about Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> because i've heard that it it the
 		they're terrible you know it's just like it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> eat dog world
 		and here you know all my all my Black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> and they're they don't you know they don't go out and abuse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and they they send their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to school and they
 		they just they uh you know really encourage them to go to college and stuff so it's just a different world
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		well i live in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> and fifty percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> is minority
 	
 	
 		oh um i talked to someone about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and um they said that they they have you have quite the problem with uh
 		the ghettos i don't know they call it the barrio down there
 	
 	
 		that's the barrios but it's it's it's i don't think it's any different of a problem than any other major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> it's just
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> here instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blacks</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah well i heard that that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX> unlike like like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Diego</ENAMEX> it seems it just has it a really bad problem
 		i i i
 	
 	
 		i grew up outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> and i don't think uh as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> violence and things i don't think it's any worse here than in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah like say <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> now i would now me not even knowing anything about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX> i would think that it's a pretty calm city
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Houston</ENAMEX> is not at all
 	
 	
 		no huh there's a lot of crime
 	
 	
 		yes there's quite a bit of crime
 	
 	
 		oh my um
 		yeah like i uh we're we're so protected up here it's it's really strange i mean our red light district
 		i mean uh you could go walking around down there and pretty much not fear for your life you know and we're just so protected
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but
 		it's it's it's
 		over in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid East</ENAMEX> especially <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> it's just like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> have a like a totalitarian system when it comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>
 		you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israelis</ENAMEX> can do anything they want but when it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinians</ENAMEX>
 		if they're out in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> it's it's really looked on as odd
 		um usually they're they're bussed in to the the um <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> neighborhoods and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX> and then at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> they're bussed out to the occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">territories</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		hum
 	
 	
 		so they don't have that but um
 		what what do you think about the mess that's we've created in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think it's unfortunate uh as far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> are concerned it
 	
 	
 		it's just what do you do for them you want to do something for them but you don't want to get so directly involved that you're occupying the the country
 	
 	
 		i
 		you can't
 		yeah
 		yeah we can't get involved in their civil war
 		um
 		unfortunately but we've kind of driven these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out
 	
 	
 		to do it yeah but you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is telling them rebel you know um uprise uprise and that's what they did
 		and now they're like asking him for help
 		and he's like no we can't get involved what what my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> had very strong feelings he he he he uh agreed with um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Schwartzkopf</ENAMEX>
 		he said um that he should have let that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> should have let him finish his job
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		he should've let he should've let them um corner the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Guards</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		well i think the war ended too soon
 	
 	
 		yeah exactly that's what everyone says
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		everyone everyone i talk to they say you know it's real easy to say that
 	
 	
 		we we didn't damage enough of their arsenal we damaged most of it  but we we should have gotten made sure we got everything
 	
 	
 		yeah i don't think the higher ups were thinking about what what this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s going to do with the rest of his war machine they're going oh well it's not going to hurt us so we're just going to let them go
 		but really we didn't think about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that he was gonna
 		try and i mean he he's just
 	
 	
 		unfortunately though the the original goal of the mission was to drive them out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kuwait</ENAMEX> and once that was accomplished
 	
 	
 		they yeah they they did they stuck right to their goals and right what they were going to say and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> when this first started they were even reluctant to let them do that so they were they were playing it very safe but
 	
 	
 		it
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it an ounce what do they say an ounce of hind sight is worth you know whatever whatever they they
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know they it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartzkopf Schwartzkopf</ENAMEX> knew what had to be done and it's too bad that he just didn't have the ability just to do it to you know the uh the go ahead to do it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		because he had the few he knew what was going to happen more than any of us because i didn't realize that um it was going to make such a mess
 		i mean i feel really sorry for these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are middle class <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> just like us can you imagine if someone started bombing your neighborhood and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and you knew this these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are going to come and if you were in your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> they were going to take you and beat you of course you're gonna just gonna pick everything up that you can carry and you're going to run
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it it's just too bad that we couldn't see that
 	
 	
 		i just have a feeling that the military involvement isn't over yet that i i still feel like there's more to come i don't think this whole issue is settled as far as we're concerned
 	
 	
 		well you know what i was hoping i was hoping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> was going to take a very um dramatic stand and invade
 		you know and and like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s the big bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you know but really if if they were going to save <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives
 	
 	
 		they've got <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty or so</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s planes
 	
 	
 		yeah i know it's like they were using them as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
 		when we were having the conflict but i i you know it's almost where
 		i'm kind of disappointed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX> why they didn't go save save i mean i don't know if the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurdish</ENAMEX> i know the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiite's</ENAMEX> are their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> but i don't know i think they have a bond with the the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		there are some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		yeah i i think they should have just done more
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and maybe if the world could have given them some type of aid it's it's just so complicated
 	
 	
 		i'm just real surprised that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> stayed out of it
 		as as much as they did
 	
 	
 		oh yeah well you knowing them they're very um oh i don't know almost compare them to a very egotistical man well damn right i'm going to protect my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> you know so
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i i i was amazed too i was really i was really um proud of them though that they stayed out of it but
 	
 	
 		yeah it from from what i can tell if they had gotten into it it would have
 		started a whole new war
 	
 	
 		oh it would have messed
 		yeah i was i that really that part scared me that that um the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptians</ENAMEX> would pull out and i just saw atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		
 		
 	