
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		yeah um
 	
 	
 		okay
 		i'm uh we're not that we're not that big at dining out but uh  in fact i guess since since uh we don't make it uh uh
 		make a big hobby of it or anything we're we're really into uh we're interested in economy and uh you know a nice enough atmosphere that you can carry on a conversation
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		good food i mean that's important too
 	
 	
 		yeah that sounds about what we i mean
 		we go out to places i mean we don't go to places where we all dress up and all that you know and all that we try to get uh you know some place that you know that's a little better than home and all but you know it's not going to cost a ton of money either
 	
 	
 		right
 		right
 		yeah well well we've got <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and so uh
 		and so uh i guess there's there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> kinds of dining out there's dining out with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and dining out without the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		huh
 		all right
 	
 	
 		and uh when we're dining out with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> the the great places are those where you you know i don't uh are you uh you in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		no i'm in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX> well they've got a couple of places here i'm in i'm calling from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> um
 		there's a place that you know i can feed the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> of us for under fifteen dollars and and it's all you can eat and uh that that's the kind of place that you take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to
 	
 	
 		yeah  well i'd go there  all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> i mean how how old are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they they range from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> and
 	
 	
 		that's pretty impressive
 	
 	
 		uh yeah oh well i i was amazed because we lived uh i'd lived uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> i was born and raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> and then uh we spent uh about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and dining out especially with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> has always been a major you know thing
 	
 	
 		yeah we're we're having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> and it's like well you know no more no more eating out for a while
 	
 	
 		oh
 		right
 		but uh i was i was just amazed there's this one place called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CC</ENAMEX>'s pizza
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and it's all you can eat and it's for for grown ups its like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> dollars and it's like i don't even think it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four dollars</NUMEX> it's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">three dollars</NUMEX> and something and for the for the the uh
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight year old</TIMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> it's
 		it's like uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two dollars</NUMEX> and something and for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> it's a dollar something
 	
 	
 		oh that's incredible
 	
 	
 		and it's all you can eat and it's decent <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>  you know and it comes with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> bar too but i mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salad</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> is essentially <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lettuce</ENAMEX> and carrots
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but uh but you know it's good enough to eat  and then um
 		there's uh another place called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pancho</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Course</ENAMEX> they have to have <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food and uh the uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		the uh the grown ups eat for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four dollars</NUMEX> and something and the and the uh the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> eat for uh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">two dollars</NUMEX> and something and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four year old</TIMEX> eats for free
 		and uh the grown ups get all you can eat and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> have to have can only have like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> items
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but you go sit down at a table the great thing about this is you sit down at the table and they have a little <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> flag and when you raise the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> flag the waiter comes over and he just gives you whatever you want
 		
 
 	
 	
 		we got to look around here find out if there's anything like that around here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh you'll find something like that uh especially when you have kids
 	
 	
 		that's
 		yeah that's incredible i mean we just we're like well we're not going out for a while you know my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> live close you know fairly close here so it's like well we if we're going out to dinner we can drop the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> off at my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		
 
 		yeah
 		
 
 		i know
 	
 	
 		and  it's like oh great grandpa you know
 	
 	
 		well <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland Maryland</ENAMEX> has some i mean um <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> has some great <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seafood</ENAMEX> doesn't it
 	
 	
 		yeah there's um there's a place i live just outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> in a town called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Olicott City</ENAMEX> and uh there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seafood place</ENAMEX> here called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crab Shanty</ENAMEX> that's really good it's like rated higher than like the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">seafood restaurants</ENAMEX> down in the inner <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">harbor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> you know the the trendy section of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		wow
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh you know we've eaten there sometimes and it's pretty good it's you know it's a little more expensive than than i normally like to spend plus the other thing is i'm not uh i'm not a big seafood fan
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		so you know it's like great we go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crab Shanty</ENAMEX> and i'm going to have veal you know
 	
 	
 		oh
 		
 
 		so what's what's eating out cheap for you is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX> or something like that
 	
 	
 		not that bad there's some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> actually we've been we end up doing a lot is uh
 		there's a couple of places around that are like uh yuppie i mean it it seems like a big thing now with uh with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX> uh
 	
 	
 		diners oh yeah the back to the fifties
 	
 	
 		yeah there's um there's a place up in my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> actually live up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX> and there's a place up there that we like to go to called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">um The Hop</ENAMEX> which is you know just a fifties diner basically and then there's um a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> around here called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silver Diner</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		right yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> and you know you and uh let's see there's another one up in uh just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralphie</ENAMEX>'s Diner
 	
 	
 		huh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralphie</ENAMEX>'s
 	
 	
 		yeah um it was fun i'm uh i'm a baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> i you know my my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girlfriend</ENAMEX>'s like you know she she puts up with me being a baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> you know but uh we go we walk into this place <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralphie's Diner</ENAMEX> and i look on the wall and there's like uh
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		there's like uh like a relief of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">of</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who Ralphie's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diner</ENAMEX> is named after and it turns out he used to work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> and she's like no not more baseball
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		oh no kidding
 		
 
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but um all these places you know you can get like you know a hamburger or um you know um i've had <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> and meatloaf at all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX> and you know we usually get out of there for around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> bucks
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's okay yeah
 	
 	
 		you know it's good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> and everything and um you know you get malts or whatever so it's really good you know my only big gripe is every time i've gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Silver Diner</ENAMEX> i have tried to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana cream pie</ENAMEX> and they they are always out
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		always out yeah we had a place like that that had uh in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> it was called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill's Barbecue</ENAMEX> and they had the grest
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">banana cream pie</ENAMEX> and it was was uh you could take it home it was was just it was so popular it was great stuff
 		and now now my mouth mouth's watering i'm beginning to think about that  yeah the uh yeah twenty dollar that's
 	
 	
 		oh sorry
 	
 	
 		we can do pretty that's that's what we try to aim for just the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of us or naw you know if we want to have some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> or something we start get into the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty dollar</NUMEX> range i guess and
 	
 	
 		well neither of us are big <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wine</ENAMEX> d rinkers yeah we went out <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX> and i had a you know i had a beer and and you know obviously since you know she's we're not we've been kind of laying off the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> since she's expecting and all that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah sure sure
 	
 	
 		but we i mean even before i mean usually we you know we might have a beer but that's about it so
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah that's the same well we'll go to a place and of course being in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> we'll go to a place and the big thing is frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">margaritas margaritas</ENAMEX> and uh so we'll have some nachos and drink and they they serve these margaritas in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		i don't know do do you ever go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Johnson</ENAMEX>'s in uh i i don't know if there are even any <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Johnson</ENAMEX>'s around any more you used to get an ice cream sundae in that big old goblet
 	
 	
 		yeah there are
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well that's how that's what they serve these margaritas in these frozen margaritas it's just huge things
 	
 	
 		yes i've seen them
 		i know that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi Chi</ENAMEX>'s has margaritas in big glasses like that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah yeah <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi Chi</ENAMEX>'s they they have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi Chi</ENAMEX>'s down here too but that's that's sort of looked down upon because they're a chain
 	
 	
 		oh oh
 		yeah well i i i would i mean you know they've got them out here because it's you know  they don't actually know what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> you know what <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> is here
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right yeah right
 		well i didn't either i mean you know to me <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pancho</ENAMEX>'s where i can where i can eat for less than fifteen bucks to me that's gourmet and everybody i say i went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pancho</ENAMEX>'s they all down at me down their noses you know it's like uh it's all right with me
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		well we've been to some what what have been rated fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> and uh they were good i have to say they were good
 	
 	
 		huh
 		yeah i've got to try i um
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> um we we're uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> were um
 		we were visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> or something and i remember being taken to a real fancy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> there called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senor</ENAMEX> something  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Senor Pico</ENAMEX> or something like that and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 	
 	
 		you know i hated everything at the time i just hated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> food i'd i'd love to go to some place like that now where it's you know a real <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> and see if i like it
 	
 	
 		did you
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah
 		yeah what kind of what kind do you like uh like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> or
 	
 	
 		i um i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> and i should experiment more the problem is that my favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX> in the world is cashew <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> so any time i go to a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> i want cashew chicken
 	
 	
 		oh yeah my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> too
 		that's her favorite too  yeah you know it's funny with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> since you can't read the menu or anything you tend to stick with one thing i used to it used to always be sweet and sour <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pork</ENAMEX> for me and then i just i i started getting a little more health conscious
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and i try to uh you know try something else you know something with a little more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vegetables</ENAMEX>  or something but yeah i was the same way but we haven't really eaten <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> that much since we've been in uh <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> it's funny
 	
 	
 		i was just thinking the same thing it's like we haven't had <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> in a while let's have a shake up we get this uh there's this take out <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> place that i mean you know stone's throw from my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		yeah right
 		yeah
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh we can get they do this thing for dinner for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> where we can get like <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">um Kung Pao</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> you know it's a big you know container full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kung</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Pao</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken um pork fried rice</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two egg</TIMEX> rolls and like you know
 	
 	
 		um
 		yeah
 		um
 	
 	
 		you know i don't know a pint or <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two pints</NUMEX> or whatever of a wanton <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> for like twelve fifty
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		ooh what a deal yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah it's great
 		we should have done that tonight
 	
 	
 		that sounds great
 		well you know it's funny because the grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> down the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> it's one of these you know super grocery <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> they have a a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> take-out
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		in the corner of it and the food's decent but it's expensive i think especially since it's all take out
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh yeah i'm well i like <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> food too but you don't there aren't that many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> around here
 	
 	
 		there's um
 		i'm trying to think there's a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> real close but we've never gone there because i'm not
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		oh i'm you know i'm not a big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> you know i i don't eat
 	
 	
 		i'm into quantity and French the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurants</ENAMEX> aren't
 	
 	
 		yeah well i also i also don't do snails so
 	
 	
 		
 
 		right
 	
 	
 		it seems to me there's an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">deli</ENAMEX> nearby that's pretty good uh
 	
 	
 		well of course when we
 		
 		
 	