
 
     		
 	
 		the uh whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> thing seems to be uh
 		a bit of a system whereby the the natural human greed was able to flourish and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were able to do some things that
 		that uh they they felt that since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> was backing them they could just uh go ahead and make these transactions and make these loans and get all this money as it were
 		and it was rather difficult to catch all if if any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that were really responsible for it and even those who were caught didn't seem to get get much in the way of punishment as far as getting a restitution made
 		so it seems like a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a really</TIMEX> set up you know the whole thing was set up to to be abused and so human nature did so
 	
 	
 		yeah i think the
 		oh yeah
 		yeah i think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is it's own worst enemy about the time it was all going on they were trying to run a loose monetary policy anyhow to stimulate the economy and plus they had cut back on the way of government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> to even investigate or keep a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">watchdog</ENAMEX> on the whole industry
 		and uh i think the whole economic situation was set up to uh put the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> in the position they were in and they mainly the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> too
 		uh economically we had gotten into pretty unsound conditions and so the idea of trying to make the money supply good and loose
 		via whatever medium whether it be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> either one was the order of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>  so needless to say they did
 		and uh since they didn't really regulate it well or watch it well uh by cutting back on uh government uh uh
 		uh monitoring in that respect then it did get out of hand and you're right you're absolutely right there were some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who saw the situation for what it was and they took advantage of it
 		and uh because of it you and i are the main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> now are going to have to pay not only for the burden of the bad investments that they made
 		but we're going to have to pay for the uh mistakes in the uh uh taking advantage of the system to some of these well really when you get right down to it crooks
 		uh uh took advantage of the system with
 		and yeah they've seem to caught a few i i've heard on TV or read in uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> about a couple of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> i forget the
 		the name of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of them but i heard that they did uh
 		prosecute him and maybe a couple of others i think you all had a major crisis down there in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> right
 	
 	
 		yeah there were quite a few down here mainly by
 		just because of the sheer numbers that were here and you know the and the chances of getting a bad one would be greater just out of the sheer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> of them being here and the whole problem seemed to start start toward uh
 		uh not that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> was the instigator of it but it seemed to start out that way and then then work its way here and it wasn't kind of funny that it wasn't a national problem until it hit the east coast
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		yeah that's always interesting isn't it see he's right
 	
 	
 		you know when it started hitting the big <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and the up then it became a nationwide problem and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> got to do something but
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh Texas</ENAMEX> is on basically on the way to recovery as far as uh the banking industry goes and they
 	
 	
 		oh i'm glad to hear that because i've been concerned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> may be going the same direction that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> primarily because uh what got the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> in trouble is the same sort of things that's beginning to get the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> in trouble
 		and that was uh the real estate uh backing in investment and just <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in general backing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> and those kinds of uh corporations
 		uh who were trying to build a lot of uh uh rental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> space and uh mall type space and things like that and uh it looked like in the seventies that that was going to be a real booming thing uh a infinitum i guess
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh anybody if they just stop and use a little common sense would realize well you can't soak up this much real estate
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and continue to have this kind of growth indefinitely i mean you you it's it's like anything eventually reach sort of a plateau where you've overbuilt if you're not careful
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh</ENAMEX> and uh it it's as if uh they went crazy just just like in gambling almost
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and there there was no
 		regulation or anything like that uh
 		i i frankly though and and i'm glad to hear you say what you said about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> because i have been concerned that the banking system
 		uh which is going through some economic difficulty now
 		and with all the foreign investments that they uh put money into also  i i've been concerned that the banking system is going to find itself in dire straits
 		or if they even didn't find themselves in dire straits we're going to find ourselves with so much of our money
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uh</ENAMEX> lent out to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owners</ENAMEX> who are willing to soak up some of this this uh capital to keep us afloat you might say hoping to make a buck off of us in interest in the future
 		but uh we find our own economic economy even though it may not have slipped into so so some kind of either deflationary or inflationary depression
 		uh we find ourselves having
 		sold out our futures in terms of what we are going to have to pay off all this debt with to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who have the money to build to buy up all the debt
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh i'm glad to hear that you do you know uh how uh they're beginning to get over the feet in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> are are is a lot of the money in loans and and the like that uh uh is that being covered by foreign investments maybe or or uh
 	
 	
 		well part of the problem as i see it uh my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s involved in  in both industries as it were i've i've got a grandfather that was in the
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S and L</ENAMEX> back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the sixties</TIMEX> and the seventies and in another part of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> and in a uh
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		my
 		immediate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were both in banking as it were and so uh we've
 		we've kept up with the industry as it were and the the feeling has been in some of the discussions that that get started on that topic has been that
 		you know we went through the the bad times of a number of bad loans and fortunately the the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Ls</ENAMEX> that uh our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> were associated with really didn't have that much problem they were fairly conservative and
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		they just had to ride out the storm with the the reputational problems that came with the news media as it were and
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		uh
 		there were a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> that made the bad loans and basically it's been a good weeding out process there's just been a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> a lot of whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> that were going to make these kinds of loans
 		and
 		and they are no longer in business uh so you know you you have some all your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> failures that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s having to take over you know that's gone up in the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred and</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty or thirty or so</TIMEX> for the state
 	
 	
 		yeah it's been quite a few every year
 	
 	
 		yeah and that's pretty well leveled off and and the that's
 	
 	
 		well do you think maybe it's peaked you think
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i don't think there's going to be that many more of them i i would
 	
 	
 		so you you you you would uh predict based on at least your knowledge and experience that in time we'll see the numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> too if they're still failing
 		uh
 		that that that the the number beginning to sort of taper off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> instead of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two hundred</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> you begin to see it go down to maybe fifty to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a hundred a year</TIMEX> and maybe
 	
 	
 		right right there's just not that many more
 	
 	
 		what kind of time frame frame would you
 		guess that's going to take
 		to wring itself out
 	
 	
 		well it's hard to say how many more bad bad <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX> or bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">apples</ENAMEX> there are out in the system but i would i'd be willing to bet that uh it shouldn't be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more than a couple more years</TIMEX> that that
 	
 	
 		oh you think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> i i would have guessed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> but you really think <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		well the
 		as far as as far as not having this getting over this peak as it is now uh there's still going to be an unusual
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		you know it depends on how far back you want to go let's say if you went back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX> and said here's a failure rate we could live with well then it may take us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three to five years</TIMEX> to get back to that level of failure
 	
 	
 		oh okay
 	
 	
 		but if you want to just say we're over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">hump</ENAMEX> and we're starting to get better i think in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> it'll be quite obvious that we're over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">hump</ENAMEX> and getting better
 	
 	
 		well tell me well all this all these bad loans and debts that
 		uh i i know in the case of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loans</ENAMEX> we're just going to have to pick it up as American taxpayer
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and the likes some some of those are merging and uh uh the the
 		the the basic question i'm trying to get to is all this bad money
 		that's essentially not going to get paid back
 		how's it going to get covered
 	
 	
 		i'm not sure if uh
 	
 	
 		i mean is inflation going to make some of it go away and the rest of it we're going to pick up the tab as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> or are we going to be able to sell some of these bad loans or pick them up somehow or another
 		uh uh by foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> uh buying pieces of our our economy like buying some of our been to some of our banks
 		uh like the things that uh i forget the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>'s name downtown here uh was involved in those <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> i think that was in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Georgia</ENAMEX> or someplace
 		uh what what what how do see that this this indebtedness of which is bad loans and the like just not going to get paid back at least by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who caused the debt
 		uh you you can't just write that off completely you can write off a certain part of it i guess but you just can't just write off the whole somewhere along the line you've got to recoup some of that money some of the even if it's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty five</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">fifty cents</NUMEX> on the dollar
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		how how how's that going to happen
 	
 	
 		well like one <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> i heard just talking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> on the topic was saying that that there wasn't any one given
 		uh you know sort of like a uh
 		suit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> making a uh suit for you it it's custom made to the individual situation if you
 		you don't try to find well write off all these to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> or have have the
 		the entire uh bank failure covered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> so you you take each individual situation yeah and if you can find a foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> or if you can find any investor that'll that'll finance i guess that's what the majority of the uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RTC</ENAMEX> is doing is trying to
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		to resolve all these individual cases in any way possible i mean they're looking for
 	
 	
 		how good a job do you think they're doing because you know there's been quite a bit in the various news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX> up here and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and various places about uh how they felt that the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> on the committee
 		were sort of selling out at uh exorbitantly exorbitantly low prices to some rather astute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> some of this had been misinterpreted who were tending the who were really tend to make the nice killing off that how do you how do you feel about that
 	
 	
 		well i was i was talking with another gentleman about that same topic it's hard to get a feel for what's going on in a nationwide uh system like that when the news media reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">segments</ENAMEX> that they report you know you hear
 	
 	
 		yeah mainly they look for the the wild news
 	
 	
 		yeah you hear things like uh the
 		
 		
 	