
 
     		
 	
 		
 
 		um she asked if i i guess they went ahead and told you we're supposed to be talking about uh drug testing and what do we think about the policy of most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and of course that's something we're familiar with
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		you want to go ahead or
 	
 	
 		okay go ahead no no go ahead
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">um</ENAMEX> personally it was something that uh
 		i mean i know it presents an emotional issue moral issue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> feel like maybe my rights are being violated but i work in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human resources</ENAMEX>
 		so i work with a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> that um are in accidents or where safety considerations are concerned and
 	
 	
 		okay yeah
 	
 	
 		i really feel like that <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX>'s decision to go with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> testing was good you know because i i feel like that you know well all all it takes is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> coming to work under the influence of some narcotic um
 		truly injure a lot more of our workers
 	
 	
 		yeah and that's that's funny you're in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">human resources</ENAMEX> and i'm in uh health and safety
 	
 	
 		are you
 	
 	
 		yes um
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		i think it's a good idea i i i don't think that they've gone far enough though i think they should they should uh also test for alcohol
 	
 	
 		well now the thing you you know course they've always said separately that um
 		you know we have a we have a policy on alcohol course if anybody's under the uh influence or if you have reasonable suspicion then that would result in corrective action for them also and that of course has been in place for years
 	
 	
 		right but
 	
 	
 		but it's not specifically tested for that
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		no and and from everything that i can gather you know reading different articles and and just a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> in general uh
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh news on the um television
 		it seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> is the is the most prevalent um addictive addictive drug
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		even though the all the college <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campuses</ENAMEX> now the they're saying that the majority of of uh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> uh drink
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and most of them are partying
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but yet we don't test for that and i wonder if we don't do that because it is so prevalent and would put probably lose
 		<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a quarter</TIMEX> of all our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> here
 	
 	
 		how long does alcohol stay in the system i mean like if somebody went out and had some drinks <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before is that going to be there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		
 
 		well they say your system a normal a normal person
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		should be able to metabolize an ounce of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> per hour
 	
 	
 		okay
 	
 	
 		and then again it it depends depends on the the bigger you are and you know the more bulk that you have you you can your system can tolerate more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> so a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> can probably
 		um
 		metabolize maybe a little bit more
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		than a smaller person
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		but even that yeah if you go out you know because some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go out maybe
 		
 
 		oh you know they drink up a gallon
 	
 	
 		yeah they do
 	
 	
 		um
 		what's what's the uh consensus down there when when <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">uh TI</ENAMEX> announced that uh the drug testing program did you get a lot of uh animosity against that
 	
 	
 		we had
 		i didn't get a lot no not like i expected um
 		we had you know one or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> that were extremely outspoken you know felt like it really violated their rights and and um
 		and it was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that i would have expected um it's uh one of them stands out in my mind as an extremely uh
 		just a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super person</ENAMEX> in management you know and he's he's very family oriented his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s very close he
 		he also opposes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> like for his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> because he says you know we are a good <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Christian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> we do not do this type of thing it definitely violates our rights and he was very outspoken
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		but for the most part <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were like well i don't like it uh it's not something i prefer to do but i understand the reasoning and i think part of the attitude is that i think <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> went to really great lengths
 		in communicating and tried to prepare them and and tell them why and you know they didn't just announce it without really any forethought
 	
 	
 		yes no that's you're right yeah
 	
 	
 		and uh i i think they don't go far enough uh kind of on a different vein and that is that i think every time we have any type of industrial accident at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> i think somebody ought to be tested immediately
 		and you know maybe that's just me personally but i i feel like
 	
 	
 		sure that's an idea too i just uh
 	
 	
 		you know i i feel like if something happens uh that causes an accident you ought to test the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> involved immediately just just if if nothing else to rule it out
 	
 	
 		yeah that's a that's a thought um i don't know if you can go
 	
 	
 		um
 	
 	
 		depends on the severity of the accident i think you know if you get like up here because we've got heavy industry we've got you know uh uh smelting
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> and we've got a
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		we've got a lot of uh metals rolling and slitting and stuff like that so we've got a lot of we are we end up with a lot of uh
 		hand injuries you know cuts and things like that but perhaps um
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		if you could weed out those the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that have chronic accidents and test those you know that's a start
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and that's a good idea that's a good point
 	
 	
 		i guess what makes me think of that you know uh you hear them doing that like it's a
 		or like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amtrak</ENAMEX> you know if if they have a derailment or or transportation industry it seems like if there's accidents train accidents things like that they test and i think well why not because we do have some large industrial accidents sometimes
 	
 	
 		yes
 	
 	
 		uh you know if you have a large <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> spill you know well gee maybe you better check this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who's handling all these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> you know i work with a wafer fab so we do a lot with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> and
 	
 	
 		oh okay yeah
 	
 	
 		uh things like that but i
 		i do feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are justified and i do feel like i i mean i i guess i hate as an individual that anything like this has ever become necessary in our you know in our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> but but i feel like that it's a good thing to do
 	
 	
 		well i can see transportation because now you're dealing with or they have the responsibility over a great
 		number of people
 	
 	
 		that's true
 	
 	
 		rather than themselves um
 		but but thinking on that yeah because we've got we've got <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX> here that go between plants you know locally
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and carry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> and they carry <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acids</ENAMEX> and things too
 	
 	
 		sure
 	
 	
 		um i don't know what the what the uh company <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> is they went through i guess key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> first
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and then it funneled down to uh the general population
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		now that started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January of last year</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i wonder if
 		yeah and i i still haven't been called yet in fact yeah in fact out of our office <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> is let's see there's uh <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four six</NUMEX> there's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of us and there's only one been called
 	
 	
 		is that right
 		well i've been lucky i've been called twice
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		well i
 	
 	
 		oh oh i i should probably shouldn't be talking to you then right
 	
 	
 		no i had to test once um when they did the key <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> they test all human resource <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> and so i i i was once there and then in the general random sampling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> i was i contacted
 	
 	
 		okay
 		and then you just got lucky again right
 	
 	
 		yeah and that you know i have that same uneasy feeling that other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> have you know i know i  i mean i don't drink i don't smoke i don't do nothing
 	
 	
 		yeah yeah i used to smoke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> but i don't now
 	
 	
 		you know but you still walk in there and go gee what if something i ate what if something i've done what if something i've eaten shows up
 	
 	
 		well it's not only that but i've read different articles and they said even the even the best of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> they come back with erroneous samples and even if they get a a reading i guess they test the same sample again
 	
 	
 		
 
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">um-hum</ENAMEX>
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		and they're going to get the same reading suppose they uh you know it's a
 		do they crucify you right then and there or do they do they go back and retest
 	
 	
 		well now if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> is making an error on the sample then when they retest the error should not be there
 		uh
 	
 	
 		but they retest the same sample
 	
 	
 		yeah but the error is on the part of the lab not on the sample in other words if somebody makes a mistake in what they're reading then they're not going to get the same reading the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> time
 	
 	
 		oh i see oh okay
 		but if they do then you're you're pretty well
 	
 	
 		if they do then you have you always have the recourse um you know before we do anything we sit down and talk with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> about is there any reason why this should have shown up and a lot of times you know uh
 	
 	
 		condemned right
 		to be retested
 	
 	
 		they'll go oh yeah i was on a prescription for this and they can go get it and bring it in
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		you know in which case they're fine obviously those are recorded as negatives if you're under you know legal qualified medical care
 		um
 	
 	
 		yeah but i often wondered wondered about that too
 	
 	
 		if if we're talking marijuana if it's in the system uh then
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		yeah you know that would be grounds for uh if it's their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> positive it would be grounds for termination if it's their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> positive then they're setup with <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">E A P</ENAMEX> counseling
 	
 	
 		do you know of any incidences of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> of uh erroneous
 	
 	
 		uh we've had a couple
 	
 	
 		you know something they they make a mistake the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> made a mistake and it really wasn't nothing
 	
 	
 		no
 		no in fact see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> actually sends uh test samples from time to time
 		uh
 	
 	
 		oh just to see just just to check on a lab
 	
 	
 		just to check the validity of the lab yeah
 		and uh so that's kind of an ongoing test process for the we do for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compucam</ENAMEX> and you know they don't know which ones are test samples
 	
 	
 		uh
 		we must be
 		yeah we must be doing the same up here too we we're probably send to a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> than you <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> down there
 	
 	
 		yeah
 		
 
 		i don't think so i think the whole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> uses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compucam</ENAMEX> which is over there on the east coast somewhere
 	
 	
 		oh
 	
 	
 		and ours actually are mailed there uh  they're the
 		i think the largest and they do a lot of the government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">contractors</ENAMEX> they have an excellent excellent rate um
 	
 	
 		oh yeah
 	
 	
 		and just uh they
 		
 		
 	