
 
     		
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">okay Jay</ENAMEX> i was thinking about um this topic and i was remembering that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> that does an advertisement on the radio
 		about drug testing and marijuana whether or not marijuana causes any trouble or not and he was saying how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">train</ENAMEX> had wrecked
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> had been under the influence and he said whether you think you know you might think that it doesn't effect anybody but it does
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly
 	
 	
 		so i think it's a good idea is what i'm trying to say
 	
 	
 		well i i do too and uh uh i work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Instruments</ENAMEX> and and they have a mandatory drug testing before you hire in and uh
 		i enjoy that environment i i want to be in in a you know drug free environment and i think that's a great way of uh of promoting it
 	
 	
 		yeah
 	
 	
 		is to have the drug testing
 	
 	
 		no
 		
 
 		i can see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> when you've been there a while though they were talking about random testing it seems like if there's no reason to suspect you
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		that i might be offended if they asked me to come in and be tested you know what i mean
 	
 	
 		would you see <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> just started that policy uh they they have a random uh drug testing policy
 		and uh uh
 		it's random in the fact that you don't know when you're going to be called but everybody will be called
 	
 	
 		and how often are they doing it
 	
 	
 		and
 		uh you mean like uh how how often would you be called up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		uh you may be called up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> times and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> will only be called up once but uh
 	
 	
 		you mean in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s time or what
 		
 
 	
 	
 		uh over the whole process i this'll be an ongoing uh process uh from now on but in uh <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>'s time you might be called up i don't know twice or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times and nobody called up any
 		uh but uh the way they have it set up or the way i understand is that they want everyone
 		they've got it set up where all current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> uh will be called on a random basis but uh you know it's very likely that some may be called more uh more than others
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		because they'd be suspect or what
 	
 	
 		no just because of the random process of it and uh i don't know they did talked about the the statistics of it and how they've tried to figure out
 		uh you know to eliminate those problems but anytime it's uh it's a purely random sample uh you will have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> called more more than others
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 		well how do you feel about that
 	
 	
 		but
 		i'm i'm all for it because uh you know uh i want a a drug free environment i don't want a uh even though i do work in the the office i'm uh a financial analyst
 		i'm probably in no danger as far as any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> or anything uh or machinery
 		but i still want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the in the office uh to have a professional demeanor about them and uh and not be under the influence influence when they come in to work and you know i guess if they
 		have the urge and and have that habit they can do that on their own time but uh i feel like when when we're at work uh you know it's a team atmosphere and i i think that would distract from the team
 	
 	
 		what if they did it though on their own time and it's still  it stays in your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> for such a long time
 	
 	
 		well that's that's true and and to me they're still under under the influence if it's in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> and uh
 		i don't know i that's i have a strong feeling that i'm against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and so if uh anyone is using <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> uh uh and it's in their system when they're tested then uh
 		you know and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> has uh a pretty uh liberal they if you're tested positive then they automatically uh test you again and uh if that one comes back positive
 		then they send you to a uh a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rehab</ENAMEX> which <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> pays for and uh
 	
 	
 		oh that's real good that's real good
 	
 	
 		uh huh
 		what's that
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug rehab</ENAMEX> and they'll send you to it so if they did have a problem they can get over it
 		i agree with that
 	
 	
 		right
 		and uh uh so they send you to that and then they monitor you i i believe
 		on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> basis you have to go in and take a test for and this goes on for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		and uh if they if you can prove to them that you've i don't know cleaned your act up or whatever then then uh they won't terminate you but
 		any <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any time</TIMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that time</TIMEX> if they do uh if you do test positive then uh it's automatic termination
 	
 	
 		hm
 	
 	
 		so uh
 	
 	
 		did you see that special about uh all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that work on the road <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crews</ENAMEX> they're putting these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> up and so many of them had tested positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and they they haven't been putting these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> together correctly
 		and like yeah and then uh on the lines for putting your <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> together same thing they're under the influence and they're not doing the job right
 	
 	
 		are you serious
 		right
 	
 	
 		now that's scary isn't it
 	
 	
 		oh <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> that's right well and you know the same could be true at <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TI</ENAMEX> if somebody's putting a missile together and they uh you know mess it up and then that puts
 	
 	
 		
 
 	
 	
 		maybe a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> or somebody at jeopardy and uh i don't know i
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i think
 		any more that uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> are so prevalent you know in our society that that uh
 		it may be up to the the work place to help try to control it because it doesn't seem like any where else uh you know we're getting that assistance
 		because in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you know i i would hate to have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> right now because i think this is going to be a tough tough period for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> with uh you know the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> as rampant as they are
 	
 	
 		uh-huh well i've got an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> and an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> says i don't understand this drug stuff why don't <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> understand all you have to do is say no
 	
 	
 		i see
 	
 	
 		you know and he doesn't realize the pressure that he's going to be under later when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> start doing this
 	
 	
 		right
 		exactly or uh uh an older peer will come up to him and and uh try to try to get him hooked on it so that he'll start selling it or something you know and uh i know uh you know just growing up
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i really looked up to the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> you know especially if they played football or basketball or whatever and and uh i know that uh you know it'd be real easy to be influenced by by someone like that
 	
 	
 		well i teach and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> a student that i'd had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year before</TIMEX> so he would have been in <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> grade came to school with ice
 	
 	
 		right
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">golly</ENAMEX> now is this uh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> type
 	
 	
 		and i mean
 		it i don't i don't know what it is it's supposed to be uh real inexpensive i know that
 	
 	
 		
 
 		oh it is huh
 	
 	
 		and anyway he's he's like a special ed child
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		you know and i could see he was probably selling it for these other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and we were doing these posters uh for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> antidrug campaign and all these little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">first graders</ENAMEX> were always drawing these pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> trucks
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> started talking to them and they said that they were selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice cream</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">trucks</ENAMEX> now
 	
 	
 		golly that is terrible
 		but i mean that makes sense because uh that's where all the uh the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are you know you have the easy access to them and uh you know uh that'd make you know that would be a logical
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i tell you what these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealers</ENAMEX> are about the best business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> there are because uh they know who the market is and they know exactly how to get to the market if uh if other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> could
 		do <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> as good as they do then uh there'd be some very profitable businesses
 		but unfortunately they prey on prey on the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		but i don't know
 	
 	
 		so you think we should do this in every profession
 	
 	
 		uh the drug testing
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		i do uh i know where my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> works he he works for a government contractor also and uh uh
 		i believe any time you have a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D O</ENAMEX> uh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX> contract you have to have the drug testing and uh you know like uh uh
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX> are starting to uh to test them for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> so i i beli <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">eve</TIMEX> that it should be you know uh widespread and uh
 	
 	
 		<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">uh-huh</ENAMEX>
 	
 	
 		that everyone should be tested what do you think
 	
 	
 		i don't know some jobs it seems like it would just maybe be a waste of money because who cares you know i mean like i don't know
 	
 	
 		right
 	
 	
 		what one would be an example like should i say postal service or not i mean are they going to screw up on mail
 	
 	
 		like what about your
 		right
 		right well what about uh teaching uh your profession
 	
 	
 		do i think they should
 	
 	
 		do you think they should in in that profession
 	
 	
 		well see i don't really see the need of it you know
 		how many elementary school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> do you think are going to be on drugs
 	
 	
 		right uh i guess the only the only concern i'd have
 	
 	
 		you might feel like you need it by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the day</TIMEX> but i don't know it would cost so much money and i think maybe we could use that money in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> you know to buy paper or something
 	
 	
 		right exactly
 		i guess so
 		somewhere else right
 	
 	
 		especially since we're going to cut
 	
 	
 		you know i guess the only fear i would have would be that uh you know if i had a child uh that one in a million <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> grade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> that would be on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> would be in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX> you know and and
 	
 	
 		well you know that's true and in teaching you don't get rid of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> very easy you know  they'd be there
 	
 	
 		that's right and and and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> are very influential too
 		
 		
 	