
   
   
      
         
            Divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fathers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza</ENAMEX> Crusts

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
Halliday

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 2, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Divorced Fathers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Crusts</ENAMEX>," click .

            The connection between
divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> and pizza crustsis understandable. The divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> does
not cookconfidently. He wants his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> to enjoy dinner.The entire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> is
supposed to be fun. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids lovepizza</ENAMEX>. For some reason involving soft warmth and  
   malleability

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> approve of melted
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> on pizzayears before they will tolerate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cheese</ENAMEX> in other situations.So
the divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s friendout for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
eat much faster than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>.Before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX> has finished his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> slice,

            the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are playing a
video game or being <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ace Venturaor</ENAMEX> blowing spitballs through straws, making this
hailthat can't quite be cleaned up. There are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> slices leftand the divorced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> doesn't want them wasted,there has been enough <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">waste</ENAMEX> already; he sits
there

            in his windbreaker
finishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pizza</ENAMEX>. It's goodexcept the crust is actually not so great--after
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> slice the crust is basically a chore--so you leave it. You move on
to the next loaded slice.Finally there you are amid rims of crust.

            All this is
understandable. There's no dark conspiracy.Meanwhile the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> are having a
pretty good timewhich is the whole point. So <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the entire evening</TIMEX> makesclear
sense. Now the divorced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> gathersthe <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sauce</ENAMEX>-stained napkins for the trash
and dumps them

            and dumps
the rims of crust which are notcorpses on a battlefield. Understandabilityfills
the pizza <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> so thoroughly there's no roomfor anything else. Now he's at the
door summoning the kidsand they follow, of course they do, he's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dad</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
