
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marooned</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Oates</ENAMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marooned</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>," click .

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winning</ENAMEX> is
fun and it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> way and I believe in it."

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staubachbusinessman</ENAMEX> and ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboy</ENAMEX>
            

            Waking at
dawn marooned in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>!On the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ninth</NUMEX> floor of a glittering pyramid!On
all sides canyon-avenues of glittering <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pyramids</ENAMEX>! Monuments to money!Money and
immortality!Money and immortality and blistering heat!<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> below
diminished figures scuttle!Descending <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">floors</ENAMEX> rapid as a
fibrillating heart you can join them!You are choking in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bus</ENAMEX> exhaust the
blackest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.A.</ENAMEX>!You are invisible amid the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pedestrians</ENAMEX> of color!On
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce</ENAMEX>! On <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>! On <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>!     Arkard! Federal! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Field</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ThanksGiving Tower</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tilting</ENAMEX> to infinity!<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">59,803</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">boots of Boot Town</ENAMEX> waiting to be filled!In the
Nieman-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus</ENAMEX> "flagship" your footsteps echo!Escalators soaring upward to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oblivion</ENAMEX>!<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty</TIMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">-ounce T-</ENAMEX>bones juicy as newborn <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">human babies</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Giant</ENAMEX> gins! Mighty
Martinis!Guts long and hardy as expressways!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marooned</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> after death,
waking astonished!Blown along the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pavement</ENAMEX> like loose pages     of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning News</ENAMEX> !Blown through canyons of sparkling fountains!Spring
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water bubbling</ENAMEX> out of nowhere cascading to nowhere!In the historic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmers</ENAMEX>
Market are giant cauliflowers,     broccoli and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beans</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>-sized <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tomatoes</ENAMEX>,
sweet     <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">corn</ENAMEX> and okra and yams!The real world exists, it can be eaten!The
real world exists, it can be sold!Futures, shares, bonds, points!You've died
not knowing why, nor why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>     waking lonely as you'd never known you
were! Why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>? --your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul</ENAMEX> swirling down a grate.Big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">City That</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Loves To Win</ENAMEX>!Come buy a ticket <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $3</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sixth</ENAMEX>-Floor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX>     (formerly
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Book Depository</ENAMEX>)     from which scowling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Harvey Oswald</ENAMEX> shot    
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy</ENAMEX>! Assassination site!
               Grassy
knoll!
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Motorcade</ENAMEX>!
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parkland Hospital</ENAMEX>!
               Love
Field / <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force One</ENAMEX>!
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Officer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tippet Murder</ENAMEX>!
               <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Oswald</ENAMEX>
Capture!
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby / Oswald Murder</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Authentic John Neely Bryan Log</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cabin</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Johnson</ENAMEX> cenotaph honoring <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">JFK</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Replica of Christ's Tomb at</ENAMEX>
Calvary!<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Swearing-in of Texas son LBJ</ENAMEX>!<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">Fifty-two tons</NUMEX> of cast-iron longhorns
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stampeding</ENAMEX>     in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pioneer Park</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OBSESSION**GENTLEMAN</ENAMEX>'S <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">CLUB***** Live Exotic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Female Entertainers Continuous ***O Corporate Cowboy America</ENAMEX>!Your love-need
misunderstood as greed!A hunger for sanctity misunderstood as rapacity!As if
great grinding jaws haven't their theologies and laws!<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas America</ENAMEX>'s
conscience!<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> our miracle of Pentecost!<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> of refrigerated
verticals!<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muzak</ENAMEX>-tombs!<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> the taste of fresh paper money!<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> these are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> of vengeance, that all things     written may be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fulfilled</ENAMEX>!<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
