
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Unexamined Game Is Not Worth</ENAMEX> Watching

            As an achiever, I constantly
look for new techniques of achievement and seek to minimize behaviors with low
achievement yield. Thus it is only natural that I have begun to worry about the
amount of time I spend watching sports on television--an activity that does not
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">measurably</ENAMEX> advance any of my personal or professional agendas.

            Most alarmingly, sports have
become a steel curtain between me and my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>
shun me when I turn on a ballgame. Occasionally I try to "relate" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>
by asking them to fetch Daddy a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, but I sense that they are drifting
away--that I have become, for them, every bit as useless, burdensome, and
low-yielding in immediate practical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">utility</ENAMEX> as they are for me.

            I realized that something
had to change. I needed to take <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX>, decisive action.

            And so I
made a solemn vow: I would teach my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> to watch sports with me.

            Yes, I would! And something more: I would become a better,
more sophisticated, more deeply engaged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> of TV sports. I would become a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for whom sports viewership is not just a bad habit, but a skill.

            I have sought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> and engaged in rigorous tests in my own home. What follows are some
simple precepts for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next Level</ENAMEX> sports viewership.

            The very first thing you must
do, before we get into any actual viewing techniques, is ask yourself why
sports are an important part of your life. Why do sports matter? Do you like
sports because they show that effort, practice, and innovation lead to positive
results? Because sports are an outlet for our primitive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">barbarian hostilities</ENAMEX>?
Because in sports we discover a dramatic metaphor for our desire to move into
new terrain and reach goals that can be statistically measured? The answer to
all these questions is: Don't be stupid. You watch sports for the simple reason
that sports don't matter a jot. You like sports precisely because of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">utter</ENAMEX> insignificance. You find this relaxing. Always remember the pre-eminent
rule of the sports junkie:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. Don't
start thinking like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Will</ENAMEX>.
            

            Next, you must configure
your viewing area. For help in this regard I called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Sabol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL Films Inc.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that produces Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HBO</ENAMEX>. Sabol,
I knew, watches a heroic amount of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>, from which he gleans the
highlights for his films. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL Films</ENAMEX> has a signature style: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sweaty</ENAMEX>, grunting,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">muddy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> move in super slow motion while the baritone <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">narrator</ENAMEX> describes the
events as though the fate of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> hung in the balance. Sabol, a former
college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>, says, "That's the way I wanted to show the game, with
the snot spraying, the sweat flying. <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Football</ENAMEX> is a very visceral sport. Before
we started it was always filmed from the top, and it looked like a little chess
set."

            His viewing procedures are
quite advanced. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Every Sunday</TIMEX> he watches <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> games at once. "I have a little
cockpit that's built in my den. There's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> set, the predominant game, that's
on a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">30-inch</NUMEX> TV, and I have <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">two 19-inch</NUMEX> TVs that are slanted inward. So it's
like a cockpit. You have to have good peripheral vision and you have to really
concentrate."

            So that's the next tip:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>. Get
more, and bigger, televisions.
            

            If you have only a single
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">19-inch</NUMEX> television and you can't afford to upgrade, just sit a lot closer. If
you get close enough to the set, it's almost as good as going out and buying a
multi-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX>-dollar "home theater."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabol</ENAMEX> said he has to take the
occasional pit <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stop</ENAMEX>, but even that is conveniently arranged.

            "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bathroom</ENAMEX>'s right by the set. If I have to take a piss I can still see the
screen."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. Keep
your eye on the screen at all times, even when you are trying to trim a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">toenails</ENAMEX>.
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabol</ENAMEX> said he sits in a
"Relax-a-back" chair, a kind of recliner, but cautions that this is not for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">novice</ENAMEX>. The worst-case scenario for the sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> is the unplanned nap.
"Those are dangerous. I only recommend those for the more experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>.
You need stamina to do this. You need a good <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s sleep. You have to be
careful about having too big a breakfast, because that will put you to sleep.
The trick is to have a series of small <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">snacks</ENAMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10-hour</TIMEX> period."

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>. Come
to the television rested. Don't eat meals--graze.
            

            (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabol</ENAMEX> reckons that on a
given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> he starts watching at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> and doesn't stop until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 p.m.</TIMEX>, at
the end of the cable-TV broadcast. Before his divorce, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> didn't quite
understand that this was work, he says.)

            Now comes the harder stuff,
the actual watching--the seeing, if you will--of the actions on the screen. You
must keep in mind that you are not directly watching an event, but rather are
watching a produced and directed telecast of an event, manipulated by talented
but not infallible <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX>. To better understand how a sports program is
put together, I called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Martzke</ENAMEX>, the TV sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , who watches <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">between 40 and 60 hours</TIMEX> of TV sports a week on the
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60-inch</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer</ENAMEX> screen in his family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martzke</ENAMEX> is full of facts and
well-educated opinions: The typical <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monday Night Football</ENAMEX> broadcast uses
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 13</NUMEX> cameras, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about eight</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX>'s primary game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goodyear</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steadycam</ENAMEX> allows sharp-focus blimp shots even when the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blimp</ENAMEX> is being blown all over the sky; the glowing puck used on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox</ENAMEX> hockey
games is officially called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox Trax</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Costas</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> is the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> in the
business; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Michaels</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> is the best play-by-play <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>.

            Unseen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, but
extremely important, are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">directors</ENAMEX>.

            "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who
calls the shots you see on the screen. He's the one who inserts the graphics,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martzke</ENAMEX>. "Got a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> sitting next to him who's called the technical
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, when he yells out the instructions, 'cut to this
picture, that picture, this camera, that camera,' the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who follows him up,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">physically</ENAMEX>, is the technical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> sits to the left of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> is the one who gets in the replays, the one who's in
charge of the format of the show. He makes sure all those commercial breaks get
in, so they're paid."

            Obviously only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Martzke</ENAMEX>
ever thinks twice about these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, but this creates a chance for you to
sound authoritative when someone challenges you on your sports-viewership
expertise. Let other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> talk about who caught what pass or made what
tackle; you can say things like, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Grossman</ENAMEX> uses down-and-yardage graphics
better than any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> in the game."

            The point of all this
is:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>. Never
let anyone know that you've forgotten the 
               name of the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX>."
            

            The hardest part of all is
knowing what to look for when you watch television. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, for example,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referee</ENAMEX> will often blow the whistle and call "illegal defense," which few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> ever see in advance. This is because they are only watching the ball.
Illegal defense occurs when a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> plays zone rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Thus
you should always look for someone who's just guarding a patch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>,
standing around looking suspicious. When you detect an illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defense</ENAMEX> before
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referee</ENAMEX> makes the call, you have completely arrived as a TV sports
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, don't just watch
the flight of the ball from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>'s hand toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">batter</ENAMEX>. Look directly
at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>'s hand and see if you can see what kind of grip he's using--that
will tell you whether it's a curve, slider, fastball, splitter, knuckleball, or
whatever.

            In <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>, look at the wrists
and elbows of the golfer as he or she putts. The great ones have almost no
movement in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>, wrists, and hands other than the gentlest of pendulum
swings.

            In hockey, change channels.
You will never see the puck.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sabol</ENAMEX> watches a football
game, he scrutinizes an area in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runner</ENAMEX> and including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runner</ENAMEX>.
"It's a semicircle with a radius of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 3 yards</NUMEX>," he estimates.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>.
Expand your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">zone</ENAMEX> of attention.
            

            In preliminary tests with my
own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, I determined that they have a long, long, long way to go before
they are major-league sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> I plunked my <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> oldest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>
in chairs directly in front of the set and channel-surfed from <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> to
basketball to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> to figure skating. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> game, my
medium-sized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, who is not quite <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4</TIMEX>, said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Dumars</ENAMEX>: "Is that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>?" So the first thing we will do, with this particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>, is work on
gender identification.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughters</ENAMEX>, meanwhile,
have decided to become figure skaters when they grow up. You can see that this
is drifting into a scary area: I might teach them to watch sports on
television, but they might decide that "sports" includes massive doses of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boitano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oksana Baiul</ENAMEX>. My natural inclination is to watch figure skating
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quadrennially</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, is simply a
lost cause. She is an extremely discerning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who can detect the most
subtle spice in a bowl of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soup</ENAMEX> or a whisper of colored thread in a suit jacket,
but for some reason she can stare at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> game on television and miss
the important details, such as the ball going into the hoop.

            "What just happened?" I
demanded to know after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> made a jump shot during a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX>
game.

            "I don't know. I was still
thinking about the last commercial," she said.

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. Don't
pay attention to the commercials, the 
               squeakiness of the basketball
court, the spitting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dugout</ENAMEX>, the sweating, or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fluids</ENAMEX> of any kind.
            

            Once the
techniques of viewing are mastered, there remains a major step: analysis. There
is no point in watching if one is not really "seeing" anything. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sabol</ENAMEX> gave me a
final tip that I will carry with me the rest of my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>:

            
               <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>.
Prepare.
            

            "You have to come into the
game prepared. You have to come into watching the game with your own game
plan," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabol</ENAMEX> said. "What are you going to look for? What are the keys to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">game?</ENAMEX>"

            It's a rule from scouting: Be
prepared. Think ahead. Anticipate problems and possible solutions. If you pick
up the book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Seven Habits of Highly Effective People</ENAMEX> , you will see
that one of the habits is "be pro-active." Do not wait for the ballgame on
television to come to you. You can go to the ballgame, mentally, emotionally,
pro-actively. You can be a better sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> than anyone on your block,
anyone with your ZIP code.

            Life is a competition. Be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">champion</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
