
   
   
      
         
            A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Strand</ENAMEX>
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890-1976</TIMEX>) enjoyed a long and prolific career spanning what amounts to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> in the compressed history of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 th</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">century</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photography</ENAMEX>. In the last <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX> of those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> he made an impressive number of
worthy images, full of human dignity and topical picturesqueness and formal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">achievement</ENAMEX>. Had those <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years</TIMEX> constituted his entire career, we could
relegate him to a historical back shelf along with so many other humanistic
pillars of midcentury photography, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwarts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Family</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Man</ENAMEX> whose work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> primarily inspires a nagging sense of duty.

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a couple of years</TIMEX> in
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strand</ENAMEX> was a radical <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Modernist</ENAMEX> who made one startling
picture after another, progressing in giant leaps that apparently occurred
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month to month</TIMEX>. With dazzling speed he went from being a promising imitator to
discovering <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> that would be explored by others in the ensuing
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Strand</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Circa 1916</ENAMEX>" is the appropriately dazzling record of that
period, gathering for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time nearly all his surviving work of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>--a mere <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>-odd photographs--into a sort of time-lapse film of the process
of discovery. If you have ever wondered what inspiration might look like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graphically</ENAMEX> represented, this is the show to see.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strand</ENAMEX> was a product of the progressive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewish New York</ENAMEX>
middle <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">class</ENAMEX>. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aunt</ENAMEX> was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> of the then-new kindergarten movement, and
his education was completed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethical Culture School</ENAMEX>, which prized the
rounding effects of training in practical skills, including--impressively for
the time--photography, taught by the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Hine</ENAMEX>. His postgraduate studies
took place at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Camera Club</ENAMEX>, a hobby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> less interested in art than in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">craft</ENAMEX>, and then he
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gravitated</ENAMEX> toward the artistic forefront of the medium, namely, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pictorialists</ENAMEX>. This movement was just beginning to splinter. Under the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proprietary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> and all-around impresario <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alfred</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stieglitz</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> had called itself <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photo-Secession</ENAMEX>, which sounded radical
and daring, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stieglitz</ENAMEX> was so obsessed with achieving artistic legitimacy
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s work restricted itself to counterfeiting the effects of
drawing and painting. The images were soft, vague studies of moony, "timeless"
subjects, maidens in dappled fields and the like. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Steichen</ENAMEX> was
particularly skilled at delivering prints that looked like daubings untouched
by any mechanical process and wholly innocent of the industrial world.

            Soon erstwhile
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Photo-Secessionists</ENAMEX> were chafing under the harness, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strand</ENAMEX> immediately took
to the more conservative elements, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1911 and 1913</TIMEX> he produced
appropriately languid views of shimmering <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">decorative sheep</ENAMEX>; and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unfocused</ENAMEX>, mildly erotic light effects. He was fascinated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX>-print
flatness bequeathed by the Impressionists<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">; in Maid of the Mist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Niagara</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Falls</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>), he managed to cheat scale so much that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX> looks like a
bathtub toy against the swirl of rocks and spume. By the time he made that
picture, though, he had already taken in works by more venturesome
Pictorialists that showed the modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as itself and had produced
Railroad <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX>): a couple of willful diagonals of
boxcars surmounted by a tangle of rails and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of steam that has nothing to
do with mist.

            Very soon he was touring the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, bringing back new
ideas about line and volume, as in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Telegraph Poles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>): some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">stripped trees</ENAMEX> leaning over, bearing aloft a neat grid of wires, towering over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flatland</ENAMEX> and stumpy <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shacks</ENAMEX>. Nothing precious or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> there, but a picture
that had never been made before (but would, in one way or another, be made
again and again by others over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 50 years</TIMEX>). Back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strand</ENAMEX>
started investigating the graphic dynamism at work in the shadows thrown down
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">el tracks</ENAMEX>, and he began seriously investing in the possibilities of the
overhead vantage, a Modernist urban trope he would will to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berenice Abbott</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">sundry Germans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>. The scooped-out city <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">canyon</ENAMEX>, embellished with a
frieze of human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> at the bottom (, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>), was a theme that looked new in
the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Winogrand</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. The row of giant black rectangles
dominating puny <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pedestrians</ENAMEX> walking below ( Wall Street , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>) inspired
numerous social interpretations, but to our eyes it might look like an
anticipation of obdurate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monoliths</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ad Reinhardt</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serra</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer of 1916</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strand</ENAMEX>
went off to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">country house</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Twin Lakes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>, and there he
decided to take on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cubism of Picasso</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Braque</ENAMEX> using available <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">materials</ENAMEX>.
He arranged bowls, jugs, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> in sunlight or whipped them with the shadows
of the porch railing, then left the objects alone and began rearranging the
position of his camera instead. The pictures become increasingly free; they can
almost be sequenced as a flipbook as they swing from still life to pure
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">abstraction</ENAMEX> and from the ground up toward dramatic diagonals in the sky. Back
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> again, he set about making portraits in the slums, arming himself with
a camera equipped with a false lens at a right angle to the actual one so he
could photograph unsuspecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--peddlers, drunks, sandwich
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>--are observed not just as formal objects, although they are affected by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shadows</ENAMEX> and textures and sign-fragments, and not just as social types, as in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hine's</ENAMEX> pictures, but also as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX>, weathered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personalities</ENAMEX>. Some of them,
such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Five Points Square</ENAMEX> and the iconic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blind</ENAMEX> (both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916</TIMEX>),
are among the greatest photographic portraits ever, an accumulated life visible
all at once in their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX>' features.

            Before his great surge gave
out in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1917</TIMEX>, he had also begun photographing machinery--a hallmark of the work
of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>--and he had also made a few
pictures that synthesized everything he had learned. Chief among these, in my
view, is From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Viaduct</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1916</TIMEX>), a picture of a billboard, a
false front, a couple of roofs, a fence, and some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> that
marches the eye up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side and down the other, seamlessly blending all his
knowledge of light and shade, volume and flatness, geometry and the shapes of
letters, human proportion and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> scene. It has been hiding out all
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these years</TIMEX> in a private collection, a barely known monument of the most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">liberating Modernism</ENAMEX>, the kind that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> can take out into the world to
transform its least prepossessing elements into jazz and verve. The same could
be said of the exhibition as a whole, and its splendid catalog: They animate a
process that, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80 years later</TIMEX>, still seems new.

         
      
   
