
   
   
      
         
            Selena

            
               (Note: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life and Art</ENAMEX>"
is an occasional column that compares fiction, in various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, with the
real-life facts it is ostensibly based on.)
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX> is the life
story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> who was murdered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 23</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham Quintanilla, Selena</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, was the executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> of
the film and had complete script approval. Before filming began, Quintanilla
said: "Nobody knows more about my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> and our life than I do. ... If they
get out of line as far as the story goes, I'll put them back on course." Either
they never got out of line or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quintanilla</ENAMEX> put them back on course, because
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX> does not stray far from the facts, at least as they are recounted
in the secondary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.

            When
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abraham</ENAMEX> discovered that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> could sing, he turned his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> into a
band called <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Selena y Los Dinos</ENAMEX>. They debuted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selena</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>, and
starting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, performed frequently at the family <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lake</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> pushed her to sing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Spanish</ENAMEX>, which she didn't
know how to speak. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> did gigs across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Texas</ENAMEX>, performing mostly
Tejano music (described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billboard</ENAMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">polkas</ENAMEX> and cumbias,
mixed with elements of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rock</ENAMEX>, pop, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, and even rap"). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX> eventually
broke into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> market on an unprecedented scale for a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tejano</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>
with spotty <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX>, giving concerts before crowds of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.
Interested in fashion since childhood, she opened a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boutique</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena Etc.</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1994</TIMEX>. The actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Selena</ENAMEX> line, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Gómez</ENAMEX>, gets a
brief mention in the film. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1994</TIMEX>, she won a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grammy</ENAMEX> for best
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> album. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1994</TIMEX>, the biggest hit of her career, "Amor
Prohibido," reached <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">No. 1</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Billboard Latin</ENAMEX> chart. Though the film
doesn't go into all the details, it is correct in indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selena</ENAMEX> was
poised for mainstream success when she was killed.

            The film also reflects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX>'s down-to-earth style, at
least as described in media accounts and in such books as the unauthorized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biography Selena</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Como la Flor</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>), by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Nick Patoski</ENAMEX>, a senior
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Monthly</ENAMEX> . Selena the movie ticks off the points
made in numerous profiles. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> drove a red <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX> convertible,
she dined at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pizza Hut</ENAMEX>, shopped in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>, mowed her own lawn, and lived in a
middle-class neighborhood in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Corpus Christi</ENAMEX> at the time of her death (next door
to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, a detail left out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX> ). The film
faithfully records her status as a role model. On-screen, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX> studies on the
tour bus and asks <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> seeking autographs how they're doing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>. In
life, she got her high-school degree via correspondence from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
School (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Osmonds</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX>), and was one of the only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tejano</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> not to
endorse a beer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">brand</ENAMEX>.

            One fact
missing from the film is that both she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jehovah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Witnesses</ENAMEX>.
Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selena</ENAMEX> was not an official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the sect, she was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believer</ENAMEX> and
went to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> study with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">believers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Chronicle</ENAMEX> reported
that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX> showed up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX>'s shooting, he said
she wouldn't want a blood transfusion because of her faith (by that point,
though, she'd already been given <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX>, to no avail).

            
On-screen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham</ENAMEX> comes across as a demanding
but good-hearted stage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. He forces his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> to form a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">band</ENAMEX> and yells
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX> for wearing a bustier during a performance. He angrily forbids his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> to marry <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Perez</ENAMEX>, a guitarist in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">band</ENAMEX>. (In both film and life,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> elope and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quintanilla</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> eventually accepts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>.) In
real life, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quintanilla</ENAMEX>'s stage-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> parenting did occasion some criticism:
Selena : <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Como la Flor</ENAMEX> recalls battles between <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Abraham and Selena</ENAMEX>'s
junior-high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>'s increasing absences.

            As for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolanda Saldivar</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan club</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> at her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boutique</ENAMEX>, and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quintanilla</ENAMEX> wanted to leave her out of the movie
entirely, until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> convinced him not to. The film implies that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolanda</ENAMEX> were friendly but not actually <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>. In truth, they were
quite close, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolanda</ENAMEX> often traveled with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX>. Currently serving a life
sentence for the crime, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolanda</ENAMEX> told <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20/20</NUMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selena</ENAMEX> called her "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>."
Selena addresses neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolanda</ENAMEX>'s obsession with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selena</ENAMEX> (her apartment
was a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">shrine</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX>) nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tabloid</ENAMEX> rumor, denied by all and not backed
by any evidence, that they were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX>.

            As the script indicates, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> thought that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolanda</ENAMEX>
was embezzling money, and confronted her. The film does not re-enact the
murder, choosing instead to "cover" the crime in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an 11 o'clock</TIMEX> news style, but
the details are accurate. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX> states that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX> had gone to the motel
to pick up papers from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolanda</ENAMEX> when she was shot, as family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> later
testified. Next we see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolanda</ENAMEX> holed up in her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> with a gun to her head,
saying, "I'm so ashamed," and, "Look what I've done to my best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>." She did
say those things during a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">9-½ hour</NUMEX> standoff with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>, though she also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accused Abraham</ENAMEX> of having raped her--a charge never substantiated.

            The final
moments of the film resemble a music-video tribute--we see an empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> and
a candlelight vigil. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX>'s death did inspire an outpouring of grief and
attract the attention of the mainstream media (inspired by the success of their
Selena-memorial issue, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> launched a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Spanish</ENAMEX> version of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>). As the movie implies with a scene in which a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> forms around
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selena</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> store and a white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> asks, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Who's Selena?</ENAMEX>" many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX> learned about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> only because of the way she died. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madonna</ENAMEX> was
reportedly the sole <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> to send her condolences.

         
      
   
