
   
   
      
         
            <I>Private Parts</I>

            
               (Note: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> and
Art" is an occasional column that compares movies with the lives they're based
on.)
            

            Toward the beginning of
Private <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Parts</ENAMEX> , a heavily made-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX>, playing himself as a
college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student</ENAMEX>, explains in a voice-over that to enjoy the movie, "you've got
to suspend disbelief." Exactly how much disbelief does this biopic require us
to suspend?

            Not all
that much, actually. Private Parts may be hyperbolic, but it basically
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">adheres</ENAMEX> to the facts, at least as they are laid out in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>'s memoir, also
called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Private Parts</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>); in interviews; and in an unauthorized
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biography</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Stern</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">King</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">All Media</ENAMEX> , by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul D. Colford</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> grew up on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Island</ENAMEX>, went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University</ENAMEX>, and
worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Westchester</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">N.Y.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hartford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Conn.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>; and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>, before making it in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. Along the way, he dropped
his fake-sounding FM voice and became a "shock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jock</ENAMEX>," talking more and more
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> himself, sex, sex with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, etc. The movie does gloss over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lengths Stern</ENAMEX> was willing to go to shock. In the movie, his racial comedy tends
toward the mildly offensive (he invents a militant black traffic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">announcer</ENAMEX>). In
his book, he writes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney King</ENAMEX>, "They didn't beat this idiot enough." On
the air, he encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> to shoot at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rioters</ENAMEX> during the uproar in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Angeles</ENAMEX>. He's talked about having sex to "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Negro</ENAMEX> race music," and he's asked his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> on the air if she "got on all fours" during sex, and if she was a
"<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-input <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>."

            
On-screen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> says he's remained faithful to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>--and by all accounts, that is true. On-screen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>'s penchant for
exposing the details of his marriage strains it somewhat. That was also the
case in real life. In the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> kisses and consoles a pregnant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison</ENAMEX>
when she complains, "I look like a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>." In his memoir, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stern</ENAMEX>
writes: "I find nothing attractive about the pregnant form. I'm like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>. If
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> got pregnant, he couldn't go near her."

            In the
movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>'s rise to the top is impeded by villainous, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">scotch</ENAMEX>-swilling
network <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX>. Were his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WNBC</ENAMEX> really that bad? In real life,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stern</ENAMEX> definitely tangled with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> heads. The movie's main meanie, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pig</ENAMEX>
Vomit," is a composite of several oppressive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, based most heavily on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Metheny</ENAMEX> (a program <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> nicknamed "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pig Virus</ENAMEX>" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>). But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>
also had what he terms a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">savior</ENAMEX>" in then general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Bongarten</ENAMEX>,
who doesn't figure in the movie. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX> would occasionally tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> to watch
his content (he advised against a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bestiality Dial</ENAMEX>-a-Date routine, for
example), but he also promoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>'s career. Among other things, Bongarten
arranged for advertisements in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WNBC</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>-drive deejay) and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Imus</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>-drive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>) got equal billing. In the film,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imus</ENAMEX> won't deign to speak to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>, much less appear in an ad with him.

            
However, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> did instruct
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bongarten</ENAMEX> to fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colford</ENAMEX> writes in his biography that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> has
elevated "the final chapter in his war with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>" to the "myth of the inventive
radio personality clashing with the stuffed shirts of a mighty <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>," but
goes on to record events that sound a lot like stuffed shirts clashing with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Rukeyser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of corporate communications at the time,
said that he alerted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant Tinker</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>'s material,
and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tinker</ENAMEX> decided <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> had to go.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stern</ENAMEX>
reached No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> during morning drive (the most competitive time
period) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall of 1991</TIMEX>, but at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">station</ENAMEX> that does not appear in
Private Parts : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WXRK-FM</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">92.3</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">K-ROCK</ENAMEX>), owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infinity Broadcasting</ENAMEX>.
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infinity</ENAMEX> hired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just months</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> fired him.) During the film's last
scene, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alison</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard kiss</ENAMEX>, he explains in a voice-over that life is
and then. What he doesn't say is that, in response to mounting fines from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX> for indecency on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>'s radio show, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infinity</ENAMEX> paid a settlement of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.7</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. Nor does he mention that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, he did make a few
compromises to stay on the air: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Infinity</ENAMEX> instituted a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">seven-second</TIMEX> delay so
that offensive portions of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>'s program could be bleeped before they were
broadcast. He was also forbidden to refer to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Karmazin</ENAMEX>, on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">air</ENAMEX>.

            See
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s review of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Private</ENAMEX> 
               Parts .

         
      
   
