
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cutting Edge</ENAMEX>

            Back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1950s</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Detroit</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Big Three automakers</ENAMEX> saw they had a problem. Nearly everyone had a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> wasn't growing. The only way to keep making money was
to make each <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobile</ENAMEX> more expensive and more profitable. The goal, their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mantra</ENAMEX> went, was not to sell more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> but to sell more <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> .

            The
marketing strategy was to link <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">automobiles</ENAMEX> to the glamour and speed of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">supersonic</ENAMEX> jet <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter planes</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> had introduced in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953 and 1954</TIMEX>. Their swept-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">delta</ENAMEX>-wing designs were sharp yet curvy--a
quality that was abstracted into the parabolic, boomerang shapes that started
to turn up on objects such as ballpoint pens and surfaces such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Formica</ENAMEX>. In
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1955</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> adopted a double boomerang corporate logo to symbolize what it
called "the forward look." By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX> were banana
splits on wheels, dripping with the extraneous decoration that stylists called
"gorp."

            Flash forward to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> dominates the global
shaving market. Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander the Great</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> because he demanded
that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> shave--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Boston</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has no new worlds to conquer.
Yet its lofty stock price assumes continued growth.

            The solution: not to sell
more razors but to sell more razor. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750 million</NUMEX> result: the triple-blade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mach 3</ENAMEX>. Its name means <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times the speed of sound. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> blades on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> look appealingly like a tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Venetian</ENAMEX> blind--an image emblazoned on the
package like a scene from a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1950s</NUMEX> noir movie. The plastic package is also
embossed with parabolas, and the razor itself is festooned with them. Starting
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> advertising campaign will show <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">jet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX> breaking
the sound barrier--and then being magically transported to their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathrooms</ENAMEX>,
where they'll enjoy the quickest, slickest shave in history.

            And, yes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> plans to charge <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> more for it than for its previous
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">top-of-the-line</ENAMEX> product, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Sensor Excel</ENAMEX>. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> has told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>,
the profit margin on each <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Mach 3</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX> cartridge will reach <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX>
percent.

            
It's like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> all over again, only
smaller.

            Yet the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mach 3</ENAMEX> is not the
sort of retro design that evokes bygone imagery of progress with self-conscious
irony. Unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lounge</ENAMEX> music revival, it's aimed not at a hip coterie but at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everyman</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mach 3</ENAMEX> razor appears to
be a sincere attempt to embody progress. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last quarter century</TIMEX> or so,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> have not made this a high priority. Products have evoked cool (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>
Ban sunglasses) or competence (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sub Zero refrigerators</ENAMEX>), upper-class aspirations
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ralph Lauren</ENAMEX> home furnishings) or adolescent rebellion (just about any
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">snowboard</ENAMEX>). Few have tried to communicate that things are actually getting
better, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Mach 3</ENAMEX> does.

            The
immediate reaction: a lower stock price for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> and quite a few jokes.

            There is, on the face of it, something ridiculous about a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-blade razor. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> introduced the twin-blade <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Trac II</ENAMEX> razor in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>,
and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX> ran a parody of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-blade
model. It featured an animation sequence that showed the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> blade cutting
what the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> one missed and the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> getting even closer. The tag line:
"Because you'll believe anything."

            So is this
Mach <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> an improvement or a mockery of consumer gullibility? The product itself
won't be in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, so it's way too early to know how the shaving
public will respond. I do know that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a couple of mornings</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mach 3</ENAMEX> has
just about wiped the smirk off my face. The damned thing works.

            
Just as the promotional copy promises, I am
able to shave with fewer strokes. This shortens an unpleasant activity and
spares me those final touch-up <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">strokes</ENAMEX> that often leave me bleeding.

            Since its first safety razor
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">almost a century ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> has always conceived the actual razor mainly as
an inducement for selling replacement blades. <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mach 3</ENAMEX> represents the culmination
of this trend; it's mainly the cartridge that's been upgraded.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX>
claims <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX> improvements beyond the extra blade. Some--such as a colored strip to
indicate when the blade needs replacing--are aimed more at beefing up the
profit margin than at improving the shave. But others--such as thinner-edged
blades with hard coatings and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>-loaded pivots for each blade
(with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sensor</ENAMEX>, the two blades pivot together)--may, for all I know, be
responsible for the razor's improved performance.

            The razor's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> is, functionally, just a handle. But it
still needs to communicate that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mach 3</ENAMEX> is worth the extra cost. So <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX>
is touting the rubberized boomerangs on its top and bottom as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">gripping aids</ENAMEX>, to
keep it from slipping in your hands, even though the parallel ridges on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sensor</ENAMEX> line probably work about as well. The difference is all in the
styling.

            Most of the improvements in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mach 3</ENAMEX>--the tiny springs and metallurgical manipulations--aren't even
visible to the casual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shopper</ENAMEX>. Like the microchip and the altered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gene</ENAMEX>, they
fall beneath the threshold of visual perception. With its outward imagery,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gillette</ENAMEX> is trying to evoke a midcentury aesthetic of progress identified with
military might, brute force, and speed. And yet while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mach</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> looks like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">throwback</ENAMEX> to a time when progress took a back seat to empty stylistic gestures,
deep down inside, the razor really does represent an advance.

         
      
   
