
   
   
      
         
            The Gamer 

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir Arena</ENAMEX> sits on the
edge of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX>, old and dim, not much more than a big gymnasium. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Bullets</ENAMEX> play here, often quite badly. They haven't made the playoffs
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight years</TIMEX>. They were supposed to be better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> but have found ways
to enforce the tradition of mediocrity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> is usually sold
out--technically--but with plenty of empty <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">seats</ENAMEX>, the signature of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> full
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> and big shots who aren't sure they want to be sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>.

            But on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 21</TIMEX>,
everything was different. A strange and powerful gravitational force surrounded
that stale and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">unloved arena</ENAMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> swarmed the access road
outside, begging for tickets. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> showed up, and the coach
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redskins</ENAMEX>, and then, to snarl traffic once and for all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> came rolling up in his motorcade.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> took his seat with
little fanfare. No one played "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hail</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> applauded
politely. The real action was over in the corner, outside the locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> were straining at the railings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX>. Eyes were
riveted on the locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">exit</ENAMEX>. No one dared look away. The great one was
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about</NUMEX> to emerge. When he finally appeared, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> did not clap--they shouted,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screamed</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> told them to back off.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>!"

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> didn't look up. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> was bowed as he jogged toward the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.
Everywhere he goes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> shout his name. He has mastered the art of not
noticing them.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> is smoother than everyone else--his movements, his
skin, the top of his shaved <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. He looks polished. Next to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>, the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Bulls</ENAMEX> are big slabs of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> with protruding limbs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luc Longley</ENAMEX>: a human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ham</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hock</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Rodman</ENAMEX>: all knuckles and knees and elbows and tattoos and nose
rings and yellow <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodman</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">every night</TIMEX>'s a full moon.

            On the
radio <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the other day</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sportswriter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Deford</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> "our <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lindbergh</ENAMEX>."
(Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindbergh</ENAMEX> really that good? What was his percentage from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-point
range?) <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This night</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir Arena</ENAMEX>, the sportswriters kept looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan</ENAMEX>
and saying, "He's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Ruth</ENAMEX>." Like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> so exceeds the norm as to be an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">anomaly</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> didn't just hit more home runs than anyone else. He hit a lot
more home runs than anyone else. How did he do it? OK, he was strong, he used a
big, heavy bat, and he had an elegant uppercut swing. But the formula for
"greatest-ever" is always mysterious. You can't reduce it to any obvious
variables. You just say a god walked among us.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34 years old</TIMEX>, borderline geriatric,
and he still leads the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> in scoring, racking up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 31</NUMEX> points a game,
while the next-highest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scorer</ENAMEX> averages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 26</NUMEX>. How does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> do it?
He's got that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Ruth</ENAMEX> stuff. The god <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX>. We just have to watch and
wonder.

            For the national anthem
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> rocked from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> leg to the other, still staring at the floor in front of
him, while nearby the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> lustily sang--or at least moved his mouth
dramatically so that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> across the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> could see him singing.

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Seconds</TIMEX>
after tipoff, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> launched a turnaround <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumper</ENAMEX>, his new signature shot,
hitting nothing but net. That proved to be the anomaly for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next three</TIMEX>
quarters of the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> missed a shot, and then he missed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more shots,
and he threw the ball out of bounds, and he got slapped with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> fouls, and by
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of the first quarter</TIMEX> he had stunk up the joint. He had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> measly
points while his sidekick, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scottie Pippen</ENAMEX>, had scorched the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bullets</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sportswriters</ENAMEX> had a potential story line: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> might
not be the high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scorer</ENAMEX> on his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> consecutive game, something
that hasn't happened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. Was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> slipping? Were we seeing it <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>?
The sportswriters were tapping on their laptops. In a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> game, you have to
write as the game progresses. It might be too soon to write the end-of-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an</NUMEX>-era
story, but one could hint at it, start practicing the inevitable eulogy.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>
kept struggling. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, he'd taken <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> shots and hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only four</NUMEX>. By the
end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third quarter</TIMEX>, he'd cobbled together <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> sloppy points to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pippen</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">authoritative</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> were winning by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> points, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Bullets</ENAMEX> were
hanging tough. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> had been outplayed by their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calbert Cheaney</ENAMEX>, a streaky
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>.

            
Then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth quarter</TIMEX> began. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan Time</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> got free on a fast
break. He streaked down the right side of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>, took a pass, veered toward
the bucket, and went airborne. The tongue emerged. When the tongue comes out,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> stand up to watch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>, flying, wore a face of absolute manic rage. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dunk</ENAMEX> was apocalyptic. It was the kind of dunk you wouldn't want a small child
to see. It was as though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> was funneling all his frustration into a single
thermonuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jam</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> roared. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bullets</ENAMEX> called a timeout,
knowing they'd have no chance if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> caught fire.

            <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">A minute</TIMEX> later <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> hit a
pull-up <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumper</ENAMEX>. Then he hit another.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bullets</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaren Jackson</ENAMEX>, tried to smother <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> and prevent him from getting the ball.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> knew what to do: Cheat a little. With his left hand <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> almost
imperceptibly held <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jackson</ENAMEX>--this showed up on the television replay--and then
dashed past him toward the hoop, taking a pass and launching himself for a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-handed dunk, hanging on the rim an extra <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> to make sure everyone knew
who was in charge.

            The next
time down the court <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> hit a wide-open <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-point shot. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bullets</ENAMEX> kept
assigning different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> to cover him, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> seemed to be emitting some
kind of paralysis beam. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX> were rooted in place. The game
plan was, "Pass it to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> hit an impossible <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">15-foot</NUMEX> turnaround <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumper</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> hit foul shots.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> hit another
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-pointer.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> juked right, shook his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, dashed right past <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">7-foot-7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Gheorghe Muresan</ENAMEX>, and burgled the backboard for
an easy layup.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> hit <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> shots in a
row, missed one, then hit again, at which point he was laughing. He knew what
everyone else in the arena was thinking: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> had done it again! Impossible!
A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">34-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geezer</ENAMEX>! The paralysis <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">beam</ENAMEX> still works. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Statisticians</ENAMEX> insist
there is no such thing as a "hot hand" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>, that accurate shots
distribute themselves in random patterns, that just the fact that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> has
made several shots in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX> does not increase the likelihood that he will make
the next <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>. So we are to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s feat <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this night</TIMEX>--his ability
to seize a game and absolutely dominate it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth quarter</TIMEX> when
everything is on the line--is a fluke. What the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">statisticians</ENAMEX> don't realize is
that some things in life aren't logical, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> phenomenon is one
of them. He scored <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> points in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fourth quarter</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">36</NUMEX> for the game, making him
the high <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scorer</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">103-99</NUMEX>.

            "There's
no way <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> was going to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> lose in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>,"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Red Kerr</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Famer</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX>, said outside the
locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.

            
There has been talk in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX> about human
cloning, and you repeatedly hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> mention the idea of cloning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> cited the idea of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX> clone in its lead
editorial. Such talk robs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> of his due. It subtly suggests that he is just
a "natural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX>" who merely has to walk onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> and let his DNA take
over. The fact is, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s greatest gift is in his head. He dominates the game
at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">34</NUMEX> even though he can no longer out-quick and out-jump and out-dunk his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. When he came into the league he was strictly a slasher, relying on
speed and a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">42-inch</NUMEX> vertical leap. He wasn't considered a top-flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shooter</ENAMEX>.
Now he has this deadly turnaround <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jumper</ENAMEX> and routinely hits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-pointers.
What do you call someone who changes his game, his style, his tactics, and
still comes out on top? A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>. (Come to think of it, didn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babe Ruth</ENAMEX> start
out as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>?)

            Like that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> sitting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> is compulsively competitive. When you
apply the lessons of their successes to your life, you get caught short,
because the rest of us don't want it that badly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> has to win at
everything, at cards, at tennis, at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">golf</ENAMEX> (he has lost <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds of thousands</NUMEX>
gambling at that game). After the death of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> took up the
doomed mission of becoming a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>. "He had balls the
size of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">elephant</ENAMEX> to fail in public in another sport," my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kornheiser</ENAMEX> said before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Greene</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>--the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">greatest basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> of all time--was motivated by a sports fantasy: that
he'd be batting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Sox</ENAMEX> in his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> professional <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> game, and
would hit a home run, round the bases and, never stopping running, just head
straight from home plate to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> leading out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX>, disappearing
in front of the awed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>.

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAir</ENAMEX> Arena emptied out, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sportswriters</ENAMEX> gathered
outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX>' locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> suddenly
appeared a short distance away, heading toward his limo. He saw the press and,
for a moment, seemed to be coming toward us. Then he stopped, and just stared.
One could imagine that he felt a little hurt when he realized that we didn't
want to talk to him. No one even shouted a question. He boarded the limo and
left.

            We went into the locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>,
and soon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jordan</ENAMEX> emerged, already dressed in a perfectly pressed olive suit, his
tie knotted tight at the stiff collar of a white shirt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> always dresses
this way in public. A professional.

            "I totally hadn't found my
rhythm <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first three quarters</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> said. "When I found it, things started
to click."

            Sweat
popped out on his head in the close-up glare of television lights. Reporters
pressed him up against the little wire <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cage</ENAMEX> that passes for a locker. He
obliged every question, then stepped outside to sign a few autographs.

            
His <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Falk</ENAMEX>, said his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX> would
play as long as he meets his own standards. He'd decide year by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. He's a
free <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this season</TIMEX> and if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX> want him back they'll have to pay
the big money. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falk</ENAMEX> got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next year</TIMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Falk</ENAMEX> wouldn't
say what it would take. How would one ever calculate such a thing? Some things
are beyond money, beyond numbers. How much would you pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">amber fields</ENAMEX>, the
purple mountains?

            Someone asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> if he'd
stick around town <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX> to watch his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alma mater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX>, play
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryland</ENAMEX>. It was a huge game in college <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX>.

            He shook his head.

            "I got a job to do."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan</ENAMEX> drives to the hoop
in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Game 2 of the 1991 NBA Championship Series</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lakers</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>; video only) :
            

         
      
   
