
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Williams</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1883-1963</TIMEX>)

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>)
            

            To hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX> read
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turtle</ENAMEX>," click .

            In the
genre of the commissioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poem</ENAMEX>, there are not many as charming as this one.
When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> addresses the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> as his noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patron</ENAMEX> ("my Lord") and alludes
to the old myth of the tortoise that supports the universe, he slyly introduces
the underlying weight of civilization and history into the interchange between
him and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. The matter-of-fact acceptance of the violence in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s
imagination is an interesting aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX>' own omnivorous imagination. I
don't think any other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> has succeeded in using the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> word "car" as
effectively as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> does in this poem and others.

            -- <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>
            

            Not because of his eyes,  
  the eyes of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bird</ENAMEX>,          but because he is beaked,

            birdlike, to do an injury,
    has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> attracted you.          He is your only pet.

            When we are together    
you talk of nothing else          ascribing all sortsof murderous motives    
to his least action.          You ask meto write a poem,     should I have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poem</ENAMEX> to write,          about a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turtle</ENAMEX> lives in the
mud     but is not mud-like,          you can tell it by his eyeswhich are
clear.     When he shall escape          his present confinementhe will stride
about the world     destroying all          with his sharp beak.Whatever
opposes him     in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>          shall go down.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">Cars</ENAMEX> will be overturned.  
  And upon his back           shall ride,to his conquests,     my Lord,        
 you!

            You shall
be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>!     In the beginning          there was a great tortoisewho
supported the world.     Upon him          All ultimatelyrests.     Without him
         nothing will stand.He is all wise     and can outrun the hare.        
 In the nighthis eyes carry him     to unknown places.          He is your
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">friend</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
