
   
   
      
         
            Theater of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">War</ENAMEX>

            
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nathaniel Hawthorne</ENAMEX>, who met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March of 1862</TIMEX>, one
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> looked like a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> schoolmaster: He was
"about the homeliest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> I ever saw." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s hair was "black, still unmixed
with gray, stiff, somewhat bushy, and had apparently been acquainted with
neither brush nor comb that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, after the disarrangement of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pillow</ENAMEX>."

            

               The man
who spruced up the shaggy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> for posterity was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathew Brady</ENAMEX>, and a brush
and comb were the least of his tools of transformation, as a comprehensive
clear. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX>'s studio <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> used vises and braces to keep their subjects
still, columns and drapes to make them look distinguished, light and shade to
give them depth and stature. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln</ENAMEX> posed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX>, during a
campaign swing through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> retouched the negative to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s roving left eye, and erased the lines on his face. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shimmering</ENAMEX> and widely published result, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, "made me
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>." A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady Lincoln</ENAMEX> is on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">penny</NUMEX>, and another on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">five-dollar</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>.

            

            
This exhibition, along with the excellent
catalog by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Panzer</ENAMEX>, is out to correct the impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady</ENAMEX>
captured the look of his times with the new apparatus that couldn't lie. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady</ENAMEX>
is often credited with bringing the war home, in the images that appeared in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> all across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX>'s name, in fact, has become all but
synonymous with <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX> photography. While it is probably true, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sontag</ENAMEX> has argued, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX>'s images of the horrors of the battlefields "did
not make <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> any less keen to go on with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>," he did convey to
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> the sheer human cost of the war. He also inspired <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">photographers</ENAMEX>--especially such 1930s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX> of documentation as Berenice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walker Evans</ENAMEX>--with the idea that there was something peculiarly
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX> about the pitiless gaze of the camera. "If he has not brought bodies
and laid them in our door<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">-yards</NUMEX> and along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>," wrote a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times editorialist at the time, "he has done something very like it." These
were the images that lit a fire in the brain of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Crane</ENAMEX> when he was
writing <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Red Badge of Courage</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years later</TIMEX>.

            But
actually, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panzer's</ENAMEX> catalog makes clear, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> was put off by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX>. The
stunning images of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Antietam</ENAMEX> dead, lying in ditches where they fell, are the
work (published under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX>'s name) of his brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy O'Sullivan</ENAMEX>. (You can see some of these battlefield photos
in 
                  Slate
               's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Taste for Taboo</ENAMEX>.")

            
Far from being a documentarian, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady</ENAMEX>
considered himself an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, and his images, in the jargon of current art
history, were highly "constructed." When a general failed to show up for a
group photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Sherman</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> had him
photographed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next day</TIMEX>, and spliced his image into the ensemble. When the
faces of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> convened to impeach <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Jackson</ENAMEX>
looked too sour, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> painted in a reassuringly genteel background. For a few
hundred dollars, he was willing to go all the way, and replace the grays of a
photograph with painted colors.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady</ENAMEX>
worked in close collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> died in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> barely
large enough to hold his bed, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> photographed the multitude of mourners
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studio</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alonzo Chappel</ENAMEX> assembled them (often
in the exact poses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> had choreographed) in a monumental and wildly popular
painting, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Last Hours</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1868</TIMEX>).

            
That <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> was a great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> who did not
take photographs was merely the most obvious of the many paradoxes of his
career. He was an impresario and a brand name, hiring talented assistants
(several of whom went on to become major <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> in their own right) to
shoot, color, and otherwise alter <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> daguerreotypes, and then--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> was
always up on the latest technical innovations--stereographs, ambrotypes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial</ENAMEX> salted paper prints, and other photographic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exotica</ENAMEX>. During the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil</ENAMEX>
War, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> sent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> into the battlefields. His own whereabouts
during much of the war remain unknown. A possible reason for this has come to
light: While pursuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> for portraits late in the war, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> was
apparently using his knowledge of troop movements to speculate on Wall Street,
sending coded messages through <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intermediaries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX> got wind of the scheme, and asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Assistant Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">War Charles</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dana</ENAMEX> to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> "how he is being deceived by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> to whom he has granted
various privileges and favors." But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> remained a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwart supporter</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">wizard behind these Oz</ENAMEX>-like wonders remains elusive--we don't even know what
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">year Mathew Brady</ENAMEX> was born, though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1823</TIMEX> is the usual guess. His childhood in
upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> is a blank. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> had serious eye trouble from his youth on;
an oil portrait in the show, by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Loring Elliott</ENAMEX>, shows him
wearing thick spectacles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> made his way to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, and by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1843</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daguerre</ENAMEX> announced his new invention, he was already active in
the slightly disreputable trade of photography, manufacturing the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leather</ENAMEX> and
metal cases for holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">daguerreotypes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> published work was an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1846</TIMEX> collaboration, with the female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">warden</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sing Sing</ENAMEX>, on a phrenological
study of prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX>--the sort of analysis of "criminal physiognomy" that
later influenced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">painters</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Degas</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baudelaire</ENAMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady</ENAMEX>
never acknowledged the project, he remained in close touch with quacks. A
detailed phrenological analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> himself, dating from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1858</TIMEX>--the year
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> moved his base of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>--is included in the exhibition catalog.

            
A tireless self-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> (a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> described
him as "felicitously prehensile"), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> was camera-shy, placing himself on the
margins of photographs in which he appeared or, more often, with his back
turned. But theatricality is the hallmark of his work. He loved to photograph
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, the more flamboyant the better. He was apparently drawn to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">specialized</ENAMEX> in "trouser roles"--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> are on display in the exhibition,
including a particularly intense ambrotype (a cheaper and less luminous form of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">daguerreotype</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Felicita Vestvali</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lesbian</ENAMEX> who often appeared as <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hamlet</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> also delighted in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> costumes: among his photographs are those of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ute</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> negotiating a treaty in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest</ENAMEX> in warpath regalia as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prince</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Metamora</ENAMEX>.

            When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brady</ENAMEX>
photographed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of the antebellum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Webster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Clay</ENAMEX>,
and the rest--he turned them into <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> too. They strike heroic, Napoleonic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">poses</ENAMEX>, hand to heart, which made these wafflers and compromisers look
ridiculous after the debacle of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Civil War</ENAMEX>. (If you want to see the original
of the pose, you can cross the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mall</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gallery</ENAMEX>, where
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacques-Louis David's 1812 Napoleon</ENAMEX> in His Study hangs.)

            But for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brady</ENAMEX> himself, war
never quite lost its theatricality. Unlike his cold-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assistants</ENAMEX>, he
preferred to visit the battlefield after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">corpses</ENAMEX> had been cleared away.
There he would stand, his back turned to us like the contemplative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>
figure in a painting by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caspar David Friedrich</ENAMEX>, and reflect on the glory and
folly of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mankind</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathew Brady</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1896</TIMEX>. Elusive till <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, he was
scheduled to lecture, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks later</TIMEX>, on his life and work as a war
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX>--with slides and patriotic music--at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnegie Hall</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
