
   
   
      
         
            The Unfairway

            Increasingly I fear that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX> has become auto racing. What makes it so riveting are the crashes. The
psychological breakdowns. The spasms of self-destruction. The carnage.

            We saw
that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Masters Tournament</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Norman</ENAMEX> debacle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
had always dreamed of winning the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Masters</ENAMEX>, and something had always gone wrong.
This time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> went into the final round with a lead so commanding--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>
shots--it seemed to be even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>-proof. What ended up happening was that he
merely raised the standard by which other blown tournaments will now be judged.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watching Norman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that day</TIMEX> was sickening, like seeing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swede</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savage</ENAMEX> crash at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indy</ENAMEX>,
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Taylor</ENAMEX> break <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Theismann</ENAMEX>'s leg. I remember calling old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>
that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I hadn't spoken to in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a long time</TIMEX>. In a world of pain,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.

            Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX> was the No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> golfer in the
world, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX> rankings. He's won more money on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PGA Tour</ENAMEX> than
anyone else in history, yet he will go down in history as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> of
extraordinary misfortune--not so much a failure as a fatality, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>'s surgical ability to bring to the surface a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s mental weakness. I
still root for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>, but I also think of him as a cadaver. He looks a mite
gaunt, and has been prone to fits of rage lately. He screamed at a volunteer at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kemper Open</ENAMEX> for making a joke about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> blowing out his knee
at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>. At another point he misheard a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>'s comment, thought he was
being heckled, and gave the fan the finger. Then at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open Championship</ENAMEX>
he played <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> rounds in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14</TIMEX> over par, a repulsive performance. Our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>.

            Two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends ago</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kemper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Wiebe</ENAMEX> had the tournament pretty well wrapped
up. It was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years</TIMEX> since he had won a tournament. With a one-shot lead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiebe</ENAMEX>
played the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> hole perfectly, hitting safely over a pond to the
fat part of the green. He lagged his putt to within <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about two-and-a-half feet</NUMEX>.
He had a straight uphill putt for par. He could make <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX> such putts in a
row on a practice green. But golf is about the torture of the weak. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Wiebe</ENAMEX>
yanked his putt left and lipped it out. His <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wheels</ENAMEX> had come off. He'd hit the
wall. There was nothing left but shards of metal and the wails of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed</ENAMEX>.
He was still tied for the lead, but that didn't matter, since the devastation
of missing that putt ensured that, on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">18 th</NUMEX> , facing an almost
identically easy putt, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">three feet</NUMEX> straight uphill, he didn't even catch any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lip</ENAMEX>, missed it wide left, game over. The world is a dark, cruel place. A few
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days later</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiebe</ENAMEX> had a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>-putt green," something so awful
you almost never hear of it--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> putts on a single green before the fucking
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ball</ENAMEX> went in the fucking hole.

            
How did golf become a sport of woe and misery?
It may be that the media spotlight is that much more intense, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfers</ENAMEX> know
how many cameras are trained on their quivering hands. Maybe it is the
purses--a missed putt now can cost a golfer a couple of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundred thousand</NUMEX>
dollars. Or maybe it is that the competition is so stiff that no single player
can dominate like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Palmer</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Nicklaus</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Watson</ENAMEX> did in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heydays</ENAMEX>. No one out there has a prayer of winning <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> major tournaments like
did. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfers</ENAMEX> win <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> tournament in their entire career--some minor
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kmart</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Classic</ENAMEX> sort of thing--and even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">golfers</ENAMEX> who are good enough to win
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">majors</ENAMEX> tend to win <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one or two</NUMEX>. The window of opportunity is small, and
they all fear having it slam shut on their fingers.

            The antidote to the recent
trend of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">golf</ENAMEX> tragedy has been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger Woods</ENAMEX>. Coming into the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX>, he had
never lost anything that mattered to him. He'd won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">USGA</ENAMEX> championships in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> junior titles and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> consecutive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Amateurs</ENAMEX>. He'd
won his first major as a pro, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Masters</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, and had done so with such
record-smashing brilliance that he'd actually exceeded the hype that had been
built up around him. When he arrived for the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX>, it was as though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX> had showed up.

            "Let's go
over there and get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiger</ENAMEX>'s divot," I heard a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> say <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX>, referring to the
tiny chunk of grass and dirt that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> had scraped from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fairway</ENAMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX> is the sport's biggest event. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
Open has a longer history and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masters</ENAMEX> is more familiar--it's played on the
same course <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX>, and some of us can recite the yardage from tee to green
on the back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>--but the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX> has the strongest field, the toughest
conditions. Everyone was buzzing about the rough, the dreaded rough, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">heinous</ENAMEX> and monstrous rough, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 inches</NUMEX> officially but sometimes looking more
like <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX>--ravenous, insatiable rough, a form of grass so severely impairing
a golf swing that it was more like an <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>.

            Woods
never got close to leading the tournament, much less winning. I followed him
some on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first and last days</TIMEX>, and he was spectacular. No one has as much
club speed, and when he strikes a ball, it whistles, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">rockets</ENAMEX> out into space on
a line and then, astonishingly, rises, as though hitting another gear, some
kind of warp drive, before parachuting to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> uncannily close to where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woods</ENAMEX>
wants it to go. His problem was that the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">U.S. Open</ENAMEX>, particularly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congressional</ENAMEX>
Country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>'s blue course, rewards conservative, risk-averse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. The way
to win is to shoot pars--on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fairway</ENAMEX>, on the green, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-putt for par, go to
the next hole. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX> played conservatively, rarely using his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX>; but, for
all his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">genius</ENAMEX>, he's not the straightest golfer in the world, and he ended up
in the spinach (isn't it fun to use sports clichés!) too often. That he didn't
putt well ensured that he wouldn't be a factor. He finished tied for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">19 th</NUMEX> , and then told the press that "the suffering's over," that the
course had "humbled me big time." He was still a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX>--in fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sony</ENAMEX>
computer bumped him to No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>, past the fading <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>--but you could imagine
that he was on his way to becoming just a golfer. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX>, eventually, a broken
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.)

            
The final day I was appalled that the only
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> leading the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open</ENAMEX> were plodders and mopers and grumpers and nobodies.
They were <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> without color, literally wearing gray and beige and brown. The
final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> were tied at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> under par going down the back <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX>, and it
was obvious, watching them labor away, unsmiling, that this was just an
endurance test to see who could avoid crashing and disintegrating on national
television. You had to root for perennial nice-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Lehman</ENAMEX>, who'd led after
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> rounds of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third consecutive year</TIMEX>. I could not bring
myself to root for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Maggert</ENAMEX>, as his name bothers me, sounding too much like
a taunt--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggert</ENAMEX>! <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggert</ENAMEX>! Also he'd committed the sin of winning a pile of
money on tour, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.6 million</NUMEX>, while winning only a single tournament. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernie Els</ENAMEX>
alone among the final <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> had won an <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Open</ENAMEX>, but was a vanilla <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>,
plain-looking and apparently without any emotions whatsoever. And finally there
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colin Montgomerie</ENAMEX>, a multiple failure in major tournaments, surely the best
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in the world never to have won one of these things.

            First, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggert</ENAMEX> destructed.
He got on a bogey run that wouldn't quit, and he grimmed his way right out of
the tournament. Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehman</ENAMEX> hit into the rough by the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> green and
lost a stroke. The next hole, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">17 th</NUMEX> , we all watched in
gut-wrenching horror as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehman</ENAMEX> hit his approach shot into the pond. Nice <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX>
finish <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lehman</ENAMEX>
said afterward, "I feel an incredible amount of pain."

            Just before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lehman</ENAMEX>'s disaster, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomerie</ENAMEX> had made the
crucial mistake of the tournament. He and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Els</ENAMEX> were on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX>
green, tied at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> under. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montgomerie</ENAMEX> had a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">five-foot</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">putt</ENAMEX>. He waited for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX> on the nearby <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">th</ENAMEX> green to finish. He waited and waited.
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Minutes</TIMEX> passed. Sometimes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> in life is faced with a crucial decision, a
life choice, a yes-or-no question, a moment when action must be taken
decisively without pause or excessive contemplation. Everyone watching thought:
Hit the putt! Just walk up and hit it! Montgomerie wandered around the green,
waiting for total silence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Tolles</ENAMEX>, a golfer finishing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>, made some
gestures as though he was going to throw his ball in the lake, and the crowd
cheered him on, which got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montgomerie</ENAMEX> flustered again. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> just did not
want to hit the putt. Because he knew it wasn't going in. He knew he was about
to crash.

            Finally he walked up and
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heartedly</ENAMEX> tapped at the putt, which missed, and he lost, and when
it was over he cried.

         
      
   
