
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swimmer</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michael</ENAMEX>
Collier

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swimmer</ENAMEX>," click .

            Nothing like him in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bosch</ENAMEX>
or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Breugel</ENAMEX>, nothing so denatured as to resemblenot a semblance of a human
facebut the substance of some form made and then unmade, or like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lump</ENAMEX> of
human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter excavated</ENAMEX> from a bog.

            His eyes askew, aligned by
a jagged axis that must have balanced once across the fulcrum of his nose. The
pupils deep and lost but ever seeinglike <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">well</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. The head
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">misshapen</ENAMEX> like a too-ripe

            melon, dimpled by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">forceps</ENAMEX> mark of his accident or whatever extracted him from normalcy, dipped
him in the searing, crushing waters of disfigurement and then returned himto
the world to fill it with the childish

            worrying sound working its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> from his mouth that's not so much a mouthas a coin purse cinched tight,
sewnwith the fragments of his lips--the yipping gait of breathlessness he
makes, which makes no sense

            without the fluttering
exuberance of his hands that come to rest, delicately, on my shoulders, as if
to say: "Help tie the drawstring of my suit, shoulder my towel, fit these
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sandals</ENAMEX> to my feet and lead me to the pool

            where you
will see how struggling to be what I am, I become--otter, seal,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dolphin</ENAMEX>--released from myself, though not absolved, not ever able to hide the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fin</ENAMEX> or the fluke, my feet webbed and unwebbed."

         
      
   
