
   
   
      
         
            Gossip

            By Thom
Gunn

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11</TIMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gossip</ENAMEX>," click .

            

               I
            

            <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">First</NUMEX> saw himon the street
in front, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thebar</TIMEX>'s garbage, identifyingunfinished <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beers</ENAMEX> and swiggingoff what
was left of them,shameless and exuberantremarking in friendly fashion"It's a
doggy <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX> world."Charming error. Hehad little idea of his lookscaught on a
brief sillbetween youthful lean timesand blowziness to come,and too unfocused
to tryhustling more than beerand a night out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>.Later, circling
vaguelythe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX>'s deep dark inside,"Hitched up from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>,"he said, "here,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wanna</ENAMEX> feel it?"It was already out,pushed soft into my hand. It wasa lovely gift
to offer an oldstranger            without conditions,a present from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
Orleansin a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">doggy dog</ENAMEX> world.

            

               II
            

            Stories of
bar-fights,boasts of glory.That's the old cattelling them, that onewith the
tattered ear."Yeah," he says,"I was passing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wash houseback</ENAMEX> of the farm
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX>,where I sometimes got handouts,and there's this passel of kittensin a
basket, mewingtheir fuckn heads off. Well,some of them were male,future toms.
You know I hadto do something about that.So I dove in, checkingthem <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">males</ENAMEX> like
I always can(call it a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX>), and I bit offthe heads of the ahcompetition.
Heh, the little galsI left to grow up a bit.Then there was that time,I was
still in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX>,facing a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bar</ENAMEX> full of sailorswith jest a broken bottle
..."<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaunting</ENAMEX> voice grateson and on, nobody listening, untilhe has drunk
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">himselfasleep</ENAMEX>. No longer deadly,no longer dashing, nothing buta shabby old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tabby</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
