
   
   
      
         
            Sign o' the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>

            Neon alters language, its
gaseous glow elevating dull verbs (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EAT</ENAMEX>), bland nouns (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HOTEL</ENAMEX>), and vapid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antonyms</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">VACANCY/NO VACANCY</ENAMEX>). In red and blue neon, even a flat announcement
like OPEN acquires a cold yet undeniable fire.

            But
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neon</ENAMEX>'s cool heat alone did not make the OPEN sign the visual loudspeaker of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> small business. First, neon had to evolve from handicraft to
commodity, from carefully considered decision to impulse purchase, from custom
manufacture to mass production. Only then could OPEN join the pay phone and
public toilet as invisible icons that don't appear until you look for them.

            The sign's ubiquity was a long time coming. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, a simple neon OPEN sign retailed for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $400</NUMEX>. That's not cheap,
but it's far less expensive than the first neon sign sold in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>,
which blinked on in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1923</TIMEX> when a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> had a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Packard</ENAMEX>" sign
made for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,200</NUMEX> (by comparison, the cheapest new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Packard</ENAMEX> on the lot sold for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,600</NUMEX>).

            Invented
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Frenchman</ENAMEX>, the neon sign quickly became an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americanism</ENAMEX>. "Neon in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>
meant progress, vitality, urban excitement. It symbolized <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> energy,"
writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudi Stern</ENAMEX> in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> book, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The New Let There Be Neon</ENAMEX> . A neon
sign in the window also advertised the fact that a merchant was flush enough to
have spent some coin. But even after the neon patents expired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX> and
the form boomed, signs stayed expensive. And thanks to their fragility and
artisan nature, they also remained locally produced. In the medium's heyday,
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1940s</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> boasted <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 2,000</NUMEX> neon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>. Today, there
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a mere several hundred</NUMEX>.

            
What changed the neon-sign business was the
beer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. In the course of a few postwar <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfits</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallon</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luminous Products</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everbrite</ENAMEX> learned how to manufacture durable,
transportable neon signs for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>, and the various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX>
brands. Protective plastic housings, sturdier mounts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lighter transformers</ENAMEX>, and
shock-resistant shipping boxes gave the signs greater mobility. Mass production
cut costs.

            But aside
from beer logos and a few other popular corporate insignias, neon was a tough
mass-market sell, despite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>' efforts to break new markets. It wasn't
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everbrite</ENAMEX> devised blue and red OPEN signs
(it's a matter of dispute who made the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>), but the way they sold
them--door-to-door, mostly--kept prices high. A generic OPEN cost about what a
local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> would charge for one made to order, and the market responded
accordingly. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a good year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everbrite</ENAMEX> sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 500</NUMEX> signs.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> Everbrite moves <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15,000</NUMEX> OPENs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallon</ENAMEX> is
just as busy. The market blossomed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the late 1980s</TIMEX>, with the rise of
wholesale <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">buyer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clubs</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Costco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SAM</ENAMEX>'S <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>. "Their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> were
mainly small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Fallon</ENAMEX>. "We showed a classic size sign to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SAM</ENAMEX>'S. They tested it, and it hit." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everbrite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Jacobs</ENAMEX> pitched
Costco, which also saw OPEN signs fly out of the aisles. Now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SAM</ENAMEX>'S <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> sells
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallon</ENAMEX>'s signs for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $115</NUMEX>; at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Costco, Everbrite</ENAMEX>'s sell for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$119.99</NUMEX>.

            Experienced production-line
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> fashion an OPEN in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 10 minutes</TIMEX>. Despite their name, many signs
contain <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gases</ENAMEX> other than neon. A few puffs of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">argon</ENAMEX> fill the blue border of an
OPEN; neon itself powers the red portion of the message. In the new generation
of OPEN signs, the red is redder and the blue bluer because the glass tubing is
coated with colored ink. If reheated, as they would have to be in the course of
repair, the inks melt into brown <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goop</ENAMEX>, making the signs such a pain to fix that
it's easier to buy another than to take a broken model into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX>.

             

            
The classic OPEN sign is a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35-inch by 15-inch</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rectangle</ENAMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> feet of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">12-millimeter</NUMEX> tube in the word OPEN and another
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8 feet</NUMEX> in the border. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason the sign has achieved world domination is
because the letters' height-to-width ratio approximates the Golden
<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Section</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1-to-1.618</NUMEX>--so beloved of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX>, and the ordinary human
eye. Another is that the size fits most transoms, windows, and walls. Still
another: The shipping box stacks easily on a standard pallet.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Mavens</ENAMEX>
can discern between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">makers</ENAMEX> at a glance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallon</ENAMEX> sets its OPEN in a molded
plastic case, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everbrite's</ENAMEX> mounts on a metal armature. Everbrite markets
the classic rectangle only, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fallon</ENAMEX> offers a vertical OPEN, as well as an
Art <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deco</ENAMEX> bullet shape.

            The OPEN sign's popularity tracks that of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">strip mall</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Immigrant shopkeepers</ENAMEX> and boomer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX> needed to let <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passers-by</ENAMEX> know
they were ready for business. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fifty years ago</TIMEX> they'd have scrawled OPEN on a
shirt cardboard and perched it to catch the eye of a passing pedestrian. But
who window <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> anymore, except at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">35 mph</NUMEX>, through a window set in the frame
of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>?

            The lingua
franca of commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> has done what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esperanto</ENAMEX> could not: achieve
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">universality</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>, a few neon signs do growl <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GEOFFNET</ENAMEX>. But more often the
word is OPEN--evidence, says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> neon <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">connoisseur</ENAMEX> there, of continental
affection for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americana</ENAMEX>, along with a changing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> culture. "In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>,
there used to be customs about when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX> could operate," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dusty</ENAMEX>
Sprengnagel, who owns a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neon Line</ENAMEX> and whose book on neon will reach
store shelves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>. "Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> closed at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekdays</TIMEX> and on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> were not open or were open only until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>. We all knew the rules, so
no one needed an OPEN sign. But things have changed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Shops</ENAMEX> may be open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX>,
they may be open all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. The OPEN sign is not pretty, but it provides
the information you need."

            
With OPEN going <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">platinum</ENAMEX>, why not a neon CLOSED
sign? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everbrite</ENAMEX> tried one, but it tanked. An OPEN sign is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">binary beast</ENAMEX>, it
seemed--if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">store owner</ENAMEX> turned it off, the message was implicit. You couldn't
say the same of a CLOSED sign--if it was off, would that mean proprietors
lurking in the back waiting to make a sale?

            An unlit OPEN has a fearsome
power of its own. "We get calls from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose signs aren't working. They're
desperate," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everbrite</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobs</ENAMEX> says. "A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> told me, 'I run a video <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>. I
broke my sign washing my window. I've got to have another <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> right away,
because my <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX> on the next block has a neon OPEN sign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> can see
that he's open, but with my sign broken they think I'm closed.' "

         
      
   
