
   
   
      
         
            <EM>Hoodlum</EM>

            
               (Note: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life and Art</ENAMEX>"
is an occasional column that compares fiction, in various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, with the
real-life facts it is ostensibly based on.)
            

            Larger-than-life figures
from the annals of organized crime--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bugsy Siegel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Capone</ENAMEX>--are often drafted
into service when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> decides to make one of its perennial gangster
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">flicks</ENAMEX>. Whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> on-screen end up bearing much relation to their
models, however, varies from film to film. Hoodlum , directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duke</ENAMEX>, tells the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellsworth</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bumpy</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gangster</ENAMEX> who did
battle with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dutch Schultz</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>. Though rooted in history, its
portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> fits into the great <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> tradition of dramatic
enhancement.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>'s central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">story concerns</ENAMEX> a battle over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlem</ENAMEX> numbers racket. The
numbers game was an illegal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> lottery--particularly popular in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>--in
which, typically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> chose a number from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">999</NUMEX> and placed bets
through "policy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> won if his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">number</ENAMEX> matched an agreed-upon daily
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">variable</ENAMEX> made known through some public <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channel</ENAMEX>--for example, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the last three</TIMEX>
digits of the total amount wagered at a given <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">racetrack</ENAMEX>, which anyone could
learn through the sports pages. Since the game never favored the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>, the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>" naturally amassed large profits. Besides, the outcome was often
fixed.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX> was one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>'s most notorious fixers. When the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX> begins, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early '30s</TIMEX>, he (played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Roth</ENAMEX>) is a white <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Prohibition</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer baron</ENAMEX> who has muscled his way into the neighborhood numbers racket,
shutting down <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX> or forcing them to join his operation. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
(<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurence Fishburne</ENAMEX>), who had made his criminal reputation in 1920s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>,
returns from jail upset by the white incursion into the trade. Meanwhile,
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucky Luciano</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Garcia</ENAMEX>) worries that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>'s
numbers-racket war may be bringing too much attention to bear on organized
crime; even as he continues to do business with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>, he schemes to take
over the latter's operation. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano</ENAMEX> form an alliance,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX> is bumped off. This plot line, though embellished, is mostly based
on reality.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lucky Luciano</ENAMEX> are renowned figures, staples of crime books and
studies. But who was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpy Johnson</ENAMEX>? And what are the major discrepancies
between the film's portrayal of him and the record? Though he may have been
overlooked in white <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> of the time and in subsequent histories of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">era</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> was certainly notorious. When he died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam News</ENAMEX> called him "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlem</ENAMEX>'s most famous underworld figure." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film</ENAMEX>, though, exaggerates his role in several instances and gives no hint as to
what happened to him after the numbers battle was over.

            
For starters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoodlum elevates Johnson</ENAMEX>'s
importance at the expense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie St. Clair</ENAMEX>, a k a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madame Queen</ENAMEX> (Cicely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson</ENAMEX>), an immigrant from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martinique</ENAMEX> who became a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">numbers millionaire</ENAMEX>, and for
whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> went to work after his release from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX>. In the film, Madame
Queen effectively drops out of the picture when she is sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen E. Quiñones Miller</ENAMEX>, a staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inquirer</ENAMEX> who is writing a book on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, says that while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Clair</ENAMEX>
was in fact imprisoned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months</TIMEX>, it was during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>, before the
fight started for control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX> racket.

            
On-screen, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Clair</ENAMEX> is depicted as being scared of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> has to
fight in her place. In life, she was less passive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Sann</ENAMEX>, former executive
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Post</ENAMEX> , writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Kill the Dutchman!: The Story</ENAMEX>
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>) that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Clair</ENAMEX> herself stood up to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>, even
asking city <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> to crack down on his racket. "It's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>'s life or
mine," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Clair</ENAMEX> reportedly said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dutch</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> know I am the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>
who can take back from their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> the racket he stole from my colored friends
and they know I'm going into action." And in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX> was dying in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Newark</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, having been gunned down in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> hit, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Clair</ENAMEX> sent a Western
Union message: "As ye sow, so shall ye reap." That telegram is omitted from the
script, which has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX> dying immediately after being shot.

            That's only one of several inaccuracies in the film's
portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>'s murder. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Viewers</ENAMEX> are left with the impression that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> orchestrated the killing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fishburne</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roth</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX> off
against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garcia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano</ENAMEX>, effectively duping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano</ENAMEX> into slaying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>. In
life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>'s murder was ordered by the national criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicate</ENAMEX> formed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano</ENAMEX> and the famed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mobster</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer Lansky</ENAMEX>. agree that the main reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>
was killed was because he'd recklessly threatened to rub out special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Dewey</ENAMEX>, who was after him for tax evasion and racketeering. He'd even
proposed the hit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicate</ENAMEX>, which rejected it: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mob</ENAMEX> couldn't afford
the attention such a murder would bring.

            

               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoodlum</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dewey</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Atherton</ENAMEX>) bears little resemblance to the real
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">district attorney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX>, and failed presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX>.
Most glaringly, he's shown taking cash from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano</ENAMEX>, some of which is meant to
prevent him from going after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>. This never happened, and there's no
evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dewey</ENAMEX> was corrupt. In fact, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dewey</ENAMEX> who later successfully
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">prosecuted Luciano</ENAMEX> on prostitution-related charges.

            
Since the film ends with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schultz</ENAMEX>'s death, it
leaves little indication as to what became of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>. And it implies that the
Harlem racket reverted to local control. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Encyclopedia of New York</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that, after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lansky</ENAMEX> took over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX> racket.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s role remained an important one, but he was definitely not his own
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boss</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Mafia</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ethnic Succession</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organized Crime</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>),
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis A.J. Ianni</ENAMEX> writes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> essentially worked as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">middleman</ENAMEX> for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">syndicate</ENAMEX>. When a black wanted to buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">franchise</ENAMEX> to establish a
numbers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX>, he went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpy</ENAMEX>."

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>,
the movie depicts him as a gangster with a heart, but a gangster nonetheless.
At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, he throws cash to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in a local soup line. At another, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> murdered while in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s employ sobs, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> call you
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> ... you're just a common <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thief</ENAMEX>," reminding us of the violence he brought
to his neighborhood. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quiñones Miller</ENAMEX> says that, though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s reputation in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlem</ENAMEX> was mixed, he was known for taking care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpy</ENAMEX> made
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italians</ENAMEX> give money to neighborhood charitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>." When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>
died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, of natural causes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Breslin</ENAMEX> wrote a column, calling him a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Hood</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX>.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrenson</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s self-proclaimed
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lover</ENAMEX>, this is a romantic view of him. In her memoir, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Stranger</ENAMEX> at the
Party (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>), she quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Daily Mirror</ENAMEX> on the news that
he was sentenced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six-to-10</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sing Sing:</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlem</ENAMEX> is in a state of rejoicing
that his reign of terror is over." But she also quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Amsterdam</ENAMEX>
News , which says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> was "welcomed like a conqueror" when he came
back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> after doing time in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alcatraz</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prisons</ENAMEX>. The film
ends with the camera zooming toward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s eye until the screen becomes more
and more grainy and ultimately black, as if to suggest that settling the big
questions of who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bumpy Johnson</ENAMEX> really was and what he meant to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harlem</ENAMEX> may be
beyond its range. After all, it's only a movie.

         
      
   
