
   
   
      
         
            Signs and Wonders

            Are they loathsome, or do
they attest to the indomitability of the human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spirit</ENAMEX>? They infiltrate every
corner of our consciousness, but do we understand them? Let us begin with the
act of exuberance that defines the genre:

            
               Raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roof</ENAMEX>: A
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-armed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">palms</ENAMEX>-skyward pump. A handstand standing up. The implication: That
play was so unbelievable I must raise the roof of this <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">arena</ENAMEX> to contain the
collective excitement I've generated. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paternity</ENAMEX> remains contested: Some credit
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas Cowboy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Emmitt Smith</ENAMEX> with the first <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roof-Raising</ENAMEX>, in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Super Bowl</ENAMEX>.
Others ascribe it to a high-school <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald's</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">All-America</ENAMEX> game. Various collegiate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> playing various sports claim
ownership. Raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roof</ENAMEX> is the celebratory sports gesture of the
moment. Like all inspired sports gestures, it's moved beyond sports. Everybody
does it--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pro athletes</ENAMEX> and college <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athletes</ENAMEX>, talk-show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> and talk-show
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX>.

            But to
trace the lineage of Raising the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roof</ENAMEX>, one must understand the history of the
sports gesture itself. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> must go back to a time few of us can remember. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> before ...

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">High</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX>: A gesture so ubiquitous
that it's hard to imagine what else <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> could have done, it wasn't invented
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Smith</ENAMEX>, a forward on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Louisville</ENAMEX>'s championship <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">basketball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. When asked why he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX> had
invented this elevated palm slap, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> replied, "We decided to be a little
odd." But how odd can the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">High</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> seem now? Like the ripped dungaree, the
High-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> has swept the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> and been duly coopted. True <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> have been
forced to forge new, more exotic gestures.

            Thus the
'80s saw "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">the Fun Bunch"</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> Redskins <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">receivers</ENAMEX>) choreographing a
leaping High-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">quartet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Jets</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Gastineau</ENAMEX> performed a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twyla Tharpish</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sack Dance</ENAMEX>" after <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tackles</ENAMEX>. Yet, all these lacked the elegant
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy of the High</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX>. All, that is, until ...

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monster Bash: A collision</ENAMEX> of hard-muscled,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pop</ENAMEX>-veined forearms, which briefly form an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">X</ENAMEX>" upon impact. A barbaric
crunching of radius and ulna bones. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bash</ENAMEX> began in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, and it went
everywhere. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">progenitors</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Canseco</ENAMEX>, brutish sluggers
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oakland A's</ENAMEX>. After each home run (and there were many), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX>'s
would meet at the plate for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Monster Bashing</ENAMEX>. Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bash</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invention</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX> marketing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> had cooked up a song. The lyrics
featured a challenge to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bash</ENAMEX>'s ancestor: "If you're a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oakland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A's</ENAMEX>/ You, too, can do the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX> craze/ When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A</ENAMEX>'s big bats
really come alive/ Don't waste time with the boring High-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five</NUMEX>."

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickey Shuffle</ENAMEX>: A hulking touchdown jig. Ickey
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woods</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fullback</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cincinnati Bengals</ENAMEX>, debuted this masterpiece in the
fall of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> banned celebratory displays, in part as a reaction to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shuffle</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ickey</ENAMEX> would not be repressed--and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> loved him. So actually
ordered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickey</ENAMEX> to keep dancing (albeit on the sidelines). Soon, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ickey</ENAMEX> added a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">post-Shuffle</ENAMEX>, hip-rolling "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woo-Woo-Woo</ENAMEX>" dance, for which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengals</ENAMEX> defensive
backs joined him. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1989</TIMEX>, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengals</ENAMEX> reached the playoffs, what
had begun as a struggle for individual expression ended in an avalanche of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">conformity</ENAMEX>.

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '90s</TIMEX>, gesture
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> sold out. They now seek the public's embrace and are aided by the
wildfire spread new gestures enjoy when shown on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SportsCenter</ENAMEX> .
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> need only see ...

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City-Boy Bounce</ENAMEX>: An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arch-</ENAMEX>backed, fists-clenched
shoulder jiggle, sometimes paired with a zombielike trance-walk. Tradition
holds it started on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playgrounds</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>. Popular mostly with <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> and
basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bounce</ENAMEX> is perhaps the best-looking gesture of all, but
it is also the hardest to perform. It requires a level of fluidity not commonly
seen in nonathletes. In this sense, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bounce</ENAMEX> is a gesture for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elitists</ENAMEX>, and
thus a glaring counterpoint to ...

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambeau Leap</ENAMEX>: A jubilant <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">vault</ENAMEX> into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Green Bay</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lambeau Field</ENAMEX>. Invented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>: After a big
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">interception</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Packers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">safety</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leroy Butler</ENAMEX> . The populist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leap</ENAMEX> is particularly
suited to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX>'s only publicly owned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, the zealously beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Pack</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Players</ENAMEX> express their appreciation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambeau</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> by hurtling into their
midst, for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">just one moment</TIMEX> becoming one of them.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Leap</ENAMEX>
reached its zenith with the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Packers' Super Bowl</ENAMEX> win <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last season</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This season</TIMEX>'s
hot new gesture?

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mile-High Salute</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Military</ENAMEX> tradition
turned football celebration. A basic salute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teammates</ENAMEX> after touchdowns.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creators</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Denver Broncos</ENAMEX>' running backs, who unveiled the salute at
preseason games <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. A gesture clearly suited to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX>'s warlike
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nature</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salute</ENAMEX> is named for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Denver</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Mile High Stadium</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broncos</ENAMEX> have
invited their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> to join in, creating a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stadium</ENAMEX> saluting in unison and
marking the pinnacle of the football culture's fascistic tendencies.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salute</ENAMEX> developed into a stadiumwide event, but several other gestures have been
designed specifically for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">herd</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60,000</NUMEX> sports <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX>. These include:

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wave</ENAMEX>: Generally traced to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seattle</ENAMEX>
Kingdome, though some insist it dates to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Michigan</ENAMEX> football
game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fans</ENAMEX> standing at appropriate <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> fashion a group undulation.
Particularly frustrating for abstainers: A cry of "down in front" will not
dampen a rollicking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wave</ENAMEX>, so sight lines are blocked at regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">time</TIMEX> intervals.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wave</ENAMEX> remains popular, though not as controversial as ...

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomahawk Chop</ENAMEX>: A robotic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hacking</ENAMEX>--only the forearm moves. Often accompanied by an outsized foam tomahawk
and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> chant." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chop</ENAMEX> gained mass attention when the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">1991 World Series</ENAMEX>, but it actually originated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Florida State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seminoles</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Native American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> hate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chop</ENAMEX>, but former
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Carter</ENAMEX> defended it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>: "With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Braves</ENAMEX> on top, we have a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brave</ENAMEX>, courageous and successful <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, and I think we can look on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> as brave, successful and attractive. So I don't look on it as an
insult."

            Though
less controversial, the most bizarre gesture of all remains ...

            

               The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Octopus Toss: In</ENAMEX> celebratory
moments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Detroit Red Wings</ENAMEX> throw real octopuses onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>. The
tradition began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> needed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> playoff victories to win the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Cup</ENAMEX>. An octopus has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> (and smells awful). At times, more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50</NUMEX> octopuses rain down at once. Another time-honored <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> activity occurs if
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rink workers</ENAMEX> refuse to pick up the cephalopods with their bare hands--the crowd
boos them.

         
      
   
