
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seven Years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>

            
               (Note: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Life and Art</ENAMEX>"
is an occasional column that compares fiction, in various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, with the
real-life facts on which it is ostensibly based.)
            

            It has been widely reported
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that Seven Years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> , the tale of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Austrian</ENAMEX> mountaineer Heinrich
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX>'s trek through <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> and his relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>, was
nearly released with an embarrassing omission. It failed to mention that Harrer
had been a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sergeant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SS</ENAMEX>. The news, revealed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> magazine
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stern</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this June</TIMEX>, took the movie's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cast</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> by surprise. At a press
conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Pitt</ENAMEX> declared: "You say 'Nazi,' and all these
connotations like concentration camps come up. That was not the case. [<ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Harrer</ENAMEX>]
was an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX> who spent the entire war in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Jacques Annaud</ENAMEX>
subsequently made a few changes. For instance, when, at the beginning of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">film, Harrer</ENAMEX> and an expedition party leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX> for the as-yet unscaled
Himalayan mountain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nanga Parbat</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX> calls Harrer "a distinguished
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Socialist Party</ENAMEX>." (The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>.) Someone else hands
him a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> flag to place atop the peak. Toward the end of the film, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX>'s
Harrer contemplates the takeover of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> by the intolerant, totalitarian
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>, he says in a voice-over, "I shudder to recall how once, long ago, I
embraced the same beliefs."

            Harrer
certainly lamented the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> takeover. Whether that meant that he renounced
previously held beliefs (or what exactly those beliefs were in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place)
is harder to ascertain. Harrer, who is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">85</NUMEX> now, kept quiet about his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> past
until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stern</ENAMEX> article was published. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> after
meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon Wiesenthal</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vienna</ENAMEX>, he issued a statement. It read, in part:
"My personal political philosophy grew out of my life in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> ... and [it]
places great emphasis on human life and human dignity. ... It is a philosophy
that leads me to condemn as strongly as possible the horrible crimes of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> period." Having already made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> an unappealing egotist
interested only in mountain climbing until the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> changed his life, the
filmmakers were able to incorporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> 's unpleasant revelation into
the story line quite easily. The press material for the movie talks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX>'s
"emotional transformation" and then says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> piece helps us
understand the "extent" of this transformation.

            Whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrer</ENAMEX> was transformed by his voyage and his
connection to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> is unclear; there is some evidence to suggest that
on crucial issues, he wasn't. But otherwise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seven Years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> does
conform to the record of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX>'s trip--although it should be noted that much
of what we know of that trip comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX>'s own memoir, from which the
movie takes its title.

            In life, as on-screen, Harrer
and his fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expeditioners</ENAMEX> were placed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>-of-war <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> at the start of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrer</ENAMEX> and several other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> escaped
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX> (the movie has the escape take place earlier). He set off alone, but
ended up traveling with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Aufschnaiter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Thewlis</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nanga Parbat</ENAMEX> expedition. They made their way across the border and into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>,
contending with treacherous terrain, frostbite, hunger, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">robbers</ENAMEX>, and an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">interdiction</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>. Finally, they reached <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lhasa</ENAMEX>, the "forbidden
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>," in part by duping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> along the way with an out-of-date travel
permit. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrer</ENAMEX> became a tutor to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">th Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>.

            In the
movie, this relationship looks suspiciously like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fairy</ENAMEX> tale. Harrer not only
teaches the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> about radios and time zones but also befriends the "god
king" and is apparently his sole source of informal contact and entertainment.
Can <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrer</ENAMEX> really have helped build a movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">theater</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>? Well,
if we consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-paragraph foreword to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX>'s memoir
some sort of guarantee of its accuracy, the answer is yes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> also
writes in his autobiography, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Freedom in Exile</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX> had a
"wonderful sense of humour" and that "as I began to get to know him better ...
he became very forthright. ... I greatly valued this quality."

            
The movie does embellish somewhat the intensity
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Austrians</ENAMEX>' relationships with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aufschnaiter</ENAMEX> did not marry a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan</ENAMEX> during their stay. Harrer was not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX> in play
(for instance, it was someone else who helped him tinker with old <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>). And it
wasn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">explorer</ENAMEX> who proposed an escape plan to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, when
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> invaded, though he did urge him to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lhasa</ENAMEX>.

            As for
the invasion, the film understandably simplifies events--it leaves out, for
instance, the unheeded pleas for help made by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> that preceded the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invasion</ENAMEX> and the unheeded pleas to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> that followed it--but on
the whole, the movie is fairly accurate. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> did fall to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, and an incident shown in the film as crucial to the success of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">invasion</ENAMEX> was indeed definitive--when, in a startling act of cowardice, Ngabo
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ngawang Jigme</ENAMEX> (played in the movie by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B.D. Wong</ENAMEX>), a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tibetan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> in charge
of defending the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamdo</ENAMEX>, not only abandoned it but also ordered the
destruction of ammunition supplies before he left. Moreover, the film's
foreshadowing of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> atrocities (as reflected by a dream in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX> sees his native village being pillaged and monks shot) reflects the
historical facts all too well. As the written epilogue to the film <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
almost all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX>'s monasteries--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 6,000</NUMEX>--have been ransacked under the
occupation.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Seven Years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> ends with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">enthronement</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 15</TIMEX> and his assumption of the role of political as
well as spiritual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. The film's epilogue mentions that he
fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, though it mentions neither that this took place in the
middle of an attempted rebellion against the occupiers nor that his <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Buddhist</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beliefs</ENAMEX> had previously led him to cooperate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX>'s
life as exiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> is beyond the movie's time frame (for more on this, see
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assessment</ENAMEX>" of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Ambassador</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shangri-La</ENAMEX>").

            However, the film is really
less historical drama than personal epic--the story of how a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> was
changed by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibet</ENAMEX> and its philosophy. We are supposed to believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX> has learned to be a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>; offered as proof is his changed
attitude toward his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolf</ENAMEX> (whose name in real life is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>). In life and
in the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrer</ENAMEX> left for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nanga Parbat</ENAMEX> when his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> was still pregnant.
(In the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrer</ENAMEX> knows she's pregnant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> reports that Harrer
denies having known she was.) She divorced him while he was gone. At various
points in the film, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrer</ENAMEX> thinks longingly of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolf</ENAMEX> and writes him letters. His
overtures are rebuffed; his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> has come to think of his stepfather as his true
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> actually was abandoned by his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mother</ENAMEX>, too; he was raised by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">grandmother</ENAMEX> during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX>'s absence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">memoir</ENAMEX>, which covers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years 1939-1952</TIMEX>, never mentions him.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pitt</ENAMEX>'s Harrer
finally returns to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>, dropping a music box--a gift from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lama</ENAMEX>--in his son's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom</ENAMEX>. The last scene shows <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> climbing a
mountain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alps</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> flag of the opening scene has become a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tibetan</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, which they place on the summit.

            However, this climb never
happened. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>, who wasn't invited to either of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX>'s subsequent weddings,
told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanity Fair</ENAMEX> , "We didn't have much of a relationship"--though he
also claimed he has no hard feelings toward his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>, whom he now sees
occasionally. The friendship between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dalai Lama</ENAMEX> continues to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
