
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Battle Station</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Johnson</ENAMEX>, ace of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Mariners</ENAMEX>, is the most thrilling, harrowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>. He's a
left<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-hander</ENAMEX> who puts the sinister back in "sinistral." He's <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 feet 10 inches</NUMEX>
tall, gaunt, with long scraggly <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hair</ENAMEX>, a rough <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complexion</ENAMEX>, humorless
eyes--altogether a bit too much of that hitchhiker look. As if throwing the
ball <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">98 miles per hour</NUMEX> isn't wicked enough, he does it with a wild, whipping,
sidearm motion, which makes left-handed batters want to dive out of the box and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dugout</ENAMEX> even as the ball is crossing the plate. For many
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hitters</ENAMEX>, the best strategy for facing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> is simple: <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Stay</ENAMEX> on the bench.

            My
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> and I watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> one <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> recently at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camden Yards</ENAMEX>, home of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baltimore Orioles</ENAMEX>. We could barely take our eyes off him.

            We didn't notice the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> (I learned days
later, when I decided to research the subject) was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Wilson</ENAMEX>. He is actually
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catchers</ENAMEX> in the game. But needless to say, he is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>.
He's no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Bench</ENAMEX>. He's not even an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ivan</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pudge</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>. It is hard to be
a star when you are a catcher, especially when there's the real thing, the
glamour boy, the icon, just <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">60 feet 6 inches</NUMEX> away on the mound.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">catcher</ENAMEX> has the least glamorous, most difficult, and most self-sacrificing job
in the game. He has to do everything--call pitches, throw out base-stealers,
reposition infielders, chase down foul balls, calm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> the ball,
establish a rapport with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">umpire</ENAMEX> so he calls a big strike zone, chase <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bunts</ENAMEX>,
run down toward <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> base to back up the throw from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shortstop</ENAMEX> and, worst of
all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> home plate even if it means getting bowled over by charging
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Fosse</ENAMEX> never really recovered from the separated shoulder he got
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Rose</ENAMEX> decided to slam into him at home plate during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970</TIMEX> All-Star
game. Rose set the all-time record for base hits while playing various infield
positions, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fosse</ENAMEX> became known only as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> who got smashed.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Acatcher</ENAMEX>'s life is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hobbesian</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Dickey</ENAMEX>,
catcher on the great <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yankee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '30s</TIMEX>, once got leveled by a base
runner even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> could have slid into home far ahead of the ball.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dickey</ENAMEX> marched over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dugout</ENAMEX> and punched the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offender</ENAMEX> in the face, earning
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX>'s suspension and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a thousand</NUMEX>-buck fine. Catching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pioneer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Famer Roger Bresnahan</ENAMEX> invented the shinguards and the helmet just after the
turn of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, when he got tired of getting whonked constantly--at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
point some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bresnahan</ENAMEX> had died after a
particularly vicious fastball off his noggin. (According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Owens</ENAMEX>'
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Great Catchers</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bresnahan</ENAMEX> worked in the off-season as a private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">detective</ENAMEX>--a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX>'s mind is never at rest, it seems.)

            A catcher
is something of a baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">martyr</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Catchers</ENAMEX> are almost invariably slow of foot
simply from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of squatting, the leg muscles shortening with time.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Statistically catchers</ENAMEX> rarely put up huge career totals in home runs or RBIs
because no one can catch a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">season</TIMEX>'s worth of games (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">162</ENAMEX>). Catching 130 is the
stuff of an iron <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catchers</ENAMEX> who can still hit retire to first
base, a position for the fat, the stiff, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame</ENAMEX>, and the halt.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> sees everything--he's in the center of the
action. Yet he is not really seen . The geometry of the game conspires to
hide him. He must wear a mask. He must wear pads and shinguards. He is obscured
by his posture--a squat--and the big mitt he must position in front of himself.
He's more of a concept than an actual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> is merely implicit--a
presumption of the game, like the scorekeeper or the grounds <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX>. The catcher
is right there in the thick of the action, but no more interesting than the
chalk lines that delineate the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">batter</ENAMEX>'s box.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> is a blue-collar
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> in a game of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaires</ENAMEX>. He wears a steel mask over a helmet whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> points backward, a style that invariably makes even the most hardened,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mature</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> seem oddly juvenile, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who failed to grow up. All that hard
work and he just looks silly.

            A baseball
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">catcher</ENAMEX> has a nickname: The backstop. He might as well be an inert mass. Yet of
course it is he, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>, who is the field general. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>
stands tall, in full view, he cannot send a signal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> as to what
pitch will come next. It is the catcher, low to the ground, with that shadowy
zone around his groin, who must call the pitch. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> also gives signals
to the infielders, letting them know what to do in case of a double steal, or
what to do if a runner at first tries to steal when there's also a runner at
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> calls the game, he must know the hitting abilities
and weaknesses of every opposing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">batter</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> is essentially the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarterback</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, only without the huge endorsement contracts.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Hoiles</ENAMEX>, starting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX>,
told me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> in the locker <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, "We're usually the dirtiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">field</ENAMEX> and the sweatiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> on the field. We stink all the time."

            He said his gear gets really
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">raunchy</ENAMEX>. It's no fun to strap that stuff on when the thermometer hits the upper
90s. And that squatting he does--it's as uncomfortable as it looks. Meanwhile
he says of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX>: "All the eyes are on him. All the recognition goes to
him." There's no whine in his voice. This is just reality. He knows that when a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitcher</ENAMEX> throws a no-hitter the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> is lucky to get in the photograph in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>'s paper.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoiles</ENAMEX> is a big slab of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">33</TIMEX>, a veteran but not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX>. The rap on him is that he can't throw
out base <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">runners</ENAMEX>. "The thing that impresses <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catchers</ENAMEX> is arm
strength," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> bench <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Etchebarren</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoiles</ENAMEX> admits he never had a
strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>. He is otherwise steady on defense and can hit home runs. He became
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> because he grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowling Green</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ohio</ENAMEX>, in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">era</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX>
Bench ruled the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reds</ENAMEX> down in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cincinnati</ENAMEX>. Meeting Bench was one of the greatest
moments of his life.

            "I
absolutely love the position," he says. "You're right in the middle of the
action. You're the one that has to make a lot of decisions. There's a lot of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">prestige</ENAMEX> in the position."

            He means prestige in terms of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. It doesn't carry
that far beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dugout</ENAMEX>, though. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> has always been a somewhat
overlooked position. Even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yogi Berra</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hall of Famer</ENAMEX>, was never the great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX>--he labored in the shadow of greater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Mantle</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whitey Ford</ENAMEX>. In my lifetime <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Bench</ENAMEX> has been the singular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">superstar</ENAMEX> of
the position (he was once on the cover of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time magazine</ENAMEX>). There have
been plenty of worthy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catchers</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlton Fisk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Boone</ENAMEX>--but the ones that
became most famous are those who went into broadcasting, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim McCarver</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Garagiola</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Uecker</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Piazza</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Dodgers</ENAMEX> is the
snazziest young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> and could be Cooperstown bound. (Lately I have been
inexplicably tempted to use "Cooperstown bound" when talking about each and
every <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX>--e.g., "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nice</ENAMEX> single there by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cooperstown</ENAMEX>-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ledesma</ENAMEX>.")

            In the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> there are
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 11</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catchers</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this century</TIMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> per <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade</TIMEX>.
That compares with, for example, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> right fielders and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">56</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pitchers</ENAMEX>. Every
position in <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> has more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>, with the sole
exception of .

            There is, in fact, a crisis
of sorts in the catcher position. No one wants to play it anymore. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Kids</ENAMEX> refuse
to catch.

            "There's
not a whole lot of them out there," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Etchebarren</ENAMEX>.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lenny Webster</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orioles</ENAMEX> backup catcher, said
he started playing the position because no one else would do it.

            "You get beat up a lot," he
says. "There are times when you have to block balls and they're not always
going to hit that chest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protector</ENAMEX>."

            Many of
the top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catchers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX>--once again filling jobs that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">native</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are reluctant to do.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">Baseball</ENAMEX> has never been allowed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">intelligentsia</ENAMEX> to be
simply a game played with a ball--it must always be a metaphor for something
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grander</ENAMEX>, like democracy, the re-creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Garden of Eden</ENAMEX>, the rights of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> vs. the needs of the collective, or whatever. In this annoying
tradition, let me suggest that the plight of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">catcher</ENAMEX> is symbolic of a dire
trend in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> society--call it the decatcherization of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> life. We just
don't get dirty like we used to. We don't sweat. We finesse our way out of
trouble, using the checkbook, rather than choose a brutal collision and trust
that we will hang on to the ball.

            We refuse to live
uncomfortably, and in so doing lose all sorts of knowledge that can only come
with the grit of hands-on labor. The problem with so many jobs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> is not that they pay poorly but that they are vaporous, the mere
manipulation of words and symbols and concepts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Pollan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> and
magazine <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, writes in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Place</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My Own</ENAMEX> about how he had become so
disconnected with the physical world that he finally decided to hammer together
a writing hut in his backyard, a desperate attempt to make contact with real
objects.

            The affluent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classes</ENAMEX> are more
comfortable than ever--we can barely, dimly imagine the world, just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">generations ago</TIMEX>, when <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> cherished the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears Roebuck</ENAMEX> catalog
for its utility as toilet paper. It is now considered normal to travel several
blocks or even miles to find a place that charges <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than a dollar</NUMEX> for a cup
of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>. But what great <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coffee</ENAMEX>! We cherish our comfort, our good <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, our
friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beverages</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> we condition our air so that we will not
sweat--except when we go to the gym, where we pay someone money so that we can
use our muscles. We are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outfielders</ENAMEX> now. We laze about in the grassy fields of
life. We wonder if someone will hit us the ball.

         
      
   
