
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curse</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler Yeats</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1865-1939</TIMEX>)

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>)
            

            To hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curse</ENAMEX>," click .

            In "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curse</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeats</ENAMEX> writes in apparently effortless couplets, demonstrating what he
says about writing--what is demanding is made to look natural and easy. The
conversation in his poem is so convincingly real yet the poetry so gorgeous in
its sounds that I always feel a little shocked to realize how sad the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> actually is. Yet the sweep and grace--to include so much of love and
art and life in such a small <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX>, with such a beguilingly intimate
surface--temper the sadness a lot.

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>
            

            We sat together at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer's end</TIMEX>,That beautiful mild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, your close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>,And you and I, and
talked of poetry.I said, "A line will take us hours maybe;Yet if it does not
seem a moment's thought,Our stitching and unstitching has been naught.Better go
down upon your <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX>-bonesAnd scrub a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen pavement</ENAMEX>, or break stonesLike an
old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pauper</ENAMEX>, in all kinds of weather;For to articulate sweet sounds togetherIs
to work harder than all these, and yetBe thought an idler by the noisy setOf
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX>, schoolmasters, and clergymenThe martyrs call the world."

                                      
   And thereuponThat beautiful mild <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> for whose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sakeThere</ENAMEX>'s many a one
shall find out all heartacheOn finding that her voice is sweet and lowReplied,
"To be born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> is to know--Although they do not talk of it at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>--That
we must labour to be beautiful."

            I said, "It's certain
there is no fine thingSince <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX>'s fall but needs much labouring.There have
been <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovers</ENAMEX> who thought love should beSo much compounded of high courtesyThat
they would sigh and quote with learned looksPrecedents out of beautiful old
books;Yet now it seems an idle trade enough."

            We sat grown quiet at the
name of love;We saw the last embers of daylight die,And in the trembling
blue-green of the skyA moon, worn as if it had been a shellWashed by time's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">waters</ENAMEX> as they rose and fellAbout the stars and broke in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>.

            I had a
thought for no one's but your ears:That you were beautiful, and that I stroveTo
love you in the old high way of love;That it had all seemed happy, and yet we'd
grownAs weary-hearted as that hollow moon.

         
      
   
