
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn Revolution</ENAMEX>

            In the
ritual bashing of wildly successful retail <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outlets</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX> has received
its share of scorn. In-the-know <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> mock the home furnishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> for
its buy-a-lamp, get-a-lifestyle attitude and its antiqued, weathered,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX>-coordinated pseudostyle. The omnipresent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> has also been accused of
inducing a bland homogenization in home design. "Everything seems more and more
the same, wherever you are," wrote architecture <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Goldberger</ENAMEX> in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times Magazine</ENAMEX> article <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. "The stuff may be good but it
ain't special."

            Goldberger, while
rejoicing that sophisticated design has finally reached the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masses</ENAMEX>,
rightly lamented that it has come at the price of individual variation and
taste. Just as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX> look has become as much of a uniform now as the preppy
aesthetic it replaced, so also has the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX> look standardized our homes
as vacuously as any traditional style. But in the big picture, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gapping of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> furniture has actually been one of the most welcome developments in
recent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>. It has made good design easily accessible and, paradoxically,
opened opportunities for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> manufacturing that may help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> develop
a sense of personal style.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> have always had bad taste in furniture. It's been
hard to say, though, whether we're innately philistine in our artistic
judgments or have merely been deprived of decent choices. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>, most
furniture that was well designed came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, was priced accordingly, and
was off-limits to most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>. Then things started to change, slowly. The
Bauhaus design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> introduced the idea that good design could be had by
anyone; in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1950s</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauhaus</ENAMEX> aesthetic led to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> manufacture of
such modernist (but still too pricey) classics as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Eames</ENAMEX>' lounge chair
and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">ottoman and Arne Jacobsen's Egg Chair</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the '60s</TIMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Englishman</ENAMEX> named
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terence Conran</ENAMEX> opened a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Habitat</ENAMEX>, selling what has come
to be called "transitional" furniture--mixable <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">pieces</ENAMEX> so neutral and
inoffensive they could fit into any environment. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conran</ENAMEX> brought the idea to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, opening his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX>. Still, big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethan Allen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Broyhill</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drexel</ENAMEX> continued to dominate the market with safe,
conservative styles or traditional looks from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last century</TIMEX>.

            What finally ended the
reign of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> was the proliferation of such
high-design/low-price <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crate & Barrel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IKEA</ENAMEX>. In
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">et al.</ENAMEX>, have realized the ideas of the Bauhaus
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conran</ENAMEX>, and then some. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Furniture</ENAMEX> has been <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gapped</ENAMEX>--streamlined to its purest
lines in a way that appeals both to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with sophisticated tastes and to
those without a lot of money. And while this standardization has produced a
certain monotony, it has also generated some good design. Many a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dish</ENAMEX> or chair
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IKEA</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX> is of better design quality--with simpler forms and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">purer</ENAMEX> colors--than its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomingdale's</ENAMEX> (although the
manufacturing quality may be not as good). Take, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX>'s
wide-brimmed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capri</ENAMEX> bowls, which come in bone or light periwinkle. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Resembling,</ENAMEX>
yet not flatly derivative of, an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rice dish</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Capri</ENAMEX> bowl confidently
walks that fine line between elegance and edge--and was on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX>
for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.99</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX> and the others have turned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> on to
furniture. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnard</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retail Trend Report</ENAMEX>, since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-1996</TIMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> have been spending more on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> than on apparel (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$296.3 billion</NUMEX>
vs. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$277.9 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>). This sudden interest can also be attributed to
other causes--we're older and nesting; we're spending more time at home; we're
making bolder purchases because of a better economy. But what's noteworthy is
that it's young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who have developed a taste for cool places to sit and
sleep. A survey by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Furnishings Council</ENAMEX> found that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under 35</TIMEX>
were most likely to agree with the statement "I like to shop for furniture."
Young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> are growing up with good design around them--in clothes, in
advertisements, in movie <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sets</ENAMEX>--and this improved climate surely makes them more
discriminating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>.

             

            Paradoxically, the
Gapping of furniture has made it easier for new, innovative design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to
thrive. You could see the stirrings of a creative revolution <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at this year</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Contemporary Furniture Fair</ENAMEX>, held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few weeks ago</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX>.
The fair still showcased some of the arts-and-craftsy "novelty" elements
(lights in the shape of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">pigs</ENAMEX> or brassieres, chairs made from shopping <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">carts</ENAMEX> or
traffic barricades) that earned it the "bad <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">flea</ENAMEX> market" label when it began a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decade ago</TIMEX>. But there were also a dozen small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">designer-manufacturers</ENAMEX> producing
funky yet rational design at affordable prices. Even though these items cost a
bit more than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX> fare, they were no doubt affected by the success of
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>'s clean, simple lines. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blu Dot Design</ENAMEX>, for instance, offered its
handsome and functional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uptown</ENAMEX> series: a cocktail table (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$499</NUMEX>), sideboard
(<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$899</NUMEX>), and media <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">cabinet</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$649</NUMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cherry</ENAMEX>, chrome, and sandblasted glass that
discreetly allow for both storage and display. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>-based
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year old</TIMEX>, its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">twentysomething founders</ENAMEX> have already got
orders from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retailers</ENAMEX> around the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. They've been written up
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsweek</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>, and an array of design <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. Most telling
of all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">series</ENAMEX>' cocktail table and sideboard are now part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joey</ENAMEX>'s living room on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Friends</ENAMEX>.

            In addition, medium-size <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Directions</ENAMEX> are
now offering sophisticated design and manufacturing quality at department-store
prices, retaining an attention to fine detail that the mass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX> lack. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvin Klein</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Karan</ENAMEX> have also got in on the act, introducing
their high-quality (though far from original) "home collections." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren</ENAMEX> has
already covered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloomingdale's</ENAMEX> furniture <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> with haute
preppy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ensembles</ENAMEX> of paisley, tartan plaid, and corduroy. The rise of "boomer
casual" has even forced the major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> to move beyond their perennial
colonial reproductions. Their more "modernized" furniture looks as if it were
designed by a committee tallying up market research, but it's a start.

            A home
swathed in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karan</ENAMEX>, of course, is no better than a home swathed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pottery Barn</ENAMEX>.
But the next stage in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s design evolution may not be far off. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, one hip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SoHo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, called <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Troy</ENAMEX>, offers new stuff next to classics by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacobsen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alvar Aalto</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tribeca</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Totem</ENAMEX>, showcases a slew of young
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> who will individualize pieces according to your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Totem</ENAMEX>'s first line of its own--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Surface Collection</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Schwan</ENAMEX>--is both
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">playful</ENAMEX> and versatile, consisting of building-blocklike tables, credenzas, and
cabinets with interchangeable parts and colors, depending on whether the pieces
are going in an office or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kid</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>. The collection won a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Best Furniture</ENAMEX>
award at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Contemporary Furniture Fair</ENAMEX>. Soon, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
will no longer be able to blame bad taste in furniture on a lack of choice.

         
      
   
