
   
   
      
         
            Elegy on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Death of Sidney</ENAMEX>

            By Fulke
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greville</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1554-1628</TIMEX>)

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Feb.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>)
            

            To hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elegy on the Death of Sidney</ENAMEX>," click .

            Fulke
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greville</ENAMEX> deserves to be better known; I personally consider him to be an equal
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Donne, Marvell, Jonson</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX> of the sonnets. He was a boyhood
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Sidney</ENAMEX>. (An early school notebook of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney</ENAMEX>'s contains, in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney</ENAMEX>'s childish handwriting, the notation "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fulk Grivil</ENAMEX> is a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>.")
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greville</ENAMEX>'s admiring biography of his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, who died young, may have somewhat
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">eclipsed Greville</ENAMEX>'s own reputation. It is important for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> of the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Elegy on the Death of Sidney</ENAMEX>" to realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney</ENAMEX>--a brilliant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, of
extremely noble <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, a statesman and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> who died of war wounds at the
age of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>--was looked on as a kind of perfect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> born with the greatest
advantages, who had the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> and goodness to make the best of them. (This
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">poem</ENAMEX> is sometimes attributed to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>, Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Dyer</ENAMEX>, also a member
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney-Greville</ENAMEX> circle.)

            
               --<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Pinsky</ENAMEX>
            

            Silence augmenteth grief,
writing increaseth rage,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Staled</ENAMEX> are my thoughts, which loved and lost the wonder
of our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age</TIMEX>;Yet quickened now with fire, though dead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">frost ere</ENAMEX> now,<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enraged</ENAMEX>
I write I know not what; dead, quick, I know not how.

            Hard-hearted minds relent
and rigor's tears abound,And envy strangely rues his end, in who no fault was
found.Knowledge her light hath lost, valor hath slain her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">knight</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney</ENAMEX> is
dead, dead is my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX>, dead is the world's delight.

            Place, pensive, wails his
fall whose presence was her pride;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> crieth out, My ebb is come; his life was
my spring tide.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fame</ENAMEX> mourns in that she lost the ground of her reports;Each
living wight laments his lack, and all in sundry sorts.

            He was--woe worth that
word!--to each well-thinking mindA spotless friend, a matchless <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, whose
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">virtue</ENAMEX> ever shined;<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Declaring</ENAMEX> in his thoughts, his life and that he
write,Highest conceits, longest foresights, and deepest works of wit.

            He, only like himself, was
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> unto none.Whose death, though life, we rue and wrong, and all in vain do
moan;Their loss, not him, wail they that fill the world with cries;Death slew
not him, but he made death his ladder to the skies.

            Now sink of sorrow I who
live--the more the wrong!Who wishing death, whom death denies, whose thread is
all too long;Who tied to wretched life, who looks for no relief,Must spend my
ever dying days in never ending grief.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart</ENAMEX>'s ease and only I,
like parallels, run on,Whose equal length keep equal breadth and never meet in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>;Yet for not wronging him, my thoughts, my sorrow's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>,Shall not run out,
though leak they will for liking him so well.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farewell</ENAMEX> to you, my hopes,
my wonted waking dreams;<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farewell</ENAMEX>, sometimes enjoyed joy, eclipsed are thy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">beams;Farewell</ENAMEX>, self-pleasing thoughts which quietness brings forth;<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">And</ENAMEX>
farewell, friendship's sacred <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX>, uniting minds of worth.

            And farewell, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">merry heart</ENAMEX>,
the gift of guiltless minds,And all sports which for life's restore variety
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assigns</ENAMEX>.Let all that sweet is, void; in me no mirth may dwell:<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip</ENAMEX>, the cause
of all this woe, my life's content, farewell!

            Now rime, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of rage,
which art no kin to skill,And endless grief, which deads my life, yet knows not
how to kill,Go seek that hapless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tomb</ENAMEX>, which if ye hap to find,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salute</ENAMEX> the
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX> that keep the bones that held so good a mind.

         
      
   
