
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Night</ENAMEX> Class

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew</ENAMEX>
Hudgins

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 22</TIMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Night Class</ENAMEX>," click .

            He'd pull a yellow
clipping from his wallet,and while you read it he stared in your face.The other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> scanned the clipping, nodded,smiled as best they could, and gave it
backto the pudgy, sweaty <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, who grinned at themexpectantly.                  
     They complained, and finallyI stopped him after class.                    
                             "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mister Kearny</ENAMEX>,maybe you shouldn't, uh, share
with your friendsabout shooting your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>."                                  
         "I didn't shoot him.""You didn't?"                         "No sir, I
hit him with a bat.See, he was whipping on my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mom</ENAMEX> againand whipping on me too
and then <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> dayI just got tired of being whipped onand I hit him with my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">uncle</ENAMEX>'s metal batand just kept hitting till he didn't move.I didn't mean to
kill him, just make him stop."His high voice trembled, his eyes were fixed on
mine."I got my picture in the paper." He reachedback toward his hip. "You want
to see the clipping?"

            "That clipping, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kearny</ENAMEX>, that's the problem.<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> get very nervous around <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">somebodywho</ENAMEX>'s killed
somebody--no matter why he killed them.Now maybe that's unfair, but if you
thinkabout it I'm sure you'll understand it's true."

            He stared down the
emptying hallat a few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> heading to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>,their late jobs, home.    
                                   "Does that make sense to you?"

            The twin fire-doors
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wheezed</ENAMEX> shut behind <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX>.His face deepened to a face I've cometo think of,
on other faces, as ancient, accepting.

            "That makes
sense to you, now doesn't it?"I said, a little sharply.

                                      
             "Yeah, I guess."He was whispering.                                
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Good</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>. I'm glad.Now don't forget the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that's due <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>."

            He pushed
his way into the stairwell. I waiteduntil I heard the outside door clank
shutbefore I followed. I wanted to be the onewhose leaving let the hall fall
into silence--silence, which I have, from talking, learned to love.But what,
when no one loved me, have I donebut talk, talk, talk until I've said, like
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>,the thing I shouldn't say or, as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">tonight</TIMEX>,until I've said exactly what
I've had to say.And as I hurtled home past dark, tires wailing,I howled with
every song on the radio,screamed some teen-age <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stranger</ENAMEX>'s stupid words,shrieked
somebody else's rage, somebody's lovetill I could bear my own voice, and its
silence.

         
      
   
