
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lavender Disaster</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. John</ENAMEX>

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov.</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lavender Disaster</ENAMEX>," click .

            It was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the old days</TIMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic City&</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">icy rain</ENAMEX> began to clear the boardwalk

            Of even the most desolate
stragglers

            I pulled my ultra-cool
thrift <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">store</ENAMEX> fedoraDown low over my eyes & just kept on walking

            & as I passed an old
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">storefront</ENAMEX> painted up

            Like a fortune teller's
bazaar its ancient bricksCovered in narrow stripes of orange and lavender

            As if it were a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gypsy</ENAMEX>'s
rippling tent

            The old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> inside said
softly to me the words Come try & nothing else but after a few
steps

            I turned & went back
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">&</ENAMEX> stepped out of the rain

            To face her across the
small round tableWhere she sat shuffling a bent pack of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tarot</ENAMEX> cards

            
               Sit down she said
& of course I did just that

            & as she laid the
cards out slowly before herShe quietly rocked a little in her chair

            Then she told me the story
of the future I might hold

            & as she spoke the
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> filled with <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a lightAs</NUMEX> thick as the mist outside & softly lavender

            As softly lavender as an
electric summer sunset

            Down at the beach with
maybe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX> or even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renata&</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gypsy</ENAMEX>'s eyes closed & my own eyes
too

            As she said You will
sit in the throne of Heaven
            

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">&</ENAMEX> die into the open
arms of your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lord Well</ENAMEX> that's really nice I thought

            All this death shit &
not a word about sex or money

            But I couldn't open my
eyelids for a second& when I did the mist had cleared although a faint

            Scent remained of my
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grandmother</ENAMEX>'s lavender sachet

            & the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gypsy</ENAMEX>'s hand was
out so I slapped down a fiveThen got out before she told me something else

            I didn't want to know but
I was worse than chilly now

            A little bent out of shape
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">&</ENAMEX> leery of the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">wayThe night</TIMEX> was coming down so black along the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>

            I just knew I couldn't go
on to work <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that night</TIMEX>

            So I turned back &
started heading home thinkingHow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX> would be pissed I'd spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">that five</TIMEX>
spot

            On the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gypsy</ENAMEX> not to
mention I'd be back

            Early with no money from
the shift I couldn't doBut maybe we'd go out to the movies

            We hadn't done that since
I'd been made a night <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>

            That would make her happy
I thought the movies& then a drink at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jake's</ENAMEX> to make up for the fact

            We'd be broke again next
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">week</TIMEX> for sure

            & as I opened the door
to our apartmentI swear I could smell the scent of lavender

            & that same mist began
rolling through the living room

            & I could hear them
then in the back bedroomMaking those little fucking sounds so fucking
softly

            So fucking tenderly it
made me want to scream

            But I just walked through
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">kitchen</ENAMEX> & <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">grabbedThe ice</ENAMEX> pick off the counter where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stella</ENAMEX>'d

            Left it after chipping ice
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">flakes</ENAMEX> for their drinks

            & as I came to the
open <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedroom doorI</ENAMEX> stood there for a second but

            They didn't notice me her
legs fiercely bicycling

            The air & he was
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jack</ENAMEX>-hammering away at herSo I just stepped up beside the bed &
punctuated

            This happy dream with a
few decisive holes

            To let the lavender air
out of the moment& I'm not kidding as I watched the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of them

            Stretched out silently
across the damp mattress

            I could actually see the
mist clearing again& again I could finally breathe a little

            So none of the rest of
this really matters

            & you reading this
matter least of allBecause I am the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who knows my simple

            Future & all of the
rest of you must live in the pain

            Of not knowing of not
believing what comesWill be finally not so different from my own

            Wild glory as I come to
sit at last upon

            My own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lordly</ENAMEX> throne so
carefully hewnOf precious woods & polished by the sweat of men

            Who before me have
mistakenly believed only

            They were worthy of this
journey I welcomeAs I am fitted with those perfect leather straps

            A helmet wired to the
future & charged by the grace

            Of God & the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Governor</ENAMEX>
to carry me into that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HeavenI</ENAMEX> was promised one distant lavender

            Night

         
      
   
