
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emission Accomplished</ENAMEX>

            In horse <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, everyone
will always remember precisely where they were and what they were doing when
they first heard the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigar</ENAMEX> was shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blanks</ENAMEX>.

            Tragedy is part of horse
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">racing</ENAMEX>, but this cut to the heart of the business, the ancient and profitable
enterprise of breeding. Every <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">thoroughbred</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is the descendant of one
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> stallions--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Darley Arabian</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Godolphin Barb</ENAMEX>, and the Byerly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turk</ENAMEX>--brought to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three centuries ago</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigar</ENAMEX> had
brought honor to the bloodline. He had won <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16</NUMEX> consecutive races and been named
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Horse</ENAMEX> of the Year twice in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a row</TIMEX>. He was the most celebrated thoroughbred since
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secretariat</ENAMEX>. Surely he would make a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monster stud</ENAMEX>. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breeder's Cup</ENAMEX> last
fall, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Khuen</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> thoroughbred <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> were
talking about wanting to have little Cigarettes."

            Cigar
retired after the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Breeder's</ENAMEX> and went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashford Stud</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kentucky</ENAMEX> for what
should have been the most important and satisfying work of his career. His stud
fee fetched the farm <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75,000</NUMEX> a pop. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigar</ENAMEX> had mares lining up around the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">paddock</ENAMEX>. Everyone wanted a piece of that code. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks</TIMEX> passed. The mares
did not come into foal. "Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> that come off the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">racetrack</ENAMEX> are slow to
start," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX>, hopefully. But then the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veterinarians</ENAMEX> looked
at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cigar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> under the microscope and discovered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>'s appalling
little secret. His <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> were slackers. They had no motility whatsoever. Many
were shaped abnormally. This incredibly fast and strong and durable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">thoroughbred</ENAMEX>, heroic of stature and stout of heart, was a genetic dead end.

            The news broke simultaneously with the story that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> had cloned an adult <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">sheep</ENAMEX>. An enterprising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> for the New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Post</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigar</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Paulson</ENAMEX>, and managed to get a quote
to the effect that perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigar</ENAMEX> could be cloned. The thoroughbred community
quickly protested. It turns out that cloning would violate Rule <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1</TIMEX>(<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">D</ENAMEX>) of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Stud Book</ENAMEX> , which reads:

            
               To be eligible for
registration, a foal must be the result of a stallion's natural service with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">broodmare</ENAMEX> (which is the physical mounting of a broodmare by a stallion), and a
natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gestation</ENAMEX> must take place in, and delivery must be from, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of
the same broodmare in which the foal was conceived.
            

            
It's a shocking provision. Everything else in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">society</ENAMEX> has been converted to mass production. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> would think that
there is a more modern way to breed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, something involving hydraulic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">machinery</ENAMEX>, vacuum tubes, pumps, stainless-steel vats, perhaps even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cross</ENAMEX>-country pipelines.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cigar</ENAMEX> was
foaled at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Country Life Farm</ENAMEX>, just north of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX>, and I drove up to check
out some <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> breeding up close. Country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Farm</ENAMEX> is as pastoral as it
sounds, smelling of grass and <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">hay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolphe Pons</ENAMEX> bought it in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>
and passed it on to his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>, who is an amiable old gentleman now, padding
around in a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cigar Ran Here First</ENAMEX>" cap and looking like you could not pay him a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million dollars</NUMEX> to get worked up over anything. He passed the reins to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, notably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Pons</ENAMEX>, who is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">42</NUMEX> and seems to run the place, although there
are <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Ponses</ENAMEX> everywhere. The place is dense with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>, as though
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fecundity</ENAMEX> is contagious.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Pons</ENAMEX> is a serious <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX>. I remarked that the
rules for breeding seem rather "low-tech" for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> and age. He looked as
though he wasn't sure if he liked the sound of that term. It's difficult work,
he said. It's also risky. It takes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four or five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> to handle the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> as
they breed. His top stallion is worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX>, and could be disabled by a
swift kick from a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mare</ENAMEX>. "If she were to hit the stallion in the penis, we'd be
out of business," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pons</ENAMEX> said.

            As it
happened, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">jumpy mare</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada Miss</ENAMEX> had come onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> to breed this
very <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. She was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9 years old</TIMEX> and a maiden. She'd never had a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> on her
back. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Gardi</ENAMEX>, stood by nervously. "It's like my <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. My big
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">baby</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gardi</ENAMEX> said. A farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> warned her to be prepared for what was
coming up: "It is a little ..."--the employee paused--"violent."

            
Everyone at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> was wary of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada Miss.</ENAMEX>
She'd come there <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day before</TIMEX>, for schooling, and she had been balky. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">veterinarian</ENAMEX> had reached inside and confirmed she was in heat, but after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nine</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of racing, she might not grasp the concept of being "covered," as they
say, by a <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,300-pound</NUMEX> stallion.

            First,
the horsemen brought out a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">teaser horse</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">teaser horse</ENAMEX> is the warm-up act, an
important but ultimately expendable <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX>. This one's name was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popeye</ENAMEX>, and
he was a gelding. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popeye</ENAMEX> nuzzled and licked the maiden on her left flank. She
urinated, a sign that she was ready. A horseman held a "twitch" that covered
her mouth, while another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> held her left front leg with a strap. Two more men
stood at her flanks. Popeye reared up and plopped on her back and there was a
sudden grunting and whinnying and with both hind legs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada Miss</ENAMEX> bucked and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">threw Popeye</ENAMEX> off her back. "Poor little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>. This is all new for her," said
her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Pons</ENAMEX> did not like this. He wasn't going to let his
prize stallion get near this <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> until she got tranked. The tranquilizer
took <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX> to take effect. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada Miss</ENAMEX> started to look a little sloppy.
Another teaser came out of the stud <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>, this one named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dew</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dew</ENAMEX> was no
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gelding</ENAMEX>--he had all the equipment.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dew</ENAMEX> tried to mount her, but
she bucked away.

            "He's a
little scared right now. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mare</ENAMEX> doesn't look like she's ready and he's not
standing there with a giant hard-on ready to knock her down," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pons</ENAMEX>. One
notices that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pons</ENAMEX> doesn't mince words. No one around here is guilty of being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pretentious</ENAMEX>.

            
Obviously, the traditional breeding method is a
lot harder than just letting a couple of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> loose in a pasture and waiting
for nature to take its course. And it's a far sight harder than artificial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">insemination</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pons</ENAMEX> said that if AI were allowed--as it is with standard-bred
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>--breeding would be a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>-pony trick.

            "Instead
of a teasing chute we'd have some sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">riding bronco bull</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">leather mare</ENAMEX>.
The stallion would mount it, and a veterinarian would collect the ejaculant in
an artificial vagina," he said.

            The prohibition is more than just tradition. It's good
business. Artificial insemination would create a rush on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sperm</ENAMEX> from a select
few <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">champion stallions</ENAMEX>. Midlevel stallions would see their stud fees
plummet.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dew</ENAMEX>, the
teaser, finally mounted <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada Miss.</ENAMEX> The process is not gentle. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> horses
mating is a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">meat</ENAMEX> in motion. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> had to control the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX>, and one
of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Eduardo</ENAMEX>, had the most critical job of all, which is to reach with
his right hand and grab <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dew</ENAMEX>'s erect penis, which is thick as a baseball bat and
almost as long, and pull it to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> side to prevent penetration. When it comes
to consummating the act, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dew</ENAMEX> don't.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pons</ENAMEX> noted that poor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Popeye</ENAMEX>, the gelding, has
been tugged to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">side</ENAMEX> like this so many times that he's developed a
pronounced curvature.

            "He's got a bent dick," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pons</ENAMEX>
said.

            Finally
it was time to bring out the breeding stallion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prospect</ENAMEX>. His stud fee
is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> and he averages <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1.7</NUMEX> covers before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mare</ENAMEX> is in foal--an excellent
batting average in the horse <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. He emerged from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn whinnying</ENAMEX> and
stamping his feet. Eduardo was now wearing a helmet, a defense against biting.
The horsemen washed the stallion's genitals in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">soap</ENAMEX> and water and led him to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mare</ENAMEX>. By now the old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>, had wandered up, and he was the only one who
looked at peace. "He's a good breeding <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>. He won't mess around." The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
horsemen held the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mare</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prospect</ENAMEX> mounted her, and the horsemen on
either side guided his penis into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mare</ENAMEX> and held onto it while the horses
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">brayed</ENAMEX> and whinnied and huffed--<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than a ton</NUMEX> of towering bucking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">horseflesh</ENAMEX>--and, after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 30 seconds</TIMEX>, the stallion ejaculated and instantly
slipped out of her and headed back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">barn</ENAMEX>.

            
"It's very draining physically and
emotionally," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Pons</ENAMEX> as he drove around the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farm</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">golf cart</ENAMEX> a few
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> later. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">studs</ENAMEX> get hurt, top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broodmares</ENAMEX> get sick and die, foals
are born dead. Nothing is easy. It's the nature of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">thoroughbreds</ENAMEX>: They're not
bred for their reproductive ability--they're bred for speed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> say even
this isn't really working, that racing times have reached a plateau and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">thoroughbreds</ENAMEX> may have even regressed in quality, watered down by excessive
breeding in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the boom years of the 1980s</TIMEX> and the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> that masks
physical frailties.

            While the
horses run in place genetically, the racetracks themselves are falling behind
the rest of the gaming world. Racetracks are getting clocked by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lotteries</ENAMEX>, riverboat gambling, and slot machines. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pons</ENAMEX> is not sure if Country
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Farm</ENAMEX> will pass to yet another generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ponses</ENAMEX>. "If it's a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX>
game and everyone's betting at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">racetrack</ENAMEX>, we're out
of business."

            
From the farm I drove to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">racetrack</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX>. I've been to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulfstream</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hialeah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa Anita</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood Park</ENAMEX>,
and they all maintain some resonance of their grand past. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gulfstream</ENAMEX>, you
enter in a broad <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">boulevard</ENAMEX> between rows of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">royal palms</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hialeah</ENAMEX>, there are
old fountains and broad <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">porches</ENAMEX> and perfectly landscaped gardens. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurel Park</ENAMEX>
has none of that magic. The entrance <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> is bumpy and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">crude</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> has
been rebuilt various times over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 81 years</TIMEX>, but now just looks cobbled
together in addition to being old. On this particular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, only a few
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were scattered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX>. Many were watching TV monitors
showing simulcasts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> at some other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>. They weren't completely here,
mentally.

            A woman
smoking a cigarette outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> turned out to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lois Ryan</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of public relations. She said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurel</ENAMEX>'s big problem is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> won't allow slots. Tracks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX> have slot machines now, and
they're pulling in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> in revenue, jacking up the purses for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">races</ENAMEX> and siphoning away both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> and top <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">racehorses</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park</ENAMEX> is getting video-lottery <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">terminals</ENAMEX>, as will tracks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Virginia</ENAMEX>. Plus
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">racetrack</ENAMEX>, as broadly imagined by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, suffers a reputation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">seediness</ENAMEX>. It's not true, she said. It's clean and lively, she insisted. Soon
they will bring in costumed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX>, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> will have something to do.

            Up in the press box, the handicapper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clem Florio</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">67</TIMEX>,
looked down from his lofty perch as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> meandered toward the starting
gate for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX> race.

            "It doesn't have the glamour
that it did," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florio</ENAMEX> said. "It had glamour! You'd see <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go from nothin' to
the big time!" He grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Queens</ENAMEX>, right next door to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aqueduct</ENAMEX>. Routinely
there'd be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">30,000 or 40,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">track</ENAMEX> on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.

            "We had a tradition along the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Seaboard</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX>. Every corner had a bookie," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florio</ENAMEX> said.

            "It was the only game in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX>."

            Tradition alone can't compete
in the churning marketplace of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> gaming. Maybe racing could use a few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cloned Cigars</ENAMEX>. Something. Anything. For the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> race at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurel</ENAMEX>, there were
only <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> horses in the field. The next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> would have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> horses, and the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> after that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only six</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> is not much of a field. You know a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">racetrack</ENAMEX> is on hard times when it can't even get <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horses</ENAMEX> to show up.

         
      
   
