
   
   
      
         
            Dead Eurocrats

            Printed money, like the
government budgets behind it, is conceived in optimism, if not in fantasy. The
very designs on the bills--such as the fortresslike <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> that appears on
our <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> note--seem to promise a happy future of redemption amid prosperity. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bills</ENAMEX> aren't called promissory notes for nothing. What they promise is a flush
till.

            In this time-honored spirit,
the new designs for the uniform currency of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Community</ENAMEX> offer
beguiling visions of unity and wealth, of responsible fiscal practice and
thriving trade. Revealed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX> and slated to go into use across the
continent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX>, these notes herald nothing less than a new and nobly
unified <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.

            But for
all their color and utopian promise, the new notes are lifeless. After all,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">coinage</ENAMEX> and currency usually reflect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX> of the issuing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, and in
this case the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> is largely bureaucratic. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Monetary Institution</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Frankfurt</ENAMEX>, which under the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Maastricht Treaty</ENAMEX> is charged with making the
new Eurodollar, is described in its own literature as "an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, with legal personality." "Legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personality</ENAMEX>" is right on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mark</ENAMEX>. This is money designed not by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> but by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eurocrats</ENAMEX>, an all-star
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">team</ENAMEX> of international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pushers</ENAMEX>.

            Everything about the new currency is vintage <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eurocrat</ENAMEX>. Its
name, the euro, was picked because it translates easily into almost every
member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s language. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Greek</ENAMEX>, with its own native alphabet, requires a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> rendering of the name on the bill. Its counterfeitproof
construction--which includes the use of unreproducible holographs--attests to
the businesslike thought of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX>. And the decision to cut each of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven</TIMEX> notes in a different size (as well as a different color), to help the
visually impaired, reveals the practical-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eurocrats</ENAMEX>' more considerate
side.

            The
specifications laid out for the look of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> notes by the institution
are as tortuously legalistic as the notorious specs issued in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>, the
seat of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eurocracy</ENAMEX>, to regulate intracontinental trade. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>
rules <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fastidiously</ENAMEX> prescribe every detail of what can and cannot be sold within
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> economic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>, yielding such creations as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Euroapple</ENAMEX>,
already infamous in the orchards of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wye, Westfalia</ENAMEX>, and everywhere else that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fruit</ENAMEX> cultivated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centuries</TIMEX> has been found not to make the grade.) Back in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1995</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Monetary Institution</ENAMEX> set up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> to choose
possible "themes" for the designs, settling at last on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>: a historical one,
the "ages and styles" of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>; and a geometrical <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, "abstract modern."
These themes were broad enough to encompass almost anything individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designers</ENAMEX> could come up with. What they ruled out were portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,
especially portraits of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Individuals</ENAMEX> inevitably raise the specter of
nationalism. No dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> here.

            
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX> next held a competition,
inviting design <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> from the central <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> of the various member <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> to
enter. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thirtysome</ENAMEX> entries flowed in, for consideration by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> experts
whose diverse national and professional backgrounds rivaled even the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Star Trek</ENAMEX> --ranging from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Baron</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philippe Robert-Jones</ENAMEX>, art <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> and
permanent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academie Royale des Sciences des Lettres et des</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beaux-arts de Belgique</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guido Crapanzano</ENAMEX>, rector of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Instituto di Scienze della Comunicazione</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milan</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last July</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> picked a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX>, although it has kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creators</ENAMEX>' identities unpublicized in the
interest of future continental unity.

            The winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">designer</ENAMEX> went
for the "ages and styles" theme, interpreted as such stock architectural
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elements</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>, windows, and gateways. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight ages</TIMEX> in which these
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bridges</ENAMEX>, windows, and gateways appear are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Classical</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Romanesque</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Gothic</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renaissance</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baroque</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rococo</ENAMEX>, the age of iron and glass architecture, and
the age of modern architecture. The colors are muted and staid, the
illustrations as innocuous, impeccable, and dispassionate as those you would
find in an economics textbook.

            They're
also supposed to have symbolic meaning. The windows and gates represent the
spirit of openness and cooperation of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">confederation</ENAMEX>, we are told, while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> is a metaphor, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> showed, guaranteed not to go over the
heads of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> of any continent. More specifically, according to the
literature, the bridge "epitomizes the dawn of the new common <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> with its
common cultural heritage and the vision of a common future in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next century</TIMEX>,
indeed, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the new millennium</TIMEX>." These are not, mind you, actual existing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX>,
like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> Bridge or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pont Neuf</ENAMEX>, but are "generic, and cannot be attributed
to any particular place in any single <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>."

            The result is an entire landscape of the generic--a place
that is never <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX> but always just <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, as it might figure in
landscapes chosen for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> travel ads. Looking at them, you try to conjure
up the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> whose wallets these bills will inhabit, the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">race</ENAMEX> of Europeans
who will have no <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> umbrellas, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">berets</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> bellies. It is not
easy.

            These notes, cool and
considered, may make more practical sense than our greenbacks, with their wacky
eye on the pyramid swiped from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Masonic</ENAMEX> lore and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Model T-</ENAMEX>era automobile that
still putts along in front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>. But will they ever really
circulate? According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Maastricht Treaty</ENAMEX>, the currency will be put into
circulation only after individual national economies have hit certain
"targets"--such as a sufficiently low ratio of debt to gross domestic product.
But these <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> still seem far out of reach. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, which has the largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> and the strongest currency in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, was supposed to lead the way,
but recently <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> unemployment has jumped to levels not seen since the Weimar
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic</ENAMEX>, and the mark is softening.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Monetary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institution</ENAMEX> promises that it will announce within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next two years</TIMEX> the exact
date on which the euros will go into use. It's supposed to be no later than
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 2002</TIMEX>. Not until then will we know whether this is real money or funny
money--whether it will be worth a continental.

         
      
   
