
   
   
      
         
            Rumble in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>

            Me, I'm a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>. Don't
tell me about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Damme</ENAMEX>'s fancy kicks--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Damme</ENAMEX>'s a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ballet dancer</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>!
Here's how the fight goes: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Damme</ENAMEX> simpers around the ring like Baryshnikov
for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few minutes</TIMEX>. Finally, he throws a kick at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>. Seagal snatches
the foot out of the air, twists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Damme</ENAMEX>'s leg <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">180 degrees</NUMEX>, and tears
half-a-dozen knee ligaments from the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bone</ENAMEX>. End of story. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Damme</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Van</ENAMEX>
Damaged. He hops around the ring, begging for mercy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX> pounds his pretty
face into a mushy pulp--just for fun. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Chan</ENAMEX>? Forget about it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 feet 4 inches</NUMEX> and full of muscle: He'd snap <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX> like a twig.

            My <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonah</ENAMEX> disagrees.
He takes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Terminator</ENAMEX>, all the way. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> wraps his Mr.
Universe <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX> around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Seagal</ENAMEX>, it's over. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX> can juke and wiggle and shout
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">aphorisms</ENAMEX> till he's hoarse, but it won't matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX> will smash his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> into the ground, then yank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ponytail</ENAMEX> till he wails like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>. Or
so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonah</ENAMEX> says.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonah</ENAMEX> and
I should settle our dispute in an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX>. But he wouldn't know a spinning
back-kick if it hit him in the ribs. And I haven't fought since <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Lars</ENAMEX> Gutenberg
TKO'd me in a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">sixth</NUMEX>-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">playground brawl</ENAMEX>. But we need to resolve this. It's
time to answer, once and for all, the most important unanswered question in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cinema</ENAMEX>: Who is really the greatest action <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hero</ENAMEX> of them all? Or, to put
it in the vernacular, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> could kick everyone else's ass?

            
               The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>
Rumble
            

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Competitors</ENAMEX> (in no particular order):

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean-Claude Van Damme</ENAMEX> (the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muscles</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>"); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Chan</ENAMEX> ;
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lundgren</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Rocky IV</ENAMEX> ); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Norris</ENAMEX> ;
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Carradine</ENAMEX> (for sentiment's sake); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Seagal</ENAMEX> ; Wesley
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snipes</ENAMEX> ; and, because this is fantasy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lee</ENAMEX> himself.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judges</ENAMEX>:

            The
likelihood that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arnold et al.</ENAMEX> will actually climb into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> and do battle is
only slightly greater than the likelihood that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lee</ENAMEX> will rise from the
grave to join them. Therefore, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> has secured the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">services</ENAMEX> of a panel of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to predict how the tournament would unfold. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">all-star judges</ENAMEX> include
a two-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultimate Fighting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX>, black-belt martial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ranger</ENAMEX>, a fight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX>, a legendary street brawler, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Chan</ENAMEX> himself.
For a complete list and bios, .

            The
Rules:

            None. Who
needs 'em? This is real fighting. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>. A fight to submission,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">knockout</ENAMEX>, or--hey, why not?--death. Just like the .

            The
Prelims:

            First, let's get rid of the
early-round losers.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kung Fu</ENAMEX> star
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Carradine</ENAMEX> is dead last, and he might die getting there. "He's kind of
lost it," says <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Belt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Coleman</ENAMEX>. Put it this way: Lundgren
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kickboxes; Carradine</ENAMEX> studies tai chi--those slow-motion exercises that old
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> do in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">9</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX> also
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">falls</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Round One</ENAMEX>. He's beefy, and he learned to box for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky</ENAMEX>
movies, but that's not enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norris</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blauer</ENAMEX>, would have
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX> "down on the ground, making convulsing pig sounds."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snipes</ENAMEX>. He's big, and he
studied martial arts for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years</TIMEX>. Those who've seen him practice say he's
tough. That experience gets him past <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stallone</ENAMEX>, but no further.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Damme</ENAMEX>. Not as good as
he looks. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Muscles</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> is fabulous on screen. He claims to be a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">karate champion</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> doubt his credentials. "He's a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ballet dancer</ENAMEX>,
not a fighter," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ultimate Fighting</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champ</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Shamrock</ENAMEX>. "In a real fight,
he'd probably panic," says fight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">historian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Perret</ENAMEX>. "He'd be lucky if he
got one kick off before a real <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> took him down and had him for
lunch."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX>. I adore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX>. Some
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> do, too. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX> does stuff that professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stuntmen</ENAMEX> won't do,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blauer</ENAMEX>. "He's crazy, and you don't want to fight someone who has fun being
crazy." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX>, more acrobat than martial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artist</ENAMEX>, is quicker and more innovative
than anyone but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>. If the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> could use props--pool cues, ladders,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">chairs</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX> would win the whole tournament. But at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 feet 10 inches</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">150</NUMEX>
pounds, he's too small to fight barehanded in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ring</ENAMEX> against monsters like
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lundgren</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chan</ENAMEX> admits this, cheerfully. "If I can use
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">tricks</ENAMEX>, I have many ways to win. But if I am standing there [in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">ring</ENAMEX>], there
is no way I can win ... But I could run away fast."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norris</ENAMEX>. The sentimental favorite. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norris</ENAMEX> would have topped
this list. He is the real deal, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">karate champion</ENAMEX> during the
1960s. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norris</ENAMEX> has pure technical ability and savvy," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army Ranger</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maj. Lucas</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Norris</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">55</NUMEX>--"past his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime</ENAMEX>," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blauer</ENAMEX>. "He should do
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX> commentary for the fight."

            The
Semifinals:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> vs.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lundgren; Seagal</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>
            

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aryan Warriors Lundgren</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> fight <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. This one's a tough call, because opinion is divided
about Arnold. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">purists</ENAMEX> mock him: "There are huge, muscle-bound <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> all over
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venice Beach</ENAMEX> who don't know what to do when they get into fights. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX>'s
probably one of them," says a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. But other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> drool. "He has enough
strength to cripple you. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX> goes in there and says, 'I have to win for
my <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">box</ENAMEX> of cigars, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> for my next
picture,' then he could beat anyone," says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blauer</ENAMEX>.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> won't beat
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lundgren</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swede</ENAMEX> doesn't have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX>'s acting range--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolph</ENAMEX> is strictly a
vicious-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">murderers</ENAMEX> kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>--but he's a better <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">athlete</ENAMEX>. He is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kickboxing</ENAMEX> and karate, and he's huge<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">--6 feet 6 inches</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around 230 pounds</NUMEX>. He
would stay away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> and fire long, cruel kicks at his jaw. If
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX> charged him, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolph</ENAMEX> could feint and punch him away. Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arnold</ENAMEX>
would tire, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolph</ENAMEX> would kick him into submission.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> fight <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enigma</ENAMEX>. On the one hand, he's got the credentials. He's an aikido
black belt who once ran a dojo in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> (no mean feat for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Occidental</ENAMEX>). He's
also large, powerful, and notoriously belligerent. "He has the will to kill,"
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coleman</ENAMEX>. "That is not the kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> you want to be in a fight with."

            But doubt lingers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX>'s a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">braggart</ENAMEX>; most great <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> are quietly arrogant. He has the mannerisms of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bully</ENAMEX>, someone who abuses the weak and is cowed by the strong. "I don't think
he has the heart or stomach for a real fight--it might mess his hair up," says
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perret</ENAMEX>. Another handicap: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aikido</ENAMEX> is too stylized for a real showdown. Blauer
says, "It's a wonderful movie system, but you have to be fighting a very sloppy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> to make it work."

            And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> would not be a
sloppy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> of martial arts,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> would be a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">flea</ENAMEX> next to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">5 feet 7 inches</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">130</NUMEX> lbs. But he was
immensely strong. He trained more fanatically than anyone in the history of
martial arts, mastering grappling, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">boxing</ENAMEX>, karate, kickboxing, footfighting,
and other styles. Unlike the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> loved to fight, instigating
street fracases as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teen-ager</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>. And he was ruthless: He would as
soon break an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX> as let him submit.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal/Lee</ENAMEX> fight would be quick and bloody. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> would circle <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX>. Once he
found an opening, he would aim lightning-fast kicks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX>'s groin or knees.
One blow would land, laming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX>. The finish would be nauseating: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> might
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cripple Seagal</ENAMEX> by kicking him in the throat or gouging out an eye. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX>'s
only hope: his size. If he managed to grab <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>, he might be able to pin him,
then punch him unconscious.

            The
Final:

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lundgren</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX>
            

            Probably
much like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal/Lee</ENAMEX> fight. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> would dance and feint, tempting Lundgren
into kicks. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lundgren</ENAMEX> struck, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> would duck the blow, counterattack with a
fast low kick, and retreat. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lundgren</ENAMEX>'s chance? If he landed a kick or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, it
might stun <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> momentarily. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolph</ENAMEX> were quick enough, he could then pull
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> to the ground and pin him into submission. But that's not likely.
Probably <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>'s barrage of kicks would stagger and tire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lundgren</ENAMEX>. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolph</ENAMEX>
weakened enough, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> would break his knee and win the tournament.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reality</ENAMEX>
Check:

            In closing, however, let me
introduce you to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David "Tank" Abbott</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tank</ENAMEX> is probably the most vicious
professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fighter</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>. He stands <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">6 feet</NUMEX> tall, weighs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">275 pounds</NUMEX>, and
bench-presses <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">more than 600 pounds</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Ultimate Fighting Championship</ENAMEX> bouts,
he has sent <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. I asked him how the best fighting
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> would fare against him. He laughed awhile. Then he said: "OK. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX>--I
would knock <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seagal</ENAMEX> out in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30 seconds</TIMEX>. I would just jack him up--straight-arm
street fighting. There was a big martial-arts <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> I fought in the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFC</ENAMEX>. He
was like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seagal</ENAMEX>. He lasted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">about 20 or 30 seconds</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> thought I killed him.
That's what would happen to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seagal</ENAMEX>.

            "Lundgren--I would slam him
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mat</ENAMEX> and beat him up on the ground. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lundgren</ENAMEX>'s a big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>, right? But I
don't think he's wrestled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21 years</TIMEX> or boxed for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> or been in more than
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">street</ENAMEX> fights or been arrested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> times for assault and battery and
attempted murder. Which I have.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">And Lee</ENAMEX>. I could beat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruce</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lee</ENAMEX> drunk off a liter of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stoli</ENAMEX>. I could backhand him and knock him out. That's
just comical."

         
      
   
