
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toys Are Us</ENAMEX>

            Ever since a scandalized
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Parisian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> greeted the unveiling of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edouard Manet</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> with
shocked indignation, controversy has been one measure of seriousness in Western
art. Of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> depicted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lily</ENAMEX>-white nude
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">courtesan</ENAMEX>, displayed on a chaise longue, elicited the outcry. Far less
attention was given her fully clothed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">companion</ENAMEX>, a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">West Indian</ENAMEX>
turban. To a contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX>, the picture is still disturbing, but for
different reasons. It's the uneasy conjunction of race and sexuality that
rankles, the suspicion that for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manet</ENAMEX>, the black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">maid</ENAMEX> added a kinky allure to
the charms of the snide white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prostitute</ENAMEX>.

            The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of Contemporary Art</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> has been at the center of some of
the recent firestorms concerning artistic expression and its public support.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> took flak in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&M</ENAMEX> images in its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Robert</ENAMEX>
Mapplethorpe show, and for displaying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andres Serrano</ENAMEX>'s crucifix suspended in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">urine</ENAMEX>. Recently, however, it has found itself on the other side of the
censorship divide, and race is what pushed it there. It has made news not by
mounting a show, but by canceling <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> before it opened. The show in question,
scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, was to be devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Polaroid</ENAMEX> close-ups of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> in his possession. These are what is
sometimes referred to as black memorabilia--including <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Jemima cookie jars</ENAMEX>,
windup minstrel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dancers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> faces, and the like--what another avid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">collector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whoopi Goldberg</ENAMEX>, refers to as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Negrobilia</ENAMEX>." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> prominent black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Louis Gates Jr.</ENAMEX>, expressed an interest in
writing catalog copy. That neither <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> was ultimately able to do so may have
doomed the show.

            According to one institute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curator</ENAMEX> (as reported by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B. Woodward</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Village Voice</ENAMEX> ), the advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> didn't feel
Levinthal was "critiquing the objects he was photographing. They weren't
transformative enough." It's not clear--nor did the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> suggest--what might
have counted as "critique" or "transformation." But such is the nervous
rigidity of our current aesthetic climate, where ambiguity is tolerated on
neither the left nor the right, that when a smaller version of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s
series "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blackface</ENAMEX>" opened in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Janet Borden Gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SoHo</ENAMEX>,
some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> followed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX>'s lead in thinking that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX>
questions needed to be posed about these photographs: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) Are the memorabilia
themselves offensive? And <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) If so, does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levinthal</ENAMEX> condemn them? The New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York Times</ENAMEX> reviewer examined the evidence and convicted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Levinthal</ENAMEX> of "moral
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indeterminacy</ENAMEX>"--he evidently hadn't condemned them vigorously enough. This was
precisely the sort of charge that was leveled at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manet</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1869</TIMEX>.

            A major
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">retrospective of Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s work, including some images from "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blackface</ENAMEX>"
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995-96</TIMEX>), is now on display at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Center of Photography</ENAMEX> on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper East Side</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>. The show, which covers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> different series
of photographs taken over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 21 years</TIMEX>, makes clear that some sort of
moral indeterminacy has always been at the center of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s art. He first
created a stir <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX>, with a remarkable book of photographs and
commentary called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX> Moves <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s collaborator was his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale</ENAMEX>
art-school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">classmate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Trudeau</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Doonesbury</ENAMEX> . The
black-and-white photographs of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> moving into the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> have the grainy, blurred look of authentic reportage from the Eastern
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Front</ENAMEX> and bear an obvious debt to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Capa</ENAMEX>'s work for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX>
magazine.

            
What was unusual about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s images was
that he had staged them himself--and not with human <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX>, but with toys. As
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> mounted on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> and cab push inexorably into the frigid
landscape--with flour substituting for snow--there's an uneasy mix of the
trompe l'oeil and the trumped up. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">photographers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s
generation, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Sherman</ENAMEX>, have testified to the influence of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
Moves East" in pushing photography away from the sternly mimetic documentary
style of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1960s</NUMEX> toward a more playful, artificial relation to the world.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>
Moves East" was produced during the final phase of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX> has recently suggested that "you come away [from the book] with a
strong antiwar statement." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s mock-doc images have none of the chaotic
horror of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. Rather, there's a soft-focus decorum, and a powerful
nostalgia for a simpler, "good" war. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> have driven out of a dream
world set far back in an imagined past, one drawn from movies and newsreels.
Nostalgia is also the hallmark of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s next major series, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Wild</ENAMEX>
West" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987-89</TIMEX>), which took him in the opposite direction, if only
geographically. Again, the medium is toys--heroic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cowboys</ENAMEX> and occasional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX>--bathed this time in muted colors. A cowboy swings his lariat before a
rearing white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and, for a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, you're caught by the power and careful
balance of the tableau. In other <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">shots</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indians</ENAMEX> with raised tomahawks and
spears give rise to a nervous wall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> at the ICP assuring us that Levinthal
is "mindful of real history," and that his work somehow "prompts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX>'s
recollections of our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forefathers</ENAMEX>' injustices: cultural expansionism, genocide
and racism." This is absurd--if we do think about the white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">settlers</ENAMEX>' misdeeds
when looking at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s work, it's only because of how much our cultural
dialogue now emphasizes them--and the urge to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX> from potential
charges of political insensitivity is part of the same lock-step aesthetics
that seem to follow Levinthal everywhere. It obscures the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s
territory in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> series is much the same as in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler Moves East</ENAMEX>," a
liminal realm of fantasy where the most successful images--like that rearing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>, or a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> hanging from a noose on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">stunted tree</ENAMEX>--toe the line between
real and make-believe. Whatever wildness remains in this toyshop <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>--as
innocent of political engagement as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s playroom floor--derives from a
visual imagination stocked with <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">'50s</TIMEX> movies and a reckless willingness to play
these overexposed scenes straight, with neither irony nor commentary.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s photographic forays into romance and sexuality
are less sure-footed. The lonely lamp-lit <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> in his "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Modern Romance</ENAMEX>"
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984-86</TIMEX>), contrived with dolls and miniature props soon after his move to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">York City</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, effectively evoke the nighttime <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diners</ENAMEX> and hotel <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bedrooms</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Hopper</ENAMEX> and film noir. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s soft-focus experiments with '50s
bathing-beauty dolls posing on piles of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sand</ENAMEX> ("<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">American Beauties</ENAMEX>," [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989-90</TIMEX>])
and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> mail-order bondage toys ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Desire</ENAMEX>," [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990-91</TIMEX>]) don't go much beyond
the genres they mimic. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s visual games with sex toys are predictably
controversial (is he complicit or "critiquing"?) without being particularly
disturbing. His latest <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> series, though, succeed at being both. While the
upbeat "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hitler Moves East</ENAMEX>" skirted any mention of the destruction of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mein Kampf</ENAMEX> " (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993-94</TIMEX>) explores, in lurid
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX>--especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nazi</ENAMEX> colors of red and black--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hitler</ENAMEX>'s crimes against
humanity. We see "inspections" of nude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> for the gas <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>, women
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> shot beside ditches, rapes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> herded into freight <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>--all
enacted by lifelike dolls. The images have some of the power of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Art</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spiegelman</ENAMEX>'s comic-book version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maus</ENAMEX> , and for some of
the same reasons. Given the rote piety of so much <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Holocaust</ENAMEX> rhetoric (there's
more of it on the ICP wall panels), openly artificial treatments from such
"nonserious" realms as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">comics</ENAMEX> and toy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> have an unsettling power to thaw
and refocus our feelings.

            
It's jarring to move from the lurid
theatricality of "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mein Kampf</ENAMEX> " to the head-on, propless portraits of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blackface</ENAMEX>" series. Again, we have some silly palaver assuring us
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX> is aware that these items depict stereotyped images of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>--as though we suspected that he endorsed them, or thought they were
realistic. In fact, the objects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levinthal</ENAMEX> has photographed are extremely
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">varied</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">galleries</ENAMEX> might have helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> out by furnishing
details about the items' provenance and use. Nor is the degree of
"stereotyping" at all consistent among the items. They range from crudely
bug-eyed pickaninnies eating watermelon--their vacant grins echoed by the great
smile of the rind--to almost idealized sculpted heads of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Levinthal</ENAMEX>'s title for this
series reveals his interest in a tradition of blackface masquerade that, by the
turn of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the century</TIMEX>, was largely a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> (think of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Jolson</ENAMEX>'s The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jazz Singer</ENAMEX> ). While <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">minstrelsy</ENAMEX> operated on the premise that black
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were inherently funny, it also reflected a complex identification of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>--an identification between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outsider groups</ENAMEX> explored by such
contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Rogin</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Blackface</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White Noise</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Lott</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Love and Theft</ENAMEX> .

            Of course, a layer of burnt
cork smeared over the face does not a new identity make. The very luridness of
the mask preserved as much distance as it bridged. And yet, these sad-faced,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cigar-munching Amos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> figures--which seem to date from the time when
white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actors</ENAMEX> yielded to black in those roles--have a racially ambiguous pathos.
It's as though their melancholy derived from the excruciating imperative to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> performing according to the conventions of blackface. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">objects</ENAMEX> that
interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levinthal</ENAMEX>, as he points out in a statement at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Borden</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Gallery</ENAMEX>, could as well be called "white memorabilia," since they record,
presumably, the fantasies of white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including the fantasy of assuming a
temporary black identity. These <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Aunt Jemima</ENAMEX> cookie jars and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>
faces, dented and scarred with use, stare back at us as unnervingly as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>
Arbus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">freaks</ENAMEX>, but with the added accusation, at least to white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, that
you made us this way.

         
      
   
