
   
   
      
         
            Reality vs. <I><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX></I>

            
               (NOTE: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life</ENAMEX> and
Art," a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>, will compare movies, books, etc., with the facts on
which they ostensibly are based.)
            

            "What makes this movie so
effective is that it doesn't sentimentalize or airbrush <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX>," wrote
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Rich</ENAMEX> about The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> in the New York
Times . "What is the point of making a film about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> that airbrushes both him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>?" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">wondered Katha</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollitt</ENAMEX> in The 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX> .

            Who's right, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pollitt</ENAMEX>? How sharply does the film diverge from real life?

            Like most biopics, The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> fudges lots of little details. For example, in the film,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staff</ENAMEX> remains more or less constant--whereas, in reality, the
masthead was constantly changing. But composite <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">characters</ENAMEX> are a cinematic
device commonly used to reduce audience confusion and maintain narrative
momentum. It's pretty harmless when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Norton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alan</ENAMEX>
Isaacman, stands in for the numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> hired through his ongoing
court battles (which numbered more than the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> the film describes). However,
serving as the all-purpose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> required <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isaacman</ENAMEX> to take a bullet that never
actually hit him. In real life, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Reeves Jr.</ENAMEX> who was shot, along with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> obscenity trial.

            Of more
significance is the accusation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milos Forman</ENAMEX>'s film turns the wholly
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">unappetizing Larry Flynt</ENAMEX> into an aw-shucks, lovably pigheaded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX>. There the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are on firmer ground. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woody Harrelson</ENAMEX>, playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> in the
movie, cheerfully describes himself as a scum bag, the movie clearly wants to
have it both ways on this, and sanitizes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s life in order to do so.

            
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> in the movie is an innocent who wakes up
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one day</TIMEX> and discovers he is a rich <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX>. But the story behind the real
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s fortune may not be so storybook. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cleveland Press</ENAMEX> reported in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> had launched his publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> with the financial help of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">vending-</ENAMEX>machine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that allegedly were linked to organized crime.
Shortly after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> made <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX>, he decided to distribute
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> himself. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> began to distribute a few titles not
owned by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. He sold his distribution <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last July</TIMEX> for a reported
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21 million</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reported back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> that "the
fraternity of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesalers</ENAMEX> and national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">distributors</ENAMEX>" viewed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> and his
alleged strong-arm tactics (his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX> supposedly beat up a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wholesaler</ENAMEX> who
couldn't pay) as "an unwelcome addition to the scene." But that fraternity
might have included some rough <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">players</ENAMEX> itself. A book by former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX>
Forum <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Heidenry</ENAMEX>, titled <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">What Wild Ecstasy--The Rise and Fall</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Sexual Revolution</ENAMEX> (to be published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> &
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Schuster</ENAMEX>), claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s move angered the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mafia</ENAMEX>, which controlled the
distribution of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazines</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heidenry</ENAMEX> also reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> was in
debt to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mob moneylenders</ENAMEX>.

            The film
leaves puzzlingly open the question of who might have shot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>,
paralyzing him, and why. At the end of the film, on-screen typescript announces
that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assailant</ENAMEX> was never brought to justice. Yet, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s case was
investigated, and most press accounts consider it closed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Paul Franklin</ENAMEX>,
a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">white supremacist</ENAMEX> currently serving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> life sentences for murder (and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to whom the right-wing paranoid cult classic, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Turner Diaries</ENAMEX> , is
dedicated), made a jailhouse confession in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s shooting. A grand jury
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">indicted Franklin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, but he was never tried. He was considered an escape
risk at trial, according to law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> (and he was in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX> indefinitely,
anyway). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> does have a history of confessing to crimes all over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. He has also confessed to shooting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon E. Jordan</ENAMEX>, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Urban League</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, a crime for which he was acquitted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>.
Nevertheless, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>, at least, believes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Franklin</ENAMEX> shot him.

            
After the assassination attempt, the movie's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> holes up in his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bel Air</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">mansion</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea</ENAMEX>, and they both
start taking morphine and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>. So far, so good. But the movie's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> stops
his <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use cold <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">turkey</ENAMEX> after a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> operation to cauterize his nerves,
suggesting he had shot up only to alleviate his physical pain. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> himself
says in his recent autobiography, <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">An Unseemly Man</ENAMEX> , that he continued
self-medicating even after his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> overdosed--indeed, until after his most
recent nerve-cauterizing operation, which was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1994</TIMEX>. He also says he
was taking amphetamines <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as 1964</TIMEX>--well before he was paralyzed--and
"spent much of my life hyped-up, doped-up, or drunk."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s
marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea</ENAMEX> was his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>, although from the movie, you'd think
it was his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX>. The film's portrayal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> as a quasifeminist
enlightened male depends in large part on its portrait of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea</ENAMEX>, played by
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Courtney Love</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Review of Books</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Menand</ENAMEX> suggests
the filmmakers "went out of their way to remake <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea Flynt</ENAMEX>" as a way to award
Hustler a place it doesn't deserve in the sexual revolution. The film
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">positions Althea</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> as intellectual and emotional equals. He retains the
right to sleep with other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>; so does she. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>, she has
extensive editorial input (which is true). Even after he is paralyzed and their
sex life comes to an end, their love endures.

            
Their actual relationship was more complicated.
In the movie, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> hits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea</ENAMEX> once; she tells him never to do it again, and
he doesn't. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidenry</ENAMEX> writes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea</ENAMEX> more than once, and she
told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> that she didn't see anything wrong with a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> striking a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>." In the film's account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> bathtub death, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> propels his
wheelchair into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and tries to save her. His memoir says he asked a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> to check on her. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">People</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> that she went into
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and then "ran to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>, who was asleep."

            And
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The film gives the impression that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> has none, although he has
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>--to the best of his knowledge. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of them, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonya Flynt-Vega</ENAMEX>, has accused
him of sexually molesting her and, in an interview in the current issue of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Penthouse</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother-in-law</ENAMEX> accuses him of molesting a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX>.

            
The main point of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gloria</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steinem</ENAMEX> (who wrote an op-ed piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ) is that the
film sanitizes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> 's unsavory sexuality. Even the most cursory look
at back issues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> confirms that the filmmakers seriously
misrepresent its content. The images we see or hear described in the movie are
vaguely countercultural (a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Santa</ENAMEX>-with-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">an</NUMEX>-erection cartoon), not sick
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hustler</ENAMEX> 's real-life jokes about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Ford</ENAMEX>'s mastectomy); they are
soft-core (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">centerfold</TIMEX>-style nudes), not hard-core (the pictorial of a woman
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gagged</ENAMEX> and bound on the top of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s "humor" often depended on
racist and sexist stereotypes, such as wide-grinned, watermelon-eating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> says he was parodying these stereotypes, but the film carefully avoids
raising the issue.

            The film also exaggerates
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s martyrdom for the cause of free speech. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> instance: At his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>
trial, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> was sentenced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25 years</TIMEX> for obscenity and for engaging
in organized crime. The film portrays the sentencing, and then a prison visit
where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Althea</ENAMEX> weeps, "Our bed is so empty." In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six days</TIMEX> in
jail.

            As for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX>'s climactic
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> victory against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">evangelist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Falwell</ENAMEX>, who sued him for
emotional distress, the film sticks fairly closely to the facts. Indeed, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">screenwriters</ENAMEX> borrowed lines from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> transcript. At an earlier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court appearance, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynt</ENAMEX> shouted, "Fuck this court!" and called the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">justices</ENAMEX> "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> assholes and one token cunt." That transcript didn't make the
movie.

         
      
   
