
   
   
      
         
            Meditation on a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Line From Whitman</ENAMEX>

            By <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>
Bogen

            
               (posted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">May</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6, 1998</TIMEX>)
            

            To hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">poet</ENAMEX> read
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meditation on a Line From Whitman</ENAMEX>," click .

            They are so lonely, our
dying <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>,specks on the vast familiar map that looks like a side of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beef</ENAMEX>,in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">boldface</ENAMEX> or marked with a circled dot,ringed by their beltways, linked into
nameless constellations by the       <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">interstates</ENAMEX>.Some are red <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giants</ENAMEX>, spreading
and cooling in the smoggy <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dusk</TIMEX>,others dwarfs with dense shrunken coresor black
holes so involuted they swallow the light around them.

            On my way out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX>, I
drive through a fold in time,a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">tunnel</ENAMEX> through the history of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shopping</ENAMEX>:boarded-up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">storefronts</ENAMEX> on the narrow commercial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">streets</ENAMEX>,the old strips
and plazas with a muffler <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shop</ENAMEX> or a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chicken</ENAMEX> fryer left,and larger <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>--a
five-and-dime blown out into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX>,fast-food <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX>, all local chains
now,with their scratchy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> and pot-holed drive-thru <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lanes</ENAMEX>;then the first
real <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX>, big as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft carriers</ENAMEX>, low and blocky,their outlying coffee
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">shops</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-screen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">theaters</ENAMEX> like escorts;at last a quieting stretch, the
freeway growing wallsand the walled tracts all around nestled in their
names--The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willows</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunt Club Crossing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hidden Acres</ENAMEX>--their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">malls</ENAMEX> planted,
soft-colored, smoothly designed,broad single lumps surrounded by asphalt
prairie,distant and unobtrusive as buttes.

            What is an executive home?
Who lives there?I imagine the orbiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>, shifted every <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> yearsto
another desirable location beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">beltway</ENAMEX>,another stand of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pines</ENAMEX> and
curving <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX>, another commute,another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> as a set of season tickets to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">football</ENAMEX> gamesor a pass even to skyboxes if they should rise so high.Some will.
At <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, in their brief stops,they glide effortlessly up the ladder of good
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>,ladder of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">yard space</ENAMEX>, of techno-buttonsin the family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>, vehicles
lined on the drive,the whole ensemble an island drifting further and further
from the rotted      core.

            Bland wealth of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">suburbs</ENAMEX>,it's futile to keep despising it, I know,unfair to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> who have to
live there--or else in slums--but sometimes its cultivated innocence feels like
an assault.I don't want to join the country <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">club</ENAMEX> because there are no <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">parks</ENAMEX>.I
don't want to leave my <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">car</ENAMEX> in an underground <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>,rise to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, sink at
the end of day,drive home unable to stop or roll down the windowstill I see the
familiar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> in his gatepost waiting at the start of our      street.

            This
sealed-off life--even the ease of it disturbs me.Secure, imperturbable, it
floats in a daydream of possibilities--a trip to the water <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX>, things to buy
at the hardware <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">depot</ENAMEX>,quality time, preparation for success, Have you
outstript the rest? Are you the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>? --a huge ball of dust drifting
and whirlingas the light from burnt-out <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stars races</ENAMEX> over it.

         
      
   
