
   
   
      
         
            Up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secondhand Smoke</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s coverage yields the typical <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> diversity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead spells bad news for secondhand smoke
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX>: on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> invalidated a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> report which had
declared secondhand smoke a dangerous <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carcinogen</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> may soften its adultery policy by limiting the
circumstances under which adultery can be prosecuted. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead
looks at national security lapses connected with the export <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">of</NUMEX> satellites to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Osteen</ENAMEX>, who issued the secondhand smoke
ruling covered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> "did not demonstrate a
statistically significant association between [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">secondhand smoke</ENAMEX>] and lung
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>." Few studies have convincingly linked secondhand smoke to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>, and
the new ruling is sure to reignite the controversy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> will
probably appeal the case, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">administrator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Browner</ENAMEX>.

            On the subject of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s adultery policy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> has proposed changes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Manual for Courts</ENAMEX>
Martial that "would result in fewer prosecutions and impose a less-serious
discharge upon convictions." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX> has generated significant debate
within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX>, which has been periodically beset by sex-related
controversies. Ironically, the changes in adultery policy must be approved by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lily</ENAMEX>-white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead raises concerns about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s monitoring of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">satellite</ENAMEX> exports to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The fear is that technological expertise from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>--which supply the satellites--could aid <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s ballistic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">missile</ENAMEX> program. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> relaxed export controls in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. Since
then, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> charge, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> may have come to "rely too heavily on voluntary
compliance by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>." Among the national security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">oversights</ENAMEX> cited by
the LAT : <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> were not required to be present at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> most recent satellite launches in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> launches did
not attend prelaunch meetings between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>.

            All papers run inside stories on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>'s
worst-kept secret"--the wedding of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX> with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graca Machel</ENAMEX>, a widely respected black liberation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> who lives in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mozambique</ENAMEX> (and intends to commute from there). The ceremony took place on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80th birthday</TIMEX>; the blushing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bride</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, is 28 years
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">junior</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> uses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> version of the story, which gushes, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Far</ENAMEX>
from a political marriage, it is obviously one of true love. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> seem to
melt from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creased</ENAMEX> face and his eyes light up . . ." Love is indeed
wonderful.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager marvels at the deluge of applications to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
Patent and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Trademark</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> for logos sporting the word "millenium." Anything
goes-- <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Playboy</ENAMEX> is prancing around as the "official worldwide brand of the
millenium," and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mars Inc.</ENAMEX> is drooling over the chance to be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">millenium</ENAMEX>'s
official candy<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">-maker</ENAMEX>. Equally coveted is the sexy Y2K logo (named for the
millennial computer bug). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Year 2000</TIMEX> boozers may have to choose between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coors</ENAMEX>
("the official beer of Y2K") and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Y2K</TIMEX>." In anticipation of the successful
delivery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1, 2000</TIMEX>, we lay claim to "The official Y2K
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">buster</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
