
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nut Cases</ENAMEX>

            Everybody leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>-related maneuverings taking place on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX>. The general consensus is that the public's support for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remaining in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> has withstood the airing of his grand jury
testimony and indeed, has even grown a bit stronger. This has, report the
papers, encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to seek a compromise outcome short of
impeachment--say, having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> testify before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>
with a guarantee that he wouldn't be removed from office, although perhaps
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">censured</ENAMEX> and/or fined. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports that former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>--and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise Man</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Cutler</ENAMEX> has been working the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hill</ENAMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">censure</ENAMEX> deal as an unofficial <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> rep.

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> is quoted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
saying that talk of such a deal is "very premature." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> expects a committee
vote recommending impeachment hearings to come in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early October</TIMEX>, with the
hearings beginning after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains the
politics of that schedule: it would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to avoid looking too soft
or too hard on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> before the elections, while still forcing
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to cast a pre-election vote on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fate.

            The papers report that as part of its anti-impeachment lobbying, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> went on the offensive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, writing a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accusing Ken Starr</ENAMEX> of deliberately leaving exculpatory statements he'd turned
up out of the formal report he tendered to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. "Ultimately, we just got
the sex," a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> is quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX>. Exhibit A of something
in evidence but not in the report is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s statement to the grand jury
that "no one ever asked me to lie and I was never promised a job for my
silence." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes, referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>'s response, that
when this statement was paraphrased in the report the modifier "explicitly" was
added. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> office <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sarcastically</ENAMEX> observed that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> now appears to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> credible on some topics but not
others.

            The papers report that at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Room</ENAMEX> reception, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson Mandela</ENAMEX>
said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Africa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and the entire world supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. It
was, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , "the kind of emotional endorsement that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has
trouble getting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> has banned a kind of
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">joint venture</ENAMEX> that was the principal way such telecommunications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>
as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sprint</ENAMEX> had begun gaining entry into <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> markets. The move is the latest
in a series of protectionist steps that are worsening the business climate for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and widening the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> trade gap. The trend is puzzling,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes, in that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic crisis has already made foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> leery of investing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story says that trade is quickly
becoming the biggest issue between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stats</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> deficit with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> is second only to the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> says
U.S statistics are exaggerated. The big leverage the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has to remedy the
problem is, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , that--especially with other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX>
markets in such disarray--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s most important export market.

            Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead reports that any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> thaw is still
a long way off, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's front, and inside stories at all the other papers,
report that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatemi</ENAMEX> told reporters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that the
fatwa issued against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salman Rushdie</ENAMEX> for blaspheming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> was "completely
finished."

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story shows that private and suburban school parents
still lead the way in fighting against threats to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> so slight as
to be all but invisible to ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folk</ENAMEX>. The latest bogeyman: <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter allergies</ENAMEX>. A number of elite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> area, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, have declared <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX>-free cafeterias. Others
serve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut butter sandwiches</ENAMEX> only in a special designated area. Some schools
have stored syringes of antidote around their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>. And thought is being
given to providing separate instructional materials to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX>-allergic
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who represents many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> is concerned,
says the paper, that <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">peanut allergies</ENAMEX> might qualify as a disability that must
be accommodated under the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Disabilities Act</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX> public
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> have done none of these things, largely because no one has complained.
(Although <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX> are not served because they are deemed a choking hazard.) The
Times notes that according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center of Disease Control</ENAMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>
through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, there were but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX> deaths nationwide from all forms of food
allergy combined.

         
      
   
