
   
   
      
         
            Headline

            After <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers: Summary Judgment</ENAMEX> wraps up the reviews of the reviews.
The papers continue to show they're much more interested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mondo Monica</ENAMEX> than
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are--all the majors lead with some aspect of it. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s comments <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> at his first post-Report
press conference that he still has the moral authority required to remain in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with a story that led elsewhere <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>--the imminent
release of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> videotape. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> combines the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> themes in
its lead, running under the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Stresses Duties</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Plans
Disclosure."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that during his joint news conference with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Czech</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaclav Havel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "sidestepped" questions about whether he'd committed
perjury. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that most of the questions posed at the
conference were about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal--including those from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czech</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> (the front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story on the press conference also
observes this). The USAT account depicts a determined, fervent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> sees political manipulation instead, calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remarks
"part of a determined effort by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> to change the subject," and
saying it was "stage-managed to put the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> in the best possible light,"
and also referring to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s speech on the global economy as "a carefully
choreographed appearance." If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's quoting of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> saying, "I have never stopped leading this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in foreign affairs
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this entire year</TIMEX>, and I never will" makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> think of jut-jawed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">globalism</ENAMEX>, by the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> gets around to the remark, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> is
half-way thinking it's actually a coded reference to some as yet undetected
frolicking with exchange <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. In noting that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> offered no defense
of his actions and voiced no protest as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> moved further down the track
toward an impeachment inquiry," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story limns <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> picture: of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">man</ENAMEX> resigned to a process bigger than he is. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that when
asked if he might consider resigning, his response--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> want him to do
his job--was less "steely" than the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchillian</ENAMEX> 'never'" he responded with
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last February</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> agrees, saying his answer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was less
confrontational.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead stresses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> of some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> committee
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> that some of the material suggested for imminent release is too
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">graphic</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that at a closed-door meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> seemed irritated by such scruples and won "a huge ovation" after
reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attendees</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> had already voted for full disclosure, and
that pulling back now would only lead to news leaks. Also, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> yesterday
acknowledged a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1960s</NUMEX> extramarital affair and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> denied
leaking that information.

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> story reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> has ordered a
review of all DOD-maintained Web sites out of a concern that they may make too
much information--including the names of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commanders</ENAMEX> and the locations of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>--available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> and other potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemies</ENAMEX>. The paper
reports, for instance, that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> site featured the floor plan and photos of
the inside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">home</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX>.

            A very good front-page WSJ feature by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Blackmon</ENAMEX> makes the case that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> is becoming more cultured. True, the piece admits, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Booty Call</ENAMEX>" made
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 million</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wonder</ENAMEX> remains the biggest single selling <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bread</ENAMEX> brand, but the
cultural common denominator is on the rise. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> book-buying is on a
dizzying upswing, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are studying abroad, theatrical ticket sales
are up, as is opera attendance, plus pubic radio <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stations</ENAMEX> have tripled since
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>--and you can get cappuccino in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>.

            The LAT front runs a piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myron Levin</ENAMEX>
that may presage a whole new dimension of tobacco scandal. Citing internal
memos from the world's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> largest tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, the piece details their
secret agreement to fix prices in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Latin</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>. The memos surfaced in a lawsuit brought by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> state
and provide the first-ever documentation of tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>' anti-competitive
deals. The story reminds that it's not just <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> who can't give a
simple answer to a simple question--it quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phillip Morris</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokeswoman</ENAMEX>'s
response: "Since we must comply with local laws and regulations in every
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in which we do business, we expect that there has been no improper
conduct in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that you have referenced." Not exactly "We didn't do
anything wrong."

         
      
   
