
   
   
      
         
            Words of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little Interest</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> may lower interest rates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> ignores <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>, but leads with a story
no other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> runs on its front: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s likely military action against
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s announcement that he may
eventually lower interest rates--an action that would cut the cost of borrowing
and encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> world-wide. Inflation looms as the negative result of
such a move. Both leads note that although a rate cut is a mere possibility,
its consideration marks a change in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s policy: he no longer sees
inflation as a far greater threat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy than the global financial
crisis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>'s remarks are the first
attempt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have made to restore confidence in foreign markets by
addressing the possibility of lower interest rates.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> has positioned <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 35,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> along its
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghani</ENAMEX> border in response to reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sunni</ENAMEX>-dominated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> regime
has murdered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Shiite</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX> in northern
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> "don't have a favorite <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> in
this fight," they do criticize the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nations</ENAMEX> for their hostility towards each
other. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> notes that while war might divert the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>'
resources away from funding international terrorism, it would also hamper their
monitoring of domestic terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> weekend papers run front page stories on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> who,
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>, said he is "very sorry about" his relationship with Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
and called his actions "indefensible." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's headline links
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s latest apology to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lieberman</ENAMEX>'s recent criticism. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and WP use the word "affair" in their headlines; the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> opts for the less scandalous "relationship."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> continues its coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Liu</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>, who was arrested, locked in a windowless <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">three</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>, and interrogated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">16 hours</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX> was released
after signing confessions that she broke laws regarding press accreditation and
the interviewing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liu</ENAMEX>'s release was no doubt hastened by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">delegation</ENAMEX> on human rights that arrives in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Sosa</ENAMEX>'s race to break <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Maris</ENAMEX>' single-season
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> run record merits front-page articles at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. The LAT
piece highlights the massive increase in popularity and prestige <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX> has
garnered as a result of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s long ball bonanza. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> examines
the racism angle, noting that in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> survey <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">79%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> said they
are rooting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX> to break the record instead of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dominican</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sosa</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> looks at the parallels between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maris</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ND</ENAMEX>. Residents have mixed feelings about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maris</ENAMEX>' record being broken and they
feel both he and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX> have been slighted by history--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maris</ENAMEX> by his absence from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Hall of Fame</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> by its unflattering portrayal in the movie
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fargo</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
