
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Employers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bitter Pill</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX>' top national story examines whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> are able
to assess accurately the global economy's health. Growing pressure on employers
to cover the cost of birth control as part of employee benefits is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>'
off-lead and top national story. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early</TIMEX> edition's top national article
details a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> plan to topple <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economic woes and decreased <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
production have <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> scratching their heads over the health of the world
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>. Current methods of economic diagnosis are being questioned, and a
global recession is seeming ever more possible to skeptical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>. The
paper notes that with currency <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> affecting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">farmers</ENAMEX>,
local economic events can set off <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> reactions felt throughout the entire
world. One prominent macro-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economist</ENAMEX> calls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s globalized economy "almost
beyond human comprehension."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that family planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are pushing federal and
state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> to mandate employer coverage of contraception as part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">employee healthcare</ENAMEX> plans. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lobbyists</ENAMEX>, decrying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX>' coverage of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> but
not birth control, have stepped up Congressional lobbying in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX>.
Most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> oppose mandated coverage--they claim mandates of
any sort make healthcare less affordable for all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>. One anti-mandate
lobbyist <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, "It may be good social policy. On the other hand, so is
affordable healthcare."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>-page report has been prepared in response to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' call for swift action against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>'s presidency. The report
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">discloses U.S.</ENAMEX> plans to: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) teach opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups organization</ENAMEX> and
recruitment techniques, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) fund an exile activities <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) index
war crimes documents for future trials, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) establish an anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio</ENAMEX>
Free <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>." Measures taken will be small in scale, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has approved a
mere <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> towards the effort.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> feature front page articles on the
behind-the-scenes negotiations for immunity between the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was in a hurry to make a deal for key
evidence (i.e., answering machine messages and semen-stained dress) that would
help provide a timely and conclusive end to his investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>--especially tough-talking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob A.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX>--had the tact and clout needed to obtain immunity for their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stein</ENAMEX> put it to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> in no uncertain terms: "I have
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> good trial left in me, and I'm going to put it at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s disposal."

            Finally, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> asks the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>-related
question that has caused much concern here at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> : what kind of person
asks her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> to keep a semen-stained dress for her? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dowd</ENAMEX> declines to answer,
but does propose a far-reaching "gross-out theory" in which politics and media,
driven by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s gradual desensitization and need for stimulation, have
fallen to new depths of tastelessness.

         
      
   
