
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenya Catch Them</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with the investigation into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX> bombings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times comes behind its lead about the passage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> state
budget with the report that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> have been arrested in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>
attack, a story included in the other bombing leads. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
LAT quote a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> lowering expectations about the arrests, as
does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which goes on to identify the arrested <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iraqis</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> extraction.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX> confirmed to a local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>--what was first
reported in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> --that there was a brief battle at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassy</ENAMEX>'s back gate that killed several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> went off.
Apparently, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> kept the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb vehicle</ENAMEX>--now described by the
papers as a small pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>--from gaining access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>'s
underground <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">garage</ENAMEX>, where it probably would have caused even more death. The
LAT interviews another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> to the attack who says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who jumped
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb truck</ENAMEX> was dressed in the uniform of an embassy security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guard</ENAMEX>.
This observation that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> jumped indicates a point not made expressly in any
of the coverage, namely that this was not a suicide <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomber</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also describes international tension at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> site:
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenyans</ENAMEX> are angered by the slow pace of the body recoveries and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rescuers</ENAMEX> are miffed at being watched closely by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, who, the paper
says, are seemingly worried that their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> might use the occasion to sift
through classified materials.

            The papers say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rescuers</ENAMEX> continue on the trail of faint noises in the
hopes of finding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX>-- USAT dedicates its news section cover story
to the ongoing hunt for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie</ENAMEX>," the last unaccounted-for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> contacted
alive inside the rubble. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes a special problem in
identifying the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">forty</NUMEX>-some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">unknowns</ENAMEX> still in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> morgues--few <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyans</ENAMEX> have
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dental</ENAMEX> records because few can afford to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dentist</ENAMEX>.

            Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have begun sifting for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> parts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
says they currently suspect plastic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">explosives</ENAMEX>, perhaps from a lot sold to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Libya</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1970s</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">80s</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also report
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reported it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>) that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has announced a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX>
reward in the case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has paid
out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $5 million</NUMEX> for anti-terrorist information.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> escorted
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> onto a transport <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ambassador</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence</ENAMEX>
Bushnell, herself injured in the attack, stood by with "a bandaged hand over
her heart and tears glistening on cheeks cut by flying glass."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead is a disturber that also gets front
coverage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and an inside mention at the WP : in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>,
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one age 7 and one age 8</TIMEX>, have been charged with murdering an
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, apparently to steal her <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bike</ENAMEX>. They also sexually molested
her. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> have confessed to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 27</TIMEX> killing. The
Times says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> think these are the youngest murder <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendants</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> history. According to their confessions, the older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> afterwards rode his
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bicycle</ENAMEX> home and watched cartoons, and the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX> went home to play with
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">puppy</ENAMEX>. One glaring lacuna in the coverage: the accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>.
They are hardly mentioned although they have obviously done a horrible job.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page feature says that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will likely conclude that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
had a sexual relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, wasn't candid about it under
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">oath</ENAMEX>, and at least tacitly encouraged others to give false testimony about it.
And, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will conclude therefore that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has
no choice but to debate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fitness to remain in office. But in a letter
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> makes a worthwhile alternate suggestion
: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> should pass a joint resolution of censure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
conduct. This would get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s questionable behavior on the record while
sparing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> the immense distraction of impeachment proceedings.

         
      
   
