
   
   
      
         
            Losing Their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nerve Gas</ENAMEX>

            With <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> shutting down for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the long weekend</TIMEX>, overseas news dominates the
papers that are still working. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s announcement of a plan
to resolve its banking crisis leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> makes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> its off-lead and goes
instead with the pledge by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> to release all political
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, a story that's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and runs on the bottom
front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> . A central issue confronting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>, the
Post explains, is whether the long-suppressed southern-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yoruba</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">peoples</ENAMEX> can win a political role within <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">any</TIMEX> compromise with the northern-based
Hausa-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">speakers</ENAMEX> who dominate the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bank</ENAMEX> plan, which must get the approval of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> before being
enacted, is intended to address the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$550 billion</NUMEX> in
troubled loans, and as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes, to assuage the rising tide of
international complaints, especially from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inaction</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains that since the plan will let some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> fail,
it is a departure from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">convoy</ENAMEX>" system via which all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> support
one another.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX> working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> feature front-page stories about
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time/CNN</ENAMEX>'s retraction of its allegation that nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> was used
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> defectors by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, with considerable
additional coverage inside. (Question: why is it only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's headline
that mentions that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> made a retraction too?) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Media</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">retractions</ENAMEX> are
rare enough, but this case produced something rarer still: firings and
resignations arising from poor journalism. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> were cut loose,
another resigned, and bigfoot <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> correspondent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Arnett</ENAMEX>, was, according to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , "given a stern reprimand" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>. The retraction
was based on the findings of an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Abrams</ENAMEX>,
who concluded, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> involved "ignored or
minimized" information that conflicted with the nerve gas theory.

            Even in the retraction and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' coverage of the retraction there is
plenty of residual bad journalism. The stories make it seem that the only
organized criticism came from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floyd Abrams</ENAMEX>--there's not even a whisper
indicating that all the key questions were raised <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after the story aired
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slate</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cyrus Krohn</ENAMEX>. (That babyish desire not to credit others is
incredibly deep-seated. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" was shocked to learn that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> piece about genetic research in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iceland</ENAMEX> lauded here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> was
wholly derivative of a prior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mother Jones</ENAMEX> piece, which was not even
mentioned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .) And although everybody now offers tons of reasons
for what the mission was not, nobody seems at all interested in a coherent
account of what it *was*. All the lemming-like movement first towards and then
away from the story leaves plenty of worthwhile questions on the table: Was
nerve gas ever used in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Laos</ENAMEX>? If not, then why does everybody now
admit that there were tactical munitions canisters called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">CBU-15s</ENAMEX>, and that
they were in-country? Were missions (nerve gas or no) ever conducted against
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servicemen</ENAMEX> or defectors?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> yesterday
ordered states to pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> under their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> programs for the indigent
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">disabled</ENAMEX>, on the grounds that under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>, prescription drug coverage
must include any <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>. The upshot, notes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is now having the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> pay for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> but not for birth control or infertility treatments for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>. And not, the
Times quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> as saying, for medical equipment needed to keep
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">quadriplegics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> with cerebral palsy out of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> especially emphasizes <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' concerns about the current lack of
knowledge about side effects, and reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> say they
will defy the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Viagra</ENAMEX> directive.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> broke the story of a defector from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s
nuclear weapons program, who as part of his process of seeking asylum in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">U.S</ENAMEX>, told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> that his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> had contemplated a nuclear <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> strike
against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>. The story got some follow-through coverage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, but now
comes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reporting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> at all, but "a low-paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">accountant</ENAMEX> for a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> that makes bathroom tiles."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publisher</ENAMEX> still has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> copies
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Speaker</ENAMEX>'s worst-selling novel "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>" taking up <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">space</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">warehouse</ENAMEX>.
"You'd think," he tells the paper, "there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> out there who
would want <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Kevorkian</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Fieger</ENAMEX>, is
running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">governor</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Michigan</ENAMEX>, and making a strong and entertaining go of
it. When asked if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kevorkian</ENAMEX> might have a place in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fieger</ENAMEX> said no:
"Can you imagine a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> with more skeletons in his <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">closet</ENAMEX>?..."

         
      
   
