
   
   
      
         
            No <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apocalypse Dow</ENAMEX>

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the collapse of the stock market led all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it's
the market's recovery. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">288</NUMEX> point Dow
upswing erased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s loss, on record volume. And the
papers continue to be scrupulous about raw numbers versus percentages--noting
that in point terms, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> biggest up move ever, but far
down the list as a percentage gain.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says the market's turnaround yesterday
could be attributed in part to the suggestion by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abby Joseph Cohen</ENAMEX> and several
other "notable <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX>" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's phrase) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> should
increase their stock holdings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
takes note of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s advisory too, but doesn't attribute any market action to
it. On the other hand, the paper dedicates most of a paragraph to passing along
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX>'s recommendations of an optimal portfolio mix. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> emphasizes
the human side, with a tale of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">broker</ENAMEX> abruptly coming back in to work from a
family vacation, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brokers</ENAMEX> making reassuring calls to their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moms</ENAMEX>. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> even throws in the information that stock market
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> were dressing differently at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, to allow for
more running around. Gratifyingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times includes a paragraph in its coverage (albeit after the jump)
about how "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>" were functioning as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> of last resort during
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s drop when no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX> could otherwise be found. Unlike the others, the
Wall Street Journal highlights the economy's
fundamentals, running a piece noting that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> economic reports released
spending, and a purchasing index--show a slow-down, but "nowhere near a
recession." A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> story reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> new car sales
remained robust in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>. "Overall it's hard to see global economic collapse
in these numbers," <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> auto <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has a
front-page check-in with a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> in which most are quoted
thinking the stock market's turmoil will not cause a recession.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s situation is on everybody's front. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> assured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> meetings that they still support democratic and free-market
reforms. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the WP fronts cover <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s platitudinous
speech to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and young business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about the values and risks
of reform. Gone, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , is the backslapping of yore between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Their state dinner was over at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:15 PM</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> trial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> raised the possibility in the
footnote of a legal ruling that she might hold <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> in contempt of
court because of apparently misleading answers he gave before her about his
relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. In the footnote, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> admits that she
has "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>" about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony given his recent public
statements.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX> experienced its very own market correction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> when
several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> pointed out (okay, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>) that the
column was mistaken in saying none of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s coverage mentioned what role,
if any, "circuit breakers" based on excessive market moves have nowadays. But
indeed, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front addresses the issue: they stop trading
upon a drop of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX> points.

            In case you worried about how the good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Connecticut</ENAMEX> are
doing during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apocalypse Dow</ENAMEX>, an inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece is here
to report that they are soldiering on. In sheer dollars, says the paper, few
towns have benefited as much from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>. The piece is accompanied by a
picture of a local <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> visiting a car <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> to pick out a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX> "just for
variety" to go with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Porsche</ENAMEX> he bought <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">just</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months ago</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
