
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unreasonable Dowd</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX>'s grand jury
appearance, a story that also makes the others' fronts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with new data indicating that the birth rate for unmarried black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> is
the lowest it's been in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times 's top non-local story is the decision by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> to form an
alliance aimed at resisting the immersion of their indigenous cultures in a
rising worldwide tide of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-made movies, television and music.

            For all the drama of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s appearance at the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>, since for
a change there were no leaks of testimony, the story has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> shortcoming that
should have thumbnailed it inside next to the corset ads: it produced no news.
In a nice bit of subversion, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> off-load a good deal of the
ink unaccountably granted to them on copious descriptions of non-events. The
Times ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bennet</ENAMEX> describes a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> tv <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>
taping a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fox News</ENAMEX> tv <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> taping his spot. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Miller</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Schmidt</ENAMEX> report that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> reported that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> was carrying a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chanel</ENAMEX> handbag, then add that others in
the media thought the stitching wasn't up to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chanel</ENAMEX> standards. Hope their
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> got the point.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that new numbers from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Center for Health</ENAMEX>
Statistics show a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996 birth</TIMEX> rate among unmarried black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">74.4</NUMEX> births per
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX>, down significantly from the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">90.7</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> recorded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. This is an
important story and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is to be saluted for stepping over Tripp
wires to run it where it belongs, but one still has the feeling the piece
somewhat mishandles the information. Several times high up, the drop is
credited to increased sex education and condom use among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX>. All this in a
newspaper that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX> has reported that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> make up but <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX>
percent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, they account for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent</NUMEX> of all new <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> cases.
And the piece waits until its fifteenth paragraph to mention welfare reform,
which removed a financial incentive for having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> out of wedlock--and
then, claiming that the drop has been steady long before welfare reform was
passed, says that "according to some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who monitor fertility rates" it was
not a significant factor. If this is indeed true, then the piece should have
made that point high up and supported it with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">more year</TIMEX>-by<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year</TIMEX> birthrate
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stats</ENAMEX>.

            Overplaying stories like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> means underplaying stories like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aircraft missile launch against an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> anti-aircraft battery that was
radar-illuminating a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>--just above the fold at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ,
bottom of the front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and only in a reefer box on the
USAT front. Or like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s conclusion <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Congolese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> massacred unarmed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutu</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996-1997</TIMEX>
and that the current <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Congolese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laurent Kabila</ENAMEX> blocked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s
investigation. No death total is given but the stories mention that according
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">180,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hutus</ENAMEX> are still missing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs this story
on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> of its early national edition. It's all too easy to
discount the lives of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in other cultures, because they are <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> we
don't know, but it's wrongheaded to play to that bias. Instead, journalism
should strive to make us know them. On its front page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the WP
effectively acquaints us with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> middle-class <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> who died in a head-on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">collision</ENAMEX>, but it runs its version of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX> massacre on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Learning Channel</ENAMEX> was
all set to run a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty</TIMEX><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">-minute</TIMEX> show about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX>, paid for by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anheuser-Busch</ENAMEX>,
until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> began making inquiries. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> implies a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Camelesque</ENAMEX> angle, noting that the show was scheduled to appear during the early
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday July 11 and Sunday July 12</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> were likely to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">channel</ENAMEX> surfing.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s papers brought the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. News & World Report</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">owner</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mort Zuckerman</ENAMEX> had fired his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor-in-chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Fallows</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers" thought this a bit too parochial for inclusion, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> '
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> thinks otherwise: she devotes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s column to an
anti-Fallows jeremiad, which ends up saying much more about her than him.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX>' excellent book on the wrongheaded culture of political
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX>, Breaking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> as a "pompous screed" and says he has "a
problem recognizing a news story." But who has bad news judgment? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX> says she
would rather read a piece by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bianca Jagger</ENAMEX> than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> about health care and
scoffs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fallows</ENAMEX> for not wanting to chase old news about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gianni Versace</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Princess Di</ENAMEX>. And who's pompous? Dowd laughs at the idea that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Downs</ENAMEX> might
have something to say about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proust</ENAMEX> and as usual wields her high school
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>--the column is called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Le Tout Swivet</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
