
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House Leaks</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with important <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX>'
calls over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to definitively explain his role
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's lead covers this too, but higher up and in its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headline</ENAMEX>, emphasizes the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s just-agreed-to grand jury
testimony could come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead covers the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s
response to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> problem.

            Now that "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> leak" has taken on a whole new meaning, presidential
liquid imagery has caught on: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes in its lead headline that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should "pour
his heart out" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> about his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. (Then there's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's economical but imagistically
unfortunate headline, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Both Sides Urge Clinton</ENAMEX> to Tell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Truth</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.") A
theme of the coverage is that the call for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> mea culpa is becoming
bipartisan.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead states that fixing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">feds</ENAMEX>' part of the millenium bug will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">billion</ENAMEX>. There are, after all, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7,336</NUMEX> "mission critical" <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> government
computer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">systems</ENAMEX>, ranging from ones controlling <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Tomahawk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> to those
processing student loans. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of these crucial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">systems</ENAMEX> can now be declared ready to work on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 2000</TIMEX>. Clearly there is an
increasing sense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Y2K</ENAMEX> gravitas among the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>: There was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead editorial calling for congressional creation of tax incentives
and subsidies for solutions, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> in a
series. And inside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> more millenium efforts: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on
the history of the awareness of the problem, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>' approach, another
stating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> is now back on track with its portion, and one pointing
out an easily overlooked aspect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> troubles--namely that
they include planning for the glitches possibly experienced by other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">militaries</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> continue to work the amazing story they broke
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week of the two three-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> discovered to have been switched
shortly after birth at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>. The WP
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U-VA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have decided they will not tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Johnson</ENAMEX> who
has her biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daughter</ENAMEX> until a court resolves the mess. That's okay--all
Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> has to do is read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , which names the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> and the couple
who had been raising her thinking she was theirs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>'s Newspaper adds a
further shocker to this real-life <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O. Henry</ENAMEX> tale: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couple</ENAMEX> was killed in a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4th</TIMEX> traffic accident.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts cover <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s warm reception in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granada</ENAMEX>, where in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> clashed with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX> and construction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
piece says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> is making diplomatic inroads in the English-speaking
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aid drops, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
that actually finished the airport the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX> were working on at the time of
the invasion. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> text mentions that both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cubans</ENAMEX>
were killed in the fighting, the caption under an accompanying picture inside
only mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> deaths.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a fine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walter Pincus</ENAMEX> story inside on a woefully
underreported topic, that of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military sales to foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. It
seems that the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> budget has created a perverse incentive: the
more surplus <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> are sold overseas, the more extra weapons the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> can
purchase. Under the arrangement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">an additional $600 million</NUMEX> in
goodies while near-state-of-the-art <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ships</ENAMEX> are going to sworn enemies <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX>
vessels) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greece</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">11</NUMEX>).

            Even as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> editorial page rails against the
progressive income tax's bite on high-income types, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's front
offers a more grounded look at big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">earners</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, noting a whiney new
development among many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professionals</ENAMEX> with annual incomes of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $200,000</NUMEX>:
envy of those who, thanks to booming job and stock markets, make even more.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Science Notebook</ENAMEX>" reports a finding that may upset many a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greenpeace</ENAMEX> campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Researchers</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scotland</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> have found evidence
that adult male bottlenose <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dolphins</ENAMEX> sometimes deliberately beat their young to
death. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> speculate that they do this so that their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> would
be willing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mate</ENAMEX> again more quickly.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> is hosting the most highly
attended exhibition in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61-year</TIMEX> history, far outstripping <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lichtenstein</ENAMEX> and
Rauschenberg retrospectives. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Five thousand</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> a day, most of them who've
never before been to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guggenheim</ENAMEX> or any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>, are coming to see a
display of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycles</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> featured <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lecturer</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Hopper</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
