
   
   
      
         
            Still No <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with the continuing political and economic turmoil in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, signaled by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> parliamentary defeat of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Ever the world citizen</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in an editorial, endorses <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VC</ENAMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX> story is but a reefer at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , which leads instead with a presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s letter to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> asking for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one week</TIMEX> to review and rebut <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter before it is submitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, a story that also
runs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> top front. Everybody gives lots of top-of-the-front-page
space and big pictures to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>'s record-tying <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">61st</NUMEX> home run.

            The papers all note that not only did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> get voted down by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duma</ENAMEX> again, but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of the central bank resigned. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
stresses the ground-level financial chaos, noting that many <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stores</ENAMEX> have
been picked clean of such items as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">toothpaste</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">butter</ENAMEX>, and toilet paper. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also goes high with this observation, mentioning shortages of
cooking <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> and flour. The WP likewise takes note of scarcities, adding
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">pharmacies</ENAMEX> are also affected. And it's not just <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
says the price of kielbasa has doubled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Siberia</ENAMEX>. The WP mentions a
nuclear weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Urals</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> haven't been paid for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is particularly strong on capturing the heat of the political debate, noting (along
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ) that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX> that "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>
reached the point where the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> went up in flames....Is this what you
want?" The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also gets in a pro-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>'s suggestion
to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> that he find out what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are saying about him and his
reforms by disguising himself and walking out among the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. "But," the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">legislator</ENAMEX> is quoted, "you'd better disguise yourself really well. You'll be in
trouble if they recognize you." A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">back-bencher</ENAMEX> charged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> with
wanting to take the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> back to pre-perestroika times. "Congratulations,"
she said, "You managed to do it. Look at the empty shop counters."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees the second <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> turn-down as putting pressure on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> to turn to somebody else as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. Everybody notes that under
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> constitution, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> defeat would allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> to dissolve
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX> and hold new elections, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> alone reports a further
element in the collision course between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duma</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duma</ENAMEX> is
considering bringing impeachment charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>, for his roles in the
breakup of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USSR</ENAMEX>, in the attack on the parliament <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, and in
the war against secessionist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chechnya</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duma</ENAMEX> vote on the charges could come,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as Friday</TIMEX>. And, explains the paper, if
impeachment proceedings start, then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> cannot dissolve the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>.
Here's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX>'s biggest stealth news story: come fall, both of the planet's
largest nuclear powers could be considering throwing out their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>.

            In its <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last few paragraphs</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead announces that the
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> denomination--not to be confused with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">National Baptist Convention</ENAMEX>, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>,
although married, admitted having an "improper relationship" with a female
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>--has called for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to resign, on the
grounds that he is corrupting young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. (Oh, he's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.) The resignation
call is also carried as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> dispatch inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that the number of black female
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architects</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> has doubled in the last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years</TIMEX>. But the raw
numbers are bracing: in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> there were <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">49</NUMEX>, and now there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">98</NUMEX>. It would have
been useful if the item had also mentioned the raw numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>, white
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, and white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> has discovered
that welfare reform has generated a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.7 billion</NUMEX> windfall for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>,
because under the reform the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> get a fixed amount of federal money no
matter how much they cut their rolls. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> have, says the paper, used
the money to start new welfare services, but many others are diverting the
money to education or tax relief, or just saving it. The upshot: welfare now
costs the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> more than it did <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">pre-reform</TIMEX>.

            The results of a USAT study of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">taxi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">safety</ENAMEX> are written up on the front of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1990 to 1996</TIMEX>, cab accidents were up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">48</NUMEX>
percent in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Phoenix</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">41 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYC</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>. The story is accompanied by a box of tips, including: always buckle up
(hitting that partition with your head is a leading cause of passenger
injuries) and always request a receipt (most receipts give the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cab</ENAMEX>'s number).
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> would add: immediately upon entry tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">driver</ENAMEX> that speeding
equals no tip.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham</ENAMEX> has apologized for saying <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX> during an appearance at a
medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX> that a rectal procedure he underwent during his recent treatment
for prostate problems was "just not natural, unless maybe you're <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barney</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
