
   
   
      
         
            Together We Train

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a lengthy article on the
reasons--stated and unstated--that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> help train foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sanctions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with the increased use of methamphetamines (speed, crystal
meth, etc.) in western <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>, as documented by a newly released <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
Department report. The good news (which catches an inside headline at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ) is that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> rates are falling nationwide. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times leads with farm troubles in the northern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">plains</ENAMEX>, caused by low
wheat and livestock prices. There's no quick fix but plenty of partisan
debate--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> want to increase farm subsidies, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> want to
find new markets. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> just approved the sale of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>,
which is under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sanctions.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> of a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-part series, raises interesting
questions about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>' overseas activities. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>
law allows the special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> to conduct overseas exercises if the "primary
purpose is to train <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>" (in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's words). Some of these
missions involve training foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, even in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> which are under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> sanctions or whose militaries have
dubious human rights records. Does training foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>--and sometimes even
financing their participation in the training--genuinely advance the training
of our own <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>? (Lamest answer cited in the WP : "by training foreign
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> [learn] how to train foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>.") Do we really want
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> to coach foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>--especially in unstable
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>--on crackdowns tactics? The sheer variety of rationales for the joint
training exercises--as given by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> --suggests
that the original purpose of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> law has been superceded by case-by-case
concerns.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> inside both run stories on the latest
political news from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>: an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> of current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX> was elected
to head the dominant political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. This development should bolster the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s stability at least for the short-term, though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Habibie</ENAMEX>'s hold on power is still fragile.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ousted CNN</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">April Oliver</ENAMEX> takes her battle-cry to the WP
Outlook section. She defends the retracted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> story on nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> used against
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> defectors in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Vietnam</ENAMEX> as "solid with the facts," and alleges that she
is the victim of a dark <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> public relations conspiracy.

            And Wall Street is getting ahead of itself, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
front page. Come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, it will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 29, 1999</TIMEX> for test computers, and
scripted mock-trading over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next few weeks</TIMEX> will preview how the industry
will handle the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year 2000 bug</ENAMEX>. If well-prepared Wall Street trips over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Y2K</TIMEX>,
then we may all be in trouble.

         
      
   
