
   
   
      
         
            Maybe-a-culpa

            Every paper leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four-minute</TIMEX> maybe<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">-a-culpa</ENAMEX>. But,
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> linguistically bobbed and weaved so much, their headline
descriptions of what exactly took place vary. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times slug, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> fessed up to an "inappropriate relationship."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says it was the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> liaison." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> sees the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky Intimacy</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
headline probably reflects what most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> heard: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Affair</ENAMEX> was
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">'Wrong</ENAMEX>'"--but it's not what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said, because, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James</ENAMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Bennet</NUMEX> points out in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s lead story, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> never used the word "affair."

            Nevertheless, in its lead, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> pithily sums up what was and was not
said: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> said he "misled <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>" and "gave a false impression," but he
didn't say he lied. And he described his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> as
"wrong," but never used the word "sex." The LAT observes that the speech
was not an apology to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> adds that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
never even used the words "sorry" or "apology." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
insisted last night that his sworn deposition in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> lawsuit was
"legally correct" even though in that deposition, he testified he couldn't
recall being alone with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> claims that in the session with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>
handled some of the questioning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says he left
that entirely to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lieutenants</ENAMEX>. The papers report that, according to one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> testified truthfully but
refused to answer some questions he found too personal. This despite, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reminds us, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s earlier pledge to testify "truthfully and
completely." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> have told it that in the grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> session, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> he may subpoena him to get all his questions
answered.

            Given the subject matter, a certain amount of waffling was to be expected,
but what, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, surprised many (including some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> who'd hoped for political reconciliation) was how much of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
speech was given over to attacking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation. Indeed, USAT
describes the speech as contrite words in a defiant tone. And the WP
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s statement "was flavored with as much anger as remorse," and
quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orrin Hatch</ENAMEX> as being "personally offended" at this aspect of the
speech. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports that later, on television <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hatch</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "a jerk."

            The other big story of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>, making <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all five</NUMEX> fronts, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s
decision to devalue the ruble and to default on <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of dollars</NUMEX> in debt.
The move was made, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , to forestall the flight of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>
from its emerging markets and to bolster confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s abilities to
pay its bills. Devaluation and partial default, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ,
means the overall amount of debt is reduced and terms for repaying it become
easier. But the move strikes at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s solidest post-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> economic
accomplishments: a stable currency and low inflation. And given the increasing
connections between markets, there is the threat posed to the currencies and
interest rates of other emerging economies, such as those in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX> and even to stronger, more established ones, like <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>.

            Inside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> have arrested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> for
questioning about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>'s bombing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omagh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> that
killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> have not yet been publicly named, but one is said to
be the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> of a prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Irish</ENAMEX> nationalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponent</ENAMEX> of the recently brokered
peace accord.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> run inside stories claiming that the man
recently arrested in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and transported back to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> to be questioned
further about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing has, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>,
neither admitted responsibility for the attack nor implicated anybody else.
This directly contradicts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s WP dispatch, which appears to have
relied exclusively on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>' accounts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
statements.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Glassman</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter is mostly
just pseudo-events, and offers the following list of alternative real issues
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> have a much greater need to know about: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) How serious is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
economic crisis? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Have defense cuts made us vulnerable? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) How broad is the
current prosperity? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) Why is crime falling? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>) Why do some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> fail and
others succeed? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">6</NUMEX>) Why is there a federal surplus? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">7</NUMEX>) How good and how
widespread is health care? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX>) How is welfare reform working?

            Back to the speech: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> repeated that he had never asked anyone to lie,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's list of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s prior but now inoperative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> statements includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX>. Are we to suppose that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> made that denial without being asked to by his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX>? Well no, we can't
because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCurry</ENAMEX> goes on to say, "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">T</ENAMEX>]he <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> was quite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> about me making
that statement."

         
      
   
