
   
   
      
         
            Kosovertures

            Nobody agrees on the lead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s promise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to resume talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
plan to send the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Dept.</ENAMEX>'s international trade point <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> to
prod the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> to stabilize the yen. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>'s belligerent
admission for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first time Tuesday</TIMEX> that it has and will continue to develop
and test ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> as well as sell them to the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Syria</ENAMEX>. This disclosure, bizarrely enough, is apparently designed to get the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to lift its near-total economic embargo on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the various natural calamities plaguing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wildfires</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>, thunderstorms in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, and floods in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that after meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>, in an attempt to forestall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> military action against his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX>,
pledged to provide relief <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">monitors</ENAMEX> with access to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> and to make arrangements for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> to
return there. However he did not, observes the paper, agree to withdraw his
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> from the area. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who, notes the
Times , are also opposed to any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> use of force in the situation,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">portrayed Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s remarks as an important breakthrough. And while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that it's not at all clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s pledges are
genuine, it's beyond curious that nowhere does the story mention that he is
believed by many to have authorized crimes against humanity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Bosnian</ENAMEX> war
and is not being hauled before an international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> to answer for them
primarily because he is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>. This context is also missing from the
LAT front-page story on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> developments. Ditto for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which carries the story inside, along with one about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
military's doubts about being able to operate effectively in and around
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that what's prompting the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> push to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is the fear
that if something isn't done soon, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis could worsen. In
particular, explains the paper, there's the fear that if the yen continues to
drop, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> will abandon its pledge not to devalue its currency, which could
set off further devaluations across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, and this would only further hurt the
region's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> and further suppress its imports. Which could hurt <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exports.
Already, notes the story, the yen's problems have contributed to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>
drop in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> sales. For all this about what is going wrong and
could go wronger, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is awfully light on what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> wants the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to actually do, not going much beyond its remarks in the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX> paragraph about the desire for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to "stimulate and deregulate" its
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> and bail out its insolvent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. There is the comment that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX>'s responses in this direction have only been "modest," but
there is no detail on what they were or why they are considered
insufficient.

            The USAT front section "cover story" reveals that one in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
stalking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of them stalked by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. The story
keys on perhaps the most famous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> of male-on-male
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stalking</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>, but also notes the cases of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressman</ENAMEX> and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> (both from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nevada</ENAMEX>) who were preyed on recently by the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.
According to the story, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> stalk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> for the same reasons they stalk <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>:
mental <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disorders</ENAMEX>, narcissism, and an anti-social streak.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Massachusetts Supreme Court</ENAMEX> has upheld
the reduced sentence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">279 days</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">au pair</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Woodward</ENAMEX>. The ruling means
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX>, convicted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> of killing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby boy</ENAMEX> in her care, is free
to return to her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> immediately
filed a civil suit against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodward</ENAMEX> (for wrongful death? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
doesn't say) seeking damages and asking that she be prevented from making
interview or book deals allowing her to profit from the death. The story also
makes front-page "reefers" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> item about a JAMA study coming out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> noting
that the number of disciplinary actions taken against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> for
sex-related offenses increased from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">42</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989 to 147</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">About 40 percent</NUMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> disciplined during this time span were allowed to return to
practice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> disciplined for sex-related offenses were more likely to be
in the fields of psychiatry, obstetrics and gynecology, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> and general
practice.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that in congressional
testimony, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> questioned how antitrust laws are being applied in
the current merger environment and indirectly criticized the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s case
against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> suggested that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> should exercise more
"humility" in wielding antitrust action because, as in the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Steel</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopolies</ENAMEX> tend to fade over time.

            In his survey of the recently released <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> financial disclosure
forms, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Kamen</ENAMEX> notices that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert C. Smith</ENAMEX> is a
big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocate</ENAMEX> of tort reform, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> nevertheless collected a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$175,000</NUMEX> jury
verdict against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheraton Hotel</ENAMEX> for a slip and fall.

         
      
   
