
   
   
      
         
            Shuttered to Think

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the New York
Times lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> decision, in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombings</ENAMEX>, to shut some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> in order to update their security. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with word that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s
upcoming report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will focus on evidence of possible impeachable acts
relating to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and will not
even include the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> financial dealings that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has been investigating
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years</TIMEX>. The WP front ignores embassy security, and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> fronts ignore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Dept.</ENAMEX> says it has received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a dozen</NUMEX> threats to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassies</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX> bombings, but that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> is emphasizing
embassies are not being closed permanently. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> suggests the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">downtime</ENAMEX> might be just a matter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> quotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX>'s
identification of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> of the affected <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX>: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swaziland</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> also names <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Uganda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>, but
refers only to a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several-hours</TIMEX> evacuation at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swaziland</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in response
to a bomb threat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> adds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ivory Coast</ENAMEX> is cutting
back its <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">business hours</TIMEX> while security is improved, and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cairo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>
moved into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>.

            This space often notes how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headlines cut to the chase, but its
headline over this story--"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">U.S. To Shut Embassies To Fix Security"</ENAMEX>--cuts too
much, with its suggestion that all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> are being affected. Better is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> header: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> Closes Down Some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operations</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Posts</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> notes that he will eventually
produce a separate and more inclusive document for the judicial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">panel</ENAMEX> that
appointed him. In the meantime though, the paper explains, the pared-down
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> report will get to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> quickly (probably shortly after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> testifies to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> grand jury)--in plenty of time to leak out and
produce much partisan acrimony during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> elections.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> top fronts feature stories about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s
court proceeding in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> in which a twelve-year-old and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourteen-year-old</TIMEX>
were given the strictest sentence available to juveniles, for shooting to death
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX>: confinement in a juvenile detention <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> until
age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> made no formal statement in court, while the other
apologized but also said he meant to shoot over everybody's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes that in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, juvenile proceedings are usually
closed to the public and press, but that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> in this case had allowed a
more open hearing. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s newspaper <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> seem to have likewise
loosened up on juvenile coverage in this case--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> run the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>' names,
and indeed, the fronts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> all
feature pictures of them. Just what are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' policies in this area? It's
hard to figure out from what they publish--just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> told the
tale of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 7 and 8</TIMEX>, arrested for murdering an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>,
without publishing their pictures or their names.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Korean War Memorial</ENAMEX>, built in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army Corps of Engineers</ENAMEX>, needs <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> to fix
buckled paving <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">stones</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX> dead shade <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, and a leaking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pool</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Remembrance</TIMEX>.
Shouldn't a war memorial be built to last longer than the war it's a memorial
to?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs a front-page feature describing
a new type of medical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consultant service</ENAMEX>: for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $800</NUMEX> a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, you get access to a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX> who, when you get sick, advises you how to
best navigate the health care <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says such a development
points the way to a multitiered medical system where the quality of medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">care</ENAMEX> might depend even more than it does <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX>'s wealth.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s signing into law by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
of a comprehensive job training bill "got lost in the backdraft of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> investigation." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> adds that "little seems to be getting done
in the capital <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> and when it does it barely causes a ripple." The
story runs on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
