
   
   
      
         
            Hashimotives

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> election results, which
will very likely force the resignation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryutaro</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX>. The top-non-local story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>'s triumph at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX>-hosted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Cup</ENAMEX>, a story that gets top-of-the-page-with-pictures coverage at not only
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , but also at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . (And a
reefer-with-picture at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .) This no doubt reflects the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>': a)
perception that they have more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant readers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> and b) chance to
justify all those upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> expense account items.

            The papers read the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> returns--described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> as "stunning" and by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> as a "brutal drubbing"--as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">electorate</ENAMEX>'s impatience with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX>'s ineffectual response to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s worse recession in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX>. As
the papers explain, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Liberal Democrats</ENAMEX>, retains power,
but its loss of control of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX>'s upper <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">house</ENAMEX> means other party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> now
feel free to maneuver for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> and hence for <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">P.M. The</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes that the results mean <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX>'s scheduled trip to meet
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> is cancelled. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads its story
with the big picture: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX> will become the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in less than
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> to be toppled from power by the region's economic crisis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ,
in its front-page effort says the crisis has chalked up new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (specifying besides <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front the firebomb murder of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> sleeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> ages <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">7, 9,</ENAMEX>
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ballymoney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>. The outrage is believed to be the work
of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extremists</ENAMEX> reacting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s recent move into a
mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> neighborhood. Although the bombing certainly seems capable of
upsetting the recently approved peace agreement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes one ray of
hope: unlike in the past, the murders quickly prompted bipartisan calls for
restraint. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX> is quoted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> wondering, "Where's the logic
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> are burned in their beds<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            The USAT front reports that high-level talks between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX>
broke off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> had been hoping that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX> would cut a deal that would
allow struck <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> to re-open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. But now, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s headline,
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Long Strike Likely</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also goes front-page with word that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> plans to
recall <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than one million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillacs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chevrolets</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pontiacs</ENAMEX> because their
air bags can inflate without a crash. Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">safety regulators</ENAMEX> have also been
busy with the problem: they are, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , investigating airbag
function in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mitsibushi Mirages</ENAMEX> (prompted by a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> death of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>) and in
several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subaru</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mazda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chrysler</ENAMEX> models.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a front-page takeout on the career of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cuban</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">exiles</ENAMEX>'
longtime top clandestine operative that jumps inside to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-page full spread
complete with pictures and time-line. The story is based on an extensive
interview given to freelance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cuba</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Louise Bardach</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffer</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Rohter</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Posada Carriles</ENAMEX>, at his <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caribbean</ENAMEX> hideout. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Posada</ENAMEX>'s
tale of anti-Castro ops, which includes a series of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Havana</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hotel</ENAMEX> bombings last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, alleges considerable consorting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>," he is quoted,
"taught us explosives, how to kill, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>, trained us in acts of sabotage....Now
they call it terrorism."

            According to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Glenn</ENAMEX>'s readmission to
the space program has had an unanticipated consequence: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty-eight years</TIMEX>
after becoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s first female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">astronaut candidate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerrie Cobb</ENAMEX> wants back in the program too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cobb</ENAMEX>, who is <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> younger than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX>, originally passed all the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> tests <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn</ENAMEX> did.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> is quoted in the piece saying, "At this time, there are no
plans to fly her."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that when the soon-to-be-released "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Small Soldiers</ENAMEX>"
got assigned a stiffer-than-expected PG-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">13</NUMEX> rating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger King</ENAMEX>
was left with a marketing tie-in promotion of action figure toys designed for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who wouldn't be seeing the movie. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> quickly devised a contingency
plan, which included pulling ads from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> shows,
point-of-purchase signs advising <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> to consider the content of the movie
before deciding to take their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, and trade-ins for Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potato Head</ENAMEX>. The
episode illustrates, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , the perils of devising marketing
plans for movies before they're made.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Corrections</ENAMEX>. Another stretch in the cooler for TP: When
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" remarked <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX> on the oddity
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s pro-homeownership remarks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> given that he'd
never owned a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>, several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> complained. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reader Ed Gray</ENAMEX> reports that
according to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pulaski County Arkansas</ENAMEX> records, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> once owned a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">816</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N. Midland</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Little Rock</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>" regrets the error.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" runs a piece about how the recent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">journalism</ENAMEX> scandals have produced a distinct article genre: the media career
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">obituary</ENAMEX>. The piece then inadvertently throws dirt on the face of director
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Levinson</ENAMEX> by crediting his hit "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX>" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James L. Brooks</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
