
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brave Newt World</ENAMEX>

            After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Papers</ENAMEX> provides the low-down on overseas
coverage of the war crimes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandela</ENAMEX>'s birthday, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Queen Elizabeth</ENAMEX>'s
rising stature in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fiji</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead with a story that's already made the rounds once this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>'s promise that his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> will return to
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilian</ENAMEX> rule. What's new is that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> he said this would
happen by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29, 1999</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> also goes with a moldy oldy: It's hot. The only
really new heat news, on the LAT front and inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , is
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border Patrol</ENAMEX> is carrying out search-and-rescue missions to save
illegal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> who court heat death while trying to sneak into the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Orleans</ENAMEX>, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the summer</TIMEX> swelter proved global warming.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abubakar</ENAMEX> apparently bowed to
military hawks in not agreeing to hand over power by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1</TIMEX> to civilian
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> doesn't explain the significance of the date, but
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> does--it's <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nigerian Independence Day</ENAMEX>.) But in a televised
speech, he said he would release all political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX> jailed by the previous
military <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX>, allow the formation of political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX>, reform the prison
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX> and put an end to "lapses" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> of public funds. The
speech, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , was intended to reassure Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abubakar</ENAMEX> is clearly making the transition to Western political values--he
summed up his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">predecessor</ENAMEX>'s reign of corruption and false imprisonment thus:
"mistakes have been made."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> runs a front-page feature on an
emerging <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> journalism, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Weekend</ENAMEX> . The
paper started out entertainment-oriented but under the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> of its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX>-oriented and literate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>, it has grown in circulation and
profitability as it moved from celebrity news and salacious scandals to real
investigative reporting. Recent stories: thefts of antiquities during a
high-profile government <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dam project</ENAMEX>, and false murder convictions. And, reports
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is changing the shape of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>. In fact,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> a government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> launched its own copycat.

            Additional perspective on the press comes in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
op-ed written by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Peruvian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gustavo Gorriti</ENAMEX>, who notes that in
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Latin America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX> are often the only check on government abuse of
power and, as a result, are generally viewed very positively. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> reason for
this, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> says, is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> principles of thoroughness, fact
checking and the separation between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> have profoundly
influenced <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. Which leads <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gorriti</ENAMEX> to wonder: What happened to
these values in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> newsrooms? His answer: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conglomerates</ENAMEX> swallowing up
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">media</ENAMEX> properties, the rush to do "impact news" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> sort, and
"relentless greed for prizes."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianna Huffington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> column connects the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most consuming
scandal stories of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s</TIMEX>. If the "perjury epidemic" is to be checked, then,
she says, the perjury cases involving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (who denied under oath
having had sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX> (who denied under oath having
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">beaten Nicole</ENAMEX>) must be pursued to their respective ends.

            The most disturbing thing "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" has read on the job yet was in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , which published an interview with a teenaged boy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David</ENAMEX>
Cash, who apparently learned right after the fact that his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> had murdered
a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> casino <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX> and yet did nothing.
LAT : "Were you appalled that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> said he killed a little <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>?"
Cash: "I'm not going to get upset over somebody else's life. I just worry about
myself <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. I'm not going to lose sleep over somebody else's problems."

            Following up its story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX>'s propensity for flying
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> around, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s WP passes along the
results of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Responsive Politics</ENAMEX> study of the free travel
accepted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> (it's still legal as long as it relates to
congressional business). The chief finding: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corporations</ENAMEX>, trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and the
like spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.4 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> on trips for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX>, and
their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> accepting the most free travel--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $44,000</NUMEX>
worth--was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> also had the single most expensive free
trip--a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four-day</TIMEX> jaunt to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX> that cost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atlantic Richfield</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33,000</NUMEX>. Asked
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,000</NUMEX> hotel bill at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>'s posh <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claridge</ENAMEX>'s, an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> offers
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> this explanation: "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arco</ENAMEX> selected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotel</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
