
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Murder</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times lead with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s dominant story: a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX>'s shooting spree in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> corridor that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> and wounded a tourist. Details
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX>'s actions vary among the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>--all describe a scene of
great terror and confusion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russel E. Weston Jr.</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helena, Mont.</ENAMEX>, who had
been investigated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> for making threats against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, marched past a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> detector and began firing, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police officer</ENAMEX> and mortally wounding a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> whose own shots brought
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX> down. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> give personal information on the
fallen <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, including their marital status (both were married) and number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2 and 3</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> focuses on the details of the shootings,
including a front-page photo of a bloody, wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">tourist</ENAMEX> and a description of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weston</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">gun</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX>-shot <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">.38</NUMEX> caliber <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wesson</ENAMEX> revolver). All make note of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senator</ENAMEX> (and cardiac <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">surgeon</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Frist</ENAMEX>'s attempt to aid
both a wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s efforts to avoid testifying before a federal grand jury
make the front page at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and get a reefer at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s personal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, has been negotiating with
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> camp about possible means of providing information to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independent</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Counsel</ENAMEX> without forcing the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ever appearance of an acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> before
a grand jury. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> mention that discussions were initiated by fresh
talk of a subpoena that, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> quotes an anonymous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>, had
been "drawn up and ready for delivery" to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The LAT
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">stresses Clinton</ENAMEX>'s desire to appear cooperative towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation,
while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> focus on the constitutional showdown that
could arise should the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> be subpoenaed.

            The election of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Foreign Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keizo Obuchi</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberal Democratic</ENAMEX>
Party <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> makes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> fronts. Obuchi, a longtime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insider</ENAMEX>, will
almost certainly succeed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryutaro Hashimoto</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s next <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>. His
prize: a ruling party divided between young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX> and conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmakers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s worst economic recession in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifty years</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front pages carry the ruling by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolina</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klu Klux Klan</ENAMEX> chapters (and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> individual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klansmen</ENAMEX>)
must pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37.8 million</NUMEX> for instigating the burning of a black <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">church</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>.
The damages, over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> more than sought by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiff</ENAMEX>, are the
largest ever awarded in a hate crimes case.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report the guilty verdict rendered by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> in the
murder trial of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force Academy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cadet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Graham</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> faces an
automatic life sentence--the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> requested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> not
seek the death penalty. He will join his former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fiancee</ENAMEX> and ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naval Academy</ENAMEX>
midshipman, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Zamora</ENAMEX>, who currently is serving a life sentence for her role
in the murder. In a biblical turn, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zamora</ENAMEX>
"vengeful" and cite her as the driving force behind the murder of the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
