
   
   
      
         
            Stock Coverage

            Everybody leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s big DOWnturn. The headlines at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> all mention that the action erased the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>'s gains for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the year</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> headline omits that detail in
favor of mentioning that high-tech stocks got hit hard. The papers scrupulously
avoid the term "crash" and all point out that despite the big raw numbers, in
percentage terms, there have been many far worse <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX>. For instance, right away
in its story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s Dow drop was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.4 percent</NUMEX>, whereas
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1987</TIMEX> crash was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> plunge of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22.6 percent</NUMEX>.

            The papers note that compared to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, the markets, although for the moment
pessimistic, appeared to remain orderly. And everyone finds it easy to produce
individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> who are not pulling out, and others who are even buying.
But basically, the coverage follows the usual pattern: There's the numbers.
There's the quotes from institutional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merrill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynch</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>" saying, "It may be that we are reaching a temporary climax,"
but adds that he also said the market was just as likely to stumble further.
And from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-in-the-street <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> saying that
"certain stocks will retain their value. I think the market in general is
headed much lower."

            All this cookie-cutting means that certain perennial basic questions don't
get answered. For instance, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> refer to "waves of
selling," they make it seem like there were no <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">buyers</ENAMEX>. But wouldn't there have
to be for these trades to occur? So why not call this waves of buying? And
although there's a fair amount of discussion about who's selling, there's
comparatively little about who's buying--why? Also, although there is some
mention of the role computerized trading played in the recent intense action,
there's not much discussion of how such trading differs nowadays from say, the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> crash in which it was considered a prime culprit. Are there "circuit
breakers" on the books now or not? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s papers don't say.

            And it's bad enough that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> are full of content-free quotes from the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>," but why is it that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>' own agendas are rarely mentioned?
For instance, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent times</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doyenne</ENAMEX> of Wall <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">St. expert</ENAMEX>-talk seems to be
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman Sachs</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abby Joseph Cohen</ENAMEX>, quoted in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> as saying, "We find
very little reason to think stock prices should have declined in the manner in
which they did," and described by the paper as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wall St.</ENAMEX>'s pre-eminent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bull</ENAMEX>."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes her as calling the current correction "overdone."
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> don't note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> has strong personal reasons to encourage
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bullishness</ENAMEX>--namely, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldman Sachs</ENAMEX> is about to go public. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Begala</ENAMEX> or
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carville</ENAMEX> are quoted in political stories, their spin is always noted. Why
don't financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> routinely get the same treatment?

            One informative bit only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> has is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> who took a big part of
their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> compensation in stock options are getting clobbered: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattel</ENAMEX> has sustained paper losses of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24 million</NUMEX>, for instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEOs</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kodak</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oracle</ENAMEX> nearly as much. We also learn via the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week</ENAMEX>" that
the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX> has been so busy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> that "I signed up for
race-car driving, and I canceled that; I was supposed to play a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">golf</ENAMEX>,
and I haven't picked up a golf club <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all summer</TIMEX>." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aetna</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX>
had to, sniff, go on a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> jaunt alone .

            The fronts at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>'s test-firing of a ballistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, a test
which sent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> stage clear across <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and displayed a far
greater range than was previously attributed to it. The story runs inside at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> .

            A story on the LAT front reports further on the increasing
difficulties with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence's explanation for why that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sudanese</ENAMEX> plant
must have been producing components for nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> (difficulties <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> broached
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ). According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have quietly expressed the belief that possibly pharmaceutical
products were made there. An <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX> is also
quoted by name supporting that view. Another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> arms <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> is quoted
saying the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> account of the evidence is "untenable."
Surprisingly, no mention has been made in the coverage of an eerily similar
episode from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> war--the strike against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX> chemical
weapons-slash-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">milk</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX>.

            The letters section of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> contains a missive from former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">terrorism</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> and current TV terrorism <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Cannistraro</ENAMEX>. He
writes because a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> article stated he was aware of intercepted
electronic communications regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cannistraro</ENAMEX> denies this,
saying he is "not aware of the specific nature of any intelligence information
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community</ENAMEX> has" <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">on bin Laden</ENAMEX>'s role in the recent attacks.
You can see why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cannistraro</ENAMEX> was moved to write this. He makes a nice piece of
change from being on TV appearing to know highly cool current spook stuff, but
of course, it would be illegal if he did, much less if he spoke about it on
TV.

         
      
   
