
   
   
      
         
            The Weak, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Spin</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> news, most of it coming out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> session,
dominates. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to abandon their
push for a big tax cut <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Following its lead <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX> about
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s intention to more strictly <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with more information about how lax government supervision
has been, reporting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between July 1997 and April 1998</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only six</NUMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">16,000</NUMEX> nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> lost eligibility for government reimbursement.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s unexpected vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> for an
overhaul of the laws governing immigrant farm <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> that would make it easier
for <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">farms</ENAMEX> to bring in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> from abroad. Both of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>
opposed the measure, says the paper, citing a recent government finding that
there's no farm labor shortage. It's unclear, says the LAT what will
happen to the measure in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are divided: some want to
help agribusiness hiring, while others worry that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> brought in tend to
stay illegally. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> a shake-up in the local
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead is a local story of broader interest: According to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Census Bureau</ENAMEX>, there's been more residential building going on in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> corridor during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s</TIMEX> than anywhere else in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>.
In fact, in that time, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s housing stock grew more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> faster than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. Among the causes cited: the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore-Washington</ENAMEX> region has one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s highest concentrations of baby
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boomers</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the main political facts that has scared top
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> off a tax-cut is their fear that any such move would be met
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s charge that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> would risk <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>'s
long-term health to give tax cuts to the wealthy. But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are intent on plans to bring to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a ten-year</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700</NUMEX>
billion tax reduction. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> account leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">outsider</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reader</ENAMEX> mystified by so much tax-cutting zeal in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> branch of the legislature
and virtually none in the other. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" also notes, but also
does not explain, this difference.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> as saying the nursing home
enforcement numbers are "shocking," and that the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> charged with
overseeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> "has failed." Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> head
puts the blame on state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead, reefered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and carried inside
everywhere else, is <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">juice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">maker</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odwalla</ENAMEX>'s agreement to pay the
biggest criminal fine ever in a food injury case--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> shipment of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">unpasteurized apple juice</ENAMEX> led to an <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> outbreak that
killed a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-month-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX> and sickened <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 66</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Some of the
fine will pay for expanding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">E. coli</ENAMEX> research.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> other developments get front coverage at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> but are inside
elsewhere: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> vote to override a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> veto of the ban on the
late-term abortion procedure involving partial vaginal delivery followed by
removal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fetus</ENAMEX>' brain. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is thought to be a few votes short of
an override. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> vote to ban most forms of Internet gambling.

            Perhaps reflecting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">L.A.</ENAMEX>'s large <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Persian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is alone
in fronting the conviction of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tehran</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> in his corruption trial. The
sentence: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>, getting whipped and being fined more than
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX>. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX> is a staunch <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s rather
d,tente-oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mohammed Khatami</ENAMEX>, the harsh sentence is viewed,
explains the paper, as a setback to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s incipient liberalization.

            In light of those cloned <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" has taken to calling the
"<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hawaiian</ENAMEX> Five-O," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a front-pager addressing how various
religions view genetic replication. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christianity</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Islam</ENAMEX> and Judaism each have a
wing that considers cloning an abomination. This includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX>, which
condemned cloning, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ten years ago</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern</ENAMEX> Baptists
are in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballpark</ENAMEX>. Denominations that take a cautious but not condemning
approach include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutherans</ENAMEX>, conservative and reformed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX>, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Muslims</ENAMEX>.
And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hindus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Buddhists</ENAMEX> are open to cloning. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that's because of
the religions' doctrine of reincarnation, but doesn't satisfactorily explain
why this is thought to support the liberal view. After all, clones are not,
unlike reincarnated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">souls</ENAMEX>, the very same <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that some presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> think
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> is about to subpoena <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and notes a new question
making the rounds, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> take a subpoena for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>?" The column notes another sex-scandal-in-the-making: a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shore</ENAMEX>-leave sex orgy indulged in by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the
gender-integrated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> of the aircraft carrier <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX> .

            *<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Corrections</ENAMEX>* If to err is human, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s column was
overflowing with humanity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Weiss</ENAMEX> is not
married to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gina Kolata</ENAMEX>--he is married to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Angier</ENAMEX>. It wasn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> I who died the
same day as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>--it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX>. (Other examples of co-mortality
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" meant to include: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aldous Huxley</ENAMEX>.) And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snoop Doggy Dogg</ENAMEX> is spelled with double-gs throughout. The
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" pledge: no more recreational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NyQuil</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
