
   
   
      
         
            Dousing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flames</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech on the global economy leads all around.
Lovey-dovey <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> pix grace the tops at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> . A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lovey-dovey</ENAMEX> shot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Homeric</ENAMEX> rivals <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sosa</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX> does the same at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> . At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
the spot goes to a shot of a post-speech <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at a fund-raiser, amid the
cast of "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lion King</ENAMEX>."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, in his speech
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council on Foreign Relations</ENAMEX>, called the current
situation "the biggest financial challenge facing the world in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">half-century</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> spoke of trying to "douse
the flames of the international financial crisis." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes that
this is a shift from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s much more minimal assessment of the threat last
fall. And indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> refers to the leading economies' "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of
silence" about the crisis. The papers note that soon after the speech, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ministers</ENAMEX> and central bank <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">heads</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G-7</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> issued a joint
statement pledging to spur global growth and restore stability to the financial
markets.

            With characteristic succinctness, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> does something the others
never quite do--spell out what the problem is: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a third</NUMEX> of the world is in
recession, and this threatens the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> because overseas trade has accounted for
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> growth since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. The remedies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> advocated include,
the papers report, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' replenishment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>, and allowing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> to
tap into an emergency line of credit. All but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also mention the
response of lowering interest rates, to stimulate growth. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> called for the world's leading economies to abandon their fear of
inflation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says such comments are being widely interpreted as
hinting at the need for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve Board</ENAMEX> to lower interest rates. But
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> avoided the
appearance of trying to dictate interest rate policy to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX> has invited an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> for
talks. This means, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, that perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primakov</ENAMEX> will not follow the
recent calls from some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX> to shut <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> off from western investment.
In the immediate balance is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.3 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> emergency loan agreed to in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, but delayed after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> devalued its currency and defaulted on its
domestic debt.

            A report highlighted on the front page of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> found
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> in immigrant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> tend to be healthier than those of
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, but that their health deteriorates the longer they live
here. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s LAT front bears yet another example of a recent skein
of research questioning the time-honored tenet that immigrating to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is
good for your health. A new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX> study finds that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only half as many</NUMEX> psychiatric problems as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-born <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> do. Fast food, lack of exercise, and especially drug abuse and the
breakdown of the extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> are implicated.

            A front-page WP piece and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">new HHS</ENAMEX> study finds that most of the possible savings to come from the growth
of managed care plans in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> have already been achieved, with the
result that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s health care costs are likely to double over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next decade</TIMEX>. Also contributing to the rise, says the study, is an increase in
the consumption of expensive prescription drugs and new medical technology,
plus greater <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient</ENAMEX> demand for choosing one's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>. Already, notes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , health insurance rates are starting to go up.

            The front page of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section reports that as part of its
antitrust case, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> is investigating accusations made by several former
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> destroyed computer files relating to
various previous lawsuits. The files, says the paper, could have served as
antitrust evidence.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports inside that a private <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Jersey</ENAMEX> telephone company
has just signed a deal to build a cellular phone system for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic</ENAMEX> sect controlling most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is said by the
Times to have been unaware of the deal but to look on it favorably as a
means to ease Western access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Under the deal the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> will
require the use of software to block "anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Taliban</ENAMEX> Web sites."

            Inevitably, some of the reporting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s economics speech suggests
that it had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>-driven spin value. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls the speech
"hastily scheduled," and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> speaks of presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> painting a
picture of an "engaged" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Well, why not--that's the next step after
dating.

         
      
   
