
   
   
      
         
            Erecting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a report, sourced to senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has discussed, but not finally committed to, a strategy of
acknowledging to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> that he'd had intimate sexual
encounters with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with a new poll, taken by the paper
together with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>, indicating that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to tell the truth to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, even if it means making just such an admission. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has
for months been secretly dissuading <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> from making
surprise inspections in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> in order to avoid prompting a new crisis with
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> appearance "the most politically
and legally perilous moment of his presidency," and says he has been conducting
practice sessions in which his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> are questioning him and designing
answers that allow him to acknowledge a relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> without going into
graphic detail. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" say that some
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisors</ENAMEX> are suggesting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> afterwards make a public statement about his
testimony.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , the theory under which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may now admit
to sexual contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is this: when he said in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case
deposition that he had never had sexual relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, he was
following the definition of sexual relations approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> trial
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>--contact with any of a list of body parts (the paper quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">advisor</ENAMEX>'s assessment of the definition: "cockamamie")--but since the list of
body parts doesn't include the mouth, it doesn't count oral sex as sexual
relations. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> inner circle realizes the
major political drawback of this line: reinforcing the notion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> (in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's choice phrase) as "a lawyerly manipulator of language use to
evade responsibility...technically truthful but not fundamentally honest."
Another bad reaction will come from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> if they ever notice that
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s definition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is saying that he didn't have sex
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, but she had sex with him.

            As the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s public position
advocating unconditional access inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX> has
been palpably softening--to the point, where, in the words of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
lead editorial, it's as if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> no longer cared about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chemical</ENAMEX>, biological and nuclear status. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead is a bombshell because it shows inner
details of the cave-in, including an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 4th</TIMEX> phone call between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> urged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX> to call off no-notice inspections at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sites</ENAMEX> thought to have forbidden
weapons components and supporting documents. After a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> such caution from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Butler</ENAMEX> canceled the inspections
and ordered his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baghdad</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> continues to report the story it broke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are looking for a missing assistant on a water truck thought to
have been the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb vehicle</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dar-es-Salaam</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> even
identifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> by name. As does the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> goes
on to say that according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, the water truck
was being discounted as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb carrier</ENAMEX>--primarily because the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> was not
obliterated in the blast. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> strongly
suggest the missing assistant is not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> runs a front-page feature on the continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economic crisis, and the story also gets
play on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section fronts. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
plight, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , has become the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s main
economic worry. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>'s main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , is that
these fears will be picked up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brazil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Argentina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>, precipitating further national crises that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX> doesn't have the
money to assuage. And of course, there's the underlying concern about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
political stability.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NAACP</ENAMEX> is urging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept.</ENAMEX> to look into whether <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> are violating the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Fair Housing Act</ENAMEX> in their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acceptance</ENAMEX> of mortgage applications. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> cites new data showing that the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> rejection rate for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53 percent</NUMEX>, compared with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 percent</NUMEX> for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">whites</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> should have noted that these aren't the relevant
figures because they aren't liability-and-asset adjusted--what we need to know
are the relative rejection rates for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> and white of the same degree of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">loanworthiness</ENAMEX>.

            Back to that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> lead for a moment: it features something "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today</ENAMEX>'s
Papers" applauds and would like to see more of: a clear explanation of the
motivations of the story's unidentified <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> who regarded the
abandoned leads as the most promising in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and objected to what they
described as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> role in squelching them." (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> generally
makes more of an effort in this direction than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which usually
opts for leaving it at "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>.")

         
      
   
