
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nifty Sixty</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead reveals that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> planned to capture terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama</ENAMEX> bin
Laden. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the arrest of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing case and the issuance of an arrest warrant for a
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> attack. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times lead announces that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial crisis means real trouble
for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy.

            Citing a senior government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reveals that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> planned a raid to capture bin Laden in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, but did not execute
the mission for fear of heavy casualties. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence had evidence
connecting bin Laden to numerous terrorist plots and had been tracking him with
eaves-dropping and picture-taking satellites since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s quick
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">retaliation</ENAMEX> seems less bold considering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence felt a strike against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX> was justified prior to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 7</TIMEX> embassy bombings.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have made the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> arrests in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing case and that a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> are already in
custody) has been named in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> case. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s largest overseas
investigation in history" has successfully pieced together the details of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombings</ENAMEX> and now looks to uncover a vast terrorist conspiracy linked to bin
Laden.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">mayhem</ENAMEX> has gone global, and the
real danger lies in the possibility of a global depression. The piece cites
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>" who say that because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> refuses to bite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bullet</ENAMEX> and make
drastic efforts to stimulate its economy, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> as the world's last
hope of avoiding a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930s</TIMEX>-style depression that could continue for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> run front page articles on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>'s sixtieth home
run. The numbers speak for themselves: in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 142</NUMEX> games, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX> has reached
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">sixty</NUMEX> homers faster than both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Cardinals</ENAMEX>' game balls now contain bar codes so that home run balls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60</TIMEX>,
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61</TIMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> can be verified. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' recent front page coverage has not
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">mentioned McGwire</ENAMEX>'s controversial use of legal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Arts & Leisure</ENAMEX> piece tells the story behind the recent
revival of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orson Welles</ENAMEX>' last <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX> feature film, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Touch of Evil</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> was part of a small <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> who re-cut the film based on a newly
discovered <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">58</NUMEX>-page memo in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welles</ENAMEX>, who lost creative control over "Touch
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evil</ENAMEX>" half-way through its editing, describes his vision of the finished
product.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> Outlook piece, written by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fidelity</ENAMEX> Magellan Fund legend
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Lynch</ENAMEX>, argues that through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nine</NUMEX> recessions, a presidential assassination,
multiple wars, and numerous political scandals the stock market has increased
in value. Thus, one shouldn't get too upset over current banking crises and
foreign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fiscal mayhem</TIMEX> or even worry about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby-boomers</ENAMEX>' retirement and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>. Stocks increase in value because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> increase their
earnings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thankfully</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynch</ENAMEX> believes earnings will continue to rise over the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 20 years</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Akira Kurosawa</ENAMEX>, a story that
broke too late for the other papers' early editions. The "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Seven Samurai</ENAMEX>"
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, who died at home in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, was "widely regarded as
the world's greatest living film <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>." Kurosawa was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">88</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
