
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ach du</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX>!

            Everybody leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swissair</ENAMEX> crash. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> headlines emphasize the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX>' search for clues to its cause. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times headline is more graphic: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Bodies Recovered from Site of Jet</ENAMEX>
Crash." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> header is more chilling still: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Victims Expected</ENAMEX>
Crash," a reference to the discovery--reported by all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>--that many of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX> were found wearing life vests.

            The papers report that there are no indications thus far of foul play.
Everybody reports that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> before perishing, the flight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> radioed that
it had smoke in the cockpit, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> explains that this came either
from the engines, the cargo hold or a short circuit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was given an overhaul, the
Post adding that the aircraft featured cargo holds offering the greatest
possible degree of fire detection and suppression. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also reports
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> disappeared from radar screens at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">8,000 feet</NUMEX>, suggesting that it
may have begun to break up, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">searchers</ENAMEX>' sonar
readings indicate that a large piece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX>, perhaps the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fuselage</ENAMEX>--which would contain many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX> and also the flight
recorders--is sitting intact in <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">about 120 feet</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>. This would mean,
explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swissair</ENAMEX> Flight 111 did not explode. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> concurs.

            Everybody notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only a few minutes</TIMEX> away from its
emergency destination at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Halifax</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nova Scotia</ENAMEX> when it crashed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
adds the detail that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> had actually gotten over land near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Halifax</ENAMEX> and
then returned over <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> to dump more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX>. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note that among the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doomed passengers</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Mann</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> program, several other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> who
worked on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>. ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> reports in its front section
cover story that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary General</ENAMEX> took the flight all the time.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> hit this information somewhat harder, with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead putting it in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> paragraph--although not mentioning
there that also dying was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mann</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX>, also a public health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX>.

            The fronts at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> all report on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s characterization by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Lieberman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
conduct in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal as "immoral and disgraceful."
Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX> didn't call for any specific punishment for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, the
papers view his remarks as high-impact because he made them on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor
and because he is, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's words, a "policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soul-mate</ENAMEX>" of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> fronting the story report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lieberman</ENAMEX>'s remarks
were immediately endorsed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Moynihan</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Kerrey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reveals that not
every <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> is taking things so seriously, quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockhart</ENAMEX>'s comment upon missing the presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ireland</ENAMEX>: "I take
responsibility for my own actions. I deeply regret it. I'm dealing with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> I hurt the most."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> continues to pursue a story it broke yesterday: the arrest by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natalie Liu</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX> television <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">producer</ENAMEX>, who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizen</ENAMEX>. After she was
taken away in handcuffs, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> searched her
apartment and confiscated notebooks, plus video and audio tapes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> has expressed concern to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>,
which has thus far refused to comment.

            In a front-page feature, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> takes note of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> apparent casualty
of the mushrooming world financial crisis: the prominent view of the past <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> that money should move freely around the globe. It seems that many
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> deep in economic turmoil will now be instituting limits on the
freedom of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> to lend and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> to borrow foreign currency. After
all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that most steadfastly resisted the
free-flow approach--<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>--stand out as least affected by the current
crisis. The problem is illustrated by the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX> and some
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Latin American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>: if foreign capital can come in easily, it can leave
easily too, driving up interest rates and pushing down local currency exchange
rates when it does so. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> also observes in its "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>
Wire" that the recent stock market jitters have probably suppressed enthusiasm
for privatizing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>.

            A letter to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> surveys some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> quotations that he would
just as soon not find their way into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bartlett</ENAMEX>'s, all taken from his deposition
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. The list includes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">71</NUMEX> instances of "I don't remember,"
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">62</NUMEX> of "I don't know," and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> of "I have no idea." All in all, the writer
figures, in his deposition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> admitted to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">267</NUMEX> memory lapses.

         
      
   
