
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blast Rites</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings lead all papers and dominate all fronts. (For
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">second day in a row</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> goes down in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>--completely off
everybody's fronts.) The respective lead headlines focus on various strands of
the story ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">U.S. Vows Bombers Will Pay</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">U.S. Teams Arrive in Nairobi: Blast Victims Mourned</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> :
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Experts Starting Search for Clues in Kenya Bombing"</ENAMEX>) but for the most part
everybody gets around to everything. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> exception is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead, which exclusively brings these
details: the likely <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb vehicle</ENAMEX> was turned away from the front gate of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> and sent around to the rear, where a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">grenade attack</ENAMEX> killed some
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> went off. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> both report that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> appears to have been on an embassy-owned water <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX>.

            The papers mention that a security camera at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> might have
been pointing right at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bomb site</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX>'s front gate, but all but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also mention that it is not known if the camera was recording to
video or just monitoring.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs an excellent news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> "cover story" on the beginnings of the
bombing investigation. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have been reporting that one focus so
far is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi Arabian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>, but this
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> story adds that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> to investigate arresting him.

            Everybody notes that the twelfth <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> identified was the consul
general at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nairobi Embassy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Bartley</ENAMEX>, whose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> also
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perished</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> that run photos feature the same top-front
shot of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenyans</ENAMEX> mourning and praying. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fourth</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
stacks a photo of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> and her young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX> who
rescued them over a shot of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> being loaded into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">vehicle</ENAMEX>, a
lifeless arm hanging out from under her shroud. The coverage reports that
besides the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">200</NUMEX> deaths in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly 5,000</NUMEX> people
were injured in the two explosions, the majority of them in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dog</ENAMEX>-assisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victim</ENAMEX> extraction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> working in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> continues
to get much coverage. The LAT front says that at a time when much of the
world is blaming <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> for the collapse of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> peace talks, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rescuers</ENAMEX>' efforts are boosting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s prestige and earning it goodwill.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-pager by media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX>
suggests that the story of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who died shortly after being told that her
insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> would only cover a bone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX> transplant if she had it in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> and not in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX> where she was--a managed-care horror story that has
been referred to by both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent weeks</TIMEX> and has also
been quoted by major media from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>--is of a piece with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cadillac</ENAMEX>-driving "welfare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX>." That is, writes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX>, there's more to the
story than appears in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clintonic</ENAMEX> version: namely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garvey</ENAMEX> ignored a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctor</ENAMEX>'s
advice to come in for blood tests and instead went on vacation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, where
the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> did not perform bone <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">marrow</ENAMEX> transplants. And the health plan
sent a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> to accompany <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garvey</ENAMEX> back to a suitable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that according to the latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Dept.</ENAMEX> figures, the economy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> suffered the biggest loss of
factory jobs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16 years</TIMEX>, a clear sign, says the paper, that the manufacturing
sector is sputtering. The main cause is apparently the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial crisis,
which has left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in the region unable to afford <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> goods.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> also runs a front-page feature about a hot topic in dry-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as</NUMEX>-dust <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Antonio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX>: who uses
inordinate amounts of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">lawns</ENAMEX>. Seems that in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Alamo-town</ENAMEX>, one of
the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> has taken to running the names, addresses, house descriptions
and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> usage amounts of the top <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> lawn waterers. The listees are generally
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rich</ENAMEX>--they have included over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the years</TIMEX> basketball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">star</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Robinson</ENAMEX> and
country <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">singer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Strait</ENAMEX>--and don't much like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cat</ENAMEX>-calling and
fist-shaking (and hate mail) listing exposes them to. A recent honoree soaked
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up 173</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">559 gallons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one month</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than ten</NUMEX> times the city
average. No wonder <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of those on the latest list persuaded the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> water
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> to withhold their names.

         
      
   
