
   
   
      
         
            Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Head</ENAMEX> Case

            Everybody has their own idea about the lead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">single-month</TIMEX> record level of sales of new single-family <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a major new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> military assault on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, a
story not on anybody else's early edition front. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> off-lead is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s arrival in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> and his anticipated contact with
ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> there. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">legislature</ENAMEX>'s passage of a bill protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 40</TIMEX> from being
replaced by younger and hence lower-paid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> purely on grounds of age. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with the decision by
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Baltimore</ENAMEX> to make a joint bid for hosting the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2012</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympics</ENAMEX>. But both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> give prime above-the-fold space to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>.

            If the pace of new home sales persists, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>'s totals will
be a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35-year</TIMEX> high. Low mortgage rates, dipping below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-year</TIMEX>
fixed-rates, are cited as a key factor. The <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Times Bosnia dispatch</ENAMEX>, by
blue-chip foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">correspondent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Hedges</ENAMEX>, describes an increasingly serious
situation: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> backed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">artillery</ENAMEX> and tanks
pressing into the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> surrounding a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> pocket. The area is
described, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hedges</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX> as "the most dangerous
place in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>." Angry heavily armed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">civilians</ENAMEX>, many of whom say they
had been pushed out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> recently by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>, appear to
be gathering to reenter their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> on the heels of the military assault. One
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly woman</ENAMEX> clutching a small bag of her belongings gives this situation
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>: "We have become <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>."

            The you-are-there feel of the story is upset only slightly by the
disorienting avalanche of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seussian</ENAMEX> place-names in such passages as: "The police
closed the main <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">road</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pec</ENAMEX> soon after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">dawn</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Policemen</ENAMEX> on the
road to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belacevac</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Obilic</ENAMEX>, northwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pristina</ENAMEX>, were..." The solution is
to move the map that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> runs inside to before the jump, where the first
geographical descriptions are encountered.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, continuing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">community leaders</ENAMEX>' roundtable in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Shanghai</ENAMEX> and an appearance on a radio call-in
show(wonder how long the delay is), as an "experiment in diplomacy as personal
performance," referring to the familiar campaign stump style <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> used in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> talks on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> national television. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story refers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">appeals</ENAMEX> in these appearances for the expansion of individual liberties and his
polite but unambiguous condemnation of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> crackdown, but
then says he's spent far more time flattering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> than
challenging them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also points out that his many <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last minute</TIMEX> speech
rewrites meant that translators couldn't adequately prepare, with the upshot
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s television <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audiences</ENAMEX> "missed large sections of his remarks." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lefty columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Scheer</ENAMEX> embraces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s talks, calling
them "a diplomatic feat of extraordinary proportions" of which "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> would
have been proud." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Cohen</ENAMEX> takes exception to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s repeated references to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese-American</ENAMEX> friendship, because
"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> are not <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts run reports of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s
arguments in federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil</ENAMEX>
Eggleston over whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s discussions with government lawyers
should be shielded from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eggleston</ENAMEX> cited
was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s discussions were part of a defense against possible
impeachment proceedings. Meanwhile, as these stories and the WP mention,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> will testify before the grand jury <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that
she is eager to dispel claims that she manipulated an unwitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, or that she made the tapes to get a book deal. "I did not cultivate
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>," she tells the paper, "she cultivated me." Maybe that's why in
preparation for her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> appearance, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Reliable</ENAMEX>
Source<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"</ENAMEX> column, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> had her hair cut and colored by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stylist</ENAMEX> who used to do
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s do.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column tells how federal
worker <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> continue to battle for pay matching the private sector, and cites
a current gap between the two calculated to be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">23 percent</NUMEX>. Surely there must be
something wrong in the figuring here: How many private sector <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> do you
know who can still make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$88,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> when they suddenly don't leave the house
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> can?

         
      
   
