
   
   
      
         
            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next Year</TIMEX> in an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Expanded Jerusalem</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s controversial plan to
expand <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>'s borders. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s call for
surveys to determine which cigarette brands underage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> prefer. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , prone to leading with financial
news, claims that while inflation remains down, prices for many products are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">zooming</ENAMEX> (to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumers</ENAMEX>' annoyance).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netanyahu</ENAMEX> wants to expand <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>'s borders,
"strengthening" the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">majority</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>, and increasing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s
tax base. The unilateral gerrymandering move goes sharply against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> wishes, and all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> agree this further jeopardizes the peace
process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> calling this a "declaration
of war on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> presence" in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX>. Many soon-to-be-annexed
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jewish</ENAMEX> neighborhoods protested the higher taxes they'll pay once encompassed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX>'s borders. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> adds that some of these <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Jews</ENAMEX> had earlier
fled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jerusalem</ENAMEX> to escape its heavily orthodox culture.) While the other papers
all put the story out front and above the fold, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> oddly buries it
on page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A22</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead, in tune with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s heavier focus on domestic
politics, covers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plan to keep <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> stats on which tobacco brands
are most popular with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minors</ENAMEX>. The executive order directs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health and Human Services</ENAMEX> to survey <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> aged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 through 17</TIMEX>, salvaging a
provision that was originally in the failed tobacco bill. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees
the move as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) image bolstering for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) "a useful way to put public
pressure on the [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> all leave the story off their front pages.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says both inflation and the Consumer Price Index are low
and steady, but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> are still griping about high prices. How can this be?
The CPI averages costs for "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of goods and services," and most
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">essentials</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cars</ENAMEX>) are fairly cheap. But prices in the service sector
("the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extras</ENAMEX> in life") are quickly rising. Among commonly complained-about
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">overcharges</ENAMEX>: video rentals, legal fees, theme <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">park</ENAMEX> admissions, and pay phone
rates (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to 35 cents</NUMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a quarter</NUMEX>).

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> covers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s troubled foray
into the cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX>'s eagerly awaited <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX> is far
behind schedule and still not ready, largely because of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nitpicking</ENAMEX> specs. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">boat</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">builders</ENAMEX> claim <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Disney</ENAMEX> requires ridiculously costly
and unnecessary guidelines for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>'s structure, and on-board decoration
involves hand-painted murals incurring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> of work.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> run front-page stories on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2-1</ENAMEX>
defeat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, marking both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s first-ever <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> victory and the
elimination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> from the tournament. Everyone agrees that the
politically heated match was marked by excellent sportsmanship from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">players</ENAMEX> on both sides. So sporting was the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ,
that it handed its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">opponents</ENAMEX> not only trinkets of goodwill, but also the match
itself.

         
      
   
