
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie</ENAMEX> and Slide

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> drop in the value of
the ruble against the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> mark after <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s central bank halted ruble
purchases of dollars. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> also gives much prime space to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> free-fall, running besides a news story on developments, a front-page
feature on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> barter economy, and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece on
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s plans for the upcoming summit with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s top
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> have reached virtually unanimous agreement that he must say
more publicly about his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, a tack so far
resisted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Family</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s taking a legal step that could lead to the appointment
of an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> to look into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s fund-raising role in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">1996 Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> campaign, which is also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's off-lead. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurricane Bonnie</ENAMEX> as it comes ashore, a story that garners
considerable text and picture front coverage everywhere.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> tells of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> lining up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> nationwide to withdraw
their savings, and captures the spirit on those <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sidewalks</ENAMEX> with quotes from a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">76-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">widow</ENAMEX> who says she lost her life savings once before during a
currency reform. She was unable to get her money <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> because many banks
are now limiting withdrawals to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> a day. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says this isn't
everybody's plight though: most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> keep their savings in dollars under
their mattresses, and many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bankers</ENAMEX> are making a killing speculating in foreign
currency. Some of this speculation, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , has been done with
money lent by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> quotes a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> advisor
saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is "now going into a kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX> crisis." The paper
also foresees a rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anti-Americanism</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , in its
off-lead on the crisis, continues to paint the picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s financial
barons sinking economic reform--with its aims of collecting back taxes and
allowing money-losing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> to go under--and reasserting their power.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> are convinced of
the need for another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> moment because they're concerned about more
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> taking flight from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the paper notes that
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> brought distancing comments from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Feingold</ENAMEX> and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic Action</ENAMEX>. Possible forums being kicked around include a
speech <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on school violence or an upcoming breakfast meeting with religious
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says another decidedly less contrite tack under
consideration, also reported inside by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , is for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
to get a courtesy early copy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report and then pre-emptively issue
its own report.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts carry word of the resignation of a hard-nosed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s
weapons inspection <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Ritter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ritter</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> released a
resignation letter in which he charged that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration had blocked the work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>, who were "on the
doorstep" of uncovering <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s hidden weapons efforts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, denies the accusation, but they also confirm
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have admitted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> urged the team
not to hold surprise inspections. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> broke the
story of secret administration resistance to inspections (a provenance not
mentioned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ), follows up hard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with a report of at least
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> such interventions. A column on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ritter</ENAMEX> resignation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Hoagland</ENAMEX> claims, citing impartial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
inspection effort went so far as to include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>'s successful undoing of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ritter</ENAMEX> plan to deliver to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> 120 prohibited <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> missile gyroscopes
earmarked for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a front-pager on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tomahawked Sudan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> that bears
watching. An international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> charged with overseeing chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> bans
says the substance cited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> as a conclusive identifier of nerve gas
production could possibly be used for commercial products, such as fungicides
or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticides</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> reached by the paper responds that academic
examples of possible non-nerve-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> use are not examples of such actual
commercial use. Another expert quoted in the piece says that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> soil
samples were, as is likely, not collected or tested under ideal laboratory
conditions, a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pesticide</ENAMEX>-related soil sample could be mistaken for a
nerve-gas-related one.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial and an op-ed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Herbert</ENAMEX> call for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX> to stop taking androstenedione, for the sake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> who watch his
every move. The front-page of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section reports that sales
of the stuff could exceed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
The story reports that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Marts</ENAMEX> sell the product, as does Weider
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nutrition</ENAMEX>, where sales are up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent just</NUMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX> story broke.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Nutrition Centers</ENAMEX> don't sell it though. Ads for the product will soon
be placed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muscle & Fitness</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESPN Magazine</ENAMEX>
and... USAT .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> admits that it was mistaken when it said previously that the
farewell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Postal Service</ENAMEX> threw for its recently departed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Postmaster General</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin T. Runyon</ENAMEX>, cost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$82,508</NUMEX>. Actually, it was
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$124,397</NUMEX>.

         
      
   
