
   
   
      
         
            Sub-atomic <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mass Hysteria</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s refusal to fast-track the legal battle between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> leads all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. The life sentence without the
possibility of parole handed to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> bombing figure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Nichols</ENAMEX> draws
front-page coverage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> puts it on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> was expected to be put
away for keeps unless he spoke to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in a particularly informative or
remorseful way, but he made no statement. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> say
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX>, called an "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">enemy</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Constitution</ENAMEX>" by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, displayed no
emotion. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that upon entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX>, he broke into
tears. As in previous key <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> bombing proceedings, no statements rivaled
in power those of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> who saw many dead babies
at the bombing site testified that whenever "I see these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> with empty
arms, I wonder, was that your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX> I kissed on his way to heaven<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX>"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s decision to return the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> case issues of attorney-client
and protective privilege back to the regular appeals court process is generally
taken as a rebuff for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s contention that these matters pose a
constitutional crisis of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> magnitude. There is more divergence about
what this does to the course of the case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that this might
keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> from questioning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> until "well into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>." But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme</ENAMEX>
Court might well end up hearing the case "by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">month</TIMEX>'s end."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" fascinates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> with a story of
breakthrough genetic research being done in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iceland</ENAMEX>. It seems that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iceland</ENAMEX>
provides the best database in the world for trying to isolate genes responsible
for such scourges as <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">Alzheimer's</ENAMEX>, adult-onset <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">stroke</ENAMEX>. That's because <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iceland</ENAMEX> has an incredibly homogenous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, further
"culled" by a plague and a natural disaster, and keeps excellent medical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">records</ENAMEX> (including a tissue sample from every autopsy conducted in the country
since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s</TIMEX>). This research environment has, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , lured
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geneticist</ENAMEX> away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Medical School</ENAMEX> and enabled him to get
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> in underwriting from drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hoffman-La Roche</ENAMEX>. The project is set
to sell public stock shares within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year</TIMEX> and if the science pays off, could
end up worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX>. Some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> are calling this exploitative "bio-piracy,"
but, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, any effective treatments it creates will be dispensed
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Icelanders</ENAMEX> for free.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that in the
wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> nukefest, a new buzzword is making the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>
rounds: "rogue <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">democracies</ENAMEX>." And in a WP op-ed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen S. Rosenfeld</ENAMEX> makes an important
point about this new leg of the arms race. Previously, it had generally been
held that non-proliferation could be secured via providing for the security
needs of the nuclear have-nots, but, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenfeld</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> didn't
really build their bombs to address security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX>. (When was the last time
before all this that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kashmir</ENAMEX> made the front page?) No, he writes, they went
overtly nuclear to achieve status . And when poor self-esteem is the root
problem, conventional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medicine</ENAMEX> doesn't work. It takes large doses of
"diplomatic therapy," which will, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosenfeld</ENAMEX> writes, "take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> fronts herald the discovery that
the sub-atomic particle called a neutrino, which is chargeless and was formerly
thought massless too, in fact has mass. The papers assure us this is
earth-shaking. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Universe May Never Be the Same</ENAMEX>" is slugged over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT Universe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Browne</ENAMEX>'s dispatch. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> says
the discovery was announced by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">120</NUMEX> physicists at a "neutrino conference."
Hoo-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boy</ENAMEX>, bet the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bartenders</ENAMEX> and hookers go on vacation during that one.

         
      
   
