
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr Crossed</ENAMEX>

            Everybody leads with a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s dismissal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> of the tax fraud
case recently filed against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster Hubbell</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> headlines put the matter flatly, speaking
only of the dismissal itself. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
headline goes further, stating, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hubbell Ruling Hurts Starr on Whitewater</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes further still, with the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Slap at Starr, a Judge Dismisses</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hubbell Tax Case</ENAMEX>," and a second front-page piece flagged "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">New Rebuke, And</ENAMEX>
Harsher."

            The federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Robertson</ENAMEX>, whom all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">appointee</ENAMEX>, ruled that in pursuing the tax case against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> exceeded
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authority</ENAMEX> and strayed too far from his original mandate of investigating
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arkansas</ENAMEX> real estate investments. Additionally, ruled the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> turned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> into an informant against himself in basing the tax
charges on records that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX> provided to him under a grant of immunity. The
view of some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> that the ruling was a quite personal assessment of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is based in large measure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s description of this records
seizure as "the quintessential fishing expedition."

            The papers note that the adverse ruling is the latest in a string of
setbacks for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>: his failed attempt to eradicate the postmortem
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer-client</ENAMEX> privilege, the death of cooperating <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James McDougal</ENAMEX>, the
release from <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">jail</ENAMEX> of the non-cooperating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan McDougal</ENAMEX>, and his failure thus
far to delve into communications between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>-supplied
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> or into the observations made of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> detail.
Most of the stories get a little lost among all these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">trees</ENAMEX>, with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> alone in high up clearly sighting the forest: the ruling will
probably "make it more difficult for [<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>] to obtain evidence of alleged
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminal</ENAMEX> wrongdoing by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">First Lady Hillary Rodham Clinton</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubbell</ENAMEX>'s former law
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">partner</ENAMEX>. But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>, the ruling doesn't
affect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> branch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s inquiry.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> taped an interview for play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> television in which
he signaled to ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> his support of continued greater
personal freedom and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has no wish to
impose its will on their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> piece inside says the show
that will run the interview, the popular state-owned news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily</ENAMEX>
Focus," resembles "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">60 Minutes</ENAMEX>" in that it features hard-hitting investigations
(mostly of local, not national <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>) unthinkable just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years ago</TIMEX>. Two
differences though, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> : the program has an audience
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, and young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A few weeks</TIMEX> back, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reported that a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in the advanced
throes of childbirth asked for an epidural anesthetic to relieve her pain, only
to be told by the attending <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX> that she couldn't have one unless she paid
for it on the spot. The suffering <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> offered to write a check or use a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">credit</ENAMEX> card, but no, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurse</ENAMEX>, it had to be cash. So the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> went
without. Today, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s front reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> has apologized to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> and has promised the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> that it's instituting a
policy of epidural anesthesia to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> in labor on demand, regardless of their
ability to pay.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Business Bulletin" reports that the
growth of registered trademarks using such words as "cyber," "link," and "web"
was off <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> exceptions that remain on the rise are "tech"
and "power."

            In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Column Left</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Cockburn</ENAMEX> reports on a survey
recently filled out by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">141</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">journalists</ENAMEX>. Among the results: While <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">77</NUMEX>
percent of the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX> think too much power is in the hands of a few
large <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 57 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> asked think this. And for
information for a story on economic issues, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">over half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> usually
call someone in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31 percent</NUMEX> usually call someone in the
corporate sector. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Only 5 percent</NUMEX> contact someone in the labor movement.

            Back to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , visited a
housing development illustrating the very recent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> phenomenon of
privately owned <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">residences</ENAMEX>, and told <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> there that home ownership is an
investment in society, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> of middle-class life. Wonder if the
Times had trouble resisting the observation that it's an investment
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s never made, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bedrock</ENAMEX> he's never stood on.

         
      
   
