
   
   
      
         
            Broken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> Pieces

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s decision to stage mock air strikes soon over <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> targets
near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>, a story that also runs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times fronts, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> --which instead reserves prime front space
for new safety rules for <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">golf carts</ENAMEX>--doesn't get around to it until <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 8</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WP</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s defense of his decision to seek closer
relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mitsubishi</ENAMEX>'s decision to end a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> fight against federal sex harassment charges in a case concerning its
treatment of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">350</NUMEX> female <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> at an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> by agreeing to the
largest harassment settlement ever--<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$34 million</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes with the
outbreak of a sympathy strike at a second <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Flint</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan GM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17-day</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> strike, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says, ended up costing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900 million</NUMEX>, adding
that continuing strikes at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> could have effects throughout the economy.

            The point of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s simulated bombing and strafing raids, to be conducted next
a taste of the power that could be turned on him if he persists in attacks on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>." It is not known, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> writes, if the "aerial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sabre</ENAMEX>-rattling" will actually employ live <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ammo</ENAMEX> or real bombs.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> says, "choosing isolation over engagement would not make the world
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">safer</ENAMEX>; it would make it more dangerous." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Bauer</ENAMEX> of the conservative <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family</ENAMEX>
Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> offers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> this response: "He's setting up a false
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dichotomy</ENAMEX>. He's claiming that the debate is between a policy of engagement and
a policy of isolationism, when in fact the debate is about what kind of
engagement we're going to have." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs this on the front, while
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> put it inside.

            With the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic crisis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly a year old</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> surveys the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GDPs</ENAMEX> in the region and concludes that the situation is now the most serious
region-wide recession since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. And although thus far, the impact on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy has been negligible, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> sees warning signs:
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>-focused <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anemic</ENAMEX> earnings, and an overall decline in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exports. The stock market sees this too--<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> worries are widely credited
for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s big Dow drop, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, anxious to bolster their case
for a large tax cut <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, are pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' budget forecasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">arm</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX>, to produce rosier estimates of future surpluses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
honchos are exercised over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX>'s longstanding overstatement of the budget
deficit and its recent understatement of the budget surplus. The story reports
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> would like to see a change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBO</ENAMEX>'s forecasting
models and probably some new faces over there too.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that financial
settlements have been reached in a case in which without permission or
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sanction</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America Online</ENAMEX> identified to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX> an active-duty
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sailor</ENAMEX> whose on-line profile suggested he was gay. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>, which on the basis
of the disclosure had originally tried to expel the sailor, has agreed to allow
him to retire with full benefits and will pay his legal fees. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AOL</ENAMEX>, which
with the disclosure violated the terms of its own service agreement, has
apologized to him and agreed to pay him damages. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">sailor</ENAMEX> has declined to
discuss his sexual orientation, and so the coverage of the story has dwelt on
the electronic privacy issue, but this episode is also relevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>'s
"Don't Ask, Don't Tell" policy. The whole thing started when a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> saw
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s email profile mentioned his hobby of "collecting pictures of
other young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">studs</ENAMEX>" and that his screen-name was "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boysrch</ENAMEX>." So here's the
unpursued question: Does such information count as "telling"? If not, then
telling has nothing to do with what common sense could easily and
non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">investigatively</ENAMEX> arrive at concerning another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX>'s sexual orientation,
and hence has nothing to do with protecting unit cohesion, which could easily
be upset by such readily-arrived-at information. But on the other hand, if so,
then the current superficially more tolerant policy immediately reduces to the
old intrusive <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, because investigations would become so easy to set into
motion.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The New Republic</ENAMEX> 's
post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX> post-mortem, which concluded that all or part of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">27</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41</NUMEX> pieces <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX> did for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TNR</ENAMEX> were
fabricated. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> segues into doubt about the effectiveness
of fact-checking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>. But a quick look at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s letters to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX>
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> suggest that here at least is one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX> of the paper
that could use a little more fact-checking. A Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald N. S. Unger</ENAMEX>, in
criticizing a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> pitch for anti-missile <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, refers to
how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aegis</ENAMEX> missile system shot down an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX> during the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gulf</ENAMEX> war,
mistaking it for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Mig</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighter plane</ENAMEX>. Actually, the shoot-down took place three
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> and occurred because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airbus</ENAMEX> was mistaken for an
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Iranian F-14</ENAMEX>. So the question arises: Do letters just go straight into the
paper without being checked? And if so, isn't this just as bad as a similar
laxity with regard to articles?

         
      
   
