
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bloody Saturday</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with new terror in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ireland</ENAMEX>: a car bomb exploded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> in a crowded shopping area in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omagh</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">town</ENAMEX> west of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belfast</ENAMEX>, killing <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and injuring <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> more.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , which runs the story at the fold,
calls it "the single worst terrorist incident in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 30-year</TIMEX> history of
sectarian warfare" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>. For its lead the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> turns to a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-story spread on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s upcoming grand jury testimony. The
banner lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> think he will revise his story for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s testimony--i.e. he will admit to sexual relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, but will not admit to perjury.

            The terrible toll in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> bombing was partly due to a
misleading warning about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>'s location. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">caller</ENAMEX> warned of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> near
the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Omagh</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX> actually exploded in an area where the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">crowds</ENAMEX> had retreated to get away from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>. Prominent among the early
suspects is a radical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irish Republican Army</ENAMEX> "splinter <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>" which opposes the
peace agreement between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> that was ratified <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last May</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> state early on that the explosion may
jeopardize the peace agreement, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> paragraph
that "local <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> insisted that the tragedy . . .
would not block implementation" of the agreement.

            Back in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scandalworld</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead, while suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may
testify to a sexual relationship, also notes that he is prone to last-minute
changes of mind and could go against his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX>' recommendations. Another
piece in the WP front-page package describes the intense legal
preparation on both sides. Strategizing aside, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony
hinges on his "own lonely struggle over whether to admit a relationship with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> despite his past denials." The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> WP piece chronicles
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s ability to cope with adversity. In related news, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
off-lead explains how the scandal could shift election-year politics: if
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' disgust translates into low voter turnout, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> will
probably suffer. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> front-pager recaps the long list of legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">precedents</ENAMEX> set in the case.

            Trouble in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX> gets front-page play at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and runs inside
elsewhere. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> there was closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, and the last <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> were evacuated as the teetering <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Congoese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> prepares to
counter advances from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX>-backed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rebels</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> adds this to the
story: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> (including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">some 1,200</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX>) are taking up
positions near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX>'s coast in order to rescue <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX> if necessary. The
Congoese take an understandably dim view of this move--very few <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreigners</ENAMEX>
remain in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Congo</ENAMEX>.

            Front page pieces at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report new developments in
the search for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African</ENAMEX> bombings. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX>, citing federal law-enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>, says that an associate of
wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> exile and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama Bin Laden</ENAMEX> has been
"tentatively linked" to the bombings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's
front-page story pursues another angle: A bombing suspect was arrested on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> border while travelling under a false passport, and is
being flown to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> for questioning.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week in Review</ENAMEX>" article urges the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to develop a
consistent, long-term policy to combat terrorism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>, a long-time
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX>, observes that, "Most of our counter-terrorism successes
are against loners." He decries quick fixes such as assassination because they
either backfire by perpetuating the cycle of violence or aren't comprehensive
enough. A better strategy, he argues, would involve gradually undermining and
weakening <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bases</ENAMEX>.

            According to a below-the-fold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page article, some
heavyweight web sites like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geocities</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lycos-Tripod</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ticketmaster</ENAMEX> have
agreed to feed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subscriber</ENAMEX> information to a tracking system. This information
will then be sold to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">advertisers</ENAMEX>, who can tailor their marketing strategies
accordingly. While this does not violate individual anonymity per se, the
prospect irks privacy-rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">activists</ENAMEX>. Their battle may be tough, however,
since privacy regulations on the Internet remain notoriously nebulous.

         
      
   
