
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tax Consultants of Swat</ENAMEX>

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first day in months</TIMEX> you'll have time to read the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> and they barely
put them out. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister candidate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s no-duh on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">national</ENAMEX> television that, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' words, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> "has entered a
fiscal nosedive and that further political squabbling could lead to social
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">chaos</ENAMEX>," a story that also makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times front, but which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> front bumps for pro football and model
trains. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads with word that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX> may extradite an accused
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">teenager</ENAMEX> to suburban <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> in a local murder case. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead is
that the job is becoming the primary focus of many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>'s lives.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the night</TIMEX> before his
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> attempt to win confirmation as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PM</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> used his TV address to defend and further explain the economic
platform he rolled out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>: printing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions of rubles</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX> to pay for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>', civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>' and defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>' back wages and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pensions</ENAMEX> and to save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, and cutting the profits tax by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> and then
in just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few months</TIMEX>, strictly controlling the currency, collecting taxes and
cutting government spending. The program has quickly been criticized, says the
Times , as "party-now, pay-later." The big fear is that the policy could
lead to hyperinflation, and indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> points out that
hyperinflation may have already arrived, with the ruble now <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times cheaper
than it was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX>. In a separate TV appearance, says the paper, the
acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">deputy prime minister</ENAMEX> advocated making the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dollar once again legal
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX> tender.

            The LAT <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> story emphasizes in its headline and in its text
right from the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> paragraph his view that fascism awaits if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
political stalemate continues. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story never mentions the word,
although in the nineteenth paragraph of its story, well after the jump, it
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">quotes Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s envisioning the possibility that "someone would want to
enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kremlin</ENAMEX> on a white <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX>." Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story emphasizes
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C</ENAMEX>'s angry attack in his speech on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>, a criticism
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> never mentions.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front pager details a sure sign of the tightest
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> labor market in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thirty years</TIMEX>--the upswing in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> looking for new
hires in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> prison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>. (The emphasis is on non-violent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">felons</ENAMEX>.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that one <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Texas</ENAMEX> construction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 150</NUMEX>
ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">approximately 85 percent</NUMEX> of those working out.
And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirage Resorts</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> has hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX>,
mostly young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> coming out of a state-run boot <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX>, for jobs in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">landscaping</ENAMEX>, flower arranging, and maintenance and custodial work. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mirage</ENAMEX> has
hired a probation <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> to monitor the ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmates</ENAMEX> and to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">co-workers</ENAMEX> deal
with discomfort--a big problem, apparently. Another: most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that
have plunged into the ball-and-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chain</ENAMEX> talent pool don't hire many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>.

            The story of burgeoning trouble between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s
lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , has dropped off the fronts altogether, but still gets
inside coverage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that a leading <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> newspaper says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commander in chief</ENAMEX> has ruled out a military confrontation.
(This isn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> paper's top story, which is: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Job Becoming The Primary</ENAMEX>
Focus Of Many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">People's</ENAMEX> Lives.") But, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , tension between the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> remains high over the status of twelve missing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranians</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> was preparing to send <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 35,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>
into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. Today, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> suggests that there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 70,000</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iranian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> operating near the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> border. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also floats the
70K <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troop</ENAMEX> estimate and offers an explanation for why <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> may be hesitant to
fight <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>--its suffering during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> war.

            According to a wry piece in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Dedman</ENAMEX>, if you're a
baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> who's taking a glove to <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">games</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX> in hopes of catching
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sosa</ENAMEX>'s or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX>'s record-breaking home run ball, you might think about taking
your tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> along too. If you catch the ball and sell it, well obviously,
you owe capital gains tax on the proceeds--which, given estimates that the
magic ball could fetch upwards of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>, means a check to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> for
nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX>. You could lower your capital gains tax by holding on to the
ball for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least a year</TIMEX>, which would drop your tax bill to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$280,000</NUMEX>. But
suppose out of a love for <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">baseball</ENAMEX>, you decide to just give the ball to
the new home run <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>. Well, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> explains, then the federal gift
tax applies. Giving the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">million-dollar</NUMEX> ball away would mean a tax bill of about
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150,000</NUMEX>. If the fan keeps the ball, he or she would avoid tax until death, at
which time it would be a taxable part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>'s estate. The only way to
avoid tax entirely is to give the ball to charity, which could then sell the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ball</ENAMEX> at a profit without paying any tax. (<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">And, Today's Papers</ENAMEX> notes, if the fan
could arrange to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">charity</ENAMEX> then sell the ball to the new home <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">king</ENAMEX>, he
would accomplish his original philanthropic goal while beating the tax <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>.)
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> observes that it remains to be seen if the "new,
customer-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> has the chutzpah to try to collect the tax from, say, a
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twelve</NUMEX>-year-old baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
