
   
   
      
         
            Arrested Development

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads continue reports on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>
shootings while digging deeper into the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX>'s troubled past. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s latest gift for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal</ENAMEX> grand jury
subpoena.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> describes Russell "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rusty" Weston Jr.</ENAMEX> as a mentally disturbed
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">loner</ENAMEX> who, when not panning for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gold</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Montana</ENAMEX> streams, raved about his ties
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedys</ENAMEX> and being betrayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports
that the wounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gunman</ENAMEX>, who has a "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">50-50</NUMEX>" chance of survival, has been charged
with murder and could receive the death penalty. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note the reopening
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Capitol</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> after the shootings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> alone specifies the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">shooter</ENAMEX>'s mental illness as paranoid <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> confirms that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has been subpoenaed to appear
before a Federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>--a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> ever for a sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX>
continue negotiating to avoid subjecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sans attorney</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX>'
questions. While legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholars</ENAMEX> can't agree whether <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can be forced to
testify, certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> have agreed publicly that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> should
answer the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>'s inquiries well before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> elections.

            Plans to arrest <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bosnia</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most wanted war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">criminals</ENAMEX> have been scrapped,
according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front page piece. Cold-footed <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and
fear that arrests would provoke further <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> aggression undermined the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $100 million</NUMEX> spent on training and surveillance in prepararation
for the roundup. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> does not explain why <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> were
needed to track <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> later described as easy to find.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front page story reports on the acknowledgment of former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">South</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African 'coloreds</ENAMEX>' that they are indeed black. Many apartheid-era blacks
claimed mixed ancestry in order to avoid more severe restrictions, often
changing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> names and falsifying birth records. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cynics</ENAMEX> cite the opportune
timing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coloreds</ENAMEX>' rediscovered blackness now that the black-majority
government has instituted policies helping those who faired worst under
apartheid.

            The WP takes a look at exploited immigrant high tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> on its
front. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> temporary visas for foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> can pay
them less and work them harder. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> need new visas to change jobs and
face stiff fines for doing so. Moreover, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> dangle green cards in front
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> working under the federally legislated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX> salary cap just to
keep them honest.

            The always <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>-conscious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports on a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> dilemma: whether
to advise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> infected with the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> virus to stop breast-feeding. Cultural
and medical considerations include fears that non-infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mothers</ENAMEX> will
discontinue breast-feeding and the danger of formula mixed under unsanitary
conditions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> statistics show that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a quarter</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>-to-child
transmissions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX> virus occur from breast-feeding.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NYT Week in Review</ENAMEX> piece questions the wisdom of recent attempts to
align the values of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> with the rest of society. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defender</ENAMEX> of
separate military culture opines, "We shouldn't be running the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military</ENAMEX> like a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">college</ENAMEX> campus." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Papers wonders if an inner-city high school
might prove a more effective model.

         
      
   
