
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Principals Make Out</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> all lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">5</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX> ruling that
school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">districts</ENAMEX> may not be held responsible for sexual relations between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> unless school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> know about and fail to stop the
activity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> ruling its off-lead but goes its own way by leading with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s order of sweeping new protections for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">recipients</ENAMEX> that will require private health plans treating them to guarantee
access to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>, the provision of translators when needed and medical
record confidentiality. The order also grants <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">beneficiaries</ENAMEX> the right
to obtain information about the financial condition of a private heath plan and
about how its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> are paid.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX> decision will make it much harder
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">student victims</ENAMEX> of sexual abuse and harassment to win damages. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> adds that this will be true even at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> that fail to establish
sexual harassment policies and fail to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> a way to complain about
abuses. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that in his dissent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul Stevens</ENAMEX>
said the decision gives school districts an incentive not to take steps to
protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead editorial says the decision "perversely
deprived" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> of an effective legal remedy. The
WP best communicates the scope of the ruling by eschewing in its lead sentence
the generality of "sexual abuse" ( LAT ) and "sexual relations"
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ) in favor of the concreteness of referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> who are
"sexually taunted, groped or harassed." Everybody points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
will be ruling soon on the similar question of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employer</ENAMEX> responsibilities
regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supervisors</ENAMEX>' sexual harassment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in a job setting. But there
is another bit of context missing from all accounts: what responsibilities the
law currently assigns to school districts with regard to other sorts of teacher
misconduct.

            In a story that's sure to develop in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> ahead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have evidence that before the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> put nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile warheads</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts report that the painkiller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Duract</ENAMEX> is
off the market after being implicated in the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and in the
liver damage suffered by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> others. The story is also flagged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>'s
front-page news box and runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> pulled the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> say the drug's
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">manufacturer</ENAMEX> took the action. The papers all observe this is the latest in a
string of prescription drug recalls, raising the issue of whether such drugs
are now being allowed to come to market too fast.

            The LAT front reports that at a time when <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX> has been taking
a softer line regarding <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>, a midget <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Korean</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">submarine</ENAMEX> of the
sort often used in spy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">missions</ENAMEX> has been captured off the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">South Korean</ENAMEX> coast.
The story runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            With stories inside, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> has agreed to sell <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">India</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> commercial nuclear power
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reactors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX> has already complained to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
government.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> main "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece, one of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s chief goals for his upcoming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine-day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">China</ENAMEX> trip, the first
by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Tiananmen Square</ENAMEX> massacre, is to get <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
back home to see via the television coverage that a changing modern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> can
be their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> and best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customer</ENAMEX>. That coverage, observes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ,
will be beamed by the very <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>-launched <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> satellites at the center of
the latest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> scandal.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that a legal tussle between a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bookstore</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> over a subpoena of records of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s
purchases there has been avoided: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has agreed to provide the information to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.
This is not, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has cooperated with
the independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>. She previously allowed her <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> to be searched
and provided handwriting samples.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column, a survey indicates
that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half</NUMEX> of all <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> feel insecure about their financial
future. On average, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">docs</ENAMEX> surveyed were worth <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than half a million</NUMEX>
dollars.

         
      
   
