
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sinister Prime Minister</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> all lead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>'s refusal to confirm
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> leads with a warning that individual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> may soon abandon the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> stock market.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> said it would not confirm acting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s choice for the job. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX> appeared to
have secured a deal to grant the parliament greater powers in exchange for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s confirmation. This deal was soon called off by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX>,
the most powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">parliament</ENAMEX>, who 1) feared that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> would not
uphold his side of the bargain, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> "an accomplice with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> in the destruction of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past years</TIMEX>." The raucous parliamentary debate
was carried on live <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> television but was knocked off the air, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> alone notes, by the broadcast of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvester Stallone</ENAMEX> film. A second
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">front-page NYT</ENAMEX> piece adds that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">about 25 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> "would still
support a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communist</ENAMEX> system of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>." A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> article
argues that the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> summit will feature <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> with
little power and little to offer each other. For each, just being seen with the
other could be a political liability.

            The WSJ lead claims that individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX>, the driving force of
the stock market, are starting to pull out. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's evidence seems
largely anecdotal, and the paper refers to "an important minority of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>" who are jumping <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">ship</ENAMEX>. Unlike <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last October</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">554</NUMEX>-point drop, the
piece argues, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investors</ENAMEX> do not view the recent decline as a "buying
opportunity." A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece says the current market woes could
"forecast" a recession: If <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> begin to doubt the worth of their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">investments</ENAMEX>, consumer spending might fall, hurting the economy. Possible
remedy: lower interest rates. The market watch is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ,
which notes that consumer spending "accounts for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX>."

            Everyone but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> gives front-page play to the continuing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Airlines</ENAMEX> pilot strike. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> has cancelled all flights through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> warns that high-traffic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day weekend</TIMEX> is imminent, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reefers a story about other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>' rush to steal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>'s
abandoned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. A funny <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">pager</NUMEX> examines the strike's
effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Grand Forks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Dakota</ENAMEX>, a remote town utterly dependent on
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>, which even delivers the mail. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Minneapolis</ENAMEX>, another <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> served
primarily by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>, will soon run out of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">flowers</ENAMEX> and fresh fish if the
strike does not end, claims a WSJ piece.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> all go front-page with the home
run chase. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago Cub</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Sosa</ENAMEX> hit his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">54th</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Cardinal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX> hit his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">55th</NUMEX> in the race to break the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX> record of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">61</NUMEX> home runs in a
season.

            A page A03 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story explains why more <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> aren't cannibals.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cannibalism</ENAMEX> simultaneously achieves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two ends</TIMEX> (finding food and killing off a
rival), so why isn't it more popular? <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Animals</ENAMEX> that feast on their own kind are
more likely to eat harmful <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">microbes</ENAMEX> than if they dined on a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>,
and thus they are more prone to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>. The article nicely characterizes
serial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX> (and cannibal) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Dahmer</ENAMEX> as having had "an unusually
consuming interest in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
