
   
   
      
         
            Prose and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cons</ENAMEX>

            Befitting a mid-summer news drought, the papers go their separate ways. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with internal dissension at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> about whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign fund-raising activities warranted an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freeh</ENAMEX> says yes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> says no. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX>'s hiring of
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">auditors</ENAMEX> to investigate spending from a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 billion</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> development
project fund after an internal check seemed to suggest kickbacks and
embezzlement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> battle over
competing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> bills regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HMOs</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, is making a rare congressional working visit to plump for
his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s bill, which unlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alternative</ENAMEX>, would strike down a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">25-year-old</TIMEX> ban against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> suing their health plans. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times front-page story with the most national impact is a federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>'s refusal to block <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s recent vote to eliminate long-term
bilingual education.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> vs. Free disagreement was discussed during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s appearance
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearings, but as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reminds the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> four
paragraphs in, it was already aired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> gets
excited enough by this virtual news to also offer a lead editorial and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> column backing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freeh</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is much calmer--calling the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearing "a familiar scene," and putting it on <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 7</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Bank</ENAMEX> investigation apparently encompasses, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , kickbacks possibly received by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> supervising a water
project in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Algeria</ENAMEX>, possible misuse of a fund set up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> government
to subsidize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX> staff expenses, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>-funded efforts in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have been notified that they are under
investigation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> as saying, "So the
question is 'Are we clean?' and it's not clear.."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's off-lead is that a federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> will not
prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> detail from being forced
to testify about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. Indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that the judge
"harshly chastised" the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> for continuing to fight <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> on
this point. So Special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Agent</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Cockell</ENAMEX> might be at the federal courthouse
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> to answer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s questions, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cockell</ENAMEX>
may be advised not to show up. Apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> is interested in asking Cockell
about what he heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s discussion with his private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bennett</ENAMEX> in the limo on the way back from the deposition he gave on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 17</TIMEX> for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> suit. Of course, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> notes, this means that
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockell</ENAMEX>'s testimony turns on, not just "protective privilege" but also on
attorney-client privilege, and hence it seems that there will be much more
court wrangling before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockell</ENAMEX> issue is resolved.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" reports on an interesting conflict between
medicine and the law. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most common causes of death in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attack</ENAMEX> and in most attacks there is only a window of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">ten minutes</TIMEX> to save
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">victim</ENAMEX>'s life. So it would seem obvious that the advent of the portable
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defibrillator</ENAMEX>--an electrical shock device that does just the trick in an
overwhelming percentage of cases--would be a universally accepted godsend.
Given, for instance, that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">heart attacks</ENAMEX> occur at home, wouldn't
it be great if defibrillators were as common as portable fire extinguishers?
Well, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> tells it, the trial lawyers don't think so, because
they don't like exempting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bystanders</ENAMEX> who use the devices from possible
lawsuits. The cops aren't crazy about them, because they fear this will lead to
a distraction from their primary law enforcement role, and besides they don't
want to get sued. And there's the fear that improper use of the machines can
*cause<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">* heart attacks</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a dozen</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> still prohibit lay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from using the
machines.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs a completely positive account of the productive and
powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partnership</ENAMEX> that has developed between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>, especially regarding international <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s issues such as the
handling of rape charges at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rwanda War Crimes Tribunal</ENAMEX>, and clamping down
on the international prostitution trade. So what does it say about the First
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lady</ENAMEX> that for this article she not only declined to be interviewed but even
declined to answer written questions?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> receive
a steady stream of requests for free books from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoners</ENAMEX>, which they
frequently honor. The article reports that self-help titles are among the most
requested, but doesn't explain the point of mailing out "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Seven Habits of</ENAMEX>
Highly <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Effective People</ENAMEX>" to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guys</ENAMEX> on death row.

         
      
   
