
   
   
      
         
            Reign of Terror

            The front-page spotlight remains on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX> in the aftermath of
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> bombings at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX>. Even as the search through the rubble
continues, the still-rising death toll is at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">149</NUMEX> (including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">12</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>),
according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , which gives the highest figure.

            The lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> details the launching of an organized
international rescue operation, replacing the heroic but chaotic efforts to
date. A contingent of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX>--whom the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> peculiarly characterizes
as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> in rescuing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> from destroyed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">buildings</ENAMEX>"--arrived in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> and quickly took charge. Among their <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> moves: pulling a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenyan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">businessman</ENAMEX> out alive from the rubble. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> also cover the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Israeli</ENAMEX> rescue effort, but further down.

            All papers report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> have been overwhelmed by
treating the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4000-plus</NUMEX> wounded; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> devotes a separate inside
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> to the story. The biggest problems are blood shortages and dwindling
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">equipment</ENAMEX> and supplies. There was little reported progress in the search for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX>, though a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> quoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> who recalled
seeing a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> waiting in a pickup <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">alley</ENAMEX> behind the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassy</ENAMEX>, where the bomb exploded.

            The front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Sunday Report</ENAMEX>" looks into a prophetic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX> study dubbed "Terror <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>," which outlined potential terrorist
scenarios--including the targeting of a major <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>, which
happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months later</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Trade Center</ENAMEX> was bombed. Dubbed too
alarmist for their time, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> were "quietly buried," says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> .

            In other front-page news--rather, news of the front page--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> story
retreated inside for the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>. Savor it: she won't stay there
long.

            A mammoth article inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook</ENAMEX>" offers cautionary words for
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s model of partial privatization
ain't as great as it sounds. The system, instituted under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Thatcher</ENAMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-80s</TIMEX>, incurred higher than expected administrative costs, and triggered
a breakdown in consumer protection as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> invested in a smorgasbord of
incompetent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. ("<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Investors</ENAMEX> could even buy a pension from the big
supermarket <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">chains</ENAMEX>.") Though an insightful glimpse into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s struggles
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>, the article makes few links to the challenges facing
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>.

            How's this for a catchy lead--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Secret</ENAMEX> sells <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> times more size <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">32</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bras</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> than it averages in other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>" (from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p.</ENAMEX>
A18). Having been hooked by this line--and by a follow-up report that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> prefer ivory-colored undergarments to black ones by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>:<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> was
deeply disappointed to discover that the article was really about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Microstrategy</ENAMEX>, whose products help <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> sort
through their databases. How <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dreadfully mis lead ing</ENAMEX>!

         
      
   
