
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presidential State of the Unit</ENAMEX> Address

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with this morning's release of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s grand jury videotape. That story also runs on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times front--where the lead is a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX> election story--but below
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s survey of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s possible career moves (samples from
various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mavens</ENAMEX>: Go on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah</ENAMEX>, go on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Walters</ENAMEX>, don't go on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
having <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> led with the details of the tape that no one else had until
today, instead goes with a close-up tick-tock of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
decision to attack that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is braced for the simultaneous release of
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tape and the transcript of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s grand jury testimony,
what it calls "a high-stakes version of 'he said, she said.'" The WP
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">stresses White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief of Staff</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Podesta</ENAMEX>'s claim on "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet The Press</ENAMEX>"
(carried inside by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) that the tape's release will produce a
backlash against the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is pursuing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter. USAT
goes high with another "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Meet the Press</ENAMEX>" suggestion--by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>--that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> have a come-to-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>, but
goes out of the story only saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX> didn't reject <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">suggestion</ENAMEX>, whereas the LAT videotape story describes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>
reaction as "qualified support," quoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> as saying the idea is
"certainly worth considering." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> (in an
inside story) quote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>'s reasoning: "I believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> would be well
served to explain exactly what he did, exactly what he was thinking." Well no,
not exactly. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also mentions a new call for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s resignation,
from the newly crowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss America</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> material contains graphic details from
phone sex conversations between her and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. Actually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says
"alleged" phone sex conversations. But this is a silly ritualistic use--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
has admitted to the conversations.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that some senior administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> now
say their case for attacking the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> relied on inference as well as
evidence--a point the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> started raising within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of the raid and
has pressed harder than anyone else. The big news is that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> now has
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">unnamed CIA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Dept.</ENAMEX> honchos saying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> may have made a
mistake. The root problem, says the paper, is the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> on the ground in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s resultant reliance on
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least one</NUMEX> of whom turned out to fabricate his information,
which had been the basis for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> reports.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Outlook</ENAMEX>" worries that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to opt for bank reform legislation is "widely believed to be
too little, too late." It isn't clear, says the paper, that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX> have the political will required to implement the new law, nor that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> can do much more to influence the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s decision making. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> notes a crucial difference between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s other
economically ravaged <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> has no foreign debt and hence is free
from foreign dictates.

            A letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> raises an interesting point regarding the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's recent description of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> tactics in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> as
including "torture." What the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> do with IRA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX>, he writes, is not
the infliction of extreme physical pain, but the use of a hood along with food-
and sleep-deprivation. If this is "torture," then why, he wonders, wasn't this
term used in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>'s treatment of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing suspect, where precisely these deprivations were employed?

         
      
   
