
   
   
      
         
            Poll Tacks

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with its over-the-weekend poll indicating that
despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> revelations, the public's support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> remains rather
robust. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> 's off-lead provides its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> polling, with a similar upshot.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead also looks at the popular reaction, summing it up as revulsion at
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior, but reluctance to put the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> through impeachment.
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">USAT</ENAMEX> leads with the political reaction to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report, claiming
that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> there was "no ground swell" in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for impeachment,
although noting that prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> from both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> called for censure of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, (a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front-pager</ENAMEX> also notes the congressional
trend, while a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page story says this is becoming more
acceptable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp as well). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , once again flashing its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">command</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX> exits, leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Sosa</ENAMEX> hitting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> home runs to tie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> poll piece says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just over 7</NUMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> of those surveyed said the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report did not change their opinion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> (of course, by
itself, this means nothing, since they might have already thought he was an
intern-bonking Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hands</ENAMEX>). The poll also detects much public support for
censure--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Censure</ENAMEX> gets the nod from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's
sample. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-page story puts the censure rate at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly six</NUMEX> in
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX>. These polls suggest a clear majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> want <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to remain
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>--but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's finds that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> would favor impeachment if
it could be proved that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lied to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. Which is precisely what
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of those polled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> did. Wackiest stat:
<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> of the LAT sample say that after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> revelations, they
now view <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> more favorably. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> story puts the size of its
sample--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">968</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>--and its margin of error--<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX>--in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">seventh</NUMEX>
paragraph. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> puts its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterpart</ENAMEX> info--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">between 449 and 631</NUMEX> people
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> for various polls--in its last paragraph, the twelfth.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 25</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> have called for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s resignation. That number is added to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in a significant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's lead editorial says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should quit because "a president
who puts his interests above the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s cannot lead."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sosa</ENAMEX> home runs drove the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubs</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fans</ENAMEX> wild but in
contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">62nd</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, there was no ceremony and no comments
over the public address system. In its <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sosa</ENAMEX> off-lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> adds that
unlike with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX>'s record shots, baseball <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> had not put
identifying marks on the game balls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sosa</ENAMEX> hit out.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> inside piece reports that new <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">premier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX> has pledged to turn his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> towards a
"socially oriented economy," which is being taken by some <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformers</ENAMEX>
to mean a restoration of communist rule. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX> stated his priorities include
the timely payment of salaries and benefits, and that it is unacceptable for
most <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> to live below the poverty line.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Outlook</ENAMEX>" is sounding what could
be an early warning alarm for a new round of international economic crisis not
related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> turmoil. Several big <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> are laying workers
off because of falling exports caused by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s surging pound. The pound's
rise, explains the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , stems from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s decision to opt out of the
coming common <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> currency, the euro. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">euro countries</ENAMEX> were
required to cut government spending and raise taxes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> wasn't, with
the result that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.K.</ENAMEX> interest rates are very high. In addition, continental
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">skeptics</ENAMEX> about the euro have been buying <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">pounds</NUMEX> as a refuge.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report confirms a number
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Drudge</ENAMEX> scoops: the existence of the semen-stained dress, the story
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> oral sex while he was on the phone with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Morris</ENAMEX>, the use of a cigar in sexual activity, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
tryst on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter</ENAMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX> still has to flash his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">guild</ENAMEX> card at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> and say
that being accurate isn't enough, a story still has to be well-sourced. The
response is obvious: How could <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> have been so consistently right if he
wasn't well-sourced? In fact, it's pretty clear from this list that his source
was someone in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. Which is trouble for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, but not for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX>.

            A high tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> quoted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and a letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> make the same point: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed a bill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to keep
pornography off the Internet and yet, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> quickly voted to put it on.

         
      
   
