
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peccadillo Re</ENAMEX>: Armadillo

            Different leads all around. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> runs a big spread on the aftermath of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> shootings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times leads with the debate over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s move to subpoena
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with a promise by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> to rescue his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s failing economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> goes with a
poll (taken by the paper) showing that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> oppose raising the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> retirement age from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">65 to 70</TIMEX>, but <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">66%</NUMEX> "support the idea of
letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX> invest part of their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX> taxes in the stock
market."

            The caskets of the two murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> will be displayed all day
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Rotunda</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Vice President</ENAMEX> will pay
tribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that this treatment is normally
reserved for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> or military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, adding that we've conferred this
honor <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only 27</NUMEX> times in our history (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX>). Others so honored
include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>. Stories further detailing the alleged <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attacker</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">nutso</ENAMEX> personality get front-page play at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , LAT
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Weston</ENAMEX> shot and killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
family <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> before his assault on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol</ENAMEX>, while the LAT
says it was <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">several</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> pegs it at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">14</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> in all. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's oddly comic sub-headline: "Did confrontation over <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cats</ENAMEX> lead to
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">rampage?</ENAMEX>"

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead claims that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will face pressure from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accept Starr</ENAMEX>'s recent subpoena. Despite evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> could win a court
victory quashing the subpoena, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> fear that any attempt to
fight it might cost them support from congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. The subpoena
gets front-page treatment everywhere, but only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> gets the internal
party pressure angle. The other papers focus on the fight over what form
testimony should take--<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> might go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might
testify over videotape or closed-circuit television; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wants his lawyer
present during testimony, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> refuses this concession.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead reports on promises made by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politician</ENAMEX> Keizo
Obuchi, who will likely become <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obuchi</ENAMEX> vows to
kickstart the flagging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> economy with a major tax cut and stimulus
package, acceding to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> pressure for prompt action. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> note <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obuchi</ENAMEX>'s reputation for timid foot-dragging, and characterize
this as a purposeful attempt to appear bold and decisive. The WP
relegates the news to page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A24</TIMEX>, running an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story with little detail or
context.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> give front-page notice to a new partnership between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Telecom</ENAMEX>. Not surprisingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> explains this business story in the
clearest terms: The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> "agreed to form a global phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> with
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 billion</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> revenue to provide low-cost voice, data and video
services to multinational <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">venture</ENAMEX> seems designed to counter the
pending merger between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MCI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Worldcom</ENAMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story says <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">armadillos</ENAMEX> are migrating north, and may eventually
reach <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New England</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> are largely harmless, but their expansion will
markedly increase the road kill counts in their new environs. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> once ran over
an armadillo. The experience held little to recommend it.

         
      
   
