
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Profits</ENAMEX>?

            As is not uncommon for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have the same
lead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> reaction to
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekend</TIMEX> revelation that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> served as a source to reporters
working the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> story. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s preparations for warning flights <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s start of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> conference considering the establishment of a
permanent international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for prosecuting crimes against humanity. And the
top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> is the national trend of grieving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> of murdered <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> working to create
laws designed to protect other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from the fates met by their own.
The most famous examples--<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Megan's Law</ENAMEX> (federal: requires notifying a
neighborhood of the presence of a convicted sex offender), the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Jimmy</ENAMEX> Ryce Act
(<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Law</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kansas</ENAMEX>: both provide for the commitment to a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mental</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> of dangerous repeat sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">offenders</ENAMEX> after the expiration of their
prison terms)-- are but the tip of a legislative iceberg that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
reports, currently consists of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 50</NUMEX> such laws added to the books in the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 18 months</TIMEX>. The paper observes that the anxiety over child safety among
current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>, the largest generation of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> ever, has
considerably broadened the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituency</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' rights.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead reports that in response to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
admission in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Content</ENAMEX> magazine interview that he spoke privately to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> about potential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-related inquiries, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> took to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> airwaves to charge that such actions were illegal and
that fair inquiry into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will be completely in question until they are
investigated. In short, we have hit the meta-motherlode: a claim that the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s investigation needs...an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>'s
investigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis Carroll</ENAMEX>, call your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>.

            And things get curiouser and curiouser as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> tries to report on
the possible wrongdoing here while at the same time exculpating its own prior
interactions with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that it (along with other papers) has
openly reported that some of its information has "come from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>,"
but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s public admission "broke an unwritten taboo leaving him vulnerable
to criticism." Why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s admission should do so when the corresponding <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> does not, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> doesn't say. It almost seems as if the
paper's position is it's okay to talk to an "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>," but not to any actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">person</ENAMEX> who works there. But then again, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> love to fuzz up the origins of
their information if for no other reason than that it makes them look more
original than they really are. This very LAT piece is a good example:
although the whole story is generated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Content</ENAMEX> article, the paper
manages to stave off using the C-word until the last--the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">twenty-third</NUMEX>--paragraph.

            The LAT front points out a little-noticed feature of the version of
the tobacco bill now working its way through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. Although the bill had
originally contained <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.5 billion</NUMEX> for helping <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX> quit, to keep others
from starting, and to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> from buying cigarettes, it now contains
nothing for any of that.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Safire</ENAMEX> wonders in his column how many millions
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brother</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hugh Rodham</ENAMEX>, will be getting for his work on
the tobacco settlement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Safire</ENAMEX> says he doesn't know because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodham</ENAMEX> hasn't been
returning his phone calls.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that according to a benchmark
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> customer survey, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple Computer</ENAMEX> has fallen from its longtime position as
the personal computer industry's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in customer loyalty. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is now
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> in the allegiance sweepstakes, behind the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gateway</ENAMEX>, and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> attribute this to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>'s
failure to provide a price-competitive entry in the booming market of computers
selling for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">under $1,000</NUMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> op-ed by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> nuclear power
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> details an important fact about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s nuclear weapons program
that has drawn little notice: the plutonium <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> dipped into for its recent
bomb tests was provided <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly forty</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX> as part of an "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Atoms for Peace</ENAMEX>"
reactor built by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> and fueled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> In return, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> had promised
both <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in writing that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">reactor</ENAMEX> would be reserved for "peaceful
purposes." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX> therefore now should, write the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>, as a
condition of lifting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economic sanctions, make <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> withhold that
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plutonium</ENAMEX> from its weapons program.

            All of the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fives</ENAMEX>'s fronts feature the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bulls</ENAMEX>' dramatic win for the title.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX>' biggest worry about the possibility that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX> will
now retire: he'll get his own talk show.

         
      
   
