
   
   
      
         
            Poses for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> lead is about a forthcoming government report saying that human
medical research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subjects</ENAMEX> are not adequately protected. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a look at prospects for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>--now in the minority by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> seats--in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>'s elections. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>'s declaration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tobacco</ENAMEX> bill is "dead in the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>." The top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
is <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>' recent tendency to purchase much less life insurance. More and
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , are viewing "whole life" insurance as a
comparatively poor investment and are instead choosing to self-insure via such
instruments as <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">401ks</ENAMEX> and annuities. And two-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX> feel more cushioned
against needing even non-investment "term" insurance.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later this week</TIMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health and Human</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> will issue reports calling for reforms in the way human medical tests
are monitored. The reports do not claim widespread abuses of test subjects but
say that the increased speed of research created by the hothouse competition
among drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> has led to weaknesses in the ways safety is monitored. No
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, says the paper, in government or industry knows how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> take part
in medical trials or how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are injured or killed in them. The story
says the reforms the reports call for include providing more education for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and preventing conflicts of interest, but doesn't elaborate. This
is a little brisk--on the part of the reports and/or on the part of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . How, it's natural to wonder, does a drug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> do an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX>
vaccine experiment on subjects that's not enmeshed up to its eyeballs in the
conflict between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> profits and subject safety?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that right now, the most likely result of the fall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
races will be a virtual deadlock between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>--which would
be, reminds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , a historic feat for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, since the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> has picked up seats in a midterm election only once since the
Civil <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">War</ENAMEX>. The paper figures there are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only about 65</NUMEX> races that are truly
competitive. And because <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX> are very pleased with the economy, most of the
action will be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 33</TIMEX> open seat races. Of course, that's really all there is
to say at the moment, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes on and on for many more column
inches. The story features one of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> journalism's time-honored ways to
positively cram <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one pound</NUMEX> of information into a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> pound sack: call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman</ENAMEX>
Orenstein of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Enterprise Institute</ENAMEX>. He's quoted saying, "With an
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX>-seat margin, even a tiny wind, not necessarily a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gale force</ENAMEX>, can make all
the difference in the world."

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> it was reported that a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX>
confirmed that during the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Vietnam War</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
carry out the nerve-gas killing of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> defectors. Why was the sole
appearance of this story on anybody's Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> the <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">one-inch</NUMEX> reefer (to a story
on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">p.</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>) on the LAT front? Could it possibly be because the story was
broken by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>? Is that a good reason?

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Outlook</ENAMEX>," one of the most
important facts about E-commerce is that it's a paradise for comparison
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">shoppers</ENAMEX>. This fact is helping to remind us that the traditional biz world's
devotion to the market has its limits. As one on-line travel <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> executive
is quoted saying: "There is nothing more terrifying than a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consumer</ENAMEX> who knows
everything about the pricing of your product."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> also reports on the hottest new recreational pursuit of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dilbertized</ENAMEX> workplace: buzzword bingo. You play by getting together with the other
drones before the meeting with the big <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bosses</ENAMEX> and setting up a bingo-like grid
made up of their favorite jargon--like "incent" and "proactive"--and then check
off the boxes as the gems flow. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">player</ENAMEX> with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">line</ENAMEX> checked off wins,
and signifies so not by shouting "bingo" but by coughing. Hmmm.wonder if this
is popular at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> supervising human medical trials.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sportswriting</ENAMEX> legend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Povich</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last week</TIMEX> at
age <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">92</TIMEX> (he was still writing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>; his last column appeared the next
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">day</ENAMEX>) and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have been full of his greatness. One wonderful line quoted
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> is his lead from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> column, when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Povich</ENAMEX> was campaigning hard to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> football <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> break the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">color</ENAMEX> line: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Brown</ENAMEX>, born ineligible to play for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redskins</ENAMEX>, integrated
their end zone <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>'s big image-buffing campaign,
personified by the likely <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">election today</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlton Heston</ENAMEX> as the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organization</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> does what it can to unbuff the
image, running a picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heston</ENAMEX> that seems to show him either a) getting a
hit off the gunpowder fumes on his fingertips, b) blowing kisses or c) throwing
up.

         
      
   
