
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr Gazing</ENAMEX>

            Everybody leads with the expected near-simultaneous release <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report. You can't tell from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> headlines what the report says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
did. And indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead never says. For that you have to turn to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headlines</ENAMEX>, which make it plain: lied (both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>), obstructed justice (the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ) and abused power (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead emphasizes the struggle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> between get-it-out-now
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> and pro-delay <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> over the timing of the report's
release, a battle, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> have won. The LAT
cites one argument <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> wielded, but to no avail: when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Ethics</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reprimanded</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, he was given an advance copy of
the report. Only the WP notices that in describing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">one-sided</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX> was analyzing a report he hadn't
read.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also tells of the pre-release battle and repeats its account of
the report's charges from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s edition: that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> obstructed justice
in trying to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> a job and lied twice under oath about his
relationship with her. These charges are expounded at much greater length in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . Oddly, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> buries until the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-from-the-bottom paragraph the news that a source says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> concludes
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> committed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eleven</NUMEX> offenses that could warrant impeachment, a detail the
WP rightly puts in its lead's first sentence.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says the report includes "graphic details about sexual
encounters" between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> but leaves it at that. The LAT
goes a little farther with such titillating non-titillation, quoting a source
telling the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, "I don't know how a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> like yours will be able to
handle some of this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX>." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP wade</ENAMEX> into the details, and even though <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> meeting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> would contain "no surprises," some of the details are new: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
testified that on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> occasions she engaged in a sex act with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> while he
talked on the phone with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> (say both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>) and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> prints the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Dutch</ENAMEX> Master-bator tale of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge Report</ENAMEX> fame that
according to her, the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> once used a cigar as a prop in a sex act.

            All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have comments from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>
who met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> behind closed doors. Most describe a repentant
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>. (In a sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Atonement Watch</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a chronology with excerpts of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> apologies to date.) But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that at the
Cabinet meeting, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HHS</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Shalala</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> if he didn't
think he had an obligation to provide moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "let her have it," saying that if her logic had
prevailed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX> would have been elected instead of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy</ENAMEX>. After that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchange</ENAMEX>, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, no other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> had anything critical to say.

            The off-lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , which
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> plays on the front below the fold, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s decision to
name <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX>, his current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">foreign minister</ENAMEX>, as his new prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX>. The papers all note that the choice met with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communists</ENAMEX>' approval
and hence is likely to be approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">parliament</ENAMEX>, possibly resolving the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> crisis. Also widely noted is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Primakov</ENAMEX>, an experienced
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomat</ENAMEX>, has no expertise in the area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s burning problem,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> seems particularly down on the move though--an
editorial describes him as a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KGB</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dictators</ENAMEX> everywhere."

            Inside pieces at both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> killed an attempt at campaign finance reform, probably tabling
such efforts for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the rest of the year</TIMEX>. The arguments of the corruptions of
money vs. the freedom to contribute and raise it were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same-old same-old</TIMEX>,
but this time, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , there was also the deepening distraction
of possible impeachment proceedings. Similarly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report
means the chances of a managed care overhaul coming out of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">zero</NUMEX>.

            The USAT front features a poll that says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Americans</ENAMEX>
think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> should stay in office. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart</ENAMEX> may not be one of
them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s broadcast of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Stewart Living"</ENAMEX> was
supposed to be a lunch get-together with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> the hostess had taped
back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>. But instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX> will see a rerun.

         
      
   
