
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire Stories</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX>'s decision to launch an inquiry into whether or not
during his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> re-election bid, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> coordinated an "issue"
advertising campaign that was in fact an improper attempt to circumvent federal
limits on his own campaign ad budget. The story also gets major play on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> front, but is not on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times front, and is just barely reefered at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s attempts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marshal</ENAMEX> congressional
support for the coming storm. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with the Dow's biggest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-day</TIMEX>
point gain ever, which is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and is also fronted at
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> gives over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three-quarters</NUMEX> of its
front page to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>'s record-breaking <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">62nd</NUMEX> home run, a story that also
cops mega column-inchage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , but which is missing
altogether--due to deadline constraints, no doubt--from the front of the first
available edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McGwire</ENAMEX> is widely quoted thanking his
family, his son, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubs</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Sosa</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that before
the game, he rubbed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Maris</ENAMEX>' record-setting bat on his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> note that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX>'s newest inquiry is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> different DOJ look at a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operation</ENAMEX> initiated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two weeks</TIMEX>. Although, notes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , this one's more personal, naming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as the principal subject.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> has, explains the paper, reviewed the issue ad issue <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least three</NUMEX> times
before, but each time stopped after an initial <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30-day</TIMEX> review. Both papers
report what has been widely suggested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent days</TIMEX>--that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Election</ENAMEX>
Commission report helped persuade her to look again. And both report a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>'s comment that the vexed ads were carefully previewed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> entices with the tidbit that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dole</ENAMEX> '96 campaign ads are also
under review at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>, but at an earlier stage of review. (Why isn't it as
far along? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't say.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> is likely
to deliver his report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as early as the end of this week</TIMEX>, probably
sooner than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> expected. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Well-placed lawyers</ENAMEX> talking to the
Times tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that the report is likely to say that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lied under oath in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case deposition and to include
embarrassing descriptions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s conduct with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WP</ENAMEX> lead and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is scrambling to marshal
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> congressional support, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> reporting that he is going to
apologize at a meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. He may also, says the
Times , apologize <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this week</TIMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> prayer breakfast. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> appearance at an elementary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">school</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> seemed subdued.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> off-lead is the confession by long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anatoly Chubais</ENAMEX>, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> "conned" the international community out of nearly
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 billion</NUMEX> in loans by hiding the severity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s fiscal problems.
If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> had told the truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chubais</ENAMEX> is quoted as saying, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> would have collapsed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX> "would have stopped
dealing with us forever."

            For once, have some pity on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corrections</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . Today,
they were somehow forced to run this one: "An article in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX> & Ideas on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 29</TIMEX> about the changing role of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> in political theater misstated
the name of a theater <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> and the title of its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>. It is
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute on the Arts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Civic Dialogue</ENAMEX> (not "for" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arts</ENAMEX>), and the writer
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actress</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Deveare Smith</ENAMEX> is its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>, not artistic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>."

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "Tax Report," just about everybody in
official <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> stood up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to denounce the idea reported earlier in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> would impose the gift tax on any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> who tried to give a
historic home run ball back to the slugger who launched it. Presidential
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">spokesman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike McCurry</ENAMEX> is quoted saying the idea was "about the dumbest thing
I've ever heard in my life." (And think of all the dumb things he gets to
hear.) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Patrick Moynihan</ENAMEX> dashed off a letter of complaint to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>, and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senator</ENAMEX> blasted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> over the
phone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> quickly issued a statement making it clear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fan</ENAMEX> would
not owe gift tax. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> problem with all this: despite the apparent oddity of
the home run ball case, not one of these horrified public <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX> has shown
why it isn't a perfectly straightforward application of the gift tax. So
shouldn't they rethink the whole idea? (Look for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> editorial to make
this point <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">any day</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>.)

         
      
   
