
   
   
      
         
            Slow and Steady

            News of slower <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">second quarter</TIMEX> economic growth leads at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
pledge to testify "completely and truthfully" at his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> questioning in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s financial woes and the effects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Motors</ENAMEX> strike kept
growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s gross domestic product at a modest <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.4%</NUMEX>, down from last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarter</TIMEX>'s scalding <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.5%</NUMEX>. The news isn't so bad, though, as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> papers
report that the current <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-year</TIMEX> expansion seems to be withstanding the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Asian</ENAMEX>
storm nicely. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls it a "slow-but-respectable performance" and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> deems the economy's pace "modest but still healthy." On the
awesome impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> shutdown, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that it shaved a full
percentage point from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">second quarter</TIMEX> growth.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has announced that he will answer questions under oath in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX>, but will have no comment on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter until then. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s testimony will be transmitted live to the federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX>,
allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> to pose questions via the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> "maintained a casual, unaffected appearance" before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX>,
despite waiting for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>'s report on the existence of "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA material</ENAMEX>" in Ms.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s dress. Amid criticism from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">supporters</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> has
announced that he will take an unpaid leave of absence from his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">nearly $1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million</NUMEX> per year post at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX> law <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> where he defended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> such as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meineke Discount Muffler</ENAMEX>.

            An above-the-fold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece reports that an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> has
pleaded guilty to selling computers to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> that can simulate nuclear weapons
testing. With no prior convictions, a contrite <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IBM</ENAMEX> received the maximum fine
possible: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.5 million</NUMEX>.

            Direct legislation gets a closer look in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story on the debate
over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s direct voter initiatives. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Defenders</ENAMEX> cite initiatives' ability to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">express</ENAMEX> public frustration with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX> claim the process is too
susceptible to monied interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and upsets the "checks and balances of
the legislative process." While no one wants to abolish the initiatives
altogether, most agree reforms are needed.

            An LAT front page article reveals a "serious slump" among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicon Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX>. Again, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s financial troubles are to blame along with
cheaper PCs and slower PC sales. Having already seen downsizing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>,
the industry faces another round of wage reductions and layoffs. This past
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>, industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stalwarts</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hewlett-Packard</ENAMEX> have trimmed payrolls
through plant closings, forced retirements, and pay cuts in the once
unstoppable <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> industry has thrived during
the slump: job and career counseling.

         
      
   
