
   
   
      
         
            Talk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Corning Corporation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.2 billion</NUMEX> settlement with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">170,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> for
illnesses caused by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s breast implants leads at all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> except
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , which presumably went to press
too early to cover it. The average dividend for each claimant will amount to
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $31,000</NUMEX>, with some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> eligible for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $250,000</NUMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> )
and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). Nonetheless, as all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> point
out, studies have been inconclusive on the degree to which the implants are
linked to sickness. The settlement ends a legal struggle that has gone on for
over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years</TIMEX>, but individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> can still pursue their claims for damages
of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">up to $550,000</NUMEX>. The settlement also pulls <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Corning</ENAMEX> out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Chapter 11</ENAMEX>
bankruptcy, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> entered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> when faced with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19,000</NUMEX> implant
lawsuits. Production of the offending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">implants</ENAMEX> ceased in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nigeria</ENAMEX> watch: All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' front pages (except for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , which links a front-page photo to an
inside story), cover the riots in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">capital</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lagos</ENAMEX> and several <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">towns</ENAMEX>, which
were sparked by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> death of opposition <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moshood Abiola</ENAMEX> and by
military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abubakar</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> dissolution of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Rioters</ENAMEX>
suspect the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> of killing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abiola</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">close to 20</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have died
already. In response, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s military <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> appealed for calm, and has
promised that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> will be brought in to perform a fair autopsy for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abiola</ENAMEX>. An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy hinges on the
outcome of the autopsy.

            Star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">editor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Brown</ENAMEX>'s resignation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> receives
front-page play at all papers. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">URI</ENAMEX>=<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">/info/contents/contents.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">html</ENAMEX>">
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> goes with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-column headline and a photo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>,
with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> additional articles inside accompanied by a timeline of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX>'s
history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> was offered a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX> contract renewal, but declined, opting
instead to start a new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> in partnership with the film company
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Miramax</ENAMEX>. The new glossy would serve as a launching pad for articles that could
later be turned into films or television shows. Congratulations go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtz</ENAMEX> of the WP : His article (in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Style</ENAMEX> section) was the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> at
all <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> not to use the words "venerated" or "venerable" to describe the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> 's A-head column claims that dots are replacing hyphens as the
new grammatical vogue. Despite the egregious lead pun ("The punctuation world
is entering a new period"), the story insightfully observes that dots are
leaking from cyberspace addresses into traditionally hyphenated items such as
telephone numbers. Among the arguments for boarding the dot-<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">wagon</ENAMEX>: dots take
less space than hyphens, and the period key is easier to hit on the keyboard.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">T.P.</ENAMEX> applauds the new trend.

         
      
   
