
   
   
      
         
            A <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Second Act of Contrition</ENAMEX>?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with assessments of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s cruise
missile attacks. Each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> claimed
moderate success and warned of possible strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> in the near
future. The papers all report that bin Laden survived the attack and that at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">21</NUMEX> ( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> were killed by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> fired into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> pinpoints the number of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tomahawks</ENAMEX> launched at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> say <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">75</NUMEX>. Splitting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hairs</ENAMEX>? Not according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's lead which gives a cost estimate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">million</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> added bin Laden
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Treasury Department</ENAMEX>'s list of official <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX>. This allows the feds
to seize any <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> assets he may possess and hopefully weakens his attempts at
financing terrorist activities. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> question why bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> had not been
placed on the list <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier</TIMEX>.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> above-the-fold news analysis says that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> attack has
shifted the fight against terrorism from a legal to a military one--national
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">security</ENAMEX> has superceded due process. The results of this change will be
psychological: bold, unilateral action bolsters moral at home, inspires
confidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>, and intimidates enemies.

            From the "If at first you don't succeed" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">department</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is considering
another public address concerning his relationship with "that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>." The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">insiders</ENAMEX> want the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> to publicly
discuss the issue, this time clearly expressing "contrition" for his
inappropriate activities with then-intern <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The particular medium for
such remarks has not been agreed upon.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s grand jury testimony leaks its way into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> testified that he gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> several
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> claim this shows he did not instruct <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to return gifts to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX> in defiance of a court order. The article also reveals that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
legal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fund</ENAMEX> has raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.2 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last six months</TIMEX>. Maybe he should
thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oscar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winners</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Hanks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Douglas</ENAMEX>,
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babs Streisand</ENAMEX> provided maximum donations of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> each.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT /CBS</ENAMEX> poll shows approval at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">around 70%</NUMEX> for the job <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is
doing and slightly below <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> himself. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50%</NUMEX> of the public now views
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> favorably, a percentage that matches her highest-ever rating. Other
issues polled include: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation
should quickly end, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 5%</NUMEX> admit to viewing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> favorably.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s Papers applauds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> for attending to a commonly overlooked,
yet always-important detail: forthright disclosure of the poll's plus or minus
margin of error.

         
      
   
