
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Un-Free Willy</ENAMEX>

            Everybody leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s sudden delivery to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> of his
report claiming there is substantial evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, in
his behavior relating to his relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, committed
crimes that may be impeachable offenses. "The fate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> presidency,"
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , is now in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' hands. The
headlines at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> ,
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
all include the word "impeachment." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> gives itself over most completely to
the development, but its headlines omit the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">I-</ENAMEX>word. Perhaps quite by accident
or perhaps with full subversive intent, a headline over another WP
front-page story--about the return of a certain movie killer <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">whale</ENAMEX> to the high
seas--sends an ominous message, though: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Whale of an Ending for 'Willy'</ENAMEX>".

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> speak somewhat vaguely of the report's
allegations of perjury, obstruction of justice and abuse of power. USAT
is more <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">concrete</ENAMEX>, saying that according to a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> with knowledge of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">445</NUMEX>-page effort--shipped over with supporting documents in
duplicate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">36</TIMEX> sealed boxes--flatly concludes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> perjured himself
twice, once in his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> case deposition and once in his videotaped grand jury
testimony. In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the report finds that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s efforts
to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> a job were obstruction of justice. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is also
somewhat detailed, quoting "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> legal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>" (hmmm...wonder if he's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A Lawyer</ENAMEX>
With <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Knowledge Of The Report</ENAMEX>?) as agreeing that perjury is charged, and
elaborating that the charge arises from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s denial of sex with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
and for claiming he could not remember being alone with her except when she was
delivering papers to him.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says the report also alleges that attempts by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX>
to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> a job were aimed at keeping her silent. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report sees no wrongdoing in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Jordan</ENAMEX>'s efforts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> quotes
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">allies</ENAMEX> of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>" as saying that the report includes many heretofore
unreleased details that will "surprise the public." Everybody notes the report
is sitting in a locked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> storage <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> while the congressional leadership
decides how to proceed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> say the report could be
made public <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says this might include Internet access.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> detects "a rising sense of helplessness" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that on the heels of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s apology
session with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> offer more of the same
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cabinet</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was "sad,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">somber</ENAMEX> and choked up" at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> session. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> says that
ill feeling towards the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pols</ENAMEX> is "pervasive." Everybody reports
another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> apology <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, delivered at a public appearance in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says he was "husky-voiced and somber" for that one. (It turns
out that sex means always having to say you're sorry.)

            There's other news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> are threatening <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> with impeachment
if he renominates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> to be his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX> (a story first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">broached</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier in the week</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ); the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> security <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guards</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beijing</ENAMEX> brutally hauled away the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of a jailed dissident to keep
her from delivering a letter of protest to the visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> on
human rights. (She was released <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours later</TIMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have focused in on a rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> repair <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> as the likely staging area for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing.

            And then there's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intrepid WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby Ingrid Copeland</ENAMEX>'s
tireless <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">575</NUMEX>-word effort to discover things that have the same circumference as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McGwire</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">arms</ENAMEX>. Such as: <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX> parking <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">meters</NUMEX>, personal pan pizzas, a
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year-old</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX>-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s thigh. Things that fall short:
Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX>-in-the-street biceps, including those of an unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>, a
coffee cup. All this and a quote from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Farrakhan</ENAMEX> too. Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>: check the ventilation in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section offices</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
