
   
   
      
         
            Superproblems

            <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> hits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s front-page jackpot. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with dire economic assessments from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergei Kiriyenko</ENAMEX>, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> takes on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> wannabe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Belarus</ENAMEX>. The actual
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">WP</ENAMEX> lead, however, is the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23 million</NUMEX> settlement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diocese</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dallas</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eight</NUMEX> ex-altar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boys</ENAMEX> who were sexually abused by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priest</ENAMEX>
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1980s</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 90s</TIMEX>. The story <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stunningly</ENAMEX> asserts that over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 20</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">up to 2000</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> have been accused of sexual
assault, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roman Catholic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dioceses</ENAMEX> have shelled out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800 million</NUMEX> since
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">1980s</NUMEX> in compensation for sexual abuse by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> also run stories on the settlement.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's lead replays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> appeal to Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> for
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20 billion</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> of it from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>) to bail out <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s faltering
markets. This amount almost doubles previously requested sums. According to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> embarked in a phonathon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, urging <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Western</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> to
pressure the ever-reluctant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">IMF</ENAMEX> to provide the money. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> means
business--his telephone short-list included <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacque Chirac</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helmut Kohl</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michel Camdessus</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>).

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead story focuses on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiriyenko</ENAMEX>'s depressing announcement
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s debts have reached <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44 percent</NUMEX> of gross domestic product.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Only a month ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiriyenko</ENAMEX> estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s debt at
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one-third</NUMEX> of GDP. The change dramatically illustrates the free-fall of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> economy. Meanwhile, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , having tackled <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s economics
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX>, goes next door to inhospitable <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belarus</ENAMEX>, where nostalgia for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX> and anti-Western sentiment reign supreme.

            The court-martial ordered for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> whose <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX> downed an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable</ENAMEX> car receives front-page play at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , but is inside at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX>--the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>'s pilot and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">navigator</ENAMEX>--face <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX> counts including negligent homicide and involuntary
manslaughter. Charges against the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marines</ENAMEX> in the back of the plane
were dropped, though they will likely testify in the upcoming court
martial.

            Another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager states that federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> are galvanizing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>' goal is to make it easier for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> to sue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> and insurance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>.

            And the adventurous WP takes a front-page whirl through controversial
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dianaland</ENAMEX> (officially called <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">"Althorp</ENAMEX>"), the glamorous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX>- cum -shrine
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Spencer</ENAMEX> created to memorialize his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sister</ENAMEX>. Among the features: a
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Temple</ENAMEX>" with a marble silhouette of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Princess</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>; a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> with her jewelry,
silk shoes, wedding gown, and other accessories; and an admission fee of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skinflints</ENAMEX> should stick to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graceland</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
