
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and Out

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with chat-show declarations by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> has opened a new war against terrorism.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s dismissal of his main
government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>, including his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergei Kiriyenko</ENAMEX>, which is
also the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">WP</ENAMEX> leads with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX>'s first extensive comments about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation
since <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Speech</ENAMEX>, which include his declaration that impeachment would require
not "a single human mistake" but "a pattern of felonies." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gingrich</ENAMEX> also tells
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that he thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will probably be made
available to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>, but that the supporting evidence will be kept
secret.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> accompanies its lead with a front-section "cover story" about
the newly announced <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> war, which states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX> has already
trained "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">tens of thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> operating in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than a dozen</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>." Question: if this is so, then how is it that there was virtually no
press mention of bin Laden until the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings? The piece
reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s strikes against <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> were
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">code-named Operation Infinite Reach</ENAMEX> (which could have also been the code-name
for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX> speech). The LAT front runs a story filed from
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> that includes an interview with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who claims to have lived through
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Tomahawk</ENAMEX> attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. "All of us were innocent," the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> tells
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, explaining that what the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> says is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist</ENAMEX> training complex
is in fact merely a religious education <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">center</ENAMEX>.

            The papers report that in the midst of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s economic crisis,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> replaced the reform-minded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiriyenko</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says that it appears <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>'s thinking is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s good
relations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">financiers</ENAMEX> and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parliament</ENAMEX> may help
deflate the widespread calls for his own departure. Everybody points out that
what makes the move odd is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> already had the job for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>
until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> let him go, in part because in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's
words, "a new young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was needed." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> say
another reason was that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> had begun to fear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX> as a
presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitor</ENAMEX>. The papers report that despite the upheaval, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will still keep to a previously
scheduled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-day</TIMEX> summit with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next month</TIMEX>. Both the
Times and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> point out that the shake-up announcement was
made on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> television after the sports news.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs an interview with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX>. At <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> point, when it is
mentioned that the major growth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Church</ENAMEX> is now taking place
outside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, the pontiff replies, "It was so at the
beginning."

            Being a celebrity often means you get for free what ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have to
pay for, even though you can afford it and they can't. So for instance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cruise</ENAMEX> makes a movie and besides paying him, the studio throws him a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benz</ENAMEX>. But
it's not just the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">studios</ENAMEX> that are complicit. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, the main column on the
front page of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> real estate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> has been "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hot</ENAMEX>
Property," which chronicles the real estate doings of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">glitterati</ENAMEX>. Now, if
you wanted to advertise your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX> for sale in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , you'd have to
pay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a hundred</NUMEX> bucks or so for a tiny little buried ad, but if you're say (as in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>'s paper), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Grier</ENAMEX>, why then at absolutely no cost to you the
paper leads the section with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> paragraphs about your <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">house</ENAMEX>, including mention
of the neighborhood, the asking price and the names of the realtors to
contact.

            It probably took a presidential sex confession and a transcontinental cruise
missile strike to keep <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's front-page feature by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Mehta</ENAMEX>
out of the paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. The story? Cell-phones are getting smaller and
lighter.

         
      
   
