
   
   
      
         
            Aye, There's the Ruble

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s deepening economic crisis, marked
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by a nearly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> percent drop in the ruble. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> each put the ruble inside and go
instead with the likely coming ashore <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Carolinas</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Hurricane</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie</ENAMEX>, packing <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">115 mph</NUMEX> winds across an extremely broad front. The storm has
forced the evacuation, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half a million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. The
LAT fronts the storm, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a reefer to its story
running deep inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says a "fresh wave of panic" is hitting <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s financial markets, with,
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> explain, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> trying to delay the scheduled
repayment of its debt, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> furiously dumping <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">rubles</NUMEX> for dollars. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">upshot</ENAMEX> is, according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> quoted in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , that "not a single foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investor</ENAMEX> in his sound mind will come to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>...." The ruble's slide has, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , awakened new fears of
hyperinflation like that seen in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 90</TIMEX>'s. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> is increasingly acting like a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lame duck</ENAMEX> as attention turns to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister-designate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s likely alliance with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Communists</ENAMEX> and
the financial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elite</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s initial public comments, says the paper,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">harks</ENAMEX> back to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> times, with his suggestion of more government support for
ailing industries. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> example of the spreading cash crunch:
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s press run of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Izvestia</ENAMEX> was halted when its
printing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> ran out of money.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead reports that in preparation for their upcoming
antitrust case against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>, federal and state <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> are looking
into whether MS ever forced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> to shelve new Internet technology efforts
because they posed a competitive threat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes that the
Internet-related conflict between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> has been well-covered in
the trade <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">press</ENAMEX>, and was even the subject of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> dialogue between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">Grove</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fortune</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> appear particularly
interested in an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1995</TIMEX> meeting between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">MS execs</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Grove</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gates</ENAMEX>, at which, according to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> memo
cited by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX>, concerned about various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> Internet
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX>, made "vague threats" about supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>. The story
also includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX>'s response to the allegation: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> is
trying to depict as evidence of an anti-competitive conspiracy what are in fact
just minor disputes arising in routine business meetings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> is also the subject of a federal antitrust suit.

            An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, including a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> of the principal <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">U.S. Cuban</ENAMEX> exile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, were indicted in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Puerto</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rico</ENAMEX> on charges of conspiring to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Castro</ENAMEX> while he was on an official
visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Venezuela</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The story also runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> . A
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> for one of the accused tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> that he will demand access
to every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> document on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nearly 40 years</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> death plots.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> broke the story that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>
was charged in a sealed indictment with various terrorist activities. (That
story, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Ricks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Greenberger</ENAMEX>, was also the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> report of the
detail in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> dispatching a general to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> to reassure that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX> were not an attack by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>.)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s USAT front elaborates on that indictment a bit. Citing a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newsday</ENAMEX> story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that one of those activities attributed to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX> in the indictment is ordering and helping to finance a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> plot to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">assassinate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a vaguer story inside about
the indictment that doesn't mention any <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> plots, but under a piquant
headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A Formality In a World of Missiles</ENAMEX>."

            No matter the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">so</NUMEX>-what attitude of most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in most parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead indicates that in official <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fate still hangs very much in the balance. The headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt Says Clinton Could Be Impeached</ENAMEX>." The story is
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minority Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX>--never, as the paper notes, close to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>--<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> repeated his criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter and is quoted saying that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> were to leave
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, "we'll get through this." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gephardt</ENAMEX> describes himself in the story as "a
prospective grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">juror</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> adduces further evidence of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inside-the-Beltway</ENAMEX> bandwagon, with media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Kurtz</ENAMEX> citing the
(mostly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>-based) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnists</ENAMEX> who thus far have said in print they want
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> out, a list that includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Page</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Wills</ENAMEX>, and Lars-Erik
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nelson</ENAMEX>. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Shapiro</ENAMEX>, in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> column, notes that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Sunday</TIMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> ran a resignation op-ed by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Nunn</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the
paper runs a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> op-ed in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> writes, "If he is not doomed,
he is awfully close."

         
      
   
