
   
   
      
         
            Let's Go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Videotape</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> leads with a sneak preview of the videotaped
testimony that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will make public on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ' lead national story says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> plans to continue his
investigation and press for impeachment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with somewhat odd comments from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prime minister</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead describes what <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX> will see on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> when
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s taped testimony is released. The article claims that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "painted a picture of himself as a concerned and even tender <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>." While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "expressed embarrassment and regret about the
affair," he also showed "flashes of fury" directed at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> and his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> refused to answer specific questions about sex acts,
instead reading a prepared speech, the text of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> prints.
In the speech, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> admits to having "inappropriate intimate contact" with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and engaging in phone conversations that featured "inappropriate
sexual banter." (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Will</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">900</NUMEX>-lines now advertise "phone banter" at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.99</NUMEX> per
minute?) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> for these leaks<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">?</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Lawyers</ENAMEX> with detailed knowledge of the
proceedings." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> helpfully adds that the only <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> at the
proceedings were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>. Hmmm.... A second
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">front-page NYT</ENAMEX> story argues that the hateful rivalry between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> has led each to overstep and use poor judgment.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a front-page story on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lack of
discernible reaction to the mess. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> has kept her schedule of appearances,
and offered no statements and no sign of her inner feelings. A front-page
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> piece quotes several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> complaining about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s inaction. One
says, "I have no problem with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. I have a problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> not taking a stand on it." In a separate story, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> claims
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> will continue his investigation in an effort to find further
impeachable offenses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> hopes to find a pattern of cover-ups, stemming back
to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitewater, Filegate</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travelgate</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead recounts comments from an interview with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keizo Obuchi</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obuchi</ENAMEX> emphasized that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> is doing all it can to end
its recession: lowering interest rates, slashing taxes, and throwing government
money into the economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obuchi</ENAMEX> then commented that the only real solution might
be massive military spending, akin to what <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> did to pull the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Great Depression</ENAMEX>. Obuchi was careful to add that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">constitution</ENAMEX> would not allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> exports and that he would "never consider"
defense spending as a solution, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Obuchi</ENAMEX> raised the
idea himself before pooh-poohing it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doth Obuchi</ENAMEX> protest too much?

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two</NUMEX> articles in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sunday Styles</ENAMEX> section offer snapshots of
the go-go <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">'90s</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> story says hotel and wait <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX> are now uniformed in
designer clothes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Mizrahi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calvin Klein</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Karan</ENAMEX> are designing
uniforms for bellboys, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">waiters</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> maids. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mizrahi</ENAMEX> put <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doormen</ENAMEX> in
"understated" <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-button suits, bellboys in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nehru</ENAMEX> jackets, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">receptionists</ENAMEX>
in "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">baby</ENAMEX>-blue twin <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">sets</ENAMEX>." The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> article describes a "reservationist to the
stars" who acts as a travel <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agent</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">super-celebs</ENAMEX>. He can get you <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> in
booked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hotels</ENAMEX> and tables at ultrachic bistros, but you'll have to pay a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>
nonrefundable fee just to talk to him (this fee is not applied to charges for
actual services), and you may have to offer character references. "If potential
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clients</ENAMEX> balk at the fee...[the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agent</ENAMEX>] decides right away not to take them
on."

         
      
   
