
   
   
      
         
            Up In Smoke

            Everybody leads with the demise of the tobacco bill, pulled off the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>
floor by a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-dominated vote. There is some variety in the headlines
though. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , with its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP Kills Tobacco</ENAMEX>
Measure" and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , with its "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP Kills McCain Tobacco</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>" point fingers and opt for the active voice. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
goes passive with "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tobacco Bill</ENAMEX> Dies in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>." And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
is somewhere in between with "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Senate Drops Tobacco Bill With '98 Revival</ENAMEX>
Unlikely; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Lashes</ENAMEX> out at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lashing came <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">moments</TIMEX> after the denouement, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>,
described by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> as "clench-jawed" and "flushed," said, "If more
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> would vote like <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, we could
solve this problem and go onto other business of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Majority
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, who led opposition to the legislation, viewed it as having
strayed from its original purpose to become instead, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's words,
"a typically <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> big-tax, big-spending" bill. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newt Gingrich</ENAMEX> is quoted by
everyone as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> will take up and pass more narrowly
focused legislation intended to reduce teen smoking, but not increase
taxes.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees this turn of events as a "major defeat" for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and public health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, and a victory for the cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,
bringing to an end "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an unprecedented year-long</TIMEX> effort to reduce smoking by
young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and strictly regulate the tobacco industry." All the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note
the crucial role played in the defeat by the tobacco industry's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> ad
campaign, but it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> that makes the analogy with the way insurance
company ads were used in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> to defeat health care reform.

            Noting that the bill came out of the need for federal legislation to enforce
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s proposed settlement deal between the cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX> and
numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains that now, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> can be expected
to resume pressing their individual <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">multibillion-dollar</NUMEX> claims.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that when the bill's chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX>, conceded defeat in a heartfelt speech
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor in which he castigated his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, he received a
standing ovation from <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> in attendance and seated silence from members
of his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. This of course, leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> hungry for more information
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">about</TIMEX> why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> bucked his own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> to fight this fight, but none of the news
stories obliges.

            All the front pages feature coverage of a bold and surprising move
undertaken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> in concert: the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>' central
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> bought <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">as much as $4 billion</NUMEX> in yen on the open market, which sparked
further purchases of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> currency by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">traders</ENAMEX>, all of which reversed
the recent steep slide in the yen. The tactic, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> observes was the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> entry into
the currency markets in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>, buoyed markets around the world, including
Wall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX> Inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is an excellent primer on the move and international currency
markets in general.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Gerth</ENAMEX>, who broke the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loral/China</ENAMEX> satellite
story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last April</TIMEX>, reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> is rethinking
a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$650 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">mobile phone satellite</ENAMEX> deal between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes Space and Communications</ENAMEX> that it initially green-lighted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. Administration <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> express to the paper their concern that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">general</ENAMEX> in charge of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s satellites has made statements
suggesting his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s military may be planning to use the system to gather
information from mobile phones in use in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>.
Another discomfiting feature passed along by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> is that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">general</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX> was hired by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> to work on the project.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> stuns with a front-page feature about <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> men
who are peddling to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> world an extremely low-cost (more
than <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three thousand</NUMEX> times cheaper than birth control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>, says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> ) chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">sterilization agent</ENAMEX> called quinacrine. Because there is considerable evidence that the
substance may well be a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">carcinogen</ENAMEX>, quinacrine sterilizations are banned in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and are opposed by nearly all family planning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX> and many
foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX>. But, the paper explains, since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> aren't running
clinical trials and aren't doing any domestic sales, they are beyond the reach
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>. They operate through a low-profile network of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nurses</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">midwives</ENAMEX> in such <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bangladesh</ENAMEX>, avoiding whatever
meager regulatory mechanisms those <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> maintain. They have already sold
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX> used in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100,000</NUMEX> procedures overseas, and envision many, many more.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "Business Bulletin" notes that despite the plethora of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Father</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX> gift ads maligning ties, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neckwear Association of America</ENAMEX>
reports that sales rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">three percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. Wonder if tie aficionado <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is responsible. If so, look for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nathan Detroit</ENAMEX> comeback soon: The
picture inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> making his remarks about the tobacco bill
depicts the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> in a sartorial style rarely seen in official
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>--a dark shirt and a light tie.

         
      
   
