
   
   
      
         
            Ain't It <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
Today , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s unprecedented grand jury
appearance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> shows it knows its way beyond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beltway</ENAMEX>,
putting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead and going instead with the news that
a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> has been detained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombing, a story that makes
everybody's front page. (Although, in its version of the story, USAT
curiously leaves the arrest out of the headline, which instead trumpets the
State <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept.</ENAMEX>'s warning against travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>.)

            The big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> leads is, of course, What will he say? All
the papers cite widespread indications that he is ready to acknowledge that he
engaged in some sort of sexual activity with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The LAT
quotes presidential private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Kendall</ENAMEX> as saying that the widely
reported prediction that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cop</ENAMEX> to an "inappropriate relationship"
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>--is "groundless speculation." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes one
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> familiar with the matter" as saying that this is indeed the phrase he's
heard mentioned by "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> who
have spoken to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> as saying he plans to admit to "sex play," but (taking the line <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> adumbrated by last
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) not to a "sexual relationship." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> compares
this tack to such previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> hair-splits as his various explanations of
his marijuana use, his draft situation, and those <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> coffees for
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX>.

            The papers say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is expected to deny that he asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> or
anyone else to cover up the relationship. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> quotes that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">well-connected lawyer</ENAMEX> as saying that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> may come armed with a subpoena in
his pocket for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>--who technically is appearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> voluntarily--in case
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tries to duck any of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX>' questions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> gives
an excellent feel for the difficulties such questions might pose, ticking off
details challenging various previous <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> statements, garnered from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> appearances of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>.

            The papers quote presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as saying that if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> makes any
sort of post-testimony public statement, it will come from his private quarters
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> dedicates a front-page feature to the
question of how history will judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in light of his aspirations, his
accomplishments and his scandals. The piece quotes <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX>'s hesitance to
change his rating of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for the paperback version of his book, going to
press soon. His explanation for holding off: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> is still out...."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Arab</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> arrested by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> the day of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> bombing, because of his presentation of a questionable passport after he
came off a flight from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX>, has acknowledged "calmly and proudly" being a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX>-man <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> that pulled off the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> attack. What's
more, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> was put together and
financed by the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">millionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>. (The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says merely that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is suspected of being a bin Laden associate
or supporter.) According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is now in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> custody. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says he's in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kenyan</ENAMEX> custody. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports he says the
other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">six</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bombers</ENAMEX> slipped by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Karachi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">airport</ENAMEX>. And, the
papers note, bin Laden is ensconced in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> have
detected a huge underground <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX> that seems to be
designed for the secret resumption of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s nuclear weapons program,
officially frozen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">North Koreans</ENAMEX> in return for the promise of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billions</NUMEX> in
Western aid.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Pressler</ENAMEX> gives a damning insight
into the contemporary political mind. The point of the piece is for the author
to rue the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> of contemporary politics from the perspective of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> suddenly
removed from it by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">an election</TIMEX> loss, but what he mostly communicates instead is
that he loves his newfound ability to: take more and better vacations, to be a
star <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">panelist</ENAMEX> (on "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">losers</ENAMEX>") at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rennaissance Weekend</ENAMEX>, and to fly <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> class
and buy a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> and take free trips from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporations</ENAMEX> without
having to explain himself.

            
               For more <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Flytrap</ENAMEX>, click here.
            

         
      
   
