
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan Hounding</ENAMEX>

            Everybody leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> strikes (generally thought to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">involve 75</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times says it could have been <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to 100</NUMEX>) against terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. There was other news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, but not much: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unabrother</ENAMEX> got a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> reward, which he
says he'll distribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">victims</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. A study shows that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> of
absentee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">fathers</ENAMEX> are twice as likely to do jail time as those raised in
two-parent <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prom</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mom</ENAMEX>, who confessed to knowingly killing her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>,
pleaded guilty to aggravated manslaughter and as a result, could be out
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">partying</ENAMEX> again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> run
banner headlines across their tops, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
holds itself to a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>-column header, leaving room for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> columns for its
off-lead about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> shot. But there is no <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> story
on the USAT front and she's driven below the fold at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headline boils things down the most: "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S. Strikes</ENAMEX>
Back." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> opt for straight, analytical headlines,
although neither mentions the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> does
mention them, although at the cost of omitting the location of the strike
targets. But with its top line, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> does best communicate the
government's sense of urgency: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">U.S. Targets Heart of Terror</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the operation was the most formidable ever undertaken by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> against a private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsor</ENAMEX> of terrorism. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX>--terrorist
training <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camps</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> and a chemical weapons <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">factory</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>--are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">associated</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> report that an arrested
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Palestinian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> in the bombings provided irrefutable evidence of bin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>'s involvement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings, a story that from the day
of his arrest, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> pushed harder than the other big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">dailies</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that there were multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">bin Laden ID</ENAMEX>. The
Post states that in a briefing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 12th</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>
told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> was behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> tentatively approved the mission on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 14th</TIMEX>, with the
final go-ahead coming in a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX> AM phone call <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>,
saying that bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> had not been hurt in the strikes. Everybody reports that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> insist that bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> wasn't personally targeted in the raids.
But why this fuss? True, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has adopted a policy against
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">assassinating</ENAMEX> heads of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX>, but bin Laden is not one. So why not try to kill
him? Also, this space noted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that in its story emphasizing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
diplomatic efforts, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reported that there was no evidence that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> was considering military action against the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">bin Laden</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers doesn't care whether the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> just missed the story, or was misled
by its government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> as part of a cover and deception plan, or like a
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX>, was let in on the deal with the promise to keep quiet
until afterwards. It's all good--scumbags don't have the right to a
heads-up.

            Everybody notes that in his address to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> cited evidence suggesting that bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX> was planning further attacks
against <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facilities</ENAMEX> overseas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says the evidence included
electronic intercepts of communications relating to a planned truck<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">-bomb</ENAMEX> attack
on an undisclosed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX> as well as to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX>. Everybody
reports that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was chosen for the action because intelligence indicated
a major gathering of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist leaders</ENAMEX> was to take place at the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> site.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> numbered "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX>."

            But <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlen Specter</ENAMEX> saying the reason was that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
wanted to "focus attention away from his own personal problems." And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Coats</ENAMEX> saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s record "raises into doubt
everything he does and everything he says." The <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">WP</ENAMEX> describes such
comments as "unusually swift criticisms" and reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Cohen</ENAMEX> "responded stonily" when asked about the comparison to "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Dog</ENAMEX>." Everybody runs "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX>" stories. Their basic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">form</ENAMEX>: there is no
evidence for the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Wag the Dog</ENAMEX>" comparison of course, but here's the comparison.
A more apt commentary appears on the LAT op-ed page in the form of a
cartoon depicting a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX> asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> at a press conference,
"How do we know these attacks aren't meant to distract us from distracting the
country?"

            The LAT op-ed page features a column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> arguing via learned
appeals to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholic</ENAMEX> doctrine and <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">English</ENAMEX> royal history that what was really
wrong with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s speech <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the other night</TIMEX> is that he didn't humbly
ask forgiveness for his bad behavior. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Uelmen</ENAMEX>. Funny, don't
recall much of that from his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">client</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">O.J. Simpson</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
