
   
   
      
         
            Tape <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Measure</ENAMEX>

            Everyone leads with the presidential tape, although true to its Rashomon
spirit, no <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> see in it quite the same thing. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> flags it as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton Decries Attempt</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">'Set Me Up</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Tape Shows Nation a Clinton Irate and Sad</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> play it somewhat straighter, with their top
headlines merely stating that the tape was nationally aired, although the
papers use their sub-headlines to interpret the event. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> sees a
"composed" <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX> offering "new insights" into his version of events,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> stresses that the initial reaction of the public and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>
prompted by the tape suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s risk of impeachment was not
thereby increased. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> cites a post-tape poll finding that
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> don't want <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> impeached, up from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">60</NUMEX>
percent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> before the tape's airing.

            To varying degrees, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> all note that the taped testimony did not
feature the politically explosive emotions or over-the-top sex talk that had
been rumored <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> notes that contrary to leaks, the tape
contained no angry eruptions. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R.W. Apple</ENAMEX> makes the point
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> appearance was marked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s fuller and more
convincing expressions of personal regret, plus more fondness for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> than the nationally televised speech he gave <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours later</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple</ENAMEX>
writes that if the speech had been more like the testimony in this regard,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might well have put the whole matter to rest.

            A key to the relative success <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> achieved in his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> appearance
is noted by the LAT : unlike ordinary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was frequently
allowed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> to go on at great length without directly responding
to questions. (Which, given that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had agreed to appear for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">only four</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX>, also meant he was able to avoid some lines of questioning altogether by
"eating the clock.") Or just as unusually, note all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> simply
didn't answer some questions at all. For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that
when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> suggested that the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> themselves wielded a definition of
sex, that like his, required sexual intercourse, some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> sent back
word that no, they wanted him to address more specifically what he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
did, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> politely refused.

            Everybody suggests that the among the most implausible moments in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
testimony came when he tried to save his testimony from perjury by advocating
arcane definitions of such words as "is" and "alone." In conjunction with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s attempt to fine-tune the notion of sexual relations so that it
required intercourse, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> helpfully notes that in a recent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>
poll, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">87 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> said they consider oral sex sex. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
answers included the enunciation of his own philosophy of such testimony: be
truthful but not helpful; say what's true, but if possible make it misleading.
But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> came out of such logic-chopping to a peroration pitched primarily
to the grand <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">jurors</ENAMEX> that was, notes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , worthy of a campaign
speech.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial says that the videotape does not change the
"unfortunate fundamentals of the case." And so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> maintains that the
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only</NUMEX> thing to do is for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to open a formal impeachment inquiry. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial on the subject says the performance might have done
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> some good, but is still "one of the most low-rent moments in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> history." The editorial concludes that any short-of-impeachment
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX> requires that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> stop demanding that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> people
"endorse his lying." We can afford, says the editorial, to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> of
forgivers, but not of enablers.

            Everybody picks over the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> material released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The
biggest new news everybody has is that keeping the dress unwashed was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s idea, one which she implemented by convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> she'd gotten too
heavy to wear the dress and hence didn't need to wash it. There's also the word
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s notes of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> visits and calls are so extensive that
they even included a spread (so to speak) sheet. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's account says her
memory for details was so good that she rattled off for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> what she
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon Jordan</ENAMEX> had to eat at their breakfast meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">some months</TIMEX> prior.

            World record-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holder</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Olympic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">champion</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence Griffith-Joyner</ENAMEX> died
in her sleep <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The story makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , and
WP fronts and runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . The widespread rumors about
her use of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">steroids</ENAMEX> during her career, made relevant by her death of heart
failure at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">age 38</TIMEX>, are mentioned prominently by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ,
not at all by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column says that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> testimony tapes were a big distraction in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> workplace
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. Trouble is, the column cites just a single workplace--that of
something called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amcat Corp.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Britain Conn.</ENAMEX> Why this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">outfit</ENAMEX> and no other?
But the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX> does go on to mention that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">300,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who
used the Internet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to view <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX>'s testimony download were at the office
at the time.

         
      
   
