
   
   
      
         
            Queen for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day</ENAMEX>

            All <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspapers</ENAMEX> lead with the same story: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> met with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The purpose of the face-to-face
meeting--the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months</TIMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">camp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>--was, of
course, to discuss testimony she might give in return for an immunity deal. And
what, exactly, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> offering? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">promised Starr</ENAMEX> she'll testify to a sexual relationship. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post hedges</ENAMEX>, saying that as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> was willing to admit to sex, but wouldn't say she was encouraged to
lie. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times give no details at all on what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> offered.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> calls the meeting a "development fraught with danger for the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">LAT</ENAMEX> describes it as "a special legal session known
as 'Queen for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Day</TIMEX>,'." Would the LAT care to explain what on earth this
means? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> paragraphs later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">non-lawyers</ENAMEX> learn that in a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">queen</ENAMEX> for a day"
session, nothing a (female?) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">defendant</ENAMEX> says can be used against her.

            A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> bit of news mentioned in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all four</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-is-in-hot-water
lead stories: a District <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> ruled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">confidant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX>
cannot claim attorney-client privilege in a criminal investigation because he
is a government <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX>. (A private <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> could claim the privilege.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> can either appeal this ruling or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> back into the grand jury <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX>.
All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> also report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> continue to spar over the
terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">attorney</ENAMEX>
would like "to sit in on Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony, have it take place at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, know in advance what it will concern and have limits on its
scope." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, reportedly, is considering the offer.

            All papers but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> have page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> stories on the proposed merger
between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell Atlantic</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GTE</ENAMEX>. The creation of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> rather
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slobberingly</ENAMEX> calls a "telecommunications <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colossus</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 21st century</TIMEX>" may be
tripped up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>, say all the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>. The merger of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> is
just <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> more instance of a trend towards consolidation in the industry.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> carries a front page story chronicling the immense success of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> relying on sweepstakes mailings to foist unwanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">magazine</ENAMEX> subscriptions
on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>. Seniors succumb because they are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) lonely; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) desirous of
excitement and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) from a generation easily convinced that a mailing is
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>." <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Just three weeks ago</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ran another front-page story
(different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX>) explaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">casinos</ENAMEX> were fleecing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">seniors</ENAMEX> are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) lonely; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) desirous of excitement and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generation</ENAMEX> with
a fondness for get-rich-quick schemes.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week</ENAMEX> column features the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> workers
show strong dedication to their jobs." The evidence: a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> and her
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">boss</ENAMEX> both say she works hard, another <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX> and another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">boss</ENAMEX> agree
that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanics</ENAMEX> work admirably hard. Also, a polling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firm</ENAMEX> finds that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">94%</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> claim to "work hard at coming out on top" while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 64%</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">non-Hispanic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> say the same. From the same <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week</ENAMEX> column we learn that
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">A House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> votes to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amish</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">14 to 17 years old</TIMEX> to work in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sawmills</TIMEX>;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor Department</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bars</ENAMEX> such work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">under age 18</TIMEX>."

         
      
   
