
   
   
      
         
            Generally <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Up To No Good</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
is alone <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> in leading with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s determination to punish
health <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurers</ENAMEX> who deny coverage to sick <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in violation of federal law.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with the rain-produced break in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> fires for
residents and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">firefighters</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Memorial Day</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX> politics story and
gives the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> fires equal billing with a profile of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with intensifying pressure on both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UAW</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> to
settle their increasingly disruptive strike.

            At issue in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Kennedy-Kassebaum</ENAMEX> law, which
guarantees <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> losing group health care coverage alternative access to
individual policies regardless of any preexisting medical condition, and
provides for uninterrupted coverage for those moving from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> job to another.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are concerned that health insurance
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are circumventing the law by discouraging sales to certain
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>, charging very high premiums or penalizing insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> who
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sell</ENAMEX> policies to those with preexisting conditions. In response, says the
paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> today will issue an order requiring that all health plans
insuring federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> not do these things.

            The LAT sums up the trouble looming for both sides and the general
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> strike: the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-week</TIMEX> stoppage is already the most expensive
ever experienced by a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">automaker</ENAMEX> and the longest since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> is
warning that as a result, its sales could plunge by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX> and
its market share from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">31 to 25 percent</NUMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> weighs in with the only other potential
drag on the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> boom: the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic meltdown. The fifty-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX>
participating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s latest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">semiannual</TIMEX> forecasting survey named the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis as the major threat facing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy and hold that it will
hit here during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next six to nine months</TIMEX> in the form of slower production
and reduced employment. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> agree that these changes will not be
drastic because our low interest rates and low inflation mean we can keep
financing big-ticket purchases cheaply. Of course, such stories would be much
more valuable to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> if they included a summary of what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's past semi-annual forecasting surveys had concluded.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" front brings news that an obscure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> has gotten a
patent for software that often performs Y2K bug fixes in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> less time
than previous tools, bringing it business from the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Citibank</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NationsBank</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior Department</ENAMEX>. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> also reports the
fix doesn't work universally.

            The death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy Rogers</ENAMEX> gets a surprising amount of coverage: sure, a
thumbnail picture/reefer at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , but also top-front-with-picture at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , below-the<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">-fold</NUMEX>-front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and a big front-page
picture/reefer at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorial (!) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">puts Proust</ENAMEX> on
the plains with, "For many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewers</ENAMEX>, the picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy Rogers</ENAMEX>, aglint in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sun</ENAMEX>, racing across the harmless West upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trigger</ENAMEX>, is a picture as invincible
to time as a childhood memory." Still, the obituaries make it clear that both
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Evans</ENAMEX> achieved something altogether missing from show
business <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>: wholesome fame based on actual wholesomeness.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> goes front-page with word that an internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense Department</ENAMEX>
investigation concluded that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pentagon</ENAMEX>'s former deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Inspector General</ENAMEX>,
retired Maj. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Gen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hale</ENAMEX>, had affairs with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX>. The
paper reports that the case is being watched closely in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, where there
are concerns that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> get treated more leniently than enlisted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. There
are other hotter background issues that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> could have also mentioned: In
light of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Flynn</ENAMEX> case, doesn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> matter show male
service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> get a different sexual deal than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">females</ENAMEX>? And, how, given his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> troubles, can <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> politically handle any eventual
disciplinary sanction against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>?

            Following in the footsteps of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s debunking <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> and academic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> now say a
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who claimed insider knowledge of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s willingness to
preemptively nuke <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> is a fraud. "He doesn't know," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who interviewed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">an hour</TIMEX>, "the most elementary facts about
what a nuclear reactor is." No further word yet from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , which broke
the preemptive strike story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> officially cherishes its "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer Principles</ENAMEX>" about lascivious
content, which basically say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> should be written so that it
could be read by a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> together at the breakfast table. But it's still
surprising to learn that actual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> actually internalize
them. Witness <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E.J. Dionne</ENAMEX> column, in which he says that when went to
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Web</ENAMEX> to look up the evangelical concept of "rapture," he got religious sites
side-by-side with porn sites. "For the record," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne</ENAMEX> immediately adds, "I
never did look at the porn sites. I knew I'd want to tell this story someday
and figured someone would ask."

         
      
   
