
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oral Arguments</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s loose lips lead. Everybody has their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX> for her supposedly
secret grand jury testimony and the general word from them is: sex with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
says the kiss-then-tell included descriptions of oral sex with him. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> said the sex happened in the small, private study down a short
hallway from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> said there were a dozen sexual encounters over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> camp has private
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> collecting information on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> that would undermine her
credibility, to be used if her testimony proves damaging.

            There is other news out of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's off-lead is the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s passage of campaign finance reform legislation that
would stop the flow of unacounted-for soft money and crack down on special
interest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> attack ads. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that the vote puts new pressure on
hostile <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> to approve the bill. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> editorial calls
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> move impressive because it occurred over the opposition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, and challenges the "do-nothing" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to pass the bill.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> editorial says and does pretty much the same. And the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> fronts all report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
committee investigating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> campaign finance practices voted yesterday
to hold <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> in contempt of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Why? For refusing to honor a
subpoena it issued for internal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> memos to her that called for the
appointment of an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> in the finance matter.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> plan for stockpiling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-germ</ENAMEX>-warfare
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> at various strategic sites, developed in record time, is now in
jeopardy. The problems include a dispute among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> concerning the merits of
such <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vaccines</ENAMEX> compared to antibiotics. The stockpile plan was developed, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, without consulting drug industry <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> about feasibility, and by a
group including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> standing to gain financially from the set-up.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FTC</ENAMEX> has
opened up an investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">alcohol</ENAMEX> advertising and has reached a settlement
with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">beer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kahlua</ENAMEX> that forced ads off television. The big issue is
how are <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">booze</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> handling marketing to young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reveals that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> hires hair-care biggie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul DeJoria</ENAMEX> (of those <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Paul Mitchell</ENAMEX> TV ads) to lecture
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>--no, not on the best kind of hairdo to hide a camera or a gun in, but
on time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>.

            The WP business section runs a story about how, with fears about
newborn switching and snatching on the rise, high-tech <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">infant</ENAMEX> monitoring systems are being put in place
in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> nationwide. The market for these has increased <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> to threefold
just in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past three years</TIMEX>. In light of that scary story of undetected baby
switching at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Virginia</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>, it's interesting to note
that, according to the paper, the devices really don't do anything to prevent
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">switching</ENAMEX>.

            For those of you who are sticklers when it comes to showbiz <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">bureaucracy</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has just the correction for you: "Because of an editing error, an
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 27</TIMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">apartment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jen Graffam-Wink</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris Wink</ENAMEX>, a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Man Group</ENAMEX>, referred incorrectly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>'s structure.
There is no head <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Blue Man</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
