
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tobacco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Lucky Strike</ENAMEX>

triumph: A federal appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Richmond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VA</ENAMEX>, ruled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Administration</ENAMEX> cannot regulate nicotine as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> without explicit
Congressional authorization. Nor, by extension, can the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> regulate
cigarettes. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2-1</ENAMEX> decision deals a crippling blow to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>'s
efforts to curb the targeting of underage <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smokers</ENAMEX>. It effectively overturns an
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> plan that required anyone under <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">26</NUMEX> to show identification before buying
cigarettes, banned cigarette vending machines from most public places, and kept
tobacco billboards away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton Administration</ENAMEX> has vowed to
appeal the decision, and the current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> regulations will remain in effect
until the appeal is resolved. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that "very little" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX>
plan had been put into effect anyhow.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> scandal is relegated to <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">A14</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , but nabs the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead and side-by-side <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pagers. There's no new
news <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, only endless speculation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> are busy
catching up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s contemplated
fudge-the-definition-of-sex defense strategy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">assesses</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
options in addressing the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>. While calling a nationally televised address
"the most likely choice," the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s lawyers
advocate a written statement instead. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> piece paints <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bleakly</ENAMEX> alone: With <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> evacuated as usual in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> (except for the
press jackals), only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea</ENAMEX> are around to keep his spirits up. The
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> story trots out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ordinary People</ENAMEX>
refrain--end this scandal soon, please.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front page story recounts in depth the extraordinary tale of a
top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Iraqi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> who defected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, after working for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX>
on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s efforts to build a nuclear <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khidhir Abdul Abas Hamza</ENAMEX>, who has
been debriefed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">paints</ENAMEX> a chilling picture of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s successful
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">deceptions</ENAMEX> against the international community, coupled with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> ignorance
about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s swift progress. The research conditions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hamza</ENAMEX> describes are
appalling: Immense pressure is reinforced by torture, and all operations are
overseen by a controlling but "illiterate" ogre--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>.

            According to another WP front-page story, starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> AT&T
will begin assessing a mandatory <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> minimum fee to new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX>. This move,
which will bring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> into line with other long distance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carriers</ENAMEX>, will
help staunch the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">annual</TIMEX> losses incurred because <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10 million</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">70 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> don't even reach this <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> minimum. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> will
exempt low-income <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">customers</ENAMEX> from the regulations.

            Recent terrorist threats have caused the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> to partially shut down its
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embassy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>, say both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> inside. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Albania</ENAMEX>
has become something of a terrorist hotbed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX>: The three
( <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">four</NUMEX> ( WP ) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Egyptians</ENAMEX> arrested there during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June and July</TIMEX>
have been identified as likely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">affiliates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist financier</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bin Ladin</ENAMEX>, whose name has surfaced repeatedly in connection with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombings</ENAMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> turned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52</TIMEX>. The celebration, complete with spice
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cake</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">goodies</ENAMEX>, is described inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style: Names & Faces</ENAMEX>." A very happy birthday it must have
been!

         
      
   
