
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dress Rehearsal</ENAMEX>

            The expected grand jury testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
gets subhead billing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's lead, which is about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
administration's revival of the claim of executive privilege in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
matter. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>'s imminent testimony below the fold (as does the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times ), leading instead with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iraqis</ENAMEX>' umpteenth snit over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
weapons inspections, which is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's top national story, and which
also gets top front placement at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . (But doesn't make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
front.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> lead states that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is prepared to testify that she
directly told to lie under oath about it, she was given suggestions it should
be kept secret. And "prepared" here, the paper specifies, means that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> going through a "final rehearsal" of her testimony with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> somehow refrains from calling it a "dress"
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rehearsal</ENAMEX>. Spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX> this way raises a question not addressed in any of
the coverage to date: How come it's ok for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to do all these dry runs?
Isn't this just coaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX>? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Newspaper</ENAMEX> makes the nifty
observation that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> marked the beginning of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> of
investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> oversells its <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> lead in saying that the latest developments mark "the first
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX> said he was ending all cooperation with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspectors</ENAMEX>.
Especially since just a few paragraphs in, the story quotes chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inspector</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Butler</ENAMEX> as saying "...there is a <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">syndrome</ENAMEX> here--going around the same
track again and again." And a little further below that, it quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Security Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> saying, "We've heard this bluster before."

            Now that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> staff <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorney</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny Breuer</ENAMEX> is invoking executive privilege
to keep from having a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> grand jury sit-down, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> usefully
documents the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s legal tacking by quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Ruff</ENAMEX>'s comments from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two months ago</TIMEX>: "We have no intention of asserting
the privilege, executive privilege, in any situation that I'm aware of."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Column One</ENAMEX>" says that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saving Private</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX>" ends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> of silence about the horrors experienced by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>
in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> ran a big front-page piece saying the
same thing. But what of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Heller</ENAMEX>'s Catch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">22</TIMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurt Vonnegut</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slaughterhouse Five</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Fussell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wartime</ENAMEX> and Doing
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Battle</ENAMEX> , or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peggy Noonan</ENAMEX>'s) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Boys of Pointe du Hoc</ENAMEX>"
speech? Isn't this just another annoying example of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Boomers</ENAMEX> mistakenly thinking
they discovered, nay, invented, something that's been around for quite a while?
(You know, like having <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> and working hard.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> follows up its front-page scoop that <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War II</ENAMEX> was
horrible with its front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shaw</ENAMEX> scoop that as internet and cable news
outlets proliferate, the pressure to be <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> is, in the quoted words of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>
Rather, "greater and stronger." Other talking heads brought on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> include
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Kovach</ENAMEX>, the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Curator of Neiman Fellowships in Journalism</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
University" (point: working fast leads to mistakes) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin Kalb</ENAMEX>, "executive
Policy" (point: being first is profitable). When was the last time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> did a
piece that didn't quote all these media <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mafiosi</ENAMEX>? And would it be too much to
ask that their ideas be more substantial than their job titles?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Books</ENAMEX>, off of
disastrous <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first-half</TIMEX> results, has hired a media investment <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">banker</ENAMEX> to explore
"strategic opportunities." It's not just that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toys</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX>" Us isn't stocking as
many books as it used to--hey, there's also the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shari Lewis</ENAMEX> death to contend
with.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the bigger challenges faced by contemporary journalism is
convincingly dressing up its desire to dig dirt in the clothes of some
principle or other. Consider the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's editorial on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>'s imminent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> appearance, which
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that her testimony "offers a welcome opportunity to turn this
investigation away from the fascinating but tangential privilege questions
about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> in which it has so long
been mired. It is a chance to get back to the core issues Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was asked
to address." Fascinating privilege questions? Core issues Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was asked
to address? Yeah, right.

         
      
   
