
   
   
      
         
and gruesome photos of wreckage from massive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> bombings at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Embassies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX>. The attacks in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nairobi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dar es Salaam</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX>, occurred less than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">five minutes</TIMEX> apart, though the worst damage was in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">At least 80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> died (including <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">8</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>) and over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1700</TIMEX> were
injured. Even as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> went to press, screams were still heard from people
trapped under the wreckage.

            Who is responsible? This is a front-page question for all papers. <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> are largely discounted; initially at least, experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> from
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> seem more likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. Though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Department</ENAMEX>
refuses to speculate on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attackers</ENAMEX>' identities, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> cites a
senior <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> as saying that "based on early circumstantial
evidence, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> were focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>." Bin
Laden is a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Saudi</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">multimillionaire</ENAMEX> who has pledged a holy war against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>, and who is widely considered responsible for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> attack in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi</ENAMEX>
Arabia which killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">19</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">airmen</ENAMEX>. Another possibility is the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Egyptian</ENAMEX> group
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Islamic Jihad</ENAMEX>, which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> issued <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-American</ENAMEX> warnings in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Egyptian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">newspaper</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al-Hayat</ENAMEX> . <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> has dispatched top-notch
investigative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teams</ENAMEX> to the scene, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> stated, "We will use
what or how long it takes."

            All papers use separate stories to spotlight the security weaknesses at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">embassies</ENAMEX> (only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's story runs inside). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's accusatory
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">headline</ENAMEX> says, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Neither Embassy Met Current Security Guidelines</ENAMEX>." The WP
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">headline</ENAMEX>, however, is more realistic-- "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Embassies Can Never Be Fully</ENAMEX>
Protected." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> writes that since the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beirut</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kuwait</ENAMEX> bombings,
more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> has been spent to upgrade certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassies</ENAMEX> to become
"state-of-the-art anti-terrorist fortresses." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tanzania</ENAMEX> were
considered relatively low security risk and thus were not among the upgrade
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>.

            The terrorist attacks relegated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Monicagate</ENAMEX> to the bottom of the front at all
papers. The latest development is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> has run afoul of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX>. Court papers unsealed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> showed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holloway Johnson</ENAMEX> ordered a probe of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> leaks. She noted the "serious and repetitive nature" of the leaks,
as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s demonstrated willingness to feed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> information.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> appealed parts of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> ruling, and got a slight break <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Monday</TIMEX>
when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Court of Appeals</ENAMEX> ruled that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> could not
question <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> or subpoena documents in the investigation. Nonetheless,
as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says, the whole matter represents a "stinging rebuke" for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>, and the investigation into the grand jury leaks continues.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs an inside story on the Internet as a time-suck (never
knew that, didya?) Specifically, it's loading web pages. The story cites a
report from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NetRatings</ENAMEX> that "the average home Internet user <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wastes</ENAMEX> just over
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">minutes</TIMEX> per day, or <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">55 hours</TIMEX> per year, waiting for web pages to load."
This otherwise depressing calculation is a persuasive argument for getting TP
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">emailed</ENAMEX> to your account--it saves you the bother of loading the page.

         
      
   
