
   
   
      
         
            Closed Doors (They're Made of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glass</ENAMEX>)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times
               , 
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX>
               , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead
with the news that, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> will release <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
videotaped grand jury testimony and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,800</NUMEX> pages of material gathered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>.
The decision was made during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a two-day</TIMEX> "closed-door" session of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX> (the top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>)
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barney Frank</ENAMEX> (the top <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX>) announced the decision at a press
conference, after which the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> traded partisan jabs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> of
"unilateral bipartisanship". <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> defines bipartisanship as
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> caving in to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>.

            The session wasn't "closed-door" in any real sense, of course, since all
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> describe each and every point the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> discussed. Every
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> mentions the remarkable partisanship displayed behind those doors.
Every article also interprets the furious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sparring</ENAMEX> as a
depressing harbinger.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s big dispute--other than whether to release--was over what to
delete from the released materials. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the proposed deletions
were of "sexually explicit material". The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> adds that some were about a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cigar</ENAMEX>, while the LAT mentions the cigar and "detailed descriptions by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> of her orgasms". (In case you're interested: <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> kept the
cigar references, while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> managed to expurgate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s orgasm
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">musings</ENAMEX>.) None of the papers catches the irony of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> introducing
sexual explicitness into the public sphere whilst <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> fight to keep it
out.

            The lead international story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is that
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> have agreed upon a financial recovery plan. Neither
paper has much more to say, since details of the deal are not yet available.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's internatioal lead says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bosnian</ENAMEX> elections didn't go the way
Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> had hoped. Instead, the surprise <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">winner</ENAMEX> is an
"ultranationalist" named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poplasen</ENAMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> failed, by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> votes, to override
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s veto of a ban on partial birth abortions. Got that? It means
partial birth abortions remain legal. The veto has already been overridden by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> hopes to pick up the required <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seats in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs a piece on rent control (in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge MA</ENAMEX>) which reports
that after price ceilings were abolished <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) poorer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> moved out; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>)
wealthier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> moved in; and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) wealthier <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> spend more money on things.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> gives prominent place to the headline "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Novice Ranchers Find Fun</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Profit</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Breeding Alpacas</ENAMEX>". Sound familiar? Maybe it's because the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ran an almost identical piece on emus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just two months</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>--substitute "emu" for each appearance of "alpaca" and the pieces are the
same (except apparently alpacas are more lucrative). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX> checked
and, astoundingly, the articles are written by different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next month</TIMEX>:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bison Are Low Fat</ENAMEX> (and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lip Smackin</ENAMEX>').

         
      
   
