
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dissing</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dissonance</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead with public and political reaction to <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Speech</ENAMEX>, which is also the
subject of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's main "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re</ENAMEX>-summoning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica L.</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>, a story that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
puts together with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX>'s post-speech support of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husband</ENAMEX> for its lead.
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> of the fronts feature pix of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Family</ENAMEX> walking across the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> lawn to start what would have to count as the worst family vacation in
history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddy</ENAMEX> is there too, on a longer leash than his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> will be on for
some time.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> draws the blinds <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the morning</TIMEX> after and sees some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>--including <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> normally <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">allies</ENAMEX>--so "infuriated" that "it
was clear the sordid spectacle would not be put to rest quickly." Looming large
in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s survey are the reactions of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">senators</ENAMEX>, both
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Feinstein</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s remarks left her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">trust</ENAMEX> in his
credibility "deeply shattered." And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Boxer</ENAMEX> is quoted saying that "he
should have told us the truth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months ago</TIMEX>" and that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
relationship was "wrong--clear, black-and-white, no-room-for-ambiguity wrong."
The paper points out that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boxer</ENAMEX>'s comments were surprisingly negative given
that she is related to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> by marriage.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> also note the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Feinstein</ENAMEX> reaction, and go
on to note that the ranks of distancing <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> include such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> bigfeet as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Gephardt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Daschle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Hamilton</ENAMEX>. The unwavering support
expressed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> is widely noted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USAT</ENAMEX> quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ashcroft</ENAMEX> calling for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s resignation. Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Delay</ENAMEX> urged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to resign, the paper describes the general
reaction among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> as "unusually tame." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says instant
polls show that the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> were satisfied with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s
statement and wanted the matter dropped. Similar observations are given
prominent placement by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> . But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> don't seem
to notice that this shows there is a serious divergence between what they and
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> think is news. For instance, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front gives
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">roughly</NUMEX> equal play to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stories: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) a discussion of whether or not the tie
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> wore on the day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> first testified to the grand
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> was a gift from her and hence worn as some sort of signal to her, and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
the health risks of breast feeding in the undeveloped world, the location of
most of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">600,000</NUMEX> new cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> among <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> off-lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> has arrested <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspects</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombings</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> were seized in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Khyber Pass</ENAMEX> while trying to cross into
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. The previously arrested suspect in the case, says the paper, has
said one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> is a pivotal bomb plot <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participant</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> are
apparently <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">devotees</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama bin Laden</ENAMEX>, the multimillionaire supporter of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorists</ENAMEX> believed to be living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, and the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kenya</ENAMEX>
together on the same <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">plane</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is urging
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> to expel bin Laden. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> continues to emphasize
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> have apparently not heard with their own ears from the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">suspect</ENAMEX> about bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>'s operations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> continues to pass
along in increasing detail what he apparently told <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX>: that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bin Laden</ENAMEX> runs and finances a terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>, which pulled off the embassy
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bombings</ENAMEX>. Today, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pakistanis</ENAMEX> were told that the bin Laden force numbers <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4,000 to 5,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> and that
it has taken part in prior armed actions, including attacks against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> forces
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Somalia</ENAMEX>, resulting in the deaths of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldiers</ENAMEX>.

            The USAT front and the insides of the other papers report that on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the "Real IRA," an IRA splinter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> opposed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX>
peace accord, issued a telephoned statement admitting that it set off the bomb
in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Omagh</ENAMEX> that killed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">28</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, including a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>. The group
apologized for the deaths, saying that they occurred only because its
evacuation warnings were not properly followed.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pope</ENAMEX> is healthy enough to keep a
busy schedule, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> and those of other <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are rushing to iron out the logistics of covering his funeral. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CBS</ENAMEX>
News, for instance, reportedly just paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180,000</NUMEX> for the exclusive use of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">terrace</ENAMEX> overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vatican</ENAMEX> for live "stand-ups" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Rather</ENAMEX> and its
other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anchors</ENAMEX>. And while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABC</ENAMEX> is said to have just obtained exclusive funeral
rights to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNN</ENAMEX> is rumored to be negotiating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> itself
for sole access to a prime property. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> quotes the headline of an
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Italian</ENAMEX> newspaper story about the scramble: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Pope: Heaven Can Wait</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Networks</ENAMEX> Cannot."

         
      
   
