
   
   
      
         
            The <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Thong Show</ENAMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> weekend papers lead with summary and analysis of the just-released
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report. The papers highlight the document's main points as: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> broke his oath of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> through perjury and obstruction of justice, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10</NUMEX> sexual encounters with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, all in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">House, 3</ENAMEX>) the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> committed <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">11</NUMEX> separate acts that are possible grounds
for impeachment. The papers all describe the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> counter-spin, too--<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> is a vicious personal attack that fails to demonstrate any impeachable
offense.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> declined comment
about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> breakfast. He did, however, make
his most emotive expression of regret to date--including a direct apology to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>. He also announced that he has ordered his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> to prepare a "vigorous defense" against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead also reveals some sordid details of the affair including
the infamous cigar story, simultaneous engagements in oral sex and phone
conversations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> rendezvous
immediately after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Easter Sunday</ENAMEX> services. The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> all note that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s justification for including such prurient details was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
numerous denials of having "sexual relations" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> according to the
legal definition established in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
lead gets right to the political consequences of the report--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> must now
decide if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s case merits the start of impeachment proceedings. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> calls the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">445</NUMEX>-page (or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">453</NUMEX>-page according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> ) document
"relentlessly accusative" and says it alleges crimes for which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
could be prosecuted even if he leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>. The article calls accusations
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> lied under oath <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> times "perhaps the most damaging portion of
the report," but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> sections about abuse of power and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witness</ENAMEX> tampering
"less conclusive."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> relate the tale of intern <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> raising her jacket and
revealing thong underwear to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Papers</ENAMEX> is puzzled by
the logistics of such a divulgence and begs to know (but is not told by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">papers</ENAMEX>) exactly where and how she was wearing a thong that became visible
simply by lifting her jacket. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> article also reveals <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
denial of charges that he harassed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Willey</ENAMEX>. According to the report,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> "he would never approach a small-breasted
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times Analysis</ENAMEX> piece reports relief among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> that
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s report contained no new allegations against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>. One
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">expert</ENAMEX> thinks that with the lack of fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dirt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> may have
"turned a corner in his favor." The piece also notes another sign of relief:
the Dow was up <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">179.96</NUMEX> points on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">All three</NUMEX> weekend fronts include stories on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yevgeny Primakov</ENAMEX>'s confirmation
as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The papers all note his appointment of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">favorites</ENAMEX> to top government posts, a sure sign of movement
towards tighter regulation of markets. Interestingly, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Primakov</ENAMEX>'s invocation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDR</ENAMEX> and the New Deal as an example of successful
government intervention in an economic crisis.

         
      
   
