
   
   
      
         
            Rocks and <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Hard Places</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with a federal appeals court ruling
that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> are not relieved from testifying before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kenneth</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> by any so-called "protective function" privilege. The story
is also the New York
Times 's off-lead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> Staff Must
Testify"--couldn't be straighter. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's adds mention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>
case. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 's highlights the political angle--"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr Wins An</ENAMEX>
Appeal on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Privilege</ENAMEX>." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , in its front-page story on the
decision, high up and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">succinctly</ENAMEX> describes the significance: moving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> "one
step closer to obtaining testimony from perhaps the last impartial and credible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">witnesses</ENAMEX> in his investigation." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> goes with the death, after
suddenly taking ill while meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoys</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s most prominent
political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prisoner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moshood Abiola</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has promised a full
and prompt <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">autopsy</ENAMEX>. The story is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's off-lead. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads
with the conviction of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">19-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Ukrainian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrant gangbanger</ENAMEX> for the
murder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">son</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby story</ENAMEX> also grabs the "talker" slot on the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> top front, and runs above the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fold. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts
it inside.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby</ENAMEX> story big, including a front-page picture of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">defendant Mikail Markhasev</ENAMEX> looking back at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cosby</ENAMEX> family <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> who were in
court (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Cosby</ENAMEX> wasn't there) as his fate was announced. The story also has
the most details from the trial evidence, such as running quotes from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Markhasev</ENAMEX>'s jailhouse letters to another <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">inmate</ENAMEX>, in which he says that he went
to kill a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dealer</ENAMEX> who wasn't home and then came upon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ennis Cosby</ENAMEX> fixing a
flat tire, and details about how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">informant</ENAMEX> who turned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Markhasev</ENAMEX> in to get a
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Enquirer</ENAMEX> reward testified that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX> told him
he'd killed <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Cosby</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">informant</ENAMEX> testified that "Markhasev
had said he shot a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says the testimony was "I
killed a [racial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">epithet</ENAMEX>]." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> renders the confession thus: "I shot
the n-----."

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that the new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$217 billion</NUMEX>
federal highway program may have a problem: with the construction trades
already stretched tight, new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> to carry it out may be hard to find.
Another problem, noted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> in its front-page "cover story," is that
new highway construction is apt to raise to "epidemic" proportions an already
high accident rate among rock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">quarry workers</ENAMEX>. This could be avoided, the paper
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">notes</ENAMEX>, by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a few hours</TIMEX> of training for new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hires</ENAMEX>. But there's a catch: federal
law prohibits enforcing safety training rules at quarries. (This brute fact is
reminiscent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s recent story about how you can't sue your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX>.) The
provision has been kept in place, says the story, by a stone industry that
gives <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> to congressional campaigns.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> flags its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX> earnings story with "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola</ENAMEX> Surprises
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Analysts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Posting Slim Operating Profit</ENAMEX>," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes the other
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> with "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Motorola Reports</ENAMEX> Earnings Plunge<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">/2</NUMEX>nd-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quarter Operating Profit</ENAMEX>
Negligible."

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" is sentencing itself to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Corrections</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
recent infractions. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s column asserted that since running a story
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about</NUMEX> a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Pakistani</ENAMEX> claiming to have inside knowledge of his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s nuclear
war plans against <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> has not revisited the story even though
both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> have reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is likely a fraud.
In fact, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> has run <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> stories reporting on the erosion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
credibility. The stories ran inside, but during a visit to the USAT
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">newsroom</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" was assured that if and when the paper issues a full
retraction, it will appear, as per <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> policy, on the front page where
the original story ran. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> stated that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> have
never owned a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">home</ENAMEX>. Several real estate-oriented <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> have pointed out that
this is not true--for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few years</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the early 80s</TIMEX> they did.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> editorialized that it was inconceivable that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wayne</ENAMEX> ever appear in the same movie. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> admits it
is conceivable, because it's actual: the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> starred together in "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dark</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Command</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
