
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Airstrike Hits Northwest</ENAMEX>

            Local stories lead at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> , but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' top international
stories are about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York</ENAMEX>
Times also leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>--more analysis of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
upcoming trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>. Expectations for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> summit are not
high, given the weakened status of both <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX>. In paragraph <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> draws a portentous parallel between the teetering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>, who met with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonid Brezhnev</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five weeks</TIMEX> after returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> resigned.

            The LAT top international story reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> acting prime
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viktor Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s voiced assurances on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> will
pursue market reforms and democracy. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> cover
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s remarks inside; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> adds that his statement, "there
will be no return to the past," may have been intended to mollify the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>, which is scheduled to give <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.3 billion</NUMEX>
loan installment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. However, a WP front-page article
headlined "<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> in Reverse" effectively belies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s assertions,
saying, "Perhaps more than at any time [since] the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> collapse, the
concepts of liberal market reform and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">democracy</ENAMEX> are in retreat."

            Also in the front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> roundup: a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> article profiles a
decidedly "undemocratic" figure in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> politics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">billionaire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris</ENAMEX>
Berezovsky, who is believed to have been instrumental in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chernomyrdin</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">reappointment</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a colorful piece on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX>' survival
strategies during the currency crisis.

            The papers continue coverage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilots</ENAMEX>' strike at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Airlines</ENAMEX>,
which began at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. All <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> flights are grounded at
least until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">midweek</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has decided not to intervene for the
moment.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-page article says that criticism of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary of State</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madeleine Albright</ENAMEX> is mounting. The reason: her tough talk has produced few
results, especially in a time of multiple international crises. However, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> also quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> who say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, scandal-dogged and
an inchworm on foreign affairs, may muffle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX>'s activism.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Outlook</ENAMEX>" lands a double-strike against the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> cruise
missile attacks. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> article decries "vigilante justice," and says that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> erred by declaring itself in effect "free to make its own rules"
against an amorphous terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>. Another piece questions the wisdom of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military strategy. It argues that while cruise <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> strikes may be
cheap in terms of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> lives (and thus are politically safe), the war
against terrorism requires a "long-term and unwavering commitment." This means
a concentrated campaign using ground <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> and special <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> as well as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">cruise</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missiles</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Week In Review</ENAMEX>," meanwhile, shudders at the
worldwide malaise of weak leadership.

            Good news for the art world: An inside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> article cheers the
country-music-loving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>, who has managed
to twang on Congressional artstrings though he has only been in the job two
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX>. In his optimistic view, "the federal role in the arts should be equal
to our role in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX>."

            A lengthy but transfixing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Style</ENAMEX>" article <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">peers</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">chambers</ENAMEX>
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church of Satan</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">San Francisco</ENAMEX>-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> whose roster of twisted
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">rituals</ENAMEX> includes "satanic baptisms" and the use of nude <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> as altars. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church's</ENAMEX> charismatic and controversial <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">founder</ENAMEX> recently died (presumably, went
to hell), which may catalyze the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institution</ENAMEX>'s demise. But devoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">followers</ENAMEX>
(who can occasionally be found jamming at the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Lucifer's Hammer death</ENAMEX>-rock
scene) vow to carry the satanic torch high.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-page piece reports that surfing the Internet causes
increased depression. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> study found that one Internet <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">hour</NUMEX> per week
made <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">participants</ENAMEX> one percent more depressed. In addition, their circle of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> shrank by an average of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2.7</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Yikes! Working <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">35</NUMEX>+ <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> a week, TP
is on course to wind up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 35 percent</NUMEX> more depressed and lose over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">94.5</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
