
   
   
      
         
            Bankrupture

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with a story tipped <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> --the imminent tightening of bankruptcy laws. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s passage of an amendment to the tobacco tax bill that
would provide a tax break to low- and middle-income married <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes with its disclosure of a secret agreement under which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>
Farm Insurance agreed to pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">117</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeowner</ENAMEX> policy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX> who
suffered damage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northridge</ENAMEX> earthquake. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX> admitted no
wrongdoing, the paper explains that--as confirmed by an internal memo it
obtained--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, without notifying <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policyholders</ENAMEX>, lowered coverage limits
and backed off its previous policy of guaranteed property <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">replacement</ENAMEX>. The
outcome could, says the paper, expose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s richest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">insurer</ENAMEX>,
to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of similar claims by other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">policyholders</ENAMEX> whose coverage was
likewise covertly pared.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> bill says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">debtors</ENAMEX> whose earnings top the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> median family
income (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $51,500</NUMEX> for a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>) and who can repay <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 20</NUMEX>
percent of their debts, will have to. The bill was backed by credit card
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lenders</ENAMEX> (who, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , have made campaign
contributions at twice the rate of the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>), who stand to recover
plenty once it's implemented. But, say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , many
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, think the bill punishes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who've
fallen on hard times while not holding the credit card <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">issuers</ENAMEX> responsible for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">promiscuous</ENAMEX> marketing. Additionally, they argue it will further hamper the
ability of ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spouses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">debtors</ENAMEX> to receive alimony and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX> support. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> note that some of the tougher aspects of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX> may fall by the wayside when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> takes up the issue later this
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> lead details classic legislative logrolling: The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.10</NUMEX> per
pack tax increase in the tobacco bill, originally all channeled to
smoking-related programs, offended many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> as classic tax-and-spend,
but <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> votes were picked up when the tax-cut provision was added. The
paper notes that the bill now not only rewards <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> who otherwise would
suffer the "marriage penalty" at tax time, but also those who would not. The
Times also observes that un-related obstacles to bringing in additional
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> votes remain, including whether and/or how much the bill should fund
tobacco price supports or programs for converting tobacco-based <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> to
other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enterprises</ENAMEX>.

            In what a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> top front story calls the "most significant legal
decision yet" on school vouchers, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wisconsin Supreme Court</ENAMEX> held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Milwaukee</ENAMEX> could spend public monies to send <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> to religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> said that this was not ruled out by current <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Wisconsin</ENAMEX> law or the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Amendment</ENAMEX> because it had neither the purpose nor the effect of advancing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">religion</ENAMEX>. This story is also on the USAT front and runs inside at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' consensus is that this decision is headed
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's off-lead tells of a widening schism between traditionally tight <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">partners</ENAMEX>: big
business and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>. It's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the age-old</TIMEX> conflict between
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ideologues</ENAMEX> and accomodationists. Right now the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> is taking
business-annoying <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">stands</ENAMEX> against increased exports to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> and against
additional <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> funding of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Monetary Fund</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> has a top front-page story about a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>'s
unprecedented award of punitive damages (as part of a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million judgement</NUMEX>) to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">survivors</ENAMEX> of a dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">smoker</ENAMEX> who had sued the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williamson Tobacco Co.</ENAMEX>
The story, by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myron Levin</ENAMEX>, notes that the
decision is only the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courtroom</ENAMEX> loss ever for a tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in such a
suit, and is certain to trigger a slew of similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> cases and hence to
further dim any fleeting hopes the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> had of gaining blanket
legal liability protection. The story runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and is flagged in the front-page news box at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that in an apparent attempt to spare <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> embarrassment on his trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> there ordered bookstores
to remove a popular new book detailing the various <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sex
scandals. The book is called "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>: A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Strong Drives</ENAMEX>."

            The lead story in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fed</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX>'s exuberant remarks about the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy. "The current economic
performance.is as impressive as any I have witnessed in my near <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">half-century</TIMEX> of
daily observation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> economy," he's quoted as testifying to a
congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>. "It is possible that we have moved 'beyond history.'"
This story is also on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front, the front of the LAT
business section, and runs inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> . Of course, everybody hopes
it's true, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have also moved a little beyond history: Somehow
these Quotations from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al</ENAMEX> stories never mention that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenspan</ENAMEX> once, as
an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX>, gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Keating</ENAMEX>'s financial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">empire</ENAMEX> a clean bill of
health too.

         
      
   
