
   
   
      
         
            Service Without A Smile

            The dramatic court fight over just how secret the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> is supposed
to be--going <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to the desk of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX>
at the request of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX>--leads at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead instead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed Martin Corp.</ENAMEX>'s decision, in
the face of government antitrust objections, to abandon its planned <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.3</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">billion</ENAMEX> acquisition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop Grumman Corp.</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>, who handles emergency matters for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> federal courts
(and who, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> note, is coming into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">town</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Innsbruck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Austria</ENAMEX>, where
he was teaching a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> course) is getting the case of what to do about subpoenas issued by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>
to several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> protective detail
because <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> a federal appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> unanimously refused to quash them.
Some of the language used by the appeals court <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> was quite strident. "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> have literally and figuratively declared war on the
independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX>," wrote one, quoted all around. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls the
appeals <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> pass a "resounding defeat" for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>.

            The papers note that top presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Cockell</ENAMEX>--pictured on
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> top fronts--was so distracted by the
events that he accepted being temporarily relieved of his presidential duties
until the matter is resolved. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cockell</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> that
"being compelled to testify goes against everything he's been trained to do,"
but that on the other hand, "He's a law enforcement <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>....He's not about
to go with a contempt route or lie."

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s involvement of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> amounts to a "high <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> confidentiality is the most contentious issue yet in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
says some senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX> argued against filing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
appeal because of the long odds.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> pullback "signals the end of major mergers in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">nation</ENAMEX>'s military industry." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company board</ENAMEX> voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> to end
the takeover, which had already been approved by both sets of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">stockholders</ENAMEX> and
which would have created the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">military contractor</ENAMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the decision was made because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> couldn't see how to
avoid a court fight. The deal, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , is the largest ever undone
because of government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> stemmed from a fear that the
deal would leave <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> in control of so much of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northrop</ENAMEX>'s electronics
business that competition would be suppressed and prices driven up. The
Times quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> antitrust <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Klein</ENAMEX> applauding the development.
(He did not, however, say he's pleased that the decision leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American</ENAMEX>
service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> free to combine <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> and radar systems as he/she sees
fit.)

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front section cover story on the closeness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">presidents</ENAMEX> they protect reports that they routinely hold him by
his belt when he goes into a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>, and have been known to disguise themselves
as cap-and-gowned <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> at graduation speeches and as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">priests</ENAMEX> during papal
visits. Not to mention that they go through his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dresser drawers</ENAMEX> looking for
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bugs</ENAMEX> and often follow him in to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bathroom</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> have signed up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s upcoming trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. The budgets of
many news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organizations</ENAMEX>, the paper explains, have been stretched thin by
travels with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable Source"</ENAMEX> column reports that both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelsea Clinton</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> were named to a list of "non-anorexic achievers" put out by
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lane Bryant</ENAMEX>, the plus-sized <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX>'s clothing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. All the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> on the list
are, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PR</ENAMEX> sheet, "accomplished, fashionable and beautiful."
The column then goes on to quite sensibly wonder what it is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> has
accomplished.

         
      
   
