
   
   
      
         
            How Now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the Dow plunge on jitters about
the spread of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic crisis. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> go with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>'s show-of-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> flights over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , what touched off the latest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX>-nturn was the yen's sinking to an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight-year</TIMEX> low against the dollar. This
is bad, explain the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, because it could prolong the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> slowdown by
making exports from neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> more expensive. But like
all stock market moves, this one is overdetermined: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also cites a
continued string of bad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">quarterly</TIMEX> earnings reports. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's story
emphasizes growing governmental <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>, quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Blair</ENAMEX>'s assessment that
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West</ENAMEX>'s economies "will not emerge from this turmoil without being affected
by it," and a senior <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX>'s revelation that communications between
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> "are getting testier, and there is pessimism here about
whether <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> has any conception about how to stop digging the hole it's in."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> explains that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> thinks <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>'s banking system needs a
radical revamp to get out from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">under hundreds of billions</NUMEX> of bad loans, but
fears that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> are reluctant to allow the widespread bank failures and
loan foreclosures this would entail. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> adds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> press is
making similar criticisms of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> report that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 80</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> warplanes of
varying mission types were involved in a mission that put <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">68</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">fighters</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">several hours</TIMEX>. The
"primary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">target</ENAMEX>" of the exercise, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX>,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>, meaning that the intent was to make it
clear to him that he has to stop the attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX>
and start peace talks with them. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX> is meeting
with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, in a preparatory <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">40 minute</TIMEX> phone
call with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> said he would express in the meeting a strong
preference for a diplomatic resolution. While this makes it sound as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX>
is on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>, a separate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story inside reports that in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s defense <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">minister</ENAMEX> bluntly dressed down the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> of
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Joint Chiefs</ENAMEX> over the timing of the air exercises. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> open
to a vigorous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> military response to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Senators</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Hagel</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> reports that to maximize the show of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Serbians</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> had asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NATO</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">aircraft</ENAMEX> to come in low, and that some
came in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as low as 2,000</NUMEX> feet. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> doesn't point out that this is getting
towards the flight profile involved in that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine</ENAMEX> flight that hit the ski
lift, suggesting that such low flying is not without its applications in this
theater of operations and not necessarily a sign of joyriding.

            While the other papers' reports of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the day</TIMEX>'s events in and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>
emphasize the details of the air activity, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">lead</ENAMEX> instead focuses
on the reactions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yugoslavians</ENAMEX>, who it depicts as "undeterred." The paper
points out in its top paragraphs that state-owned <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Yugoslavian</ENAMEX> television called
the flights "an international scandal," and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milosevic</ENAMEX>'s forces
nevertheless continued their attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">villages</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> area, driving
more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Albania</ENAMEX>. The other papers also tell of the attacks and the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, but not nearly so high in their dispatches. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> has a
top-of-the-front photo of a long line of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">refugees</ENAMEX>, many of them <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>,
following a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">soldier</ENAMEX>, the whole scene looking like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pied Piper of</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hamelin</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunbeam</ENAMEX>'s decision to fire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chainsaw Al" Dunlop</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX> gets a
lot of front-page coverage, inordinate really, given the relative size of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. But the LAT front-page piece offers an explanation: the move
signifies the "demise of the slash-and-burn turnarounds of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 90s</TIMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> has the best headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Chainsaw Al Gets</ENAMEX>
Cut."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> both run stories inside reporting that in an
interview with a conservative talk show <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> called homosexuality a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sin</ENAMEX>, like <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>, kleptomania and sex addiction.

            In a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed, literary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scholar</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A.N. Wilson</ENAMEX> points out the shakiness
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Baptists</ENAMEX>' biblical justification for their recently announced
doctrine that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wives</ENAMEX> should "graciously submit" to their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">husbands</ENAMEX>. Does this
mean, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilson</ENAMEX> wonders, thinking of other <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Bible</ENAMEX> passages, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern</ENAMEX>
Baptists condone slavery, or pool all their property, or abjure money lending
or investment? And does the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Southern Baptist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Convention</ENAMEX> embrace pacifism?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Reliable Source"</ENAMEX> column passes along <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>'s reaction to
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> fab final: ""I tell you, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jackson</ENAMEX> is unbelievable,
isn't he? "

            In its recent obituary of a legendary cold war <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> suggested
that he was the conduit via which the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> arranged for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Vietnamese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generals</ENAMEX> to
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">assassinate South Vietnam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ngo Dinh Diem</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>. Today, a letter
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> who once interviewed the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spy</ENAMEX> claims that to the dead <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>'s
knowledge, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authorities</ENAMEX> never approved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diem</ENAMEX>'s assassination. The author of
this anti-conspiratorial missive? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Stone</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
