
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU Starin</ENAMEX>'?

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s announcement of new federal
enforcement policies governing nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX>. The story is also on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
but absent from the other fronts, an odd elision for a slow news day in a
country getting grayer by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the minute</TIMEX>. The top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> vote, despite much previous conservative
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consternation</ENAMEX>, to maintain current levels of financial support for the National
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Endowment for the Arts</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> 's top national story details <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the five-month</TIMEX>
manhunt for suspected abortion clinic bomber <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Rudolph</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s nursing home plan, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , will require more
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">random</ENAMEX> inspections at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekends</TIMEX> and impose immediate civil monetary
penalties on serious or chronic violators. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> sums up the situation
to which this is a response: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Two-thirds</ENAMEX> of nursing <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">homes</ENAMEX> are not in full
compliance with federal standards. And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> explains the political
timing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s announcement: A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX> report to be
released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> will make "explosive" charges of lax federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">enforcement</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> sees the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> NEA turnabout as a new comfort level created
by recently imposed limits on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s grant-giving in general and a fresh
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> decision allowing limits on the funding of indecent art in
particular. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> instead sees the influence of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> elections,
going so far as to call the aforementioned new grant limits "political cover"
for long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> who voted yes. The vote, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> continues, also
reflected anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> sentiment because under the new endowing rules New
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">York</ENAMEX>, long the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>'s largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">beneficiary</ENAMEX>, can receive <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">no more than 15 percent</NUMEX>
of all direct grant monies.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">200</ENAMEX> law enforcement trackers braving rough
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">terrain</ENAMEX>, boiling temperatures and <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">snakes</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Carolina</ENAMEX> woods in search
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rudolph</ENAMEX> have not garnered any new clues since a neighbor had a run-in with
him near his <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">hometown</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> made off with an ex-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neighbor</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">pick-up</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">truck</ENAMEX> and some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">food</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>, says the story, expresses grudging
admiration for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rudolph</ENAMEX>'s outdoor skills. The piece also notes that the last
movie <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudolph</ENAMEX> rented at the local video store before going underground was the
psychological thriller "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Game</ENAMEX>." (Oh, he's the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>.)

            The LAT front reports that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">consortium</ENAMEX> of software companies
including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> is close to settling its dispute with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
public school system over illegal copies of programs made by school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>.
An outright payment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> as well as administrative and replacement
costs will mean that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> will be out <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.8 million</NUMEX> originally earmarked
for educational purposes. In other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> news, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gates</ENAMEX> will focus on products and delegate most <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">day-to-day</TIMEX> business operations
to his No. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ballmer</ENAMEX>. In the testosterone-addled world of big deal biz,
there's no higher compliment than the description of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballmer</ENAMEX> given to the
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> stock <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX>: "He's a
trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">killer</ENAMEX>."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX>, contending that its name is
being tarnished, has filed a federal lawsuit against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">operators</ENAMEX> of a sexually
explicit Web site that features a secret camera purportedly spying on
scantily- but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYU</ENAMEX>-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">logoed</NUMEX>-clad women <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> romping in their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">dormitory</ENAMEX>. The
paper says university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> said they first learned of the Web site from a
Daily <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">News</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporter</ENAMEX>. (Yeah, right.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university</ENAMEX>'s housing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX>,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , was then called in and--through a grueling review of the
Web site, no doubt--ascertained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">rooms</ENAMEX> depicted are not on <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">campus</ENAMEX>.
Another clue: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> aren't discussing feminism.

         
      
   
