
   
   
      
         
            Incomplete Sentences

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the New York
Times lead with the passage of a major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> overhaul. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> goes with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Tobacco</ENAMEX>'s negotiations with
numerous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> in an attempt to settle their claims, which remain in the wake
of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' failure to pass comprehensive tobacco legislation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s ruling that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> may not sue <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Chemical</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co.</ENAMEX> for any alleged harm caused by its breast implant subsidiary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Corning</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> points out this limits implant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">plaintiffs</ENAMEX> to a share of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">pool</ENAMEX> of money in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Corning</ENAMEX> settlement announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. None of the
other leads even makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> 's front--hey, it's the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silicone</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX> leads supply the bill's basic facts: it establishes an outside
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> designed to trim the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>'s powers and shifts the burden of proof in
tax cases from the filer to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IRS</ENAMEX>. And both have the tacked-on provision
shortening the holding period required for the optimal tax treatment of capital
gains (although only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> mentions that this will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13 billion</NUMEX> over
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next decade</TIMEX>.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> gets into details about the organizational
overhaul that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> does not. On the other hand, who do you think gave a
clearer account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Gumbyesque</ENAMEX> history with the bill? The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says, "Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX> had opposed the bill in its early
stages <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, the measure built up unstoppable momentum after a series of
hearings in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Finance Committee</ENAMEX> laid out horror stories from
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">taxpayers</ENAMEX>..." while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> puts it thus: "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, who initially resisted
the overhaul, now says he looks forward to signing the bill."

            The tobacco/<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> talks broke up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports, over the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>' demands for an up-front payment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about $20 billion</NUMEX>, twice the amount
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> offered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s negotiated settlement, left in limbo by
the failure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to implement it. But, the paper points out, there
is certainly pressure to continue talking: in the form of more bills in the
making that could hit the cigarette <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> with a large tax surcharge.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Grossberg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Peterson</ENAMEX> were respectively sentenced to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">® and 2 years</TIMEX> in connection with the death of their newborn at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Delaware</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motel</ENAMEX>. Compare the two front-page headlines on the story: WP : "Pair
Whose <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby Was Left in Trash Get Short Terms</ENAMEX>" and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> : "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Teen-Agers Get</ENAMEX>
Terms in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Prison</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Baby's Death</ENAMEX>." Doesn't the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> headline better
communicate the gravity of the action and the incommensurability of the
sentence?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story inside reporting that a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Miami</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executive</ENAMEX> was
charged with soliciting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> in foreign contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democratic</ENAMEX> election
campaigns. The story doesn't mention what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> tips in the headline
of its version and plays high up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>: that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX>.

            The Wall
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> separate suicides
by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> in and around <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent months</TIMEX> have the service
rattled.

            "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" wants to make a clean breast of the mistake it made
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, when it guessed that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> had not made a fuss about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow Corning</ENAMEX> implant settlement because the news broke after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> went to
bed. Actually, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> didn't have to make a fuss--it had the story the day
*before.*

            At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> Page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> meeting, the editorial top <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">guns</ENAMEX> at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> were rightly wowed by the stellar photograph that graces the top
front <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. It's a geometrically pleasing and emotionally charged
picture of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sons</ENAMEX> at their firefighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s funeral. After all the
expense and complications the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> has experienced putting color
pictures on the front page, it might be a little difficult for the brass to
admit that the picture has something else going for it: its main colors are
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">blue</ENAMEX> and white, giving it the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moody</ENAMEX> feel of...<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">B&W</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
