
   
   
      
         
            Vici, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veni, Video</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> lead with congressional <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX>' push
At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , where the lead is local primary results,
the video is the top national story. At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> ,
state and local election returns lead, and the top national story is further
polling indicating that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are increasingly dubious
about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s moral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">character</ENAMEX>, most still don't think he should be impeached
or forced to resign.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX>--who
are in the majority there--will vote either <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> to make the video
(and other evidence <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Starr</ENAMEX> turned over) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX>. The paper explains that
although grand jury testimony must be kept secret, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is not covered by
that restriction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that release would mean the videotape could
be airing on TV <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>. (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last weekend</TIMEX>, the book, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>, the movie.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next weekend</TIMEX>--scratch and sniff?)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead stresses the rancor inside the committee the video has
caused, calling <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> "infuriated." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">front-page NYT</ENAMEX> story cite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s behavior on the tape as the reason
for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concern</ENAMEX>: there are times in his testimony when, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> ,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> "reacted angrily," and is "visibly upset." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> "even erupted at a couple of points" (Note to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX>: Insert own joke
here). He is also, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , shown repeatedly refusing to answer
some questions. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> quotes the assessment of a congressional aide
familiar with the tape: "devastating."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that censure is losing ground among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bigfeet</ENAMEX>--not a serious enough punishment, they say. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> lead
reports that at a meeting between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX>, at
least <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawmaker</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should consider resigning. The WP
reports that at that meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Biden</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> might be better
off if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> resigned, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX> emphasized then and later that he wasn't
urging resignation. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> has a similar account of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biden</ENAMEX>'s remark. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Senators</ENAMEX> besides the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> at the meeting privately
told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> should step down.

            A sense of what should be engaging the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> more than all of this comes
with a reading of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> editorial about the current situation in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Serbia</ENAMEX> .
Various <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">diplomats</ENAMEX> are quoted claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Serbian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">command</ENAMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slobodan Milosevic</ENAMEX> have shot many ethnic <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Albanians</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX>, and through a
scorched-earth policy are fixing to let many more--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX>--starve to death. This disaster cannot be ended, writes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> resolve to use force, resolve that, the paper notes,
has been altogether missing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>. "The longer Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> dithers," the editorial concludes, "the greater the costs will be."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> say that some of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> hardest hit by the region's economic crisis are now in a
<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">depression</ENAMEX>, meaning of a much longer duration and with much more unemployment
than a recession. Cited are <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">South Korea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Thailand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hong Kong</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Malaysia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, while not in a depression yet, is, reports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its worst recession</TIMEX> since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWII</ENAMEX>.

            Reading the various obituaries, it's been hard to know what to finally make
of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wallace</ENAMEX>. Was his late-in-life outreach to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">blacks</ENAMEX> genuine or a selfish
bit of pre-<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">obit cosmetics</ENAMEX>? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> op-ed page brings the assessment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rep.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lewis</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> of the civil rights
movement, who was seriously injured by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>'s thuggy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Selma</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewis</ENAMEX>
says that "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> deserves recognition for seeking redemption for his
mistakes, for his willingness to change and to set things right with those he
harmed and with his God."

            The main <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece reports
that the moderate "<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">New Democrat</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>, with its "values agenda" of
such issues as V-chips for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TVs</ENAMEX>, more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> leave and increased parental
responsibility, is feeling particularly betrayed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. A
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorist</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">wing</ENAMEX> does note however, "The fact of the matter is, the
New <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> never had an adultery position...."

         
      
   
