
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hail</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farewell</ENAMEX> . . . At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX>

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> testified before a federal grand jury <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>,
and the surprisingly swift development captured the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">leads</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX>
papers--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , the New York
Times , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were cleared to testify when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX> denied a last-ditch DOJ appeal to stay their testimony. Even
before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> issued his decision ("just <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four minutes</TIMEX> before a high-<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>
deadline," says the ever-dramatic WP ), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX> summoned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courthouse</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two hours</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> hearings. Such
was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s haste that he had to use a different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>--one that has never
previously handled the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter--to hear the testimony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Cockell</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodyguard</ENAMEX>, did not testify though he may be called <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.

            Among the legal subtexts to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>'s decision: Even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
agrees to hear the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>'s case that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> should not be
allowed to testify--and, further, in the unlikely event that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>
overturns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Court of Appeals</ENAMEX>' decision discounting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>
claim of "protective function privilege"--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX>'s testimony in the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> matter will stand. In a widely quoted statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> said,
"Disclosure of past events will not affect the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>'s relationship with
his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">protectors</ENAMEX> in the future." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> will hear more
testimony by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.

            The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> burial of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s last <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">czar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas II</ENAMEX>, and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>--<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years to the day</TIMEX> after their gory <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar</ENAMEX> deaths the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ural mountains</ENAMEX>--takes front
space at all papers. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> decided to attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Petersburg</ENAMEX> ceremony <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">barely 24 hours</TIMEX> before it took place, his remarks were
heavy with remorse. "All of us are guilty," he said (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> uses a
slightly different translation). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> notes that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yeltsin</ENAMEX> was a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communist Party</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Urals</ENAMEX>, he ordered the destruction of the house
and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cellar</ENAMEX> where the executions took place, in order to eradicate a potentially
important symbol for pro-czarist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">factions</ENAMEX>. The impact of the ceremony is open
to interpretation. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> is optimistic--"The ceremony fulfilled
the hopes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">organizers</ENAMEX> who wanted the event to provide a grand gesture of
reconciliation"--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story takes the tone of its headline--"<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s
Conflicts on <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Display at Burial</ENAMEX>."

            On the front pages of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> (but inside at the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) is the approval of an international criminal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UN</ENAMEX>
conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rome</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> will prosecute <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">perpetrators</ENAMEX> of war crimes,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">internationally</ENAMEX> deployed <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">troops</ENAMEX> could be prosecuted by a politically
motivated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>--voted against the treaty, which was a major blow to its
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX>. The final tally was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">120 to 7</TIMEX> (with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> abstaining); in
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dissenting</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> joins such human rights <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">luminaries</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sudan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Indonesia</ENAMEX>. Implementation of the treaty is probably years
away, since it must be ratified by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at least 60</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, according to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80</NUMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> will have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> and convene in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">The Hague</ENAMEX>.

            With less than a week elapsed since the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> just can't
enough of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> sports. A front-page story reveals that the entire top <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the week-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Tour de France</ENAMEX> has just been expelled for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> use. The team
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">masseur</ENAMEX> was caught on the border of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in a car
packed with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, and the team <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coach</ENAMEX> has since admitted to giving illegal
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> to his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">riders</ENAMEX> "to optimize performance under strict medical control." The
news probably won't impair the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World Cup</ENAMEX> celebrations in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>.

         
      
   
