
   
   
      
         
            Devil on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Dress</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> lead story: A dress surrendered by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> will be tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA material</ENAMEX>, possibly proving a sexual
relationship between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with news of accelerating growth in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> wages, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> leads with fears that we may be
entering a recession.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s dress will go to an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> crime <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>, which will extract any found
"DNA material" (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' preferred phrase) for comparison with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> sample
from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">blood</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">saliva</ENAMEX>. The entire process could be complete in as soon
as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three days</TIMEX>. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> uses the word "semen" to describe what the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> is looking for. (The other papers force <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">readers</ENAMEX> to guess that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
didn't sneeze toward the garment, or perhaps inadvertently drool on it.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> calls the dress "black," while sharp-eyed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> deems it
"<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> blue." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> also claims that lab <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX> must determine
"whether the quality or quantity [of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">semen</ENAMEX>] is sufficient" for accurate
testing, meaning a legal break for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> might be an affront to his
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">manhood</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> stories out front and
above the fold, while the suddenly prudish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> leaves the scandal off its
front entirely.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> wages and benefits rose <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.5 percent</NUMEX> in
the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>--the biggest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-year</TIMEX> gain since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>. Tight labor markets have
spurred higher salaries, which in turn have spurred record consumer spending.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> adds that, despite the wage gains and consumer confidence, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> has slowed down, but still asserts that "few if any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">economists</ENAMEX> are
worried that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> is on the brink of a recession." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX>
dissents. While recognizing the wage and spending lifts, the WSJ lead
argues that many indeed fear an impending recession: "Signs are emerging that
some important engines of recent growth--particularly profits and business
investment--are faltering." The villain: The <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis, which is boosting
our trade deficit and causing worldwide oversupplies that crush our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>'
ability to sell.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> go front-page with a story on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">babies</ENAMEX> who
were switched at birth. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Now 3 years old</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX> left a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX> maternity
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ward</ENAMEX> with the wrong <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX>--an error discovered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only this month</TIMEX> when one
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>'s blood tests did not match her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX>'s. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX>
claims its procedures are precise enough that only foul play could be
responsible. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> will now decide whether to swap <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX> or stick with
what they've got.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> story profiles a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrat</ENAMEX> who embezzled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">more than $6</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">million</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6 years</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, crippled by muscular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dystrophy</ENAMEX>,
used simple accounting lies to siphon funds to his bogus private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>. His
family lived in opulence until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DEA</ENAMEX> finally caught on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. Now it's
doubtful the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> will get much of its money back. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> more losing battle in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Drug War</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs this correction: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Making Books</ENAMEX> column on
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>...misquoted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Mailer</ENAMEX> on the length of combat patrols the author
made on foot in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">World War</ENAMEX> II.... He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrols</ENAMEX> were up to <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">miles long</NUMEX>, not <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">215 miles</NUMEX>." It was good of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> to save <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mailer</ENAMEX> the
effort of doing his own macho posturing--why must they now back down?

         
      
   
