
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cable Hook-Up</ENAMEX>

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech/biz</ENAMEX> dominates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX>'s purchase of cable
company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX>. (The story is also on the front at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and is flagged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> 's front-page news digest.) The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with the ruling by a federal appeals court undoing a previous
lower court order that had required <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> to make Windows <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">95</NUMEX> available
separate from its <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Internet Explorer</ENAMEX> browser. The ruling is widely viewed as
boding well for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s upcoming federal antitrust trial concerning the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>'s joint packaging of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Windows 98</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IE</ENAMEX>. (This story also makes the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> fronts and the WSJ front news box
and gets a front-page "reefer" at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .) The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">LAT</ENAMEX> leads with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s expected announcement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> of a plan for giving
minority <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> preferences in the awarding of government contracts when
independent surveys show that their share of federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> is smaller than
their overall market share. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> hopes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports, that the
new approach will satisfy a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruling that minority set-asides per
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">se</ENAMEX> are unconstitutional and that race-based awards are permissible only if they
are a remedy for a proven record of discrimination. Nobody else puts the new
preference plan on the front page.

            Of the early editions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> available to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>, only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">flatly</ENAMEX> states that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ATT/TCI</ENAMEX> business was a done deal. The acquisition, says
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, will shake both the cable and phone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, giving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX> new clout
and phone expertise and allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> to offer local phone service over
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX>'s cable lines. The deal could, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Money</ENAMEX>" section analysis
piece, mark the beginning of real competition in both local phone service and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">cable TV</ENAMEX>. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> shows that it also contains the seeds of greater
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">monopolies</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TCI</ENAMEX> already has a cable <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">monopoly</ENAMEX> in virtually every one of its
service areas, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AT&T</ENAMEX> already has <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 50 percent</NUMEX> of the
long-distance market. The merger will no doubt get a close government review.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> runs an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCC</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX>'s favorable comment, while the
Post quotes a powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> saying the deal "runs up
a red flag."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's off-lead <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">concerns</ENAMEX> testimony given <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>
hearing about how a secret encoded circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> containing sensitive <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
technology was missing from the wreckage of a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> aboard a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX>
rocket that blew up in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that "the disclosure of the missing
circuit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX>.was made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>." Well actually, to be fair, it was made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt</ENAMEX>
Drudge, in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20th</TIMEX> Report. No mention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drudge</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX>
though. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> reports that the congressional investigation is trying to
determine if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> was missing because the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> "took" it. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wonder</ENAMEX> why
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> doesn't say "stole" it.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reports that the result of a recent high-level <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> military war game set in a
conflict between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pakistan</ENAMEX> shocked and disappointed many of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> participating: none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>' heavy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">divisions</ENAMEX> could get to the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian</ENAMEX> subcontinent in time to have any effect on the war's outcome.

            The WP front reports that new laws in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Florida</ENAMEX> governing patient treatment by HMOs
have been so effective they may well become the models for federal legislation.
Among the provisions: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> needn't go through their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> to see their
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dermatologists; HMOs</ENAMEX> cannot forbid <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX> to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> about expensive
treatments available; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> can protest to an outside <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> a plan's
refusal to pay for a procedure.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front tells of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>
report just out disclosing that in certain parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> one in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">four</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX> is infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">HIV</ENAMEX>--and most of them will die as a result because
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Africans</ENAMEX> cannot for the most part afford the combination drug therapies that
can keep the virus in check--and that worldwide, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">AIDS</ENAMEX> now rivals the greatest
epidemics of history. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says this is the gloomiest picture of the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">disease</ENAMEX> painted since it was <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> recognized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> off-lead reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">IRS reform</ENAMEX> bill moving towards
passage in both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">houses</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> now includes a provision lowering from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">18</NUMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just one year</TIMEX> the holding period required to enjoy a drop in the tax
on investment profits from a top rate of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">28 percent</NUMEX> down to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> is also on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front and inside at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> .

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> carries an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AP</ENAMEX> story inside reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> police
have charged <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Amish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX> with buying <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine</ENAMEX> from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">motorcycle</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">gang</ENAMEX> and then
distributing it to young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of their sect. This is apparently the first
drug case ever involving <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Amish</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>. Stay tuned for <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">horse</ENAMEX> and buggy
drive-bys.

         
      
   
