
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>'d Up

            The global economy dominates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX>
leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s push for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to enact fiscal reforms
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">now</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF-World Bank</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22 billion</NUMEX>
in loans to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, which also leads the national edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> .
The metro edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> puts <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>/loans in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">off-</ENAMEX>lead and
goes instead with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX>'s finding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Rev.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Sharpton</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tawana</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Brawley advisors</ENAMEX> defamed a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX> assistant <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.A.</ENAMEX> when they said on several
occasions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX> that he kidnapped and raped Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brawley</ENAMEX>. (The verdict
also makes the WP front.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times pairs <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>/loans and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>/reforms together in the lead
spot.

            According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is urging <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> to undertake tax
cuts and banking reforms, and to open up its domestic markets to more foreign
competition. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> had been counting on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryutaro Hashimoto</ENAMEX> to
do these things, but as a result of his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX>'s severe election losses, he
resigned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> 's headline indicates doubts any new government
will be any more capable of swift reform, but what the headline giveth, the
subhead taketh away: ".but others say losses may jolt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> into action." The
Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> back-of-the-front-section
"<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Politics and Policy</ENAMEX>" piece also worries that the post-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX> period may not
see much improvement.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX> will serve, say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, until a successor is chosen, probably
in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or so</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> do take-outs on the leading
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contenders</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , perhaps reflecting a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">city</ENAMEX> loaded with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">restaurants</ENAMEX>, describes the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> most likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">successors</ENAMEX> as respectively "spicy"
and "bland." The WP fronts an interesting survey of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">electorate</ENAMEX>'s mood. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> seems to speak for many when he says his
anti-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX> vote was a "wake-up call."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> question not answered in the coverage: Why does reform for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> mean
cutting taxes and reform for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> mean raising taxes?

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Sharpton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> will next proceed to deliberate about any damage award. The ex-D.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> is seeking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$395</NUMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">million</ENAMEX>, a sum the paper notes he may have trouble collecting even if awarded,
given that one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brawley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> is a suspended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX>, another is a
disbarred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharpton</ENAMEX> says he owns no home or other substantial property.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> story says that the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">D.A.</ENAMEX> spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$320,000</NUMEX> bringing the
case.

            Given all the press attention lavished on the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Year 2000 bug</ENAMEX>, it's hard to
fathom that only <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> fronts Wall Street's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX> test <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Twenty-nine</NUMEX>
security <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and twelve <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">exchanges</ENAMEX> began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first day</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks</TIMEX> of
simulating what it would be like to run the markets as the nines turn over. The
test so far has excluded small securities <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">firms</ENAMEX> and international markets, but
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Day One</ENAMEX> was, says the paper, glitchless.

            If you think conservative fiscal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">theorists</ENAMEX> are on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's
front page is a reminder that you are at least sometimes right: It details how
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Kudlow</ENAMEX> , a former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> budget <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">economics</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Review</ENAMEX> , is easing back into the policy
life <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX> after hitting bottom as a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cocaine binger</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Work Week"</ENAMEX> column reports that according to a survey
done by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> pen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">executives</ENAMEX> say e-mail has cut back
on their need for meetings. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Nine</NUMEX> out of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> say it has also reduced the need
for paperwork and has improved overall productivity. But <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">nearly half</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">execs</ENAMEX>
say they still attend too many meetings. And <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> of them say that during
those meetings, they take notes to make it look as if they are listening--a
trend "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" is quite sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX> pen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> deeply deplores.

         
      
   
