
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodbye Dolly</ENAMEX>

            No single story dominates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with a story that makes everybody's
front page--the mass cloning of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Hawaii</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>, the first
documented cloning of adult mammals since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolly</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>'s test-firing of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">missile</ENAMEX> with a range sufficient to strike
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Saudi Arabia</ENAMEX>, and most of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>--a story nobody else has on the front
page. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> goes with worries <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the Y2K</TIMEX> glitch could severely affect the health
care system. And the top national story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>'s rejection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">administration</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">nominee</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX>. The nomination gets lots of space
elsewhere, but only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> infuses the vote with racial overtones from
the git-go, saying in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> sentence that the vote "killed the candidacy of
the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> black ever nominated to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">secretary</ENAMEX>," even though the
issues that brought him down were discrepancies in his statements about his
career as a pilot and his apparent practice of pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">subordinates</ENAMEX> to buy
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Amway</ENAMEX> products from him.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Weiss</ENAMEX> quotes a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Princeton</ENAMEX> genetics <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> saying
human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cloning</ENAMEX> will "happen sooner than we thought <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>," and guessing
that means within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. Talk about cloning--the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> gets
practically the same quote from the same prof for its front-page take on the
results.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also reports in the story that sophisticated DNA techniques
have proved beyond doubt that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dolly</ENAMEX> is a clone. The paper waits until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">the ninth</TIMEX>
paragraph to mention that, oh by the way, both of these developments are from
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> does it right, giving
Nature credit at the start of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> paragraph.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> are certain <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> successfully conducted a firing of that medium-range missile,
purchased from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">North Korea</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> former intelligence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> is quoted saying
the major reaction of the test--conducted entirely within <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX>--is going to be
from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Israel</ENAMEX>, which views <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> as the main threat in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>
will be looking for assurances, says the paper, that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iran</ENAMEX> is not trying to
develop <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> of mass destruction.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">Y2K</NUMEX>/health care story is hooked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearings to be held
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on such problems as: crashing computers wiping out medical records,
intravenous feeders and dialysis machines going haywire, and back-up generators
failing. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wry</ENAMEX> commentary or poor word choice? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nation</ENAMEX>'s Newspaper says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> is "staging" the hearings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> have discovered,
says the paper, that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 30 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX> have formal Y2K plans, and
that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicians</ENAMEX> are not addressing the issue in their own
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">offices</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> continues to ride <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> hard on her relative inaction
regarding allegations of illegalities in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> campaign
fund-raising <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">operations</ENAMEX>. The metro edition features an off-lead reporting that
the departing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice</ENAMEX>'s look at the matter has concluded in a report to
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reno</ENAMEX> that an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutor</ENAMEX> should be named to investigate further. And
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>'s lead editorial uses this news as the springboard to once again call
for just that.

            Death continues to strike down <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">celebrities</ENAMEX> are no exception,
sometimes, like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, dying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> at a time. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>, the
latest famous to follow in the co-mortal footsteps of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">William</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shakespeare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Jefferson</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JFK</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aldous Huxley</ENAMEX>, are
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Shepard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Young</ENAMEX>, who together take up a good <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX> of the
LAT front and considerable space at the other papers. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Incidentally</ENAMEX>,
such episodes evince the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX>' basic celebrity obituary photo policy: don't
use recent pictures.) At the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> gets not only the front, but
also <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> more stories inside. The instant upwelling of space lore in the papers
prompted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX>'s passing is a sure indication that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s 30th
anniversary of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>-on-the-moon will be a media big deal.

            The culture's yawning need to celebrate such past events has meant, says a
Wall Street Journal front-page feature, redefining
"past events" to include things that aren't really either. So it is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Addiction</ENAMEX> recently did a reunion tour, that the compilation CD "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Living</ENAMEX> in the
90s" has sold <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">500,000</NUMEX> copies, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanilla Ice</ENAMEX> is doing concerts again and
just signed a record deal. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> 's style sheet calls for
referring to the recovering has-been as "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ice</ENAMEX>." Does <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snoop Doggy Dogg</ENAMEX> get
"Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dogg</ENAMEX>"?)

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reuters</ENAMEX> item inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> about the controversy in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">England</ENAMEX> over
whether or not the age of consent for gay sex should be lowered from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 to 16</TIMEX> makes a
rather fundamental omission. Although the story says that sentiment against the
move has been criticized as discrimination against gay <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>, nowhere does it
mention the age of consent for straight <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">men</ENAMEX>. (Nor does it mention if there's a
similar differential in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>)

            It's often interesting to wonder who brings the need for a correction to a
paper's attention and why. Consider for instance, the following item in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s
Times : "An article on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 18</TIMEX> about allegations of sexual misconduct
among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX> police <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX> misstated the street number of what was
said to be a brothel frequented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officers</ENAMEX>. It was at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">335</NUMEX> West <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">39th Street</ENAMEX>,
not <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">355</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">West 39th</ENAMEX>."

         
      
   
