
   
   
      
         
            Poll to Poll

            For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the third straight day</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> lead with stories about the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">revitalized U.S.</ENAMEX> war on terrorism. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> must freeze all of bin <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laden's</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">associates</ENAMEX>' assets;
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> says that all their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> assets are
already frozen, but fails to make it clear if any such assets exist. Everyone
reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, in his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> radio address, warned of a "long
battle" against bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>'s terrorist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> runs a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>-column off-lead on <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nigeria</ENAMEX>'s "self-imposed
poverty." <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Africa</ENAMEX>'s most populous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX> has everything it needs: arable land,
quality <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corrupt</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, however, has left the nation
racked with poverty and unable to correct itself--a predicament blamed largely
on the prevalence of graft among <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nigerian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. In the words of one
would-be <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reformer</ENAMEX>, "They have no love of their <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>. Only love of their
pockets."

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP /ABC News</ENAMEX> survey agrees with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT /CBS News</ENAMEX>
poll: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">folks</ENAMEX> think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> is doing a good job as <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX>, but they don't
trust him. And they don't like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> article's
headline reads "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Voters See</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Distinct Bill Clintons</ENAMEX>," but the article
reveals that polling was done among <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of "randomly selected
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adults</ENAMEX>"-selected, that is, from a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> in which <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 49%</NUMEX> of those eligible voted in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> election.

            Crime has dropped but fear hasn't, according to an <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunday Report</ENAMEX>. The piece says that manipulation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> fear by
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX>, and the crime-prevention industry has created something
akin to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>'s "military-industrial complex." The article particularly
criticizes police <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> that take credit for falling crime rates while
padding their budgets by fueling unwarranted <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">paranoia</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 40,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX>'s total
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">population</ENAMEX>, live in polygamous <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">families</ENAMEX>. A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Utah</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girl</ENAMEX>, who claims
she escaped from an abusive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">father</ENAMEX> and an arranged marriage to her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">uncle</ENAMEX> (her
1st, his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">15th</NUMEX>), has drawn national attention to the issue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. A recent
poll finds that, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mormon Church</ENAMEX> has officially banned polygamy for
more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a century</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 54%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> support the
prosecution of polygamists.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William S. Cohen</ENAMEX> talks tough in a WP <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> Outlook piece. Mr.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Secretary</ENAMEX> says that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s missile strike signifies a "long term,
fundamental way in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States</ENAMEX> intends to combat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> of
terror." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohen</ENAMEX> reminds us that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> never "cringed at <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">the feet</NUMEX> of communist
or fascist bullies" and warns terrorist-friendly <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> that they are "not
beyond the reach of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s military might."

            From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Redundancy Department</ENAMEX>: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers discussed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> article about the rapid growth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
legal defense fund. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> had previously covered the
topic back on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 13th</TIMEX>.

            Finally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">NYT Week in Review</ENAMEX> examines how <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Americans</ENAMEX> rationalize
their decisions to eat some <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> and not others. The article cites perceived
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">intelligence</ENAMEX> and fluffiness as big plusses in the "don't eat" column, but fails
to mention what historical role taste <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">buds</ENAMEX> may have played.

         
      
   
