
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Scraping Off The Barnicles</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> grand jury
appearance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> 's lead is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> initially kept
quiet because she believed her relationship with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> might last
beyond his <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> term. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
national edition leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s demand that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>
provide a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA specimen</ENAMEX>, a move the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says strongly suggests that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">lab</ENAMEX> has determined that the infamous blue dress contains DNA evidence of a
sexual encounter. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> was seeking the sample from
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethesda Naval Hospital</ENAMEX> and that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> didn't oppose the request.
(<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC News</ENAMEX> was reporting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had indeed provided a DNA
sample.) The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later</TIMEX> metro edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> instead leads with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>'
strategizing about how to capture suspected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">terrorist mastermind</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Osama</ENAMEX> bin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>, currently in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times goes with new evidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles County</ENAMEX> is moving
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">impressive</ENAMEX> numbers of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> off its welfare rolls and into jobs. The findings
are likely to be cited, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> , as a model for welfare overhaul in
other large urban areas. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">front</ENAMEX> also carries the story.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> is set to testify to the grand jury
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Currie</ENAMEX> sought her out to get back the gifts that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> had given
the intern. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says that when asked by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> whether he had
asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Currie</ENAMEX> to get the gifts back, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> didn't really answer the
question.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> reports that in a telephone interview, a high-ranking
official of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>, the fundamentalist Moslem <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> controlling
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>, said that if the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> provided hard evidence of bin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>'s
involvement in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">embassy</ENAMEX> bombings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX> would be willing to
discuss with <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> what to do about him. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that any
negotiations might be complicated by prior <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> complaints about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>'s
harsh treatment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">women</ENAMEX> and its involvement in drug trafficking, but goes on
to note that the timing may be right, since <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">rulers</ENAMEX> are desperate
for international recognition and aid. There is no evidence, says the
Times , that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is instead considering military action against bin
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Afghan</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> off-lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> has approved an
average <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.6 percent</NUMEX> pay raise for federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> and proposed a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4.4</NUMEX>
percent raise on top of that for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the following year</TIMEX>. The story makes two
mistakes typical of federal pay raise reporting: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) it suggests that federal
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> earn much less than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> in the private sector even
though there is much evidence to the contrary. Thus the piece mentions that the
typical white-collar federal <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> who will receive the bulk of the raises
earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">over $44,000</NUMEX> but doesn't note that the average salary in this <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> is
far, far less; <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2</ENAMEX>) it doesn't mention the real cost of federal raises. Thus, the
story says the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> pay raise will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.9 billion</NUMEX>, when in fact it will end
up costing much more because it increases federal pension payouts, which are
based on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">worker</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last few years</TIMEX> of salary.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page feature gives a tour
of the wacky world of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> "national interest" visas--granted upon the
ruminations of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">a few hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> who make their decisions without much in
the way of guidelines. The results therefore, are pretty random. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">acrobat</ENAMEX> gets in, as does a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Chinese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> specializing in detecting
radioactive leaks. And so does a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montrealer</ENAMEX> out to fill a "huge
void in the telesphere" by launching a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">youth</ENAMEX>-oriented global news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX>. But
an <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineer</ENAMEX> skilled at protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridges</ENAMEX> from earthquakes does not. Nor
does a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teacher</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bronx</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homeless</ENAMEX> shelter. "Being a qualified, caring,
competent and committed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX>," reads the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">INS</ENAMEX> rejection letter,
doesn't show "that her contributions are significantly above any other member
of the education profession" or that they would "provide a prospective benefit
to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>"

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front-pager brings word that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">just eight days</TIMEX> after salvaging
his career from a controversy over his lifting material from a book, longtime
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Barnicle</ENAMEX> resigned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> after it was
revealed that there was no evidence <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> he wrote about in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> column
had ever existed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> carry the story inside--both
reporting that there was cheering in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">newsroom</ENAMEX> when the
announcement was made. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> may have felt the need to front the
story because it owns the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> .)

            In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the days</TIMEX> since The Speech, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> have been fairly spattered with
editorial complaints that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> should have come clean <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven months</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>--he shouldn't have had to be cornered <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>. Well, the same goes for the
papers themselves. Many of them know that they are harboring on their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffs</ENAMEX>
fiction <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">artists</ENAMEX> and plagiarists. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Papers</ENAMEX> knows about a few of them,
still drawing fat salaries, still writing with undeserved reputations--and will
print their names here if it comes to that. So <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX> issues this
challenge to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">America</ENAMEX>'s press: Come clean about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Barnicles</ENAMEX> still in your
midst before you have to.

         
      
   
