
   
   
      
         
            Nuts So Fast

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s statement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> summit that he
would support further <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> aid if <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> presses on with economic reforms, a
message the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says he also made in private talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boris Yeltsin</ENAMEX> and
prominent <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">communist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">politicians</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with other comments <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> made
there, expressing his view that his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 17th</TIMEX> televised speech was a clear
expression of his profound regret for his actions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> sex
scandal. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> calls it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s "extramarital affair with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica S.</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the crash off <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Nova Scotia</ENAMEX> of a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swissair</ENAMEX> flight carrying <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">228</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that originated in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York City</ENAMEX>, a story
that broke too late to make anybody else's <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> editions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> is
alone in leading with the stock market's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45-</NUMEX>points-down day, its coverage
including this assessment from a market <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategist</ENAMEX>: "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pros</ENAMEX> are scared to
death. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amateurs</ENAMEX> are reasonably confident."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> lead reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s promise of more aid clashes with the stance taken by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IMF</ENAMEX>'s number <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">official</ENAMEX> is quoted citing the recent tumultuous
changes in the valuation of the ruble and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> banking system as
grounds for delaying its decision to distribute additional aid until
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> says the summit turned out to have more substantive results
than were predicted: an arms accord providing for the sharing of nuclear
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">missile</ENAMEX> launch warning data and the disposal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">bomb</ENAMEX>-grade <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">plutonium</ENAMEX>. The
LAT front-pager on the meeting is somewhat less upbeat, referring to its
"futility" and describing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> as "conspicuously subdued and
visibly unhappy." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says he was "unusually downcast." All the
pictures of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> support this.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says presidential <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisors</ENAMEX> consider <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Speech</ENAMEX> "a bust" (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeez</ENAMEX>,
why not just come right out and describe it as a "blown opportunity"?) and
fully expected a question about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> to come up in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>. When it did,
says the paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> went with the answer he had prepared during a prep
session with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aides</ENAMEX>. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> violates a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journalism</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">101</NUMEX> tenet by never
actually saying what the question was. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> in its inside piece
about the reasons the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reporters</ENAMEX> gave for asking the questions--frustration over
lack of access--makes the same omission.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> adds that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> figured being grilled about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
at the summit might be politically useful, in that this could make reporters
appear unpatriotic.

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> fronts feature grand-jury-leak-based
stories about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX>'s testimony that he took a direct role in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Monica</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s job hunts. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says these disclosures were first made
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> edition available to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>'s
Papers doesn't mention this.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">tribunal</ENAMEX> investigating
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">mass</ENAMEX> killings in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Rwanda</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> handed down the first guilty verdict ever by an
international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> for the crime of genocide. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">defendant</ENAMEX>, held responsible
for the killing or <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of rapes, is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Rwandan</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mayor</ENAMEX>, who now faces a maximum sentence of life in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">prison</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> runs
the story on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">20</NUMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs it on page <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">40</NUMEX>.

            The LAT front reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has approved the sale of the
first-ever "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> after" emergency birth control kit. The <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication</ENAMEX> is
essentially a sequence of high dosage birth control <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pills</ENAMEX>, which is thought by
its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturer</ENAMEX> to be less politically controversial than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">French</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning-</TIMEX>after <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">medication RU486</ENAMEX>, because it doesn't cause an abortion, but
rather interferes with ovulation. The story also runs on the WP front,
while on the USAT front it's paired with news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
approved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> new anti-breast <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> front story on these
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> points out that one of them, tamoxifen, is already approved as a
treatment for preventing the recurrence of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">breast cancer</ENAMEX>, but now becomes the
<NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> ever approved for the prevention of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> in those who've never had
it.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> front-page feature takes a close
look at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Afghanistan</ENAMEX>'s ruling <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cabal</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Taliban</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regime</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> says the
world had better get used to, since it's become pretty firmly ensconced. The
paper says the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cabal</ENAMEX> keeps its hold with public floggings and executions (the
story describes a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">burglar</ENAMEX>'s raucous public hand amputation), intensive street
patrols and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> of informants. And in a big cultural change, it has
disarmed most of the general <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populace</ENAMEX>. With renewed law and order has come the
comparatively safe transportation of goods, increased tax collection and
improved essential services. There is now electricity, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , in a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> that didn't have it for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>.

            <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of Transportation</ENAMEX> has
informed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX> that, in an expansion of disability rights policy, they must
soon provide <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanut</ENAMEX>-free buffer zones for any <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> who declares a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">certified peanut allergy</ENAMEX> prior to a flight. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> story prompted numerous calls to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airlines</ENAMEX>, some of whom haven't
decided how to handle the new reg. But many have--if a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">passenger</ENAMEX> with the
problem calls in advance, there will be no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">peanuts</ENAMEX> on that flight. Apparently,
having a "no peanuts" section has been ruled out.

         
      
   
