
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Teachers</ENAMEX>' Pet Peeves

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with the rejection of a proposed
merger of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> main <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teachers</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">membership</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
and is above the fold at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> leads with the
retreat of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">nation</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">HMOs</ENAMEX> from managed care programs for the poor
and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> goes with the launch in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Yugoslavia</ENAMEX>'s troubled
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">province</ENAMEX> of patrols jointly conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
diplomatic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patrols</ENAMEX>, explains the paper, were first proposed by
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russians</ENAMEX> but have since been embraced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">envoy</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Holbrooke</ENAMEX>,
who stresses that the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are now working together to defuse the
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kosovo</ENAMEX> crisis.

            Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> explain that had the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> merged with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Federation of Teachers</ENAMEX>, this would have created the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>' largest
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says that the no vote came even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> favored
the move. The merger idea, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , had gained strength recently
in response to increased attempts to limit teacher rights and to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>
publicly funded vouchers to attend private <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX>. But, both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> say, the
stumbling block appears to be a fear among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of becoming affiliated
with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>, of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFT</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX>. The WP mentions an NEA
fear of being aligned too closely with the causes and politics of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>
without specifying what these are. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> does explain that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">NEA</ENAMEX> tends to
view itself as more non-partisan and more like a professional organization
(like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AMA</ENAMEX>) than a trade <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">union</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says that according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NEA</ENAMEX>,
the rivalry between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">unions</ENAMEX> cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">between 1973 and 1992</TIMEX>.

            According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , general operating losses and cuts in government
payments have prompted the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX>--such names as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacificare</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaiser Permanente</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Cross and Blue Shield</ENAMEX>--to quit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> coverage in many different markets.
The retreat from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX>--government-subsidized care for the poor and
disabled--is the more pronounced of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>. Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicaid</ENAMEX> withdrawals,
says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , have come in the most populous <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX> with large pockets
of urban poverty. With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medicare</ENAMEX>, it's tended to be rural <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> with few
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinics</ENAMEX>, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">doctors</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> flight portends, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> ,
a return to skimping care for the poor and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">elderly</ENAMEX>.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> reports that the semiconductor
business--seriously affected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> crisis, a production glut and the
advent of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> PC--is in a global slump, and that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">manufacturers</ENAMEX>
are certainly taking their share of the hits. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> chip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that have
laid off <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> or tipped upcoming bad earnings include, says the paper,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Semiconductor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atmel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cypress Semiconductor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seeq Technology</ENAMEX>. Even
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intel</ENAMEX> has projected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a flat second quarter</TIMEX> and lower profit margins.

            The WP passes along word from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a weekend</TIMEX> chat show that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>
has decided he will not submit an interim report on his investigation of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> recesses for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the fall</TIMEX> election campaigns. He
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">will</ENAMEX>, said an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX>, submit a report only if he determines there is substantial
information that crimes have been committed. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">aide</ENAMEX> also opined, reports the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> , that subpoenaing a sitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> is legally unproblematic, as
is indicting one.

            In its editorial advocating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> abandon their
current policy against the use of computer encryption technology the feds are
not at least indirectly privy to, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
failure to oppose this law enforcement stance thusly: "[<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S</ENAMEX>]<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">ince Attorney General</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Reno</ENAMEX> has protected Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> from an independent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counsel</ENAMEX> on campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> is said to be loath to oppose either her or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis</ENAMEX>
Freeh, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F.B.I.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX>, on this issue." But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> isn't told who says
this. A recurring theme of the many media post-mortems on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time/CNN</ENAMEX>/nerve
<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">gas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX> debacles--including of those issued by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> --has been a fervent tsk-tsking directed at unnamed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. So
shouldn't this apply to the editorial pages too?

         
      
   
