
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hyde Crimes or Misdemeanors</ENAMEX>?

            The big story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is what happens when blue tape meets red tape, with the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Judiciary</ENAMEX> wrangle over the release of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> report evidence--including
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> video--leading at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> , the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , and the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times . The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
puts that story on the top front, but goes instead with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' likely
decision to transfer control of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">satellite</ENAMEX> exports back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Dept.</ENAMEX> from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Dept.</ENAMEX>, a development with its roots in a now-nearly forgotten
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> technology-transfer-for-political-donations scandal broken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>
by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> , a development nobody else's front page covers. The
provision is part of the defense budget bill, which makes it politically hard,
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Times</ENAMEX> points out, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to veto it.

            Contrary to expectations, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX> did not release
the video of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s grand jury testimony. But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report, the delay
didn't have much to do with the tape itself, but rather with all the other
material involved, much of it <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX>'s quite graphic descriptions of
Oval Office sex. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> debated the material line by line--or "sex
act by sex act," as one committee <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX> tells the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> . Basically, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> are trying to screen out as much <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">material</ENAMEX> as possible, holding it to
be not probative but merely inflammatory, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are opting for
maximum disclosure, arguing that the full <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> has already voted for just
that. It's widely reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> are winning all the particular
votes on this matter--with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> video expected to be made
public by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the weekend</TIMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> sees the contentiousness as a harbinger of the difficulties
ahead in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next several months</TIMEX> as the committee debates <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
fate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> notes that the politics aren't all black and white, with
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrats</ENAMEX> (not on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committee</ENAMEX>) calling for the immediate
release of all the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> materials. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Democrat</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Feinstein</ENAMEX> is still so angry at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> about what she
calls his "betrayal" that she recently turned down an invitation from him to
talk it over.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> leads all report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> will also shortly
receive a videotape of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s deposition in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jones</ENAMEX> case. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> points out that this sets up the prospect of the TV <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">networks</ENAMEX> running
contrasts of that deposition with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>'s later and often conflicting
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">jury</ENAMEX> appearance. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that the
video of the latter begins with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">prosecutors</ENAMEX> asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> for his
understanding of the meaning of the oath to tell "the whole truth."

            There is much reporting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> of the fallout from the revelation
that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Judiciary Committee</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Hyde</ENAMEX>, had an adulterous affair in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1960s</TIMEX>. (The story was broken in <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Salon</ENAMEX> , a fact you could learn
everywhere but in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's story, which merely cites "an on-line
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">magazine</ENAMEX>'s disclosure.") The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> report,
has asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> to investigate if the story was part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> smear
campaign. And there is plenty of reporting on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> fears about who's
next, detailed for instance in a WP front-pager. Apparently now the
concern is that those running for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX> won't be asked what they've done, but
who they've done. Both the USAT front page "cover story" and an inside
story at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> refer to the newly poisoned atmosphere as "sexual
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCarthyism</ENAMEX>."

            According to front-page stories in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> about the
report to be issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s much-ballyhooed commission on
<ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">race</ENAMEX>, (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> covered the report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">commission</ENAMEX>'s principal
recommendation is the creation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">a...</ENAMEX>commission on race. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">charitably</ENAMEX> calls the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">15-months</TIMEX>-in-the-making report "modest." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> is
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">harsher</ENAMEX>, running the headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Panel on Race Urges Nothing but More Talk</ENAMEX>."

            Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> (which has been hitting such stories
hard lately) report inside that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dissidents</ENAMEX> attempting to register a
democratically oriented political <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">party</ENAMEX> in various parts of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> were detained
by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">police</ENAMEX>. This on the heels of a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">China</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX>'s human rights
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">commissioner</ENAMEX> that, says the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , she hailed as "groundbreaking."

            A letter in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> makes you wonder about the
commitment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> to excellence in teaching. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">writer</ENAMEX> is a retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">submarine skipper</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s engineering degrees, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>
graduate credits in education, and college teaching experience. He explains
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">that earlier this year</TIMEX> he applied for a teaching job, sending his resume and
transcripts to every middle school and high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Fairfax County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Virginia</ENAMEX>.
He received <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only one</NUMEX> letter back--merely an acknowledgment--and got no
interviews. For God's sake, if a middle or high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">principal</ENAMEX> in the area
reads this <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">item</ENAMEX>, get in touch with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> and give this <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guy</ENAMEX> a
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">jingle</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">The Reliable Source</ENAMEX>" says that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">D.C.</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> in the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miss America</ENAMEX> contest was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> intern--a
fact she now omits from her contest resume. "I didn't," she tells the paper,
"want anybody to have any preconceptions about who I am."

         
      
   
