
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Da Bear</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> all lead with a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">299</NUMEX>-point drop in the Dow Jones industrial
average. The cyclopean <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with scandal news again--this time
continuing battles over attorney-client privilege.

            The Dow's plunge was its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>-largest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-day</TIMEX> point loss ever, according to
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.4 percent</NUMEX> drop means the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dow</ENAMEX> stands <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.1 percent</NUMEX> below its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17</TIMEX> peak. (A <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> drop is termed a "correction," while a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>
drop means a bear market.) Factors in the nosedive: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>'s financial crisis, a
too-strong <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> dollar, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s political worries. (Now
that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> has destroyed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and the economy, isn't there
something she could do about <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Hollywood</ENAMEX>?) The papers all note that a sluggish
market is nothing new for small stocks, which are down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> for the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>--it's the high-profile blue chips that are only now feeling the pain.
Hardest hit: the tech-focused <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nasdaq</ENAMEX> market, down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 36 percent</NUMEX> from its
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">52-week</TIMEX> high. Influential (and widely quoted) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analyst</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bull</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Acampora now</ENAMEX> predicts we are headed for a bear market. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> says the
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">economy</ENAMEX> remains strong, with inflation, interest rates, and unemployment still
low.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny Breuer</ENAMEX> refused to answer
several questions before the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> grand jury <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, citing
attorney-client privilege. It's not clear if this refusal will lead to another
round of legal battles, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>'s attempts to block <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breuer</ENAMEX>'s
testimony were previously denied. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breuer</ENAMEX> did answer some questions yesterday
and will give more testimony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's article adds a new
wrinkle: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX> will hand over, in addition to phone messages and the sex
dress, a "photograph of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> that he had inscribed to her."

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> runs a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kelly</ENAMEX> editorial claiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> can't
possibly confess to a lie now. Why not? <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) It means admitting that the entire
mess could have been avoided had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> fessed up in the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> place. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>)
Confessing only after you have no other option looks really bad. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>) It would
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">confirm Clinton</ENAMEX>'s rep as a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">liar</ENAMEX>, and his "every utterance on every subject,
past and future, would be suspect." <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">4</NUMEX>) The public won't be as forgiving as we
imagine.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> front-page piece says <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX> is "frustrated"
at the lack of minority law <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX> hired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> tried to discuss the minority <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> dearth with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Justice</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Rehnquist</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> said he doubted that a discussion
"would serve any useful purpose." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> offers these helpful facts: Among
his <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> hires, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> has <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX>, who has been on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, has hired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">79</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerks</ENAMEX>. None was
black; one was <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Hispanic</ENAMEX>."

            A front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> story explains why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Modern Library</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">100</NUMEX> books
list seems so screwy: The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> never ranked the books. They were given a list
of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">440</NUMEX> titles, and put checks next to books they deemed worthy. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX>
checked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">fewer than 100</NUMEX> books. Books with checks from the greatest percentage of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">judges</ENAMEX> were given the highest rankings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Judge</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore Vidal</ENAMEX> found that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">21</NUMEX> of his
own books were on the master list-"more than <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Faulkner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry James</ENAMEX> and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Conrad</ENAMEX> put together."

         
      
   
