
   
   
      
         
            I <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Just Met a Girl Named Lewinsky</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> all lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s agreement to testify for
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> puts the story at the top of its
World-Wide News box. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> will give testimony (scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 17th</TIMEX>)
from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> present during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s questioning. The
interview will be videotaped and subsequently presented as evidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">grand jury</ENAMEX> hearing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> agreed to testify only after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> withdrew his
subpoena, thus making the testimony "voluntary." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX> agreed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s
demands (videotape, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> present) in an effort to avoid any further delays as
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> sought to block the subpoena in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">court</ENAMEX>.

            An intriguing detail is caught by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , but missed
by all other early editions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Lewinsky</ENAMEX> will offer not just testimony, but
physical evidence: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) answering machine messages with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s voice on them
and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) the infamous, allegedly semen-stained, sex dress. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX>
refrains from characterizing the dress, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> valiantly
euphemizes, referring to possible matter on the dress as "<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA material</ENAMEX>,"
"biological material," and "scientific evidence." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> notes that DNA
tests linking the dress to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> would move the case beyond a "simple,
he-said-she-said disagreement." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> adds that the phone messages
contain nothing suggestive, but do "indicate an unusual relationship between a
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> and a low-level correspondence <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">clerk</ENAMEX>."

            <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> 's <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> front-page scandal stories spins out possible
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> tactics. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX> say it makes no legal sense for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to agree
to testify, and thus he must be facing political pressure (a theory first put
forth by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> can now: <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">1</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Stick</ENAMEX> with his story
and contradict <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lewinsky</ENAMEX>, gambling that he'll win a he-said-she-said battle, or
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Give a preemptive public speech before his testimony, admitting that he lied
to "protect his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>."

            In other scandal news, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Tripp</ENAMEX> gave a short statement following the last
of her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">grand jury</ENAMEX> appearances. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tripp</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, "I'm you. I'm
just like you." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX> added that she had been "vilified for taking the path of
truth," and complained that "many in the entertainment industry have chosen to
ridicule me" (presumably referring in part to a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Saturday Night Live</ENAMEX>
sketch in which she was portrayed by obese <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">actor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Goodman</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> runs the
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">full</TIMEX> text of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tripp</ENAMEX>'s speech on page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A10</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> run front-page stories on another speech:
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Thomas</ENAMEX>' remarks before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Bar</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> lashed out at
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">African-Americans</ENAMEX> who criticize his views (especially his opposition to
affirmative action). Defending himself against charges of betraying his race,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> said, "I refuse to have my ideas assigned to me because I am black." The
papers disagree on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX> reaction: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas "</ENAMEX>was given <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">two</TIMEX>
standing ovations," while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> claims that "<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about half</NUMEX> the audience
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">applauded</ENAMEX>, some standing, while the other <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">half</NUMEX> remained silent." The WP
runs the story on page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A03</TIMEX>.

            Everyone gives front-page notice to the death of famed <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">ballet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Broadway</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">choreographer Jerome Robbins</ENAMEX>. Robbins, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">79</TIMEX>, was the artistic direction behind
such musicals as "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">On the Town</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fiddler</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Roof</ENAMEX>," "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Pan</ENAMEX>," and--<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>'s
<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">favorite--"West Side Story</ENAMEX>." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> feels pretty, oh so pretty, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> pities any
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">cyberjournalist</ENAMEX> who isn't <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.

         
      
   
