
   
   
      
         
            We Are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family</ENAMEX>

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> ' lead national story: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s approval of a campaign
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX> bill. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> leads with more news on the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">girls</ENAMEX> switched at birth. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> go with scandal-related leads.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> calls the provisions of the campaign finance bill "the most
sweeping reforms since those inspired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Watergate</ENAMEX> scandal." Approved <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">237</NUMEX>
to 186 (with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">51</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republicans</ENAMEX> breaking party lines to support it), the bill would
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>) Ban unregulated "soft money" donations to political <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parties</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>) Restrict
"issue-advocacy ads," which sometimes mask their true <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sponsors</ENAMEX> and currently
skirt regulation. Despite approval, the bill still faces competition from other
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> bills, and even if passed is not expected to win approval from the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> go front-page with the news, while the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> puts it inside on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A02</TIMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> continues to lead the way on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engrossing</ENAMEX> switched-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">at</NUMEX>-birth
tale. Latest news: The <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> girls' respective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">guardians</ENAMEX> have agreed to maintain
status quo and not swap their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three-year-olds</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Chittum</ENAMEX>'s grandparents
(her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">parents</ENAMEX> were killed in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 4</TIMEX> car crash) will continue to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rebecca</ENAMEX>,
while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Johnson</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mother</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Callie Johnson</ENAMEX>, who is thought to be genetically
related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chittums</ENAMEX>) will continue to raise <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Callie</ENAMEX> and not seek custody of
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rebecca</ENAMEX> (thought to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paula</ENAMEX>'s biological <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>, but raised from birth by the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chittums</ENAMEX>). Perfectly clear, yes? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> adds that each <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> will
establish visitation rights with the other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">child</ENAMEX>. (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TP</ENAMEX>'s movie-of-the-week
script is already in its <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> draft.) The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> goes front-page with the
story, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> story hides inside and lags <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a full day</TIMEX> behind in
its reporting.

            In scandal news, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> run the same story with
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">opposite</ENAMEX> spins. The story: Everyone wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> to fess up to the
hanky-panky we all know he's guilty of, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> stubbornly asserts
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s innocence. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">In Political Washington, A Call</ENAMEX> for
Confession." <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> headline: "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Calls for Clinton to Confess Affair Are</ENAMEX>
Turned Aside." Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">congressmen</ENAMEX> are hinting that a public mea culpa would
end all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s worries, but a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">spokesman</ENAMEX> stated, "The
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> has told the truth about this and he will continue to do so."

            Elsewhere in scandal-world, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> has asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> Chief
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Justice</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> to temporarily stay a subpoena of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanny</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breuer</ENAMEX>. If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rehnquist</ENAMEX> refuses the stay, it's likely that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clinton</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lawyer/confidant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lindsey</ENAMEX> will have to testify, too. (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead
offers the clearest explanation of this legal maneuvering.)

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> 's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Times</ENAMEX> runs a fascinating story about a mathematical
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">theorem</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Benford's Law</ENAMEX>, by comparing the digits in a list of numbers to the
outcome that probability would predict, can identify cases where a series of
numbers (tax returns, accounting records) may have been faked. <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">Benford's Law</ENAMEX>
shows that in any given number, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> digit is most likely to be <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. (For
the reasoning behind this astonishing fact, TP highly recommends reading the
<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">article</ENAMEX> in full.)

         
      
   
