
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Econ Games</ENAMEX>

            Different leads all around. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> leads with the dramatic rebound <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in
the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> financial markets off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> coordinated yen buy. The
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Angeles Times</ENAMEX> goes with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>' widening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">monthly</TIMEX> trade deficit for
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>--attributable, says the paper, to a much-reduced demand for <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> exports
among the crisis-stricken <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economies. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> says the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
deficit is a record, whereas the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> says it's the worst since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>. But
both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> indicate it's widely believed the numbers mean the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Asian</ENAMEX> economic
crisis will soon enough affect <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> productivity and employment. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
goes with word that <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> is violating post-<ENAMEX TYPE="EVENT">Gulf War</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.N.</ENAMEX> sanctions on its oil
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">trade</ENAMEX> by smuggling large quantities of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oil</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX>. The smuggling involves
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">tanker trucks</ENAMEX> openly transporting <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">tons</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fuel</ENAMEX> along
<ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">roads</ENAMEX> in northern <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Iraq</ENAMEX> that are under <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S</ENAMEX> and allied air surveillance. Even
though the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has lobbied hard to keep the sanctions in place and these
shipments are enriching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> tell the
paper that the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> has chosen to look the other way because the illicit trade
also benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">ally</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Turkey</ENAMEX> as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Kurds</ENAMEX> who keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>
from controlling <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA Today</ENAMEX> leads with the aftermath of the tobacco
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bill</ENAMEX>'s defeat: A scaled-down <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Republican</ENAMEX>-sponsored <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> measure that neither
raises cigarette prices nor offers tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> legal indemnification but
which would take aim at teen smoking by revoking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">drivers</ENAMEX>' licenses of
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">teenagers</ENAMEX> caught with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tobacco</ENAMEX>, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">determination</ENAMEX> of numerous state
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">attorneys general</ENAMEX> to pursue their individual lawsuits.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> lead reports that at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> news conference
<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Prime Minister</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hashimoto</ENAMEX> appeared delighted with the success of that
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX>-<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> yen buy and pledged himself ready to "do my best to help write off
bad loans, achieve growth driven by domestic demand, open <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> markets
further and promote deregulation." The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> has
provided no further details of a course of action. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> also notes
that a deputy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">treasury secretary</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Federal</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve</ENAMEX> are in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tokyo</ENAMEX> to meet with senior <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX>. The
main issue they confront is what to do with all the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>, which are
saddled with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> in bad loans. The less ambitious plan being discussed
focuses mainly on ways to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX> resolve bad loans, the more ambitious,
which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> says the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> is pushing, focuses on closing failing
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">banks</ENAMEX>. Things "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" finds missing from the coverage: any mention or
explanation of whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> has, like the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, any sort of
government-supported system of loan insurance. As well as
<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">references/analogies/disanalogies</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">savings and loan</ENAMEX> crisis of the
1980s.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> 's front section "cover story" addresses a fact that may soon
become a big issue in health care policy debates, but which is still fairly
unknown to most <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">voters</ENAMEX>: in general you can't sue your
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMO</ENAMEX> for medical malpractice. The piece tells how under such an armored
<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">shield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMOs</ENAMEX> have quite widely refused payment for <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> opinions and
<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bills</ENAMEX> changing the situation are working their way through the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Critics</ENAMEX>, who include in their number <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Majority Leader</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Armey</ENAMEX>, argue that the change would raise health care premiums and lower
coverage. The argument figures, says the story, to get louder during the fall
elections.

            A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> front-page story reports that the tobacco <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">nearly</TIMEX>
<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> times as much on their <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">anti-</ENAMEX>tobacco bill TV ad campaign as the health
insurance <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> did on their "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX>" spots.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSJ</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Washington Wire</ENAMEX>" reports that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Sen.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> thinks being
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vilified</ENAMEX> in that ad campaign may have helped his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> chances. "They've
made me a household word," the paper quotes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX>.

            The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> report that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston Globe</ENAMEX> (which is
owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> ) has asked for the resignation of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">columnist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">finalist</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, because a routine internal review
determined that she had fabricated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and quotations in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> of her columns
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> , the transgressions included an
entirely made-up column purportedly about a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX> dying of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>
acknowledges her "misdeeds" in her farewell column <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX>
account says that some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Globe</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">staffers</ENAMEX> are worried that the dismissal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smith</ENAMEX>,
a black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>, might have racial repercussions. Question: Do such worries have
anything to do with the fact that although both stories mention the recently
outed white <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">male</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Glass</ENAMEX>, neither mentions black <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">female</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Cooke</ENAMEX>, the
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">fabricator</ENAMEX> who cost her paper a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Pulitzer</ENAMEX>?

         
      
   
