
   
   
      
         
            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr Needs Agent</ENAMEX>

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USA</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> lead with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Starr</ENAMEX>'s issuance of
subpoenas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> for grand jury testimony from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret Service</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> who
work closest to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">President</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>
Times leads with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAO</ENAMEX> report to be released <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> warning that while
raising the retirement age would enhance the solvency of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Social Security</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">system</ENAMEX>, it also would cause serious health problems for blue-collar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX>
leads with a groundbreaking collaboration between the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Mexico</ENAMEX>
in the investigation of the drug trade: a jailed former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX>
national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">police</ENAMEX> was recently brought secretly to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">U.S.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Houston</ENAMEX>), where he
testified about drug payoffs at high levels of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>.

            
               <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> note that the latest round of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Starr</ENAMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">subpoenas</ENAMEX>, supported by an appeals court decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> impugning the
notion of "protective privilege," <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets agents</ENAMEX> with far more intimate
knowledge of presidential behavior and movements than the uniformed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Secret</ENAMEX>
Service <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> previously interviewed. Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOJ</ENAMEX> is expected to
contest the subpoenas, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX>' compelled testimony, says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> , is
not expected anytime soon. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAT</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> put the
development deep inside. Odd discrepancy: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">seven</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were
subpoenaed while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX>.

            Pictures from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> of little coffins get lots of front space all
around. In its news <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">section</ENAMEX> "cover story," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> says the arson deaths of
the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">brothers</ENAMEX> have given both <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Catholics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Protestants</ENAMEX> pause and appear
to have brought <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northern Ireland</ENAMEX> "back to sanity, back from the brink."

            Everybody reports that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">airline</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">America West</ENAMEX> has agreed to pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX>
a fine of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">at least $2.5 million</NUMEX>, the highest ever assessed
against an air <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">carrier</ENAMEX>, because of maintenance lapses the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX> alleges,
including continuing to fly <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">17</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">airplanes</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">41,000</NUMEX> flights past
the time when detailed inspections of the cargo-door and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crew</ENAMEX> areas were
required.

            <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Wall Street Journal</ENAMEX> dedicates a front-page <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leader</ENAMEX> to
catching up with some dual career <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">couples</ENAMEX> it wrote about more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty years</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>. Nice idea, but the piece turns out to be one part sociological reporting
and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX> parts nationally distributed resume and family album. Whoopee for
the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Baums</ENAMEX>, with their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">kids</ENAMEX>, their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">million-dollar apartments</ENAMEX> in
<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Manhattan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Greenwich</ENAMEX> and their chauffeur-driven <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rolls</ENAMEX>! In a world with too
much good stuff to read, "<ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Today's Papers</ENAMEX>" suggests the following rule of thumb:
Always skip a story that starts off with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">woman</ENAMEX>'s valiant struggle to keep off
her cellular phone for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a few days</TIMEX> for the sake of her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX>.

            The WP front notes the launch of an anti-gay newspaper advertising campaign by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">coalition</ENAMEX> of
conservative religious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> say they have been inspired by the
recent remarks by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Lott</ENAMEX> comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">homosexuals</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alcoholics</ENAMEX>, kleptomaniacs
and sex <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">addicts</ENAMEX>. Ads are running <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NYT</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WP</ENAMEX> , and
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USAT</ENAMEX> . Where are the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>' ads campaigning against <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">alcoholism</ENAMEX>,
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kleptomania</ENAMEX> and sex addiction?

            <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen Dowd</ENAMEX> takes note of a recent journalism trend: the tendency
of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">media</ENAMEX> "to forget about news and focus on themselves." And she has no
difficulty in culling support for her thesis from the recent list of hot
stories: the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Yorker</ENAMEX> succession, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time/CNN</ENAMEX>/sarin, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Fallows</ENAMEX>' firing,
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nina Burleigh</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oral Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Brill</ENAMEX>, etc. But therein lies a problem
for Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dowd</ENAMEX>: she's written at length about all of these matters, a length she
could have used to write about "news," but didn't. And indeed, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s column
just adds to her own media-saturated word count.

         
      
   
