
  
    
      
        
        As a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>, we pride ourselves on the uniqueness of our brain. Relative to our body
        size, the human brain is bigger than that of any other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX>. It may also contain unique
        structures and patterns of organisation that presumably underlie our intelligence and
        ability to manipulate our environment. But how did our unique brain originate, and under
        what selective pressures did it evolve? Some of the answers may lie in the genetic
        differences that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> are now uncovering between us and our closest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        What <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Is So Different about the Human Brain</ENAMEX>?
        When we compare our brain to those of other <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, the first thing that strikes us is
        its size. Human brains weigh on average <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">1,300 grams</NUMEX>; a squirrel brain weighs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">six grams</NUMEX>.
        Some of this difference is because, as larger <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, we need more brain to run our
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. However, the brains of our nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>, the great apes, weigh <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">only 300‚Äì500</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">grams</ENAMEX>, even though their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">body</ENAMEX> size is similar to ours (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). ‚ÄúHumans sit on the top of
        the pile when it comes to relative brain size‚Äù, notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">geneticist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lahn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) (see <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>).
        Throughout mammalian and primate evolution, there has been a gradual increase in brain
        size, superimposed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúspikes‚Äù</ENAMEX> of fast growth such as the tripling in human brain size
        that occurred <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1.5 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4 million years</TIMEX> after the human lineage diverged
        from that of the great apes. ‚ÄúEven in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">ape</ENAMEX> lineage, the brain has been expanding but
        along the human lineage it has really taken off‚Äù, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lahn</ENAMEX>.
        In addition, over time, different parts of our brain have increased in size at different
        rates. The cerebral cortex has expanded more than other areas, and within the cortex, some
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX> have expanded differentially while others have lagged behind.
        
          ‚ÄúHumans sit on the top of the pile when it comes to relative brain size.‚Äù
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paleoanthropologist Ralph Holloway</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) uses
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">endocasts</ENAMEX> to look for macroscopic differences in the brains of our human <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ancestors</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúWe
        fill human fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">skulls</ENAMEX> with vulcanised rubber and once it has set, we pull it out of the
        large hole at the base of the skull and the rubber snaps back into the shape of the skull‚Äù,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holloway</ENAMEX> explains. Endocasts are particularly useful for comparing brain sizes, but they
        also provide information on when the asymmetries that are present in our brain first
        appeared. These often reflect cerebral specialisation, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holloway</ENAMEX> believes that some of
        the asymmetries he sees in human fossil <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">skulls</ENAMEX> may indicate when our ancestors acquired
        language.
        More details about how the shape of our brain differs from that of our closest living
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX> are emerging from the work of neuroscientist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Zilles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of Medicine</ENAMEX>,
        Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center J√ºlich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>). He prepares magnetic resonance images of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX>, ape, and
        human brains and then uses a nonlinear elastic algorithm to transform one brain into
        another (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). ‚ÄúWe know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> we have to apply to the images to do this‚Äù, he
        explains, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúwhich</ENAMEX> tells us which areas of the brain have changed most during primate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evolution‚Äù.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zilles</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> also are currently using molecular imaging techniques
        to update the existing maps of the different areas within our brains. Until we have this
        information, it is hard to make meaningful comparisons between our brain and that of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chimpanzees</ENAMEX>. Already, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zilles</ENAMEX> has discovered that there is much more interindividual
        variation in human brain organisation than anyone suspected. This means, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zilles</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúthat
        a general statement like ‚Äòthe neocortex is bigger in human brains than in ape brains‚Äô
        actually tells us very little. It gives us the general direction that evolution has taken
        but not whether an ape brain is different because of its sensory, motor, or association
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">areas</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Scientists</ENAMEX> are also using other techniques to investigate more subtle changes in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">organisation</ENAMEX> of the human brain compared to the brains of other mammals and primates.
        Indeed, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holloway</ENAMEX>, the reorganisation of the brain during evolution has been at least
        important as its increase in size. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neurobiologist John Allman</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California Institute of</ENAMEX>
        Technology, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pasadena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX>, for instance, have
        discovered that a special type of large spindle-shaped neuron, first described in the early
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20th century</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Constantin von Economo</ENAMEX>, is unique to apes and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> and much more numerous
        in the latter. These neurons are found in brain areas that are implicated in decision
        making in uncertain situations so, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allman</ENAMEX> speculates, they may help <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> to interact
        rapidly in complex social situations.
      
      
        Costs and Benefits
        A bigger, more complex brain may have advantages over a small brain in terms of
        computing power, but brain expansion has costs. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> thing, a big brain is a metabolic
        drain on our <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>. Indeed, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> argue that, because the brain is one of the most
        metabolically expensive tissues in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, our brains could only have expanded in
        response to an improved diet. Another cost that goes along with a big brain is the need to
        reorganise its wiring. ‚ÄúAs brain size increases, several problems are created‚Äù, explains
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX>). ‚ÄúThe most serious is the increased time it takes to get information from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> place
        to another.‚Äù <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> solution is to make the axons of the neurons bigger but this increases
        brain size again and the problem escalates. Another solution is to do things locally: only
        connect those parts of the brain that have to be connected, and avoid the need for
        communication between hemispheres by making different <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">sides</ENAMEX> of the brain do different
        things. A big brain can also be made more efficient by organising it into more
        subdivisions, ‚Äúrather like splitting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> into departments‚Äù, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaas</ENAMEX>. Overall, he
        concludes, because a bigger brain 
        per se would not work, brain reorganisation and size increase probably
        occurred in parallel during human brain evolution. The end result is that the human brain
        is not just a scaled-up version of a mammal brain or even of an ape brain.
        For natural selection to work, the costs of brain evolution must be outweighed by the
        advantages gained in terms of fitness. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">many years</TIMEX>, explains ecological psychologist
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Dunbar</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Liverpool</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>), ‚Äúpeople thought that the ability to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hunt</ENAMEX> or forage better was what drove the evolution of our brains. But a better diet had to
        come before we could grow a bigger brain.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Dunbar</ENAMEX> believes instead that brain evolution in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">primates</ENAMEX> and more generally in mammals ‚Äúhas been driven by the need to manage social
        relationships, and in primates, in particular, to coordinate coherence in social groups
        through time and space‚Äù. More complex social interactions, he says, mean that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individuals</ENAMEX>
        are better able to pool resources to solve problems like finding food, and so they survive
        better.
        This theory, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunbar</ENAMEX>, is supported by a correlation between social <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> size and
        neocortex size across primates and modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, during primate brain
        evolution, the trend has been to add more material to the front than the back of the brain.
        The front of the brain is where information from the rest of the brain is interpreted, and
        the capacity to interpret information underlies social interactions, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunbar</ENAMEX>. The
        number of problem-solving cognitive tasks you can do may well depend on how much frontal
        lobe volume you have and how it is organised. Just think of how few moves you can run a
        chess game into the future with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980s</TIMEX> personal computer compared to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st century</TIMEX>
        mainframe machine, he suggests.
        
          The human brain is not just a scaled-up version of a mammal brain or even of an ape
          brain.
        
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genetics of Human Brain Evolution</ENAMEX>
        Selective pressures like those considered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dunbar</ENAMEX> and, before him, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holloway</ENAMEX> work on the raw material of random gene mutations, and molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> now
        have some clues to the gene changes that may underlie brain evolution. Take brain size, for
        example (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, including those led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lahn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neurologist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">geneticist Geoffrey Woods</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Leeds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>), wondered whether the genes
        that cause microcephaly, an inherited human disorder in which brain size is greatly
        reduced, might include genes involved in human brain evolution. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, mutations in the
        genes 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASPM</ENAMEX> (abnormal spindle-like microcephaly associated) and 
        microcephalin were identified as <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> causes of microcephaly. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Three</NUMEX> groups
        have since reported that both these genes have been under selective pressure during primate
        evolution. 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASPM</ENAMEX> encodes a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> involved in <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spindle</ENAMEX> formation, so it is tempting
        to think that changes in its sequence might result in an increased rate of cell division
        and hence brain size. But, cautions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúwe really have no idea yet how or even if 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASPM</ENAMEX> is involved in brain evolution‚Äù.
        Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lahn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> believe that 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASPM</ENAMEX> and 
        microcephalin may be only the tip of the iceberg when it comes to genes
        that have helped to shape our brains. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> has recently reported that
        deletion of a gene called 
        Nde1 produces <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> with very small brains. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúOur</ENAMEX> experiments indicate that
        the loss of 
        Nde1 causes neurons to mature prematurely. This stops them dividing so
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> end up with small brains‚Äù, explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>, who is now investigating whether human 
        NDE1 <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">variants</ENAMEX> have been positively selected during human evolution.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lahn</ENAMEX> is also searching for additional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> genes that might help to explain how our
        brains evolved. In a recent 
        Cell paper, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lahn</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> identify <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">several hundred</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> that
        are involved in nervous system biology and show that, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, there are significantly
        higher rates of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> evolution in these genes in primates than in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">rodents</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Protein</ENAMEX>
        evolution rates are particularly high in the lineage leading from ancestral primates to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lahn</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúso some of these genes may regulate brain size and behaviour‚Äù.
        However, he warns, as with 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASPM</ENAMEX> and 
        microcephalin , ‚Äúdefinitive proof for this will only come from functional
        studies, which are difficult to do‚Äù.
      
      
        Enter Glutamate Dehydrogenase
        For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gene, evidence for an effect on brain function may be emerging. <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Geneticist</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henrik Kaessmann</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lausanne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Switzerland</ENAMEX>) studies the origin of new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in
        primates, in particular genes that arise when a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> copy of an mRNA transcribed from an
        existing gene is integrated back into the genome. Usually this new ‚Äúretrocopy‚Äù is not
        expressed, but if the DNA inserts near an active <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX>, it can become a transcribable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äúretrogene‚Äù.</ENAMEX> This is the origin of 
        GLUD2 , a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">retrogene</ENAMEX> derived from 
        GLUD1 , which encodes glutamate dehydrogenase. 
        GLUD2 , which first appeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18‚Äì23 million years ago</TIMEX> in hominoids,
        probably immediately picked up a brain-specific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoter</ENAMEX> and then over the next few million
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX> acquired <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> critical amino <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> changes, explains <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaessmann</ENAMEX>. These allow 
        GLUD2 -encoded glutamate dehydrogenase to work better in the brain than
        the 
        GLUD1 -encoded enzyme. Because glutamate dehydrogenase recycles the
        neurotransmitter glutamate, the presence of 
        GLUD2 may permit a higher neurotransmitter turnover and greater neuronal
        activity in hominoid brains than is possible in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey</ENAMEX> brains, which lack 
        GLUD2 , suggests <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaessmann</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Expression</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaessmann</ENAMEX> plans to search his extensive database of retrocopies in the human genome for
        other functional genes that could, like 
        GLUD2 , be implicated in brain evolution. By contrast, evolutionary
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">neurobiologist Todd Preuss</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yerkes Primate Research Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emory University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Atlanta</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Georgia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>) hopes to identify genes involved in human brain evolution by
        comparing gene expression patterns in different primates. Preuss, who began training as a
        paleoanthropologist before turning to neuroscience, has been comparing post-mortem human
        and chimpanzee brains since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid 1990s</TIMEX>, believing that ‚Äúif we want to understand human
        brain evolution, we really have to compare <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">chimpanzees</ENAMEX>, our nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">relatives‚</ENAMEX>Äù,
        even though chimp brains have been evolving separately from ours for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5‚Äì7 million years</TIMEX>.
        But, warns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preuss</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúwe have to do these studies now. There are few chimps left and if we
        lose the opportunity to study them and their brains, we will lose forever a fundamental
        source of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">insight</ENAMEX> into our own <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        To begin with, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preuss</ENAMEX> used staining techniques that exploit <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> to examine the
        neural components of chimpanzee and human brains. Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, he was asked to collaborate
        in a microarray project. ‚ÄúMy <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> approach was very labour intensive so I jumped at the
        opportunity to screen <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> at once‚Äù, he says.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preuss</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX> now know that <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than 100</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> are differentially
        expressed in chimpanzee and human brains. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúImportantly</ENAMEX>, when we go back into tissue with
        probes for these gene products, in some cases there are remarkably different spatial
        patterns of expression in <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>, chimps, and macaques‚Äù, notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preuss</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúWe don't know yet
        what these differences mean in terms of functional organisation in these different brains
        but our results open up new and exciting vistas‚Äù, particularly since many of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentially</ENAMEX> expressed genes have not previously been considered as being potentially
        involved in brain evolution. The microarray data produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preuss</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
        also indicate that many of the gene expression changes that have occurred during brain
        evolution involve gene upregulation. For example, there is increased expression of genes
        involved in metabolism, <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">synaptic organisation</ENAMEX>, and synaptic function. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúAll</ENAMEX> told, it seems
        that the human brain may be more dynamic than ape or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkey brains‚Äù</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preuss</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúThe
        human brain seems to be running hot in all sorts of ways.‚Äù
      
      
        Scratching at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Surface</ENAMEX>
        As far as understanding how our brains evolved, more questions remain than have been
        answered. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> problem is that we don't really know enough about how our brains differ from
        those of other mammals and primates, although work by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zilles</ENAMEX> and others is helping here. We
        also know very little about how the areas of our brain are physically linked up, and we
        need to understand that before we can see how we differ from our nearest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">relatives</ENAMEX>. And as
        far as identifying the gene changes that were selected during evolution, although we have
        several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, we don't know how or if these gene variants affect our cognitive
        abilities. It is one thing, concludes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunbar</ENAMEX>, to identify genetic or anatomic differences
        between human and ape brains, but quite another to know what they mean in terms of actual
        cognitive processes.
      
    
  
