
  
    
      
        
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientist</ENAMEX> living in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is often asked <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> questions: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄúWhy haven't you left?‚Äù and
        ‚ÄúIs it still possible to work there?‚Äù The best response to the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> question is, ‚ÄúWhy
        should I?‚Äù‚Äîwhich either terminates the conversation or leads to a stimulating discussion
        about the fate of the world. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> question, however, deserves a serious answer. In
        fact, this is the question that every one of us keeps asking ourselves.
        There is no simple answer. The biggest problems we face are brain drain, inadequate
        infrastructure, and lack of money (or perhaps, lack of money, lack of money, and lack of
        money). In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Soviet Union</ENAMEX>, fundamental science was supported to a great extent by
        military expenditure. Thus, it is not surprising that <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> physics and mathematics were
        more successful than other fields, such as biology. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, military spending on
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX> declined sharply, although the exact numbers are hard to estimate. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the
        direct funding of science constitutes <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1.78%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>'s national budget (an additional
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.46%</NUMEX> is allocated to the space program), although the law stipulates that this figure
        should be <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">at least 4%</NUMEX>. Still, this funding amounts to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">46.2 billion rubles</NUMEX> (approximately
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.6 billion</NUMEX>), more than twice the amount spent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Although this figure looks
        negligible compared with spending on science in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and many <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, it could still be sufficient to support existing actively <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">working groups</ENAMEX> at a
        reasonable level.
      
      
        Funding
        There are several mechanisms for distributing funds for research. The major share comes
        via <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russia</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Science</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy of Sciences</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>, unlike
        its Western analogs, not only acts as a consulting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX>, but also has the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">authority</ENAMEX> to distribute money (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The funds come both as long-term support for
        scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutes</ENAMEX> and as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX> research programs. The former covers base
        salaries, which are small even by local standards (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about US$200</NUMEX> per month for a laboratory
        chief), and basic infrastructure (<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX>, electricity, etc.). This system of long-term
        support inherited all the old <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> ills, such as the lack of correlation between
        scientific output and the level of funding. As a result, the available resources are spread
        thinly over <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>, most of which are just barely alive. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academy</ENAMEX>
        research programs can provide funding at a higher level, sometimes even enough to do
        experimental research. However, the procedure of establishing such programs, though
        formally competitive, is often not transparent, and a major role is played by the so-called
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúadministrative resource‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allakhverdov</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pokrovsky 2003).</ENAMEX>
        Money is also distributed through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian Foundation for Basic Research</ENAMEX> (RFBR). The
        decisionmaking mechanism used by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFBR</ENAMEX> is closer to Western standards, and involves
        anonymous refereeing followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">board</ENAMEX> discussions. Although its grants are rather small
        (at most, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">several thousand dollars</NUMEX> per year for a maximum of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years</TIMEX>), they provide
        important additional support for many small and mediumsized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> that may receive several
        such grants for different projects. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFBR</ENAMEX> supports the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> and
        translation of books, travel to international conferences, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> of conferences
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and similar activities. Unfortunately, several programs (in particular, support
        for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>) have recently been transferred from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFBR</ENAMEX> to a newly established
        government <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, and have thus become less independent.
      
      
        Collaboration
        International collaboration and research grants are a major source of support for many
        active research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 1</ENAMEX>). Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> have programs for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and/or former <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">republics</ENAMEX>. Some of them, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes Medical Institute</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Chevy Chase</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>), fund individual <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>)‚Äîstipulate that <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">projects</ENAMEX> should be submitted jointly by academic and military
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>; and some agencies‚Äîin particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European INTAS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Belgium</ENAMEX>) and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American John E. Fogarty International Center</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Bethesda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Maryland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>)‚Äîsupport
        collaboration between <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> and Western <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX>.
        Another source of financial support is direct collaboration between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">laboratories</ENAMEX>. Even after a relatively short visit, the salary of a visiting researcher
        abroad can be stretched for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several months</TIMEX> back home in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>; even more importantly,
        experimental <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> visiting foreign <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> have access to modern instruments and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX>, which allows them to do modern research. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX> of such visits are often
        (although definitely not always) recent <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">immigrants</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>, and in such cases the
        collaborations may have roots in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">older days</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>).
        As well as supporting <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> science directly, international collaboration plays an
        important indirect role because it is less influenced by local politics. In fact, one of
        the main positive impacts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York‚Äìbased International Science Foundation</ENAMEX> set up by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Soros</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990s</TIMEX> was that it demonstrated the possibility of open competition
        with clearly defined rules‚Äîsomething unheard of in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Soviet</ENAMEX> times‚Äîand thus served as a model
        for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFBR</ENAMEX>, which was organized at approximately the same time.
        Unfortunately, international ties, especially with the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, have been
        adversely affected by recent changes in visa procedures, which have become lengthy (leading
        to many missed conferences) and, even worse, completely unpredictable (e.g., Brumfiel
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">grapevine</ENAMEX> distributes stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúbad words‚Äù</ENAMEX> that should be avoided when
        describing one's research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">area</ENAMEX> during an interview at the consulate. Examples of such words
        include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">adjective ‚Äúnuclear‚Äù</ENAMEX> (even within a innocuous terms like ‚Äúnuclear magnetic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resonance‚Äù</ENAMEX>) or, more recently, anything that involves <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúbacteria</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        The demand for fundamental and even for applied biological research from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
        industry is almost nonexistent. The pharmaceutical industry is content to produce generics,
        while <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are still exploiting old strains developed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soviet</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX>. However, some <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> are conducting outsourced research, and there are now
        research outposts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Japanese</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> organized as standard
        industrial <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>. On <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> hand, this work is a dead end for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, because the
        results of such research normally cannot be published. This is a serious problem,
        especially for young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> who want to establish themselves. On the other hand,
        royalties from patents or commercialization of the products can be used to support further
        research. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> that has followed this path successfully is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergey Lukyanov</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shemyakin Institute of Bioorganic Chemistry</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. They have developed the
        subtractive hybridization technique for enrichment of clone <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> by rare transcripts
        or specific genomic fragments (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rebrikov et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>), and are distributing it via a company
        called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evrogen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">http://www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">evrogen</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">com/</ENAMEX>about.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">shtml</ENAMEX>).
      
      
        Infrastructure and Bureaucracy
        Another major problem is the degradation of infrastructure. Only a few <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> can afford
        modern equipment and instruments, and for many others, even standard <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">chemicals</ENAMEX> are too
        expensive. This leads to a vicious circle: without equipment, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> cannot conduct
        experiments at the level demanded by highimpact journals‚Äîand without such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publications</ENAMEX>, it
        cannot compete for large grants. Smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFBR</ENAMEX> grants, while simpler to obtain, are
        insufficient to purchase large pieces of equipment, and funds from several grants or
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> cannot be combined due to bureaucratic restrictions. Thus, the only hope for
        these <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>, apart from international collaboration, is a personal connection with senior
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bureaucrats</ENAMEX> that might result in an (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">un</ENAMEX>)expected windfall.
        Having the funds to purchase modern equipment abroad is only the first hurdle; the many
        conflicting rules and restrictions, inefficiency, and corruption within the system can
        subsequently hold up the process. Some items, such as tissue samples or <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>, are
        virtually impossible to import legally. The process of clearing the shipments through
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">customs</ENAMEX> is a difficult, timeconsuming job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grigory Kopelevich</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard Hughes Medical</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX>, recalls a story of a grantee whose microscope was
        stopped at customs because the box contained <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> screwdrivers not specified in the order.
        Fortunately, to resolve the issue, it was sufficient to present one of the screwdrivers to
        a customs <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> as a gift.
        Even basic access to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> is a problem, especially outside the main research
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">centers</ENAMEX>. Indeed, out of a random sample of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> where electronic library
        catalogs were available via the Internet, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only six</NUMEX> had subscribed to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX> , and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">only two</NUMEX> to 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> . More specialized <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> are available only in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> and
        perhaps <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>. This is partially offset by the proliferating open-access <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Library of Science and BioMed Central</ENAMEX>, free electronic versions of older
        issues provided by some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, free subscriptions for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academic</ENAMEX> institutes
        granted by some <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> or purchased by international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundations</ENAMEX> (e.g., the
        e-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">library</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ru</ENAMEX> project organized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFBR</ENAMEX> and supported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Society Institute</ENAMEX> [the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros Foundation</ENAMEX>, based in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>] and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX>) (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Table 2</ENAMEX>), reprints
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX>' Web pages, and last but not least, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> abroad who break copyright laws
        by e-mailing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PDF</ENAMEX> files; there is even a popular bulletin board coordinating this activity.
        However, these are only partial solutions. <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is not considered a developing <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>,
        and thus is excluded from many international efforts that provide free access to journals
        (such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HINARI</ENAMEX>). Moreover, many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX> have page charges, but no <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Russian</ENAMEX> grants cover
        these, and the cost of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX> may be prohibitively high for many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Brain Drain
        These problems, along with low salaries, have naturally led to a huge brain drain.
        Entire <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generations</ENAMEX> have been decimated (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>); the dearth of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> at the postdoc
        level, has caused a gap in the teaching and maintenance of scientific traditions. Many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>
        now consist of older <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chiefs</ENAMEX> and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate students</ENAMEX> who plan to leave
        immediately after getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> degree (the equivalent of a Western doctorate).
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúLeaving‚Äù</ENAMEX> does not necessarily mean leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX>; many capable young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> go into
        business. While that might be good for the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">country</ENAMEX> in general, it is bad for science, at
        least in the short term. However, even emigration is not a completely negative thing; it
        creates a network of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">collaborators</ENAMEX>, and in many cases enhances ties with the international
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">community</ENAMEX>.
        Despite all this, science in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> is very much alive. Not-yet-<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nobel-prizewinner</ENAMEX> Alexei
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Abrikosov's</ENAMEX> repeated exhorations to the scientific community ‚Äúto help all the talented
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> leave <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and to ignore the rest‚Äù were met by universal disgust (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoffman</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>; Leskov <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Migdal 1993).</ENAMEX> There are several competitive <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> doing
        first-rate research and publishing in the top-tier <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>. Old habits die hard; even in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these days</TIMEX>, very decent results are often published in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russianlanguage</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, the best
        of which have impact factors that are around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each year</TIMEX>, many intelligent and capable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> enroll in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, and competition for admission is steadily increasing from
        the lows of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1990s</TIMEX>. There are also well-attended international conferences in
        several <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">cities</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Prospects
        What can be done by the international community to support what is left of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX>? Of course, direct support in the form of competitive grants is important,
        especially if there are few restrictions on spending; even the most carefully considered
        procedure cannot foresee all possible situations. But even more useful is the creation of
        joint research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>, such as the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> opened by the international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ludwig Institute for</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancer Research</ENAMEX> (LICR) based jointly in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Zurich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>, and the Belozersky
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of Physico-Chemical Biology of Moscow State University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>. This
        research <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">center</ENAMEX> began with limited support for several stronger <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX>, and is gradually
        moving toward integration of a research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">program</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> with other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LICR</ENAMEX> projects, and
        real collaboration between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LICR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> elsewhere.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the most essential elements of successful research is access to up-to-date
        information. Consequently, any initiative that provides open access to scientific
        literature and databases is extremely useful. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seminars</ENAMEX>, lecture <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">courses</ENAMEX> (such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>
        University [<ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Moscow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>] cycle on oncology and immunology sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LICR</ENAMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">www.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">oncoimmunology</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">ru/index_e.</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">htm</ENAMEX>), and the participation of Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> in
        scientific conferences in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> are important not only because they provide a fresh
        understanding of emerging trends, but also because they create personal contacts between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Russian</ENAMEX> and Western <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> that often lead to fruitful collaboration.
        By contrast, some other types of joint project may be less successful. Artificial
        programs aimed at creating various <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">participant</ENAMEX> ‚Äúnetworks‚Äù usually do not work as expected,
        and training programs in Western <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> often attract potential emigrants rather that
        those willing to continue active research inside <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX>.
        The contribution of the international community cannot be the sole decisive factor in
        the future growth of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> science. Important as it is in this transition period, it is
        no substitute for a systemic change. The ills of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> science are not unique; the same
        issues have been raised by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> from other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> (e.g., Wojcik
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). Even the existing funds could go much further if scientific policies were more open,
        better structured, and more competitive. Large grants should be provided, on the basis of
        well-defined criteria, to only the strongest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> doing the best research. An often-heard
        opinion that no independent review is possible in a small, well-entrenched community is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">irrelevant</ENAMEX>, since international <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">boards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> can be formed‚Äîthe example of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Soros</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">foundation</ENAMEX> clearly demonstrates that this is feasible. However, smaller <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">pilot</ENAMEX> grants are
        also needed to support young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX> contemplating new projects. This would
        create competition at all levels and provide doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> and postdocs with an
        incentive to stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and enroll in a strong <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>. But again, the procedure for
        awarding such grants should be well defined, transparent, and independent from
        administrative influences.
        Thus, the traditional model of top-down distribution of funds must be changed, and this
        may be difficult. The current system of decision making by <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> is
        clearly inadequate. Moreover, the problems of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> science mirror the problems of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Russian</ENAMEX> society in general, and it would be naive to expect that they will be solved
        overnight, even given the political will. Still, if successful, this combination should
        provide both high-level research in established <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX> and sufficient flexibility to find
        new directions.
      
    
  
