
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúI</ENAMEX> didn't want to be just another MBA,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pascal Herzer</ENAMEX>, one of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">recipients</ENAMEX>
        of a new graduate credential known as the professional science master's, or PSM. ‚ÄúNot many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> have the ability to understand science and business, and [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX>] program was
        designed for that very purpose.‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSMs</ENAMEX> are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s degrees financed in large part by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred P.</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sloan Foundation</ENAMEX> to cultivate science <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">managers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sloan</ENAMEX>'s ultimate goal is to make science
        careers more attractive to talented young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herzer</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Biosciences</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Arizona</ENAMEX>, who believes his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> makes him more
        marketable to science-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúI am at the true junction of science and
        business,‚Äù he says.
      
      
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Missing Degree</ENAMEX>
        Fortunately for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herzer</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX> of science is booming. Jobs for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">engineers</ENAMEX> grew <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX> times faster than the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> national average since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>, and
        should outpace the market until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">at least 2010</TIMEX>. Surprisingly to many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX>, most of
        these jobs are in industry. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> with complete data, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> out of three
        employed science and engineering (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&E</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> worked in industry, including the
        great majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bachelor</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s degree <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">holders</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40%</NUMEX> of doctorates. In other
        words, industry, not academe, now drives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American S&E</ENAMEX> employment, and will for the near
        future.
        Like academia, industry needs scientifically literate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>; unlike academia,
        industry wants <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX> with business savvy as well. However, in the past, graduate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> received either science or business instruction, not both. ‚ÄúIndustry simply hired
        regular master's-degreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>, or MBAs, or more likely <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PhDs</ENAMEX>, and just expected them to
        learn their weaknesses on the job,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor L. Babco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Executive Director</ENAMEX> of the
        Commission on <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professionals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science and Technology</ENAMEX>, a nonprofit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">corporation</ENAMEX> with funding
        from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sloan Foundation</ENAMEX> to assess <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> graduates.
        For science-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>, then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">American</ENAMEX> S&E doctorate‚Äîviewed by many as the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">worldwide</ENAMEX> gold standard for science education‚Äîis too specialized for their needs (see <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Box</ENAMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). But a master's degree may be just right.
      
      
        Bridging the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gap</ENAMEX>
        During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 20th century</TIMEX>, the master's degree evolved as a professional credential in
        many <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">fields</ENAMEX>, including business, education, and social work, and more recently, pharmacy,
        physical therapy, and accounting. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, non-incidental master's in the sciences‚Äîin
        other words, intentionally terminal degrees, not consolation prizes for failing out of
        graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">school‚</ENAMEX>Äîcrept into engineering and applied mathematics, too, as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> grew more
        reliant on computational analysis and hired accordingly. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1981 to 2000</TIMEX>, for example,
        the number of earned master's degrees in mathematics and computer science more than
        doubled.
        With hopes of spurring a ‚Äúsignificant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">movement</ENAMEX>,‚Äù in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sloan Foundation</ENAMEX> bet big on
        professional master's degrees, eventually spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> on <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost 100</NUMEX> programs
        across the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sloan Foundation‚</ENAMEX>Äìbacked PSM programs now operate at <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">states</ENAMEX>, in such fields as microbial biotechnology and applied genomics; similar programs
        have also developed independently of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sloan Foundation</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master of Science</ENAMEX> in
        Bioinformatics at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns Hopkins</ENAMEX>. And while most PSM-style programs are currently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>,
        this may soon change: the <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1999 ‚ÄúBologna Agreement‚Äù</ENAMEX> requires all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>
        to adopt uniform undergraduate and graduate degrees ‚Äúrelevant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> labour
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">market‚Äù</ENAMEX>; so master's-level industry-centric degrees are sure to follow. At Leiden
        University in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Netherlands</ENAMEX>, for example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> can now add <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">a ‚Äúscience</NUMEX>-based business‚Äù
        focus to any research <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX> of science (MSc) program.
        Like all graduate programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSMs</ENAMEX> offer advanced coursework in a (science or math)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">specialization</ENAMEX>, usually in an emerging or hybrid field such as bioinformatics. Most PSMs
        also provide business courses‚Äîincluding finance, project <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">management</ENAMEX>, regulatory affairs,
        and intellectual property law‚Äîand information technology classes as well. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSMs</ENAMEX> are
        ‚Äúindustry relevant‚Äù by design, with external advisory <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">committees</ENAMEX> populated by local
        business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weekly</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">colloquia</ENAMEX> led by corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representatives</ENAMEX>, special arrangements
        for employed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, and industry internships or final projects exploring realistic
        business scenarios (see <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 2</ENAMEX>).
        A key principle underlying the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX> is interdisciplinarity. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are
        encouraged to reach out to other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX> and broaden their expertise in multiple areas,
        to better understand the collaborative culture of industry-style scientific enterprise. To
        promote such <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">connections</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> programs explicitly teach teamwork and effective scientific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX>, with authentic case studies analyzed alongside MBA <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, classroom
        presentations and public seminars, and open defenses of final projects. Consequently, PSM
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>, unlike many doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX>, are trained to possess a wide array of
        interactive skills, including sizing up an <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">audience</ENAMEX> for their ability to comprehend the
        presented material and adapting appropriately.
        In a science-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">business</ENAMEX>, ideas must flow freely between <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and
        non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> in and out of the company‚Äîbetween <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">marketers</ENAMEX>, say, or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">inventors</ENAMEX> and patent lawyers‚Äîto capitalize on discoveries and comply with regulations. When
        non-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> misunderstand the science underpinning a business model, profits suffer. But
        the presence of a central <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employee</ENAMEX> who streams data between differently educated <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">network</ENAMEX> may boost the bottom line. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are specifically trained to act as such
        ‚Äúscience translators.<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">‚Äù ‚Äú</ENAMEX>[<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">My PSM</ENAMEX>] allows me to serve as an efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mediator</ENAMEX> between
        corporate <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">entities</ENAMEX>, university <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herzer</ENAMEX>.
        For this reason, small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> and start-ups, which cannot afford <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX> for
        every position, may particularly benefit from PSM-credentialed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">employees</ENAMEX>, able to connect
        different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and function in multiple roles; indeed, many PSM <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> have job
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">descriptions</ENAMEX> expressly created for them. ‚ÄúWe need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">generalists</ENAMEX> rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">specialists</ENAMEX>,‚Äù
        says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James L. Ratcliff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chairman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rowpar Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>, a dental products
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Scottsdale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Arizona</ENAMEX>. For small <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> like his, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ratcliff</ENAMEX> says, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">‚ÄúPSM</ENAMEX> graduates
        have an appropriate combination of project management expertise, an understanding of
        business environments and priorities, and advanced knowledge in the physical and life
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">sciences</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        Although it is too early for comprehensive assessment, employment outcomes for PSM
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> have been examined, and this result is clear: they are getting industry jobs.
        According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Conference Board</ENAMEX>, an independent business management <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX> funded
        by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sloan Foundation</ENAMEX> to survey <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">alumni</ENAMEX>, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91%</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> PSM <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> had
        obtained full-time <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">positions</ENAMEX> within their field despite a white-collar recession,
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two-thirds</NUMEX> with salaries of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> or more. A separate analysis by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission on</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Professionals</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science and Technology</ENAMEX> found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">61.5%</NUMEX> of employed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">respondents</ENAMEX> were hired
        by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">businesses</ENAMEX>. Employment opportunities range from marketing to bioinformatics (see <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 3</ENAMEX>).
        ‚ÄúCompanies need <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> that can work in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindy A. Brigham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">coordinator</ENAMEX> of
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Applied Biosciences PSM</ENAMEX> program at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Arizona</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Not a <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Perfect Cure</ENAMEX>
        Although most scientific careers demand a graduate degree, a professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s in
        many hard sciences still encounters entrenched academic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">opposition</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>-Jen
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wei</ENAMEX>, then acting chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Biostatistics</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard School of Public</ENAMEX>
        Health, quoted in the 
        Wall Street <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúHarvard</ENAMEX> tries to create <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leadership</ENAMEX> in industry,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">academics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX>, and our philosophy is we don't think that with a master's degree
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> can fill that role very easily.‚Äù
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> appears to agree with this view. While most doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX> receive
        federal funds for tuition and other expenses, there is little money for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>,
        who disproportionately end up in industry regardless of specialization. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX> are
        especially affected by this problem because <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúinterdisciplinary‚Äù equals ‚Äúexpensive</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        Similarly, ‚Äúinterdisciplinary‚Äù can also mean ‚Äúhard to find‚Äù‚Äîcompanies with targeted
        recruitment often miss <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, who are not ‚Äúin‚Äù any particular department‚Äîand
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúconfusing‚Äù‚Äîdifferences</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">these new</TIMEX>, still somewhat vaguely defined programs can make
        hiring comparisons difficult. But perhaps the most conspicuous drawback to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSMs</ENAMEX> is their
        newness, and resulting obscurity: <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">almost half</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduates</ENAMEX> say they are ‚Äúnot sure‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">employers</ENAMEX> will value their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX>, or the unique skill set it affords.
      
      
        But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will They Succeed</ENAMEX>?
        Still, many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">observers</ENAMEX> of higher education support the PSM concept. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Glazer-Raymo</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the forthcoming book 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professionalizing Graduate Education</ENAMEX>: The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Master</ENAMEX>'s Degree in the
        Marketplace , argues that converging market forces will lead to the success of the
        professional master's degree in science. These <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">forces</ENAMEX> include: rapid technological change;
        the rise of alternative learning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">channels</ENAMEX> such as online and distance education, corporate
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX>, and hi-tech certification programs; the proliferation of degrees in general,
        and in multidisciplinary fields specifically; and a fundamental societal shift away from
        public service and toward entrepreneurship, profitability, and competition.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth R. Smith</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dean</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eller College of Business and Public Administration</ENAMEX>
        at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Arizona</ENAMEX>, and others make the case that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSMs</ENAMEX> may protect <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>'
        careers from outsourcing to foreign countries. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American S&E</ENAMEX> labor pool is
        shrinking, and industry has already responded by transferring much of its research and
        development overseas; however, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> are mostly moving lab <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, not strategic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">analysts</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cross</ENAMEX>-training in both science and business could thus provide an edge for
        domestic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">workers</ENAMEX> in the near-term employment environment; in fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> programs have a
        higher proportion of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">residents</ENAMEX> than <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">S&E</ENAMEX> doctoral programs.
        Further, in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> report, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science Board</ENAMEX> urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">government</ENAMEX> to better
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">align S&E</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate</ENAMEX> education with ‚Äúexpected national skill needs,‚Äù including
        ‚Äúinterdisciplinary skills.‚Äù The report also recommended federal funding for a wider range
        of educational options and more attention on the real economic concerns of students‚Äîcode
        words for support of professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s degree initiatives. In the same vein, top
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> now advocate <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúinterconnections‚Äù</ENAMEX> between their professional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">schools</ENAMEX> and
        traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">departments</ENAMEX>, as a way of strengthening the overall academic mission, and many
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> are sponsoring initiatives to stimulate university‚Äìindustry links, to maximize
        marketing of technological innovations.
        For <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advocates</ENAMEX>, then, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PSM</ENAMEX> both advances the cause of science education reform and
        addresses changing employment conditions with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> big idea: reinvention of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two-year</TIMEX>
        graduate credential for an entrepreneurial age. Herzer, for one, now a technology
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scripps Research Institute</ENAMEX>, has staked his future on the
        potential of professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">master</ENAMEX>'s degrees. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúScientists</ENAMEX> rarely understand business
        dealings, and business <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">personnel</ENAMEX> rarely comprehend scientific discoveries,‚Äù he says. ‚ÄúThe
        overlay of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> is crucial for any successful business transaction of scientific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">origins</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
      
    
  
