
  
    
      
        
        The study of genetic material from ancient specimens was, in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early years</TIMEX>, dominated
        by a race to sequence <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from extinct species like the dodo and the woolly mammoth. Now
        that the supply of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">crowd</ENAMEX>-pleasing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">curiosities</ENAMEX> has run dry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> are starting to
        ask new questions of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> (aDNA) that are revealing how the genetic make-up of
        prehistoric <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">populations</ENAMEX> changed through time. These findings look set to trounce
        assumptions about how evolution really unfolded. However, there is still concern that many
        studies are not paying enough attention to the exacting protocols needed to overcome the
        technical challenges of the discipline and to defend it from the ridicule that has plagued
        it in the past.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, while 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Jurassic Park</ENAMEX> was still taking in <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">millions of dollars</NUMEX> at the box office,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> claimed to have extracted and sequenced <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from an <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">80-million</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur</ENAMEX>
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">1</ENAMEX>]. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sceptical researchers</ENAMEX> took a look at the sequence, it turned out to be of human
        rather than <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">dinosaur origin</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúTo make that mistake, you'd have to try really, really hard,‚Äù
        says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Cooper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Wellcome Ancient Biomolecules Centre</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>
        University in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>. If you think you've sequenced some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">dinosaur DNA</ENAMEX>, the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> thing you'd do is run a phylogenetic analysis on it, he says. ‚ÄúHad they done that
        properly, with any mammal at all involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">tree</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Ä¶they</ENAMEX> would have found that their
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">sequence</ENAMEX> was grouping with the mammals and not with the reptiles or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">birds</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX>. Perhaps they'd watched <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Crichton</ENAMEX>'s inventive fiction one too many times, he
        suggests.
      
      
        Setting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Standards</ENAMEX>
        It was this kind of bungling study that highlighted the need for an exacting protocol
        that would steer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> around the significant pitfalls posed by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA decay</ENAMEX> and
        contamination. A list of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúauthenticity criteria‚Äù emerged</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1990s</TIMEX>, aimed at
        preventing similarly bogus claims from entering the literature [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">2</ENAMEX>]. This list includes
        stringent laboratory controls; cloning of products amplified by polymerase chain reaction
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PCR</ENAMEX>); replication of results from a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, independent extract; and, for really new or
        unexpected results, replication of results by an independent research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>.
        Such requirements have allowed work on aDNA to move on and mature. Now, it's possible to
        focus on the really interesting questions that aDNA can answer. ‚ÄúWhat we're able to do with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ancient DNA</ENAMEX> is really look at evolution,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX>. The fossil record can only hint at
        how evolution unfolded. ‚ÄúIt just shows you there's a bear and then there's not a bear,‚Äù he
        says. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX> doesn't show you where it came from or what the relationship between the groups
        is.‚Äù By contrast, aDNA can do just that, giving <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> a window onto the population
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">genetics</ENAMEX> of the past and revealing how evolution really played out. And the signs are that
        descriptions of the evolutionary process based on the fossil record and modernday gene
        pools are far too simple. ‚ÄúThe modern data is clearly misleading us,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX>.
        ‚ÄúEvolution is much, much more complex and dynamic than we would hope.‚Äù
      
      
        Thinking Big
        Because of the decay that occurs with time, there is a limit to how far back aDNA can
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gaze</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>). ‚ÄúYour ideal preservation conditions are something that falls under <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ice</ENAMEX>,
        freezes instantly, and stays frozen until you get it,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúAs</ENAMEX> soon as we get up
        to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 million</NUMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years ago</TIMEX>] we can't get anything to work, and that's even under deep-frozen
        conditions.‚Äù But within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past 60,000 years</TIMEX>, there are several major evolutionary events
        that are worth studying‚Äîincluding a glacial maximum around <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18,000 years ago</TIMEX>, the invasion
        of the New World by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12,000 years ago</TIMEX>, and a global mass extinction about
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11,000 years ago</TIMEX>. These relatively recent events should be a good model for working out how
        similar events affected genetic diversity throughout evolutionary history.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX>'s latest work has analysed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">over 400 bison</NUMEX> fossils from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beringia‚</ENAMEX>Äîthe
        frozen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wastes</ENAMEX> between eastern <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Siberia</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Canadian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Northwest Territories</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">3</ENAMEX>]. ‚ÄúWhat
        we've done is carbon-date a shitload of bison and get <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> out of them.‚Äù It's the largest
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aDNA</ENAMEX> study to date, he says (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). The icy conditions mean that good quality
        mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> could be extracted from most of the specimens. The bison could also be
        dated accurately. This allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> to trace the changes in the bison
        genetic diversity from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">150,000 years ago</TIMEX> to the present. It was even possible to predict
        the effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> size throughout this period of bison evolution. ‚ÄúOur analyses
        depict a large diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX> living throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Beringia</ENAMEX> until around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">37,000</NUMEX> years
        before the present, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>'s genetic diversity began to decline dramatically,‚Äù
        they note.
        This finding challenges some common assumptions. It has been argued that modern bison
        are descended from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beringian</ENAMEX> bison, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX>'s data suggest otherwise. ‚ÄúAll modern bison
        belong to a clade distinct from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beringian</ENAMEX> bison,‚Äù he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> report.
        Furthermore, the dramatic decline in the numbers of bison occurs long before <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> arrive
        on the scene, scuppering the idea that hunting pressure was primarily responsible for the
        demise of the bison. As the glacial maximum approached <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18,000 years ago</TIMEX>, the cooler, dryer
        conditions were probably responsible for the downturn in the bison <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">population</ENAMEX>, argues
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúClimate change is giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> an absolute whacking,‚Äù he concludes.
        A similar analysis of brown bear <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA excavated</ENAMEX> from permafrost and cave deposits in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arctic</ENAMEX> is also challenging conventional evolutionary wisdom [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">4</ENAMEX>]. Being able to get both a
        radiocarbon date and some <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from a specimen pins a particular genetic sequence to a
        particular moment in time. These data suggest that genetically and geographically distinct
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">groups</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">bear</ENAMEX> have replaced each other relatively often during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the last 60,000 years</TIMEX>.
        Regional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">extinctions</ENAMEX> and replacements seem to be tied to climate change and competition
        with the much larger short-faced bears, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> argue (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>).
        Recent analysis of aDNA from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Haast's eagle</ENAMEX> has also thrown up a surprising result. This
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">giant</ENAMEX> had a wingspan of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">up to three</NUMEX> metres and a weight of <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">around 14 kilograms</NUMEX>,
        says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bunce</ENAMEX>, an anthropologist at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacMaster University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Ontario</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Canada</ENAMEX>. Analysis
        of aDNA from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2,000-year-old</TIMEX> specimens indicates that this extinct <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">creature</ENAMEX> is closely
        related to the little eagle from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Guinea</ENAMEX>, which typically weighs <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">less than</NUMEX>
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> kilogram. The common ancestor of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">eagles</ENAMEX> lived <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as recently as 1 million years</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ago</TIMEX>, he and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> estimate [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">5</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX> means an eagle arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">New Zealand</ENAMEX> and
        increased in weight by <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10‚Äì15</NUMEX> times over this period,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunce</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúSuch rapid size change
        is unprecedented in terrestrial vertebrates.‚Äù
        In addition to illuminating these natural events, the study of aDNA can also show
        changes in the frequency of key genes that occurred during the domestication of <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crops</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX>. For example, aDNA from samples of early <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maize</ENAMEX> reveals when certain desirable
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">traits</ENAMEX> appeared [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">6</ENAMEX>]. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> study of ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> that looks at phenotype,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Svante P√§√§bo</ENAMEX>, an evolutionary <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthropologist</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max Planck Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Leipzig</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúOne can actually look at specific genes that early <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> selected during
        domestication of an important <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">crop</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äù P√§√§bo</ENAMEX>'s analysis suggests that the alleles typical of
        contemporary <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maize</ENAMEX> were already present in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Mexican</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">maize</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4,400 years ago</TIMEX>, so just a couple
        of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">thousand years</TIMEX> after its initial domestication from the wild grass teosinte (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>).
        ‚ÄúQuite early on, properties were selected that were not only the structure of the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> but
        also the biochemistry,‚Äù he says.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aDNA</ENAMEX> is also being used to decipher human origins. Mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX>
        looks quite different from the mitochondrial <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> of early modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">7</ENAMEX>]. This lends
        support to the hypothesis that modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> have a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">‚Äúsingle African</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">origin‚Äù</ENAMEX> rather than the
        alternative hypothesis of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚Äúmultiregional evolution‚Äù</ENAMEX>, where the ancestors of modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>
        bred with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Neanderthals</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aDNA</ENAMEX> could also, in principle, be used to shed light on the
        evolutionary position of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18,000-year-old</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúhobbit‚Äù</ENAMEX> recently unearthed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Indonesian</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">island of Flores</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">8</ENAMEX>]. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooper</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">P√</ENAMEX>§√§bo have offered to have a go at isolating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚Äúhominid‚Äù skeleton</ENAMEX>, but the early signs are that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> has not survived. ‚ÄúThe somewhat
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">moist</ENAMEX> and tropical preservation conditions make the recovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> improbable,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, the paleoanthropologist at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New England</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Armidale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Australia</ENAMEX>, who
        led the hobbit study. Efforts to extract <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from other bones collected at the same site as
        this tiny hominid have not produced results. ‚ÄúWe have made attempts with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stegodon</ENAMEX> molars,‚Äù
        he says, ‚Äúbut so far without success.‚Äù
      
      
        Ongoing Controversy
        However, in spite of the authenticity criteria and this transition towards testing the
        big questions in evolutionary biology, aDNA research continues to invite controversy. In
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> claimed to have cultured a bacterium sealed
        inside a <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">250-million</NUMEX>-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt crystal</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">9</ENAMEX>]. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cooper</ENAMEX>, this is the sort of study that
        should require replication by an independent laboratory before publication. ‚ÄúWhen we
        repeated that work with the same primers, we were pulling up halobacteria from everywhere,‚Äù
        he says. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúWe</ENAMEX> took some dust from the top of the natural history <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oxford</ENAMEX>, extracted
        [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>], used their supposedly halospecific primers and extracted a whole bunch of sequences,
        including some that fell within their diversity.‚Äù This strongly suggests, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX>, that
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacterium</ENAMEX> that was cultured was a modern <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacterium</ENAMEX>, rather than an ancient specimen. ‚ÄúI
        can't see any logic for having <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">250 million years</TIMEX> without any evolution.‚Äù
        But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Vreeland</ENAMEX>, a microbiologist at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">West Chester</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> and
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">salt-crystal</ENAMEX> study, is adamant that his methods were exacting. ‚ÄúThe
        probability of having a contaminant in our sample was <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> chance in a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion</NUMEX>,‚Äù he
        calculates. ‚ÄúIf you use a <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Band-Aid</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> on your skin or your <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">children</ENAMEX>, you are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> times
        more likely to have an infection from that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Band-Aid</ENAMEX> than I am to have a contaminant.‚Äù It's
        completely unscientific to argue that the cultured <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacterium</ENAMEX> was a result of contamination
        simply because it resembles modern <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vreeland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThat</ENAMEX>'s throwing out the baby
        with the bathwater. If you can show that nothing has penetrated your sample and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> is
        inside, then the age of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> has to be equal to the age of that rock,‚Äù he says. ‚ÄúI think
        you can make your criteria so stringent that you miss reality.‚Äù
        Others are alert to this danger. Sticking rigidly to the authenticity criteria can be a
        problem, argues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Gilbert</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Ecology</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Evolutionary Biology</ENAMEX> at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Arizona</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚Äú</ENAMEX>[The criteria] can both hinder the publication of good studies that
        do not adhere to all the criteria, and also enable the publication of erroneous results
        that adhere strictly to them,‚Äù he says. Part of the problem is that many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referees</ENAMEX> of aDNA
        papers do not have a background working with aDNA, so are inclined to use the authenticity
        criteria as a checklist rather than critically evaluating each bit of research on a
        case-by-case basis. For example, he says, a recent high-profile study that followed all the
        criteria found that aDNA from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Cro</ENAMEX>-Magnon-type <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> was very similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from
        modern <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX> [<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10</TIMEX>]. But this could just mean that the specimens were contaminated by modern
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">humans</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúAs no information was provided on the sample's handling history,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äúit</ENAMEX> becomes impossible for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reader</ENAMEX> to decide whether the sequences are authentic or
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">contaminant‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 2</ENAMEX>). Such <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">papers</ENAMEX> will continue to appear as long as the authenticity
        criteria are used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">referees</ENAMEX> as a checklist, he says. This does not mean the
        criteria should be relaxed, he adds, but they should be used in a more intelligent way.
        But allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">authors</ENAMEX> the freedom to use the criteria as they see fit could come at a
        cost, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooper</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúThe trouble with a case-by-case basis is that it basically equates to
        no standards, because then <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> will do what they feel like doing and we're back to the
        1990s again,‚Äù he says.
      
      
        Agreement
        This ongoing disagreement over how aDNA studies should be judged does, however, stem
        from a common concern. As more and more <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> come to appreciate the unique ability of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">aDNA</ENAMEX> to probe the evolutionary process, it is more important than ever to stress the
        immense challenges of working with just a few fragments of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">degraded DNA</ENAMEX> that might have
        come from several different <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sources</ENAMEX>. It is obvious why an archaeology <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> might want to set
        up its own aDNA <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">facility</ENAMEX>. But this is like creating molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> without a license,
        says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">P√§√§bo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúYou</ENAMEX> wouldn't buy an accelerator and say 'I will now start doing my own carbon
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">dating</ENAMEX>,'‚Äù he says. ‚ÄúYou have to really have experience working with low copy number.‚Äù
        However, in spite of the continual problem of eager but inexperienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> trying
        to extract <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from specimens in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">university museum</ENAMEX>, there is a sense that aDNA is
        starting to fill in the gaps in our understanding of key moments in evolutionary history.
        So at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the start of 2005</TIMEX>, as aDNA research enters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">its 21st year</TIMEX>, the discipline is, perhaps,
        coming of age.
      
    
  
