
  
    
      
        Phytohormones: What Are they?
        Plant growth and development involves the integration of many environmental and
        endogenous signals that, together with the intrinsic genetic program, determine plant form.
        Fundamental to this process are several growth <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> collectively called the plant
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> or phytohormones. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> includes auxin, cytokinin, the gibberellins (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GAs</ENAMEX>),
        abscisic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene</ENAMEX>, the brassinosteroids (BRs), and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">jasmonic acid</ENAMEX> (JA), each of
        which acts at low concentrations to regulate many aspects of plant growth and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>.
        With the notable exception of the steroidal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bear</ENAMEX> little resemblance to their <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animal</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">counterparts</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). Rather, they are
        relatively simple, small molecules such as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene gas</ENAMEX> and indole-<NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>-acetic <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">acid</ENAMEX> (IAA), the
        primary auxin in the majority of plant species. The concept of plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> originates
        from a classical experiment on phototropism, the bending of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> toward light, carried
        out by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Darwin</ENAMEX> and his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1880</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darwins</ENAMEX> were able to demonstrate
        that when <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">oat seedlings</ENAMEX> were exposed to a lateral light <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>, a transported signal
        originating from the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> apex promoted differential cell elongation in the lower parts of
        the seedling that resulted in it bending toward the light <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">source</ENAMEX>. This signal was
        subsequently shown to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">IAA</ENAMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> known plant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        What Do They Do?
        Virtually every aspect of plant growth and development is under hormonal control to some
        degree. A single <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> can regulate an amazingly diverse array of cellular and
        developmental processes, while at the same time multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> often influence a single
        process. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Well-studied</ENAMEX> examples include the promotion of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">fruit</ENAMEX> ripening by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene</ENAMEX>,
        regulation of the cell cycle by auxin and cytokinin, induction of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed germination</ENAMEX> and stem
        elongation by <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX>, and the maintenance of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seed</ENAMEX> dormancy by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX>. Historically, the effects of
        each <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> have been defined largely by the application of exogenous hormone. More
        recently, the isolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">biosynthetic</ENAMEX> and response mutants has provided powerful
        new tools for painting a clearer picture of the roles of the various phytohormones in plant
        growth and development.
      
      
        How Do They Work?
        Plant <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> have been fascinated by the regulatory capacity of phytohormones since
        the time of their discovery, and the notion that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> levels or responses could be
        manipulated to improve desired plant traits has long been an area of intense interest.
        Perhaps the best-known example of this is the isolation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">dwarf</ENAMEX> varieties of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">wheat</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">rice</ENAMEX> that led to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúgreen revolution‚Äù</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the second half of the 20th century</TIMEX>, which is
        credited with saving <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">millions</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> around the globe from starvation. These dwarf
        varieties have shorter stems than wild-type, making these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plants</ENAMEX> less susceptible to damage
        by wind and <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">rain</ENAMEX>. The molecular isolation of these <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">‚Äúdwarfing genes‚Äù</ENAMEX> has revealed that they
        encode components of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX> biosynthesis and response pathways (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peng et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sasaki et</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">al. 2002</ENAMEX>).
        To elucidate the molecular mechanisms underlying phytohormone action, several
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> have utilized the genetically facile model plant 
        Arabidopsis thaliana to isolate mutations that confer altered
        response to applied hormone. Molecular and biochemical analysis of the gene products
        defined by these mutations, coupled with expression studies aimed at identifying the
        downstream target genes that mediate hormonal changes in growth and development, has begun
        to unlock some of the mysteries behind phytohormone action. While no <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> transduction
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathway</ENAMEX> is completely understood, we now have a rudimentary understanding of many of the
        molecular events underlying hormone action. Several reviews covering the individual hormone
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathways</ENAMEX> in greater detail have recently been published (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Turner et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomi</ENAMEX> and
        Matsuoka <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Himmelbach et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; Kakimoto <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dharmasiri</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Estelle</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guo</ENAMEX> and
        Ecker <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He 2004).</ENAMEX>
      
      
        Common Themes
        Regulation by proteolysis has emerged as a resounding theme in <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plant</ENAMEX> hormone signaling.
        The ubiquitin-mediated degradation of key regulatory <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> has been demonstrated, or is
        at least likely, for all of the phytohormone response pathways (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smalle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vierstra 2004).</ENAMEX>
        In the case of auxin, the response pathway is normally subject to repression by a large
        family of transcriptional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aux/IAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). These proteins
        dimerize with <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">members</ENAMEX> of the auxin response factor (ARF) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of transcription factors,
        thus preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ARFs</ENAMEX> from activating auxin-responsive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tiwari et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). Upon an
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">auxin</ENAMEX> stimulus, an SCF (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SKP1/Cullin/F-</ENAMEX>box <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>) ubiquitin ligase (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Deshaies 1999</ENAMEX>)
        containing the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">TIR1 F-</ENAMEX>box <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> ubiquitinates the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Aux/IAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, marking them for
        degradation by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 26S</TIMEX> proteasome thereby de-repressing the response pathway (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gray et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>). The hormone promotes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Aux/IAA‚</ENAMEX><ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ÄìTIR1</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">interaction</ENAMEX>; however, the molecular mechanisms
        behind this regulation are unclear. Most <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">yeast</ENAMEX> and animal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">SCF substrates</ENAMEX> must be
        post-translationally modified, usually by phosphorylation, before they are recognized by
        their cognate <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">F-</ENAMEX>box <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>. Despite numerous efforts to identify auxin-induced
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">modification of Aux/IAA</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX>, no such signal has been discovered, raising the distinct
        possibility that auxin uses a novel mechanism to regulate SCF‚Äìsubstrate interactions.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ethylene</ENAMEX> and cytokinin are both perceived by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> sharing similarity to bacterial
        two-component <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX>. Common in prokaryotes, but apparently restricted to <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">plants</ENAMEX> and
        fungi in eukaryotes, these modular signaling systems involve a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">membrane-bound</ENAMEX> receptor
        containing an intracellular histidine kinase (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">HK</NUMEX>) domain (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wolanin et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>). Ligand
        binding activates the kinase, resulting in autophosphorylation and initiation of a series
        of phosphotransfer reactions that culminates with the activation of a response regulator
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX> that functions as the effector component of the pathway. Cytokinin signaling
        appears to largely follow this paradigm (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kakimoto 2003).</ENAMEX> Ethylene response, however,
        appears more complex (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ecker 2004).</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Ethylene</ENAMEX> is perceived by a family of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>. ETR1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">ERS1</ENAMEX> contain a consensus
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK</ENAMEX> domain, however, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK</ENAMEX> domains of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ETR2</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">ERS2</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">EIN4</ENAMEX> are degenerate and lack elements
        necessary for catalytic activity. This fact, together with studies of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚Äúkinase-dead‚</NUMEX>Äù mutants
        of 
        ETR1 , suggests that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HK</ENAMEX> activity is not required for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene</ENAMEX> response.
        Mutations that abolish ethylene binding in any of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">five</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor genes</ENAMEX> are dominant and
        confer ethylene insensitivity, indicating that the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> function as negative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene pathway</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genetic</ENAMEX> and molecular studies have positioned these <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> upstream of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Raf</ENAMEX>-like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase kinase kinase</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CTR1</TIMEX>, which interacts with the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX> and also acts as a
        negative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> (Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">3</NUMEX>). The integral membrane <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">protein</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">EIN2</TIMEX>, and the transcription
        factors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">EIN3 and EIL1</TIMEX> are positive <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene</ENAMEX> signaling downstream of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CTR1</TIMEX>.
        Current <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">models</ENAMEX> propose that hormone binding inactivates the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptors</ENAMEX>, thus resulting in
        down-regulation of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CTR1</TIMEX> activity. Since the identification of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">CTR1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> have
        speculated that a <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">MAP kinase cascade</ENAMEX> may be involved. Only recently, however, have putative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">MAP kinase kinase</ENAMEX> and MAP kinase components of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene</ENAMEX> pathway been identified (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chang</ENAMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). Interestingly, these kinases appear to positively regulate ethylene response,
        suggesting that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">CTR1</ENAMEX> must inhibit their function. If so, this would represent a novel twist
        on the traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">MAP kinase signaling paradigm</ENAMEX>. Precisely how the ethylene signal is
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">transduced</ENAMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the EIN3 and EIL1</TIMEX> transcription factors remains unclear. However, the recent
        finding that ethylene stabilizes these transcription factors, which are targeted for
        degradation by an SCF <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">complex</ENAMEX> in the absence of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene</ENAMEX>, clearly indicates a role for the
        ubiquitin pathway (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Ecker</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Potuschak et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> of the known targets for
        EIN3 is the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ERF1</NUMEX> transcription factor, which activates several genes involved in a subset
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene</ENAMEX> responses.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Signal Integration</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combinatorial Control</ENAMEX>
        Long ago, <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">plant</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physiologists</ENAMEX> noted the apparent antagonistic interactions between some
        of the phytohormones, such as between auxin and cytokinin in the regulation of root‚Äìshoot
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">differentiation</ENAMEX> and between <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ABA</ENAMEX> in germination. Other processes are synergistically
        regulated by multiple <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>. While it has long been obvious that <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> do not
        function in discrete pathways, but rather exhibit extensive cross-talk and signal
        integration with each other and with environmental and developmental signaling pathways,
        the molecular basis for such coordinated regulation has been unclear. Several recent
        findings have begun to elucidate the molecular details of some of these events.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">One</NUMEX> example of such signal integration was recently described for the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene</ENAMEX> and JA
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathways</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo et al. 2003).</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genetic</ENAMEX> studies had previously implicated both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> as
        important <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulators</ENAMEX> of pathogen defense responses, as well as of the wounding response and
        other stress-related pathways. Additionally, microarray analysis has identified a large
        number of genes that are responsive to both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">ERF1</NUMEX> transcription factor was
        recently found to be an intersection point for these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> signaling pathways (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo</ENAMEX> et al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>). Like <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JA</ENAMEX> rapidly induces 
        ERF1 expression, and treatment with both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> synergistically
        activates 
        ERF1 . Induction of 
        ERF1 by both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> alone or in combination is dependent upon both
        signaling pathways, and constitutive overexpression of 
        ERF1 rescues the defense-response defects of both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">ethylene</ENAMEX>- and
        JA-insensitive mutants. These findings suggest that 
        ERF1 represents <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of the first signaling nodes identified in the
        complex web of hormonal cross-talk.
        The auxin and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX> pathways also appear to converge and mutually regulate some
        developmental processes. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX> promote cell expansion, and microarray studies have
        revealed that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">as many as 40%</NUMEX> of all BR-induced genes are also up-regulated by auxin (Goda
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">et al. 2004</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nemhauser et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX> is perceived by the cell surface <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX> kinase
        BRI1 (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wang</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">He 2004).</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">SHAGGY/GSK3</ENAMEX>-type <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">kinase BIN2</ENAMEX> acts as a negative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">regulator</ENAMEX> of
        the pathway downstream of the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor</ENAMEX>. In the absence of a BR signal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BIN2</ENAMEX> phosphorylates
        the transcription factors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">BES1 and BZR1</TIMEX>, targeting them for proteolysis by the 26S
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">proteasome</ENAMEX>. Upon a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX> stimulus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">BIN2</ENAMEX> is inactivated, allowing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">BES1 and BZR1to</TIMEX> accumulate in
        the nucleus, where they are presumably involved in regulating <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">BR-responsive genes</ENAMEX>.
        Using combined genetic, physiological, and genomic approaches, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nemhauser</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>
        (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>) were able to demonstrate that auxin and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX> regulate 
        Arabidopsis hypocotyl (embryonic stem) elongation in a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">synergistic</ENAMEX> and interdependent fashion. Elevating endogenous auxin levels rendered plants
        more sensitive to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX> application in hypocotyl elongation assays, and this response was
        dependent upon both the auxin and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX> signaling pathways. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genetic</ENAMEX> studies suggest that the
        convergence of these <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> pathways occurs at a late point in hormone signaling, perhaps at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> of the many genes responsive to both <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormones</ENAMEX>. In support of this notion,
        bioinformatic analysis identified distinct sequence elements that were enriched
        specifically in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">promoters</ENAMEX> of auxin-induced, BR-induced, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">auxin</ENAMEX>/BR-induced genes.
      
      
        Many Unanswered Questions
        While great strides have been made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> in understanding the molecular basis
        of phytohormone action, many fundamental questions remain. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Receptors</ENAMEX> and other upstream
        signaling components remain to be identified for the majority of the phytohormones. Equally
        important are the elucidation of hormonal networks and the integration of these networks
        with the morphogenetic program, such that our understanding of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hormone</ENAMEX> action can be placed
        in a developmental context.
      
    
  
