
  
    
      
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science</ENAMEX> looks set for a fundamentalist revival within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>. Its leading
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> are taking advantage of unprecedented political upheaval‚Äîas <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">ten</NUMEX> new Member
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">States</ENAMEX> accede to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union‚Äîto</ENAMEX> press their case for funding of basic research that is driven
        solely and independently by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> themselves in the pursuit of excellence.
        The broad thrust of their appeal calls for the setting up of a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agency</ENAMEX>, most commonly
        referred to as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄòEuropean Research Council‚Äô.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> could be an entirely new organisation
        or a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> within an established <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, run by a small staff able to draw on the best
        expertise available. It would administer a new fund from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> coffers, tagged the European
        Fund <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">for Research Excellence</ENAMEX>, that would be valued modestly, initially at least, at much
        less than half of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>'s existing budget for research. Most importantly, dispersal of
        that fund would reflect the wishes of eminent peer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX>, assessing competitive bids in
        search of the best science, rather than the judgements of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eurocrats</ENAMEX>, looking for the most
        politically and economically expedient solutions and operating on a lead time of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years</TIMEX>
        or more.
        Although the modus operandi of the proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> has still to be worked out, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> have been looking to the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and at the way that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard Hughes Medical Institute</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wellcome Trust</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>. In particular, they seek the independence and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">excellence</ENAMEX> achieved outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> framework. More to the point, they are weary of the
        bureaucratic formulations that determine how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>'s research budget, currently known as
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Sixth Framework Programme</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">2002‚Äì2006</ENAMEX>) and worth <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">around ‚Ç¨4.4 billion</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">/year</TIMEX> (or just over
        <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5%</NUMEX> of all public spending on nonmilitary research in the region), is spent and distributed.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>'s guiding principle is often one of 
        juste retour , or fair reward, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Member States</ENAMEX> traditionally seek
        to recover grants at least equal to their contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> pot (see <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Box 1</ENAMEX>).
        ‚ÄòMost of the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Anglo-Saxon</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Europe‚Äîthe Scandinavian</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Kingdom</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Netherlands‚</ENAMEX>Äîoperate a peer review process and a research funding council
        process that's very similar to best practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äô</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Morgan</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">consultant</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wellcome Trust</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> issues and former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX> of the
        Trust's <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Genome Campus</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hinxton</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄòThe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">French</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Germans</ENAMEX>
        and others have elements of that but they also have what you might call more ‚Äústate-funded
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">science‚Äù</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> as civil <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">servants</ENAMEX>, and there is obviously much greater possibility of
        science being funded for less than the best scientific reasons,‚Äô notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morgan</ENAMEX>, referring to
        the opportunities for greater political influence on decision-making. ‚ÄòI'm not suggesting
        that that is the case, but it is the possibility,‚Äô he adds.
        ‚ÄòWhat we need in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is something that should strictly adhere to the international
        standards of research funding and be evaluated by peer review,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äô</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Gruss</ENAMEX>, professor
        of molecular cell biology at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of G√∂ttingen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max Planck</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Munich</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄòThe sole criterion has to be quality, not geographical
        distribution, not management capacity,‚Äô he adds, alluding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> practice of 
        juste retour . ‚ÄòWe want to encourage excellence in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>. We want to
        have as a benchmark a <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> standard that should be as high as the standard is in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX>.‚Äô
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gruss</ENAMEX> acknowledges the tensions that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> proposal has generated among <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Member States</ENAMEX>:
        ‚ÄòI'm not saying that there aren't <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> that have this standard‚Äîlike the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>, parts of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>, and some other <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Nordic</ENAMEX> countries‚Äîbut of course this is not the general
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> standard, and in order to get <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> and the same, the common standard, we need a
        common structure.‚Äô
      
      
        A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fund for Excellence</ENAMEX>
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX> now appears ready to accept the need for a common structure that
        would have, as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> puts it, ‚Äòmore open and less binding‚Äô programmes of basic
        research, in contrast to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Framework Programme</ENAMEX>, whose emphasis is on applied research
        with commercial objectives. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> expects to publish its endorsement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX>
        proposal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>, so that approval by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of the EU</ENAMEX> should follow later this
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX>. On this timetable, setting up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> could begin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX> when the next <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year</TIMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Framework Programme</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">FP7</TIMEX>, gets underway.
        Over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>, its grant is expected to grow from around <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">‚Ç¨500</NUMEX>
        million/<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚Ç¨2 billion</NUMEX><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">/year</TIMEX>, and to derive from a reallocation of funds within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>'s
        budget rather than from any top-up contributions from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Member States</ENAMEX>. Furthermore, Gruss
        released a legal opinion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> that advised how an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> need not be an executive agency
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>, as many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> had feared it would have to be under the terms of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU Treaty</ENAMEX>, but could be established as an independent and autonomous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>. The opinion is a
        real coup for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lobbyists</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Origins of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX>
        Moves to establish an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> are founded in a ‚Äònew strategic goal‚Äô for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> that the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> of its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">15</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">Member States</ENAMEX> set during their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Council</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lisbon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2000</TIMEX>.
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the first decade of the new millennium</TIMEX>, they urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> ‚Äòto become the most
        competitive and dynamic knowledge-based economy in the world‚Äô. They enthusiastically
        endorsed a notion, floated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Commission</ENAMEX>, of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Research Area</ENAMEX> (ERA).
        ‚ÄòResearch activities at national and [<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX>] <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> level must be better integrated and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">co</ENAMEX>-ordinated to make them as efficient and innovative as possible, and to ensure that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX> offers attractive prospects to its best brains,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äô</ENAMEX> concluded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX>, eager to
        reverse the flow of trained <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">talent</ENAMEX> abroad, notably to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>. All appropriate means,
        they added, ‚Äòmust be fully exploited to achieve this objective in a flexible, decentralised
        and non-bureaucratic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">manner‚Äô</ENAMEX>.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years later</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Council</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">leaders</ENAMEX> went <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> step
        further by defining the target more precisely. ‚ÄòIn order to close the gap between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>
        and its major <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competitors</ENAMEX>,‚Äô they said, ‚Äòoverall spending on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R & D</ENAMEX> and innovation in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> should be increased with the aim of approaching <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX> of GDP by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Two-thirds</NUMEX> of this
        new investment should come from the private sector.‚Äô
        The scale of the challenge is illustrated by the latest figures for <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R</ENAMEX> & D
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">expenditure</ENAMEX>, published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Statistical Office of the European Communities</ENAMEX>
        (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eurostat</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>'s estimated <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R & D</ENAMEX> spending in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.99%</NUMEX> of GDP, still far short
        of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.80%</NUMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.98%</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>), and a long way from the target of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX>.
        Emphasising the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>'s uneasiness about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>'s escalating enthusiasm for a regional
        science <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">base</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Society</ENAMEX> (the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX> national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">academy</ENAMEX> of science) poured scorn on the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äòambitious‚Äô</ENAMEX> GDP target by noting how the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> alone would have needed an extra <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¬£11 billion</NUMEX> in
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 60%</NUMEX> of total spending on <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R & D</ENAMEX>, to lift its ratio of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.85%</NUMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3%</NUMEX>
        target. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Society</ENAMEX> also noted how public funding of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R & D</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> matches that
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Japan</ENAMEX>, with the disparity among GDP ratios reflecting the differentials in
        private investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R & D</ENAMEX>, over which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> has little control.
        Nevertheless, the challenge could not be ignored. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob May</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> of
        mathematical biology at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Oxford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Society</ENAMEX>, and
        former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Chief Scientist</ENAMEX>, such initiatives might be ‚Äòdriven more by political expediency
        than common sense, but the moment you see that train beginning to roll, there's a chance to
        do something useful with it‚Äô.
        Among the leading <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernard Larrouturou</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director general</ENAMEX> of the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Centre of Scientific Research</ENAMEX> (CNRS) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">France</ENAMEX>. For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larrouturou</ENAMEX>, a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">biomathematician</ENAMEX> currently engaged in streamlining the organisation, the changes at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> level are a breath of fresh air. However, he is not convinced that funded
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> should expect to exclude Commission <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">strategists</ENAMEX> entirely from their lives.
        The scientific community should lead an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX>, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larrouturou</ENAMEX>, ‚Äòbut I do not like the idea
        that this should be completely under the guidance and wisdom of the scientific community
        with no strategy guidance. You cannot ask for <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Euros</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">every year</TIMEX> and say there
        will not be any strategy and [that it will be done solely] on this basis of excellence.‚Äô
        And <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larrouturou</ENAMEX> distances himself from the idea that basic and applied research can be
        treated separately because this suggests, wrongly he says, a conflict between the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX>.
        On these issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Larrouturou</ENAMEX> moves onto some common ground with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Taylor</ENAMEX>, former
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director general</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Research Councils</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> and now <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chairman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roke Manor Research</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">subsidiary</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Siemens</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> electronics <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>. Research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Councils</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> oversees spending
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>'s national research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">councils</ENAMEX> (currently, just over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¬£2 billion</NUMEX> from its <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2004‚Äì2005</NUMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Budget</ENAMEX> of nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">¬£2.7 billion</NUMEX>). Interactions across disciplines and between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and technologists ‚Äòare not helped by making artificial distinctions between this
        kind of research and that kind of research,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äô</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄòThe distinctions I make are much
        more between top-down and bottom-up.‚Äô
        While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> is a joint <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architect</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> proposal to create an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX>, he remains
        unconvinced that the research funding system is broken, especially from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">perspective</ENAMEX>, and needs to be fixed. Nor is he convinced that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> funds for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> will not
        affect national <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">R & D</ENAMEX> budgets. ‚ÄòI'm middle of the road,‚Äô he says. ‚ÄòMuch greater
        collaboration is good. It has to be a slow process, with all the different cultures
        involved. Collaboration on various areas of science is an excellent way to go, provided you
        don't try to organise it from the top and legislate for it all to happen in a particular
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way</ENAMEX> and to a particular timescale. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Excellence</ENAMEX> is key.‚Äô
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s cautions reflect his experience of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Framework Programme</ENAMEX> and his
        reservations that any initiative from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> can be free of red tape. ‚ÄòIf you want to do
        research, then you can't lay out beforehand all the answers you're going to get,‚Äô he says.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄòAnd</ENAMEX> if you try to get <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to stick rigorously to a plan, then you get a lot of silly
        things going on. If you try to form very complex bureaucratic organisations to do the
        research, you get a lot of delays and so on, so things are not very timely.‚Äô
        But the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Framework Programme</ENAMEX>'s failures need not spell disaster for the fledgling funding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">council</ENAMEX>, insists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lennart Philipson</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director general</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Molecular</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biology Laboratory</ENAMEX> (EMBL) in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Heidelberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>, and now an emeritus <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">professor</ENAMEX> at the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Karolinska Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Stockholm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sweden</ENAMEX>. Drawing on his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11 years</TIMEX> as head of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMBL</ENAMEX>, until
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philipson</ENAMEX> recalls how ‚Äòpan-<ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> peer review was the best method for distributing
        the funds of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMBL</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMBO</ENAMEX> [<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Molecular Biology Organization]‚Äô.</ENAMEX> The continuing high
        status of the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> organisations, he says, is testimony that the system works. In fact, EMBO
        is mentioned as a possible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">incubator</ENAMEX> for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX>, in spite of its specialisation.
        Other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of the proposed research changes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> include <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">45</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> Laureates
        from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> or of <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> origin, who headed a petition organised by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMBO</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Scientists Organization</ENAMEX> (ELSO) organised another. Its <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">president</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kai Simons</ENAMEX>, also the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max Planck Institute for Cell Biology</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Genetics</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Dresden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>,
        says research funding in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is just not working. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄòIt</ENAMEX>'s not geared for basic research‚Äîit
        has other aims,‚Äô he notes. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> funds are ‚Äònot grants, they are contracts with in-built
        milestones that have nothing to do [with basic research]. Basic research doesn't work like
        that.‚Äô
        The evaluation and peer review system is falling apart, continues <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simons</ENAMEX>. He says that
        the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are not interested in peer reviewing a system that doesn't work: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>ÄòYou're
        not attracting the peer <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">reviewers</ENAMEX> that you need to maintain quality.‚Äô But at last,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acknowledges Simons</ENAMEX>, someone in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX> is listening. ‚ÄòIn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the past two years</TIMEX> there has
        been enormous progress.‚Äô
      
      
        Many Questions Remain
        Within <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month</TIMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barcelona Council</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Science Foundation</ENAMEX> (ESF),
        which brings together the funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">29</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">countries</ENAMEX> and acts as a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">bridge</ENAMEX> to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>, had formed a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High Level Working Group</ENAMEX> to review the case for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> and how it
        might operate. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX>, chaired by Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Sykes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rector</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Imperial College</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">London</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2003</TIMEX>. It endorsed the creation of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> as
        ‚Äòthe cornerstone for the ERA and the key approach to developing a locus for‚Ä¶long-term
        fundamental curiosity-driven research judged on the basis of excellence and merit‚Äô. The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sykes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> also proposed, controversially, an enhanced <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESF</ENAMEX> as the most effective medium
        for establishing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> swiftly.
        ‚ÄòSome <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> say that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESF</ENAMEX> has no experience in funding large amounts‚Ä¶ for research,‚Äô
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">acknowledges Enric Banda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director general</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catalan Research Foundation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Barcelona</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Spain</ENAMEX>, who finished a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five-year term</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESF</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">chief executive</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the end of 2003</TIMEX> and is
        credited with ‚Äòwaking up‚Äô the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">foundation</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄòBut</ENAMEX> certainly if you create a new
        [organisation], that's the same thing. So the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESF</ENAMEX> is in a good position because its member
        organisations are the funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.‚Äô
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertil Andersson</ENAMEX>, who was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sykes Group</ENAMEX> before taking over from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banda</ENAMEX> at
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESF</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, also stakes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESF</ENAMEX>'s claim to nurture a fledgling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX>. But he accepts
        that any one of the respected national funding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">German Research</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> (DFG), or even a specialist <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">body</ENAMEX>, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMBO</ENAMEX>, could do the job. ‚ÄòWe don't need
        a new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">skyscraper</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Brussels</ENAMEX>, but a lot of‚Ä¶ peer review and running of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> could be
        done by existing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">bodies</ENAMEX>.
        ‚ÄòCompared to <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">soccer</ENAMEX>, we have only the national leagues‚Äîwe don't have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Champions</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">league</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>'s best <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">teams</ENAMEX>],<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äô</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andersson</ENAMEX>. There is no competition for
        basic research grants across national boundaries in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, he insists. ‚ÄòThe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">Swedish</ENAMEX> league
        is exciting, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Champions League</ENAMEX> is more exciting.‚Äô
        In the meantime, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sykes</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> was still deliberating, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council of the EU</ENAMEX>
        appointed another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">experts</ENAMEX> to evaluate the case for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX>. Chaired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Federico</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Organization</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNESCO</ENAMEX>), the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC Expert Group</ENAMEX> also delivered its verdict‚Äîa resounding
        endorsement‚Äîwithin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 months</TIMEX>.
        ‚ÄòThe <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> and main task for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> should be to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigator</ENAMEX>-driven research
        of the highest quality selected through <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">competition</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äô</ENAMEX> concluded the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> report,
        published in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2003</TIMEX>. ‚ÄòIn doing so, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> should create and support nodes of
        excellence in <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">universities</ENAMEX> and research <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX>, strengthening the
        knowledge-base that underpins economic, industrial, cultural and societal development, and
        thereby stimulating <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> competitiveness and innovative capacity at all levels.‚Äô
        While few disagreed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> report's sentiments, the absence of a detailed
        analysis exposed underlying tensions over the rationale for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX>, in
        particular, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> seemed concerned that their mature and respected system for
        funding research risked dilution.
        ‚ÄòThe <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> have always had doubts about what goes on in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>,‚Äô notes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kai Simons</ENAMEX>.
        ‚ÄòThey always think that they can do it better. But the big problem for the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> is that
        they are also too small to fund a new innovative area,‚Äô he says. ‚ÄòOf course, we can do it
        without <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, but they are an important part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and it would be sad if they're
        not part of it.‚Äô
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agnostic</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Taylor</ENAMEX>, who was a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">member</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor group</ENAMEX>, recalls his early
        reservations when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">group</ENAMEX> convened. ‚ÄòI'm way beyond the euphoria; I'm into practical
        pragmatics,‚Äô he notes. ‚ÄòMy major input into the whole thing has been to get them to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúget
        real‚Äù instead of just philosophising. They've been using the sort of, dare I say it, Gallic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">approach‚Ä¶</ENAMEX> of thinking about the reasons why, and the philosophy, and not thinking about
        what you would actually do.‚Äô
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> dismisses the notion that wariness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">representative</ENAMEX> of a general
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antipathy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX> towards <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">European</ENAMEX> integration. ‚ÄòWhat we're saying is that science in
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX> is not yet well-funded enough to say we would rather do this [the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX>] instead of
        the things that we're already trying to get done in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">UK</ENAMEX> scene.‚Äô
        Anticipating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Mayor</ENAMEX> report's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publication</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Society</ENAMEX> quickly pulled together a
        detailed background paper <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last year</TIMEX> that identified ‚Äòa number of problems that need
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">resolution</ENAMEX>, although not necessarily through the establishment of any major new
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> within <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe‚Äô.</ENAMEX> An addendum followed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, in direct response to the Mayor
        report. That addendum highlighted what it saw as the paucity of solid evidence in the Mayor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">report</ENAMEX> and, in some cases, the confusing data in the report's case for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX>.
        On balance it looked as though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Society</ENAMEX>, and as such the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> science
        establishment as a whole, had weighed the disadvantages of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> as greater than its
        advantages, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob May</ENAMEX> is quick to refute this charge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄòMy</ENAMEX> vision and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Society</ENAMEX>'s
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">vision of the ERC</ENAMEX> is that it will fund the very best science,‚Äô he insists. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄòThe</ENAMEX> Mayor
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committee</ENAMEX> itself was really good <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who'd produced basically a good <ENAMEX TYPE="PLANT">report‚Ä¶</ENAMEX>. I'm
        basically in favour of this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Research Council‚Ä¶</ENAMEX> provided it can be set up properly,
        which is by no means certain.‚Äô
        For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>, and other <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> on the continent, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> offers a real chance to redress
        the balance of fortune in favour of young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄòThe way to encourage science is to
        get the best <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> and set them free to express their creativity while they are young,
        which means bring them into the best laboratories‚Äîdon't let them get entrained in
        hierarchies of deference to second-rate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX>,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äô</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">May</ENAMEX>.
        ‚ÄòThe most important single thing to create <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> in science is a flexible
        postdoctoral programme that gets the best young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> wherever they are and lets them go
        to the best places,‚Äô enthuses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ERC</ENAMEX> will then foster those collaborations, he
        forecasts. ‚ÄòIt won't ask whether they're 
        juste retour , whether they're serving some industrial purpose, it will
        just try to fund the best science. But I hope increasingly the best projects will involve
        collaborations, as they do in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Britain</ENAMEX>, collaborations among <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institutions</ENAMEX> within
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.‚Äô
      
      
        
      
    
  
