
  
    
      
        
        
          
            
              <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄòYou‚Äô</ENAMEX>, your joys and your sorrows, your memories and your ambitions,
              your sense of personal identity and free will, are in fact no more than the behavior
              of a vast <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">assembly</ENAMEX> of nerve <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">cells‚Ä¶‚Äù ‚ÄîCrick</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">p. 3</ENAMEX>)
            
          
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Crick</ENAMEX> was an evangelical atheist. He believed that scientific understanding
        removed the need for religious explanations of natural phenomena. From <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Watson</ENAMEX>'s and
        his early work, the structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> explained the Œ±, the origins of life. This was a
        starting point; from the elucidation of the structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, there was an explosion, a
        massive diversity of science that in part removed the need to postulate a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">creator</ENAMEX> or a
        creation myth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> still felt that life was no less astonishing just because it was
        biological and natural in origin. He had a consistent and completely rational world view
        without a need to invoke vitalism, or any non-material <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">force</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. Crick 2004).</ENAMEX> And in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last decades</TIMEX> of his life, he applied this philosophy to the Œ©, consciousness.
        Once the structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was known, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Gamow</ENAMEX> formed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNA Tie Club</ENAMEX>,
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">eighteen</NUMEX> others including his close <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Orgel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Sydney</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brenner</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>); it was an ingathering that sowed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">seeds</ENAMEX> for future molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX>
        (Judson <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> had become the ‚ÄúŒ±,‚Äù the beginning (<ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Bronowski 1978</ENAMEX>), not just of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>'s career, but of a whole new culture of scientific life and understanding (Crick
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>).
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Ten years later</TIMEX>, the secrets of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA transcription</ENAMEX> and translation unmasked, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
        turned to consciousness. He admitted he knew little at <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX>, only that the structure of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consciousness</ENAMEX> was as tough a problem as <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>'s structure. <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> was certainly not played out,
        but the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Ferrier Lectures</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Proceedings</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Society of London</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hubel</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Torsten Wiesel</ENAMEX> were just available, tempting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> with an almost <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physicist</ENAMEX>'s view of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neurons</ENAMEX> in action. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hubel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiesel</ENAMEX> wrote of functional <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">architectures</ENAMEX>, embedded in
        beautiful, almost crystalline structure. The comprehension of mind invoked by a biological
        mechanism appeared ripe for the sort of thoughtful, theoretical science he had applied to
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> was now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sixty years old</TIMEX> and moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salk Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">La</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jolla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">California</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> began with the brightest young minds he could find.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Marr</ENAMEX> was a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">mathematician</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">physiologist</ENAMEX> whose doctoral thesis on a theory
        of mammalian brain function at <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX> had brought him into some contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brenner</ENAMEX> and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomasio Poggio</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max Plank Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">T√</ENAMEX>ºbingen on a computational theory of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neuroscience</ENAMEX>. Following an invitation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poggio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marr</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the month</TIMEX> of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April, 1979</TIMEX> extending their intense examination of the core problems of visual perception.
        They spent <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">hours</TIMEX> sitting at the most western end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salk Institute</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cafeteria</ENAMEX> or
        in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">office</ENAMEX>, gazing into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX> with all its daily changes, discussing
        not only architecture of visual cortex and visual perception, but the ramifications of a
        good theory of brain function. We know of these conversations, as the probing of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marr</ENAMEX> by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> is captured in the final chapter of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marr</ENAMEX>'s now classic book <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">‚ÄúVision‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marr 1982).</ENAMEX>
        (Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marr</ENAMEX> speaks of a three-way conversation, judging from our own experiences as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>'s younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX>, the interlocutor simply seems to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>.)
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marr</ENAMEX> had been diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">acute leukemia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the winter of 1978</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaina 1991).</ENAMEX>
        The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">one-month</TIMEX> visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salk Institute</ENAMEX> was an intellectual gift, for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eighteen months</TIMEX>
        later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marr</ENAMEX> died. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> had simultaneously lost a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friend</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleague</ENAMEX> who had
        brought an ‚Äúincisive mind and creative <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">energy‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Crick 1994, p. 77</ENAMEX>) and his best new ideas
        of a theoretical neurology to the brain (Marr <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969, 1970</TIMEX>). And he saw the tragedy of Marr
        being cut off from solving the big problems for which he was so clearly destined.
        During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">those early years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> must have thought that consciousness was tractable‚Äîif
        only the right way of thinking was brought to bear on it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>'s brain was capable of
        collecting and filing away many disparate data, which he could then combine uniquely and
        imaginatively, leading to that ‚Äúdramatic moment of sudden enlightenment that floods the
        minds when the right idea clicks into place‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Crick 1990, p. 141</ENAMEX>). Whatever his initial
        thoughts about the nature of the problem, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> soon came to realize that the problem of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">consciousness</ENAMEX> was even tougher than he imagined, that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">‚Äúclick‚Äù</ENAMEX> was not happening with
        consciousness. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, he wrote, ‚ÄúI have yet to produce any theory that is both novel and
        also explains many disconnected facts in a convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">way‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Crick 1990, p. 162</ENAMEX>).
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the quarter century</TIMEX> he was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salk Institute</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> did propose solutions to
        some smaller problems in neuroscience (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sejnowski 2004) and</ENAMEX> brought consciousness into the
        scientific fold (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rich</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens 2004).</ENAMEX> But something else was going on quietly and behind
        the scenes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> was building an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX> to help him take on consciousness. This was not
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">empire</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">head</ENAMEX> of a group of directed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Cambridge</ENAMEX>
        or <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">German</ENAMEX> model. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> continually encouraged and assisted young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to approach
        the hardest problems of the brain. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marr</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poggio</ENAMEX> were just the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> recruits he helped
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">embolden</ENAMEX>. He started his long-time collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christof Koch</ENAMEX>, once a post-doctoral
        trainee with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poggio</ENAMEX>, on ‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Problem of Consciousness‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koch</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990, 1992</TIMEX>). His
        door was always open to graduate <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">students</ENAMEX>, postdoctoral trainees, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">faculty</ENAMEX> who wanted to
        discuss those problems as many others and we can attest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> could be found <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">daily</TIMEX> at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">tea</ENAMEX> time, an ingathering of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salk Institute</ENAMEX> computational and vision <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratories</ENAMEX> of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simon LeVay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Sejnowski</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Albright</ENAMEX>, surrounded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">graduate students</ENAMEX> and
        post-doctoral <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">trainees</ENAMEX>, with conversation ranging across science‚ÄîFrancis listening to their
        stories of their explorations and encouraging them to reach beyond their horizons. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
        had a ‚Äúlove of the truth and helped others to move to the truth‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Watson 2004).</ENAMEX>
        When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> worked on the structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, he had some simple facts, such as
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chargaff</ENAMEX>'s Laws, and means to make point mutations from which it could be determined how
        function followed structure. But not a single neuroanatomist knew how many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neurons</ENAMEX> actually
        converged in their input to a particular single cell. No one knew how to eliminate a
        specific cell type from a circuit‚Äî to make a point mutation, so to speak, in the structure
        of consciousness. His <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> article in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scientific American</ENAMEX>, ‚ÄúThinking about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brain,‚Äù</ENAMEX> did
        not have much impact at the time, even when it explicitly described <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> needed methods:
        first, a method by which all the connections to a single neuron could be stained; <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX>, a
        method by which ‚Äúall neurons of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">just one</NUMEX> type could be inactivated, leaving the others more
        or less unaltered‚Äù; and <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">third</NUMEX>, a means to differentially stain each cortical area, <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">‚Äú‚Ä¶so</ENAMEX>
        that we could see exactly how many there are, how big each one is and exactly how it is
        connected to other areas.‚Äù By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> had realized that these massive holes
        in our understanding of the most simple brain facts were not being filled. Something needed
        to be done.
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the twenty years</TIMEX> since the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RNA Tie Club</ENAMEX>, molecular biology had matured. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
        actively began encouraging the inclusion of the critical tools of molecular biology in the
        study of neural circuits and perception; in his thinking, molecular biology was critical to
        understand how the brain worked because it provided tools. He would encourage junior
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, postdoctoral trainees, and faculty‚Äîall those who had visited him over the
        years‚Äîto think about using these tools. He would give short homilies about the plethora of
        sub-types of neurons in the retina; would not the cortex be at least as rich in
        possibilities? Molecular tools could unravel this knot.
        As we reminisced after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>'s death, we discovered that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> had spoken with each
        of us on these molecular methods, across a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">twenty-year</TIMEX> interval. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the mid-1980s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>
        spoke with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX>, pressing him to consider how he might do highly specific <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">lesions</ENAMEX> of
        single neuron types in motion cortex using molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">identifiers</ENAMEX>. At the time, the only
        tools imaginable were some sort of <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">killer</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibody</ENAMEX> approach. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> recalls
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> continuing to encourage this cross-disciplinary molecular and systems approach. It
        was absolutely imperative to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>'s vision of the maturation of neuroscience that there
        would be a conjoining of molecular biology and systems <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neuroscience</ENAMEX>. We are sure we were
        not unique in hearing this call; with how many others had he shared his vision?
        The science of the mind is a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">thinker</ENAMEX>'s game. It is chess against the grandest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">masters</ENAMEX>,
        biological evolution and natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">selection‚</ENAMEX>Äîand we are just learning to move the pieces. Our
        viewpoint is often myopic, with our noses pressed against the back row of the chessboard.
        It is hard to see the pieces, let alone their arrangement or the strategies they are
        forming. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> may not have had the overview needed to reveal evolution's gambit, but he
        knew the moves needed to clear the ‚Äútangle of difficulties‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Crick 1994, p. 77</ENAMEX>) that
        prevented an unfogged view of his opponent's pieces.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> hoped for simplicity. He wrote, ‚ÄúCuriously enough, in biology it is sometimes
        those basic problems that look impossibly difficult to solve which yield most easily‚Ä¶. The
        biological problems that are really difficult to unscramble are those where there is almost
        infinity of plausible answers and one has to painstakingly attempt to distinguish between
        them.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Crick 1990, p. 157‚Äì158</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crick</ENAMEX> had picked the right pieces of
        information to construct their <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">model</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> early on had had the same hopes to open the
        doors of consciousness (to paraphrase <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huxley 1963).</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crick</ENAMEX> used their intuition
        to fill in the gaps. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> found that there were just too many possibilities, and the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gaps</ENAMEX> in knowledge were still just too big for consciousness.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> felt that gentle and informal direction was not enough. Thus, he
        convened a meeting of molecular <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">biologists</ENAMEX> and neuroscientists at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salk Institute</ENAMEX> to
        encourage them to work together. He brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Albright</ENAMEX>, Ursula
        Bellugi, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ed Callaway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rusty Gage</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Heinemann</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Sejnowski</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Stevens</ENAMEX>, and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Inder Verma</ENAMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">room</ENAMEX> and said it was time to get serious. He reminded them of the
        advantages of genetic methods for targeting specific cell types within complex neural
        circuits, and he reiterated the need for methods that could be used to identify,
        manipulate, and observe neural circuits in action. Not only were methods to be used in
        transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>, but also methods based on viral <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">vectors</ENAMEX> were needed to study the visual
        system of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">monkeys</ENAMEX>. From this, a number of initiatives moved forward, with studies ranging
        from the molecular biology of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Williams</ENAMEX> syndrome to basic molecular tool <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">building</ENAMEX> (Naldini
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">et al. 1996</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blomer et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bellugi et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pfeifer et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zhao et</ENAMEX> al.
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kaspar et al.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">2002a</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002b, 2003</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lechner et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lein et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>).
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> the tools are emerging at an ever faster pace, at least in part due to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>'s
        maneuvers behind the scenes and his encouragement of junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> is curing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>'s bout of scientific prematurity (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stent 1972).</ENAMEX> Individual cell types will soon be
        reversibly inactivated (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johns et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lechner et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slimko et</ENAMEX> al. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Ibanez-Tallon et al. 2004</ENAMEX>); viral methods of tracing connections will start to fill in the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">gaps</ENAMEX>; new sensor methods for simultaneously recording from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">hundreds</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">thousands</NUMEX> of
        identified neurons are coming (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guerrero</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Isacoff</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zemelman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Miesenbock</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>;
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Tsien 2003</ENAMEX>). There is a new field <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> termed ‚Äúmolecular psychology‚Äù or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">‚</NUMEX>Äúmolecular
        biology of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">systems neuroscience‚Äù</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albright</ENAMEX> simply calls it <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neuroscience</ENAMEX>.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> was diagnosed with colon <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX>. He realized that the problem of the
        neural correlates of consciousness might outlast him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> was walking with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">cane</ENAMEX>,
        still not waiting for anyone, nor allowing anyone to wait for him. He continued to find
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">time</ENAMEX> for new faces in the field and continued to work on consciousness. While he had made
        many strides forward, he saw the race for him was winding down. He had had his hope for
        understanding the structure of consciousness. He had laid the groundwork. He decided to
        encapsulate his ideas in a ‚ÄúFramework‚Äù <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koch</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Koch 2003).</ENAMEX> For many of
        us it was clear that he was laying out where he would go, had he enough time.
        Each of the points of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Framework</ENAMEX> could form a major research initiative. Perhaps they
        should. But the central point is the 
        approach to understanding consciousness; it is both structural and
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">functional</ENAMEX>, peering forward into the future into what the shape might be. It was clear to
        his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> was leaving a last testament.
        As the <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">cancer</ENAMEX> finally caught up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>, he focused on the role of the rarely
        studied claustrum (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherk 1986).</ENAMEX> He wrote internal memos, brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">friends</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> to
        working <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">lunches</ENAMEX> at home with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Odile</ENAMEX>, his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">wife</ENAMEX> of fifty-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years</TIMEX>. Why do this? Why all this
        focus on another part of the brain, when <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">only months</TIMEX> remained? (Indeed it turned out to be
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">weeks</TIMEX>.) Was it his way of saying goodbye, of bringing his extended <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> close again? We
        think not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> wanted to make sure his plan went forward. He stressed to his visitors
        queries about the origins of the claustrum, its molecular biology, its role in
        consciousness. He was using his framework, pointing out the route to understanding the Œ© of
        his career.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> was doing what he truly loved to his last moments. He needed to be doing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">science</ENAMEX>, perhaps more than ever, to take him away from the physical pain that he surely
        felt. He had built his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">army</ENAMEX>. Perhaps none of us even knew we had enlisted, but we had. And
        he was setting us off on the long march forward into a time that soon would not be for him.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> died on the cusp of a new age of molecular systems <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">neuroscience</ENAMEX>. Soon, we will have
        the tools and the data, but we will not have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> had existed between the Œ± of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> and the Œ© of consciousness. And for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX> who never believed in the afterlife, he had
        indeed achieved immortality.
      
    
  
