
  
    
      
        
        By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summer</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">more than 40%</NUMEX> of 
        Streptococcus pneumoniae strains in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> will
        resist both penicillin and erythromycin, according to a recent prediction from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard</ENAMEX>
        School of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Health</ENAMEX>. The forecast, based on mathematical modeling, was published in the
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring of 2003</TIMEX>. It's too early to tell whether that prediction is precisely on track,
        according to the senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">author</ENAMEX> on that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Lipsitch</ENAMEX>. But no one doubts that
        multidrug <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> in this common bug‚Äîresponsible for <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> that range from sinus
        trouble and ear infections to meningitis and pneumonia‚Äîis speeding up.
        It is the certain fate of all antibacterials to be fought off eventually by the
        pathogens they target. The fact that the process is accelerating has been alarming public
        health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officials</ENAMEX> for some time, especially in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>. We need new ways to defeat
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease</ENAMEX>, and we will need them forever.
      
      
        Tried and <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">True‚Äîand Tired</ENAMEX>?
        Antibiotics have traditionally been plucked from nature's battleground. For <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">years</TIMEX>, tiny <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> have engaged in an arms race, hurling toxic molecules at each other
        in the struggle to prosper. Nearly all of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s antibiotics are versions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">weapons</ENAMEX> long
        wielded by microbes and fungi. Chemical synthesis of entirely human-created antibiotics has
        so far yielded only fluoroquinolones, a group of broad-spectrum antibiotics that includes
        Cipro, which became famously scarce during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 2001</TIMEX> anthrax scare, and linezolid
        (trade-named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zyvox</ENAMEX>), which is effective against some resistant strains of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">Staphylococcus ,</ENAMEX> 
        Streptococcus , and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterococcus</ENAMEX> .
        The usual way to find a new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic</ENAMEX> has been laborious screening of immense libraries
        of compounds, natural and otherwise. Some argue that screening chemical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> is
        approaching a deadend. There may be diminishing returns from screening, but it's not quite
        dead yet: in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wisconsin</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">Madison</ENAMEX> reported a new
        class of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacterial RNA polymerase inhibitors</ENAMEX> with antibiotic potential. They were found by
        screening for molecules that prevent 
        Escherichia <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">coli</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">transcribing RNA</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher T. Walsh</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard Medical School</ENAMEX> says screening's problem may be simply
        that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> aren't good enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">Marine organisms</ENAMEX> have not been studied well, he points
        out, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> in the biosphere can't be cultured in standard ways. He says,
        ‚ÄúWe're missing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90%</NUMEX> of them every time we go and look in nature.‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> is doing his bit to create new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX>. He and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have recently
        employed combinatorial biosynthesis to learn how to use part of the machinery for
        assembling cyclic peptide antibiotics to control their architecture. The result was a small
        library of natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">product analogs</ENAMEX>, some of which have improved antibiotic activity against
        common bacterial pathogens. ‚ÄúThere are <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of such enzymatic domains that in principle
        one could clone, express, and test with other substrates. I view that as the kind of thing
        we should do,‚Äù he says. For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> suggests, it is a reasonable approach to
        second-generation improvement of daptomycin, the antibiotic most recently approved for sale
        in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>.
      
      
        Improving on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX> collaborates with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chaitan Khosla</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University</ENAMEX> on finding ways to make
        existing antibiotics better. They are studying biosynthesis of rifamycin, an antibiotic
        that is increasingly less effective against its prime target, tuberculosis (<ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">TB</ENAMEX>) (see Figure
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1</NUMEX>). ‚ÄúIn the course of learning about that pathway, we've learned a few interesting things
        lately about how that molecule is initiated, and we're trying to apply it in other
        contexts, especially in the context of erythromycin biosynthesis,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Khosla</ENAMEX> says. The idea
        would be to make a molecule that might be more effective against <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> that are becoming
        resistant to rifamycin‚Äîand are already naturally resistant to molecules like
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">erythromycin</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúBasically</ENAMEX>, what we do is to try and figure out new ways to hijack the biosynthesis of
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">antibiotics</ENAMEX> in nature so as to modify their <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> with the goal of improving them,‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khosla</ENAMEX> explains. He works with an important class of natural <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotics</ENAMEX> called polyketides
        that have generated <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">dozens</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, including erythromycin.
        Polyketides are secondary metabolites (which give their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">producers</ENAMEX> a competitive
        advantage in their environment) produced mostly by <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> and fungi and made by a complex
        and structurally diverse <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">family</ENAMEX> of enzymes called polyketide synthases (see the primer by
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hopwood</ENAMEX> in this issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> ). Among them are the anthracyclines, a group of anticancer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> and antibacterials that includes tetracycline. In this issue of 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PloS Biology</ENAMEX> , <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Khosla</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> report that they can make
        selective positional modifications in existing anthracycline antibiotics by starting in a
        different way with a different starting molecule. The molecule came from a natural
        anthracycline <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic</ENAMEX>, an estrogen <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">receptor antagonist</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">R1128</ENAMEX>. R1128 is made via
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> modules of enzymes that work sequentially; the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> module starts the process, and the
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> completes it. This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of labor permitted the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> to tack the first
        R1128 <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">module</ENAMEX> onto <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">two</NUMEX> other enzyme systems, thus engineering completely new anthracyclines.
        Some were more active in two types of assays than the natural parent molecule. ‚ÄúOne setting
        was an assay on an <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">estrogen-sensitive cancer</ENAMEX> cell line. Another setting was an assay to
        probe activity of an enzyme that's of particular interest in <ENAMEX TYPE="LANGUAGE">Type</ENAMEX> 2 <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diabetes</ENAMEX>, called
        <ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">glucose-6-phosphate translocase.</ENAMEX>‚Äù The work also revealed fundamental mechanistic features
        of the polyketide synthases, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khosla</ENAMEX> says.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> didn't study the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">anthracyclines</ENAMEX>' effects on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>, but Khosla
        notes that the general principle should apply to other classes of compounds, although the
        details of how it's implemented will vary from system to system. He says, ‚ÄúThe upshot of
        this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">paper</ENAMEX> is that it is now possible to modify a particular <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> in just about any
        anthracycline <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
      
      
        Finding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Targets</ENAMEX>
        Instead of searching for new antibiotics by modifying existing ones, some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX>
        are trying something completely different‚Äîfirst finding the most vulnerable targets in a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacterium</ENAMEX> and then designing something that hits <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> or more of them hard. ‚ÄúYou have to
        understand a helluva lot more about how these little cells work. In fact, we think we
        understand a lot, but I think we can understand almost everything now that we have all the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">genomes,‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Shapiro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford University School of Medicine</ENAMEX>. While having full
        genome sequences‚Äîmore than 100 microbe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">sequences</ENAMEX> have been completed‚Äîis essential, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shapiro</ENAMEX>
        believes that knocking outs genes galore to find out which ones are necessary and going
        after them all is not a sensible strategy. She observes, ‚ÄúPeople have been doing that for a
        while with absolutely no success. That's really going after the problem with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howitzer</ENAMEX>
        instead of with an intelligent approach.‚Äù
        So instead of screening <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">libraries</ENAMEX> of existing compounds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shapiro</ENAMEX> prefers using
        structural information about <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> or their natural ligands to create new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX>, an
        approach known as rational drug design. And instead of looking at all essential genes in a
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacterium</ENAMEX> and choosing one to target, she and her <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> look at genetic circuitry that
        controls the cell cycle, the pathway that coordinates cell growth and differentiation. They
        have identified key control points, or nodes, in the circuitry for their favorite study
        subject, 
        Caulobacter crescentus . Thus, they have found critical genes
        encoding <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">proteins</ENAMEX> that control several critical functions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>. Their first
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidate</ENAMEX> was an essential enzyme, a methyltransferase called <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CcrM</ENAMEX>, that prevents a
        particular piece of <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> from being expressed in a cell by tagging it with a <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">methyl</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">group</ENAMEX>.
        Antibiotic discovery is all chemistry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shapiro</ENAMEX> says, which is why she joined with
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">biochemist Stephen J. Benkovic</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State University</ENAMEX>. They didn't know the
        structure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CcrM</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benkovic</ENAMEX> explains, but the literature about other methyltransferases
        suggested that the adenine molecule, which is the substrate for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CcrM</ENAMEX> within <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, binds to a
        specific region of the enzyme.
        The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> designed adenine-like molecules that would bind to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CcrM</ENAMEX> and then
        developed <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benkovic</ENAMEX> says, ‚ÄúWe already knew what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> we wanted, and
        we simply fine-tuned it.‚Äù They worked their way through <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">1,000</NUMEX> inhibitor <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>, ending
        up with a small subset‚Äîno <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">more than about 20‚</NUMEX>Äîthat not only inhibited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CcrM</ENAMEX>, but also killed 
        Caulobacter very quickly.
        And not only inoffensive 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caulobacter</ENAMEX> . The compounds knock out other <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gram</NUMEX>-negative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>, such as the pathogens 
        Brucella abortus and 
        Francisella tularensis . Some even killed off anthrax, a big
        surprise because it is <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gram</NUMEX>-positive and so has much thicker cell walls than <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gram</NUMEX>-negative
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> undertook an exhaustive series of experiments to identify which
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">gram</ENAMEX>-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> would be affected by which compounds. The list of sensitive
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">pathogens</ENAMEX> now includes multidrug-resistant 
        Streptococcus , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Staphylococcus</ENAMEX> , and 
        Mycobacterium tuberculosis .
        More recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shapiro</ENAMEX> reports, they have demonstrated efficacy against rats infected
        with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anthrax</ENAMEX> or multidrug-resistant 
        Staph , although the compounds save <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only about 60%</NUMEX> of the rats
        at present. She notes, ‚ÄúSo we have a long way to go. But this has proven that if you go
        after something using some rational approach instead of hit-and-miss, you'll probably have
        more success than by the other method.‚Äù
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Benkovic</NUMEX> points out that theirs is an entirely new class of compounds, small molecular
        weight compounds that can be made in a few steps. He says, ‚ÄúThey don't look like the normal
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">antibiotic</ENAMEX>, so that's why I think they're fairly unique.‚Äù The basic research was done under
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense's</ENAMEX> (DOD) central research and development <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">organization</ENAMEX>, and once the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> realized they wanted to develop <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> against <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">three</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> that have been
        considered bioterrorism threats ‚Äî 
        Brucella , tularensis, and <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">anthrax ‚Äî</ENAMEX> they established a separate
        operation, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anacor Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>, which is developing them with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOD</ENAMEX> funding and without
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shapiro</ENAMEX>. In her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanford</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX>, she continues her fundamental research to define the complete
        genetic circuitry of 
        Caulobacter , hoping to identify additional nodes in the
        circuit. She says, ‚ÄúI am not doing it to develop antibiotics; that's what comes out of the
        work. My goal is to understand how the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell works</ENAMEX>. I think a lot of studies in pathogenesis
        should not be just to understand pathogenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX>, but to understand the complete
        network of regulatory mechanisms that controls the bacterial cell.‚Äù
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Phage Therapy</ENAMEX>
        The most radical approach to new antibiotics may be the resurrection of an old idea:
        bacteriophage therapy (see Figure <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2</NUMEX>). Late in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 19th century</TIMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">researcher</ENAMEX> noticed that
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">water</ENAMEX> from some of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">India</ENAMEX>'s sacred rivers <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">combated cholera</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Some years later</TIMEX>, the active
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">agents</ENAMEX> were identified as viruses that infected <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>. Such viruses are called
        bacteriophage, or phage for short. There were reports of phage success against dysentery,
        typhoid, and plague, and bacteriophage therapy had a brief heyday, especially in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1920s</TIMEX>.
        Results on other <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX> were mixed, and with the appearance of antibiotics, phage therapy
        became unfashionable in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX>, although it has continued in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Russia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
        Phage were the model organisms of choice for genetics research in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the 1930s and 1940s</TIMEX>,
        but became less fashionable as research tools when <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">investigators</ENAMEX> moved on to eukaryotes. A
        few held on, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ry Young</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas A&M University</ENAMEX>, who has made phage-induced cell
        lysis his life's work. ‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX> is basically genetically dead as soon as the phage goes in
        there, but it will keep living as sort of an infected <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">zombie</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">as long as the phage</TIMEX> wants
        it to, with <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">virus</ENAMEX> particles accumulating inside the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cell</ENAMEX>,‚Äù he explains. ‚ÄúOnly when the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">phage</ENAMEX> is ready and has decided that it's the right time will it pull the trigger. And the
        cell blows up.‚Äù The freed <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">phage</ENAMEX> then spew forth to infect new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">cells</ENAMEX>.
        Antibiotic <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">resistance</ENAMEX> has led to new interest in phage therapy by several small biotech
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>. Young continues basic research at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas A&M</ENAMEX>, but has also joined <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> of
        them, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">GangaGen</ENAMEX>, providing bacteriophage expertise to its <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">labs</ENAMEX>.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Phage</ENAMEX> do kill <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">pathogenic bacteria</ENAMEX> effectively, and they do it without penetrating human
        cells, which they can't even recognize. So what is keeping phage therapy out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">clinic</ENAMEX>?
        Problems that some doubt can be overcome.
        Because <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> develop resistance to phage rapidly, phage therapy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> will need
        to direct <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">cocktails</ENAMEX> against a single pathogen, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Fischetti</ENAMEX> at The
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rockefeller University</ENAMEX>. Phage are also antigenic, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibodies</ENAMEX> they stimulate will
        neutralize their effects during subsequent treatment, he says. But the chief problem
        appears to be regulatory‚Äîregulatory in the political, rather than the genetic, sense. When
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">bacteriophage</ENAMEX> package their <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, they occasionally include varying amounts of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>'
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX>, too. This miscellany, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischetti</ENAMEX> points out, is likely to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug</ENAMEX>
        Administration unhappy. ‚ÄúPhage normally are very fragile, their tails break, so lot-to-lot
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homogeneity</ENAMEX> could be a problem too,‚Äù he adds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúSo</ENAMEX> even though it will work, I think they'll
        have an uphill battle.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Phage</ENAMEX> may well enter agricultural or veterinary use, he predicts,
        but are probably not going to be available to <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patients</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United States</ENAMEX> any time
        soon.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fischetti</ENAMEX> chose a different approach to phage therapy. It does not rely on phage
        themselves, but on enzymes that phage produce to smash their way out of their <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">host</ENAMEX> bacteria
        so they can infect new <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">hosts</ENAMEX>. He and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> employ these enzymes externally to kill
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>. He reports, ‚ÄúWe now have enzymes that will kill 
        Strep pyogenes , pneumococci, 
        Strep pneumoniae , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus anthracis</ENAMEX> , 
        Enterococcus faecalis , and group B 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strep</ENAMEX> . The beauty of these enzymes is that they are targeted
        killing. You only kill the <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">organism</ENAMEX> you intend to kill, without destroying or affecting the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">surrounding organisms</ENAMEX> that are necessary for health.‚Äù
        The enzymes can be loaded into a nasal <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">spray</ENAMEX> that wipes out pathogens such as 
        Pneumococcus , 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Staphylococcus</ENAMEX> , and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> A 
        Strep on contact with mucous membranes. The strategy might
        prevent bacterial infections from spreading in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">close quarters</TIMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospitals</ENAMEX>, nursing
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">homes</ENAMEX>, and daycare <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">centers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischetti</ENAMEX> says, <ENAMEX TYPE="GAME">‚ÄúClinical</ENAMEX> trials would tell us how often we had
        to treat, but more important, we'd have a reagent that could treat <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> who walk out the
        door of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">hospital</ENAMEX> to eliminate or reduce the transmission of <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">resistant organisms</ENAMEX> into
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">community</ENAMEX>. We don't have that capability <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">right now</TIMEX>.‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fischetti</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">colleagues</ENAMEX> have moved on to using the enzymes systemically to wipe out
        
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">Bacillus anthracis spores</ENAMEX>, preventing them from germinating and
        seething through the bloodstream, producing deadly <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT_DESC">toxins</ENAMEX>. An <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">IV</ENAMEX> drip would be started
        after exposure to the spores. The method, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fischetti</ENAMEX> reports, is already successful in <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX>;
        clinical trials will determine how long treatment must be continued, perhaps <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week or so</TIMEX>.
        They have also eliminated septicemia from pneumocci with the same intravenous method.
        Up to now the enzymes must make contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX> to kill, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischetti</ENAMEX> is hoping
        that a new generation of engineered <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">enzymes</ENAMEX> will be able to kill pathogens inside cells
        too. A <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">second</NUMEX> disadvantage is that they are effective only against <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">gram</NUMEX>-positive <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>,
        although that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">group</ENAMEX> includes many vicious pathogens.
        But phage enzymes seem to offer <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> very big advantage: resistance to them has yet to
        develop. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischetti</ENAMEX> says, ‚ÄúWe've tried very hard to identify resistant <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">bacteria</ENAMEX>, but so far
        we haven't found resistant <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">organisms</ENAMEX> in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">all three</NUMEX> of the enzymes we're working with. It
        appears to be a very rare event, much rarer than resistance to antibiotics.‚Äù Fischetti
        cautions against expecting that gladsome <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE_DESC">state</ENAMEX> to last forever, but he points out that even
        if widespread resistance takes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the same 40 or 50 years</TIMEX> that antibiotics required to become
        significantly resistant, phage enzymes could buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">decades</TIMEX> for inventing other
        approaches.
      
      
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Antibiotics</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">21st Century</ENAMEX>
        There is no shortage of ideas for unearthing new antibiotic <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">candidates</ENAMEX>. Why are they so
        slow to enter medical practice? The bottleneck, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> agree, lies in the development
        process of turning them into effective therapies. Several <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> blame the big
        pharmaceutical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that got so big by leading the way to new <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drugs</ENAMEX> for battling
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">infectious disease</ENAMEX>, but in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">recent years</TIMEX> have dropped out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Fischetti</ENAMEX> complains, ‚ÄúThese are
        the big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> that have the money to develop antiinfectives, but they leave it to small
        biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX>, and it's not going to happen as rapidly as it should. I think it's
        really unconscionable for these big <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">companies</ENAMEX> to drop the ball because it's not going to be
        a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">billion-dollar</NUMEX> market for them and that's what they're looking for.‚Äù
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Half a billion</NUMEX> at least, says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Tally</ENAMEX>, a big pharmaceuticals <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">veteran</ENAMEX> who is now
        chief scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">officer</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubist Pharmaceuticals</ENAMEX>, a biotech <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">company</ENAMEX> located in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Lexington</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tally</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cubist</ENAMEX> produced daptomycin, approved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2003</TIMEX>,
        by licensing it from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eli Lilly</ENAMEX>, which shelved the new <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">compound</ENAMEX> after concluding its
        potential market was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">only $250 million</NUMEX>.
        But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tally</ENAMEX> argues, the size of the market is not the only barrier to new antibiotics.
        Combinatorial chemistry and the genomics revolution have simply not delivered on their
        early promise. ‚ÄúThe <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">pipeline</ENAMEX> is very dry,‚Äù he says. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThere</ENAMEX>'s been a real lag at the basic
        research level.‚Äù
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúAntibiotic</ENAMEX> discovery is hard,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Shapiro</ENAMEX> says. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s a huge long process to get a decent
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic</ENAMEX>.<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù Walsh</ENAMEX> agrees. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s easier to find <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">inhibitors</ENAMEX> of particular enzymes for
        particular processes‚Äîand a very long road to convert that into something for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">development</ENAMEX>.‚Äù
        In the meantime, there is a rising clamor to slow down the rate at which bacteria
        develop resistance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Doctors</ENAMEX> are exhorted to cut back on prescribing antibiotics and decline
        to prescribe for viral <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">diseases</ENAMEX>, which antibiotics can't combat, even when their patients
        badger them.
        But even if <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic</ENAMEX> consumption slowed, we will still need new antibiotics. ‚ÄúI always
        say it's not a matter of if, it's only a matter of when,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walsh</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúThere</ENAMEX> will always be
        a need for new antibiotics because the clock starts ticking on the useful lifetime of any
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">antibiotic</ENAMEX> once you start to use it. That cannot be argued.‚Äù
      
    
  
