
  
    
      
        
        The global debate over access to primary research literature heated up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>,
        fueled by a slew of congressional and parliamentary recommendations, claims of political
        victory by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">critics</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">proponents</ENAMEX> of open access, and redoubled lobbying efforts on every
        side of the issue. After <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> of often dizzying rhetoric from virtually all <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">camps</ENAMEX>, one
        concrete development has indisputably emerged from the fray: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> around the world
        have begun to take an interest in the question of who can and can't read the results of the
        scientific research they fund. ‚ÄúWe are convinced,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> concluded a recent report from the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science and Technology Committee</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Commons</ENAMEX>, ‚Äúthat the amount
        of public money invested in scientific research and its outputs is sufficient to merit
        Government involvement in the publishing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">process‚</ENAMEX>Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Commons Science and Technology</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States National Institutes of Health</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elias Zerhouni</ENAMEX>
        echoed the <ENAMEX TYPE="NATIONALITY">British</ENAMEX> assessment, asserting that ‚Äúthe <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">public</ENAMEX> needs to have access to what
        they've paid for,‚Äù in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 28</TIMEX> meeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">stakeholders</ENAMEX> in scientific and medical
        publishing. ‚ÄúThe status quo,‚Äù he added, ‚Äújust can't stand‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Park 2004).</ENAMEX>
        While such pronouncements may sow fear in the hearts of some <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>,
        concerns that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> are poised to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> where or how to publish seem
        largely unfounded. Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX> report and rumblings from the <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">US</ENAMEX> government suggest that any
        legislative dictates on access to scientific literature are likely to be structured to
        minimize potentially deleterious implications for established, subscription-based <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">for-profit</ENAMEX> and not-for-profit alike. Mandates for open access to articles summarizing the
        results of publicly funded research would not be mandates for <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to submit work
        only to the handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journals</ENAMEX>, like 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Biology</ENAMEX> and 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PLoS Medicine</ENAMEX>, that currently make their content immediately free online
        in centralized repositories. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US House of Representatives Committee on Appropriations</ENAMEX>, for
        example, recently passed language that would allow many, though not all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">six</TIMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">months</TIMEX> between the date of publication of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>-funded research articles and the date of
        their deposition in a free-to-use archive. (At the time of this writing, the bill is
        awaiting further discussion in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.)
        In any case, it is a perfectly reasonable premise that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> should attach
        conditions to grants mandating public access to resulting peer-reviewed, published
        articles. Making funding for research contingent on the results of the work being
        disseminated as widely as possible is hardly a revolutionary proposition. All funders
        expect, of course, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> won't simply stash their findings in a desk drawer.
        Most, like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>, include in their mission statements clauses <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">about ‚</NUMEX>Äúfostering the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">communication</ENAMEX> of medical and health sciences information‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US National</ENAMEX>
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library of Medicine</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">division</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX>, goes so far as to provide the infrastructure for
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">hosting</ENAMEX> and storing the full texts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">journal</ENAMEX> articles online, in the form of PubMed
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central</ENAMEX>. Actually requiring that publicly funded works be 
        included in publicly funded electronic archives like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PubMed Central</ENAMEX>, as
        the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US Congress</ENAMEX> might, would be less a paradigm shift or a radically interventionist
        mandate than a sensible extension of existing policy for most <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">governments</ENAMEX> and their funding
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">agencies</ENAMEX>.
        Increasingly, it seems, this is the view being adopted by policy makers‚Äîthat it is the
        status quo, rather than prospective policy revision, that is anomalous or hard to justify.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúWe</ENAMEX> would be very surprised,‚Äù the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science and Technology Committee</ENAMEX> notes, ‚Äúif Government
        did not itself feel the need to account for its investment [in research] in the publishing
        process. We‚Ä¶ hope that this report will be a catalyst for change‚Äù (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House of Commons Science</ENAMEX>
        and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Technology Committee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>).
        As a matter of sheer principle, it strikes many <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> as odd that ‚Äúanyone can download
        medical nonsense from the Web for free, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">citizens</ENAMEX> must pay to see the results of
        carefully conducted biomedical research that was financed by their taxes,‚Äù as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Weiss</ENAMEX>
        noted on the front page of the 
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Post</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weiss 2003).</ENAMEX> While neither the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">US</ENAMEX> nor the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UK</ENAMEX>
        has yet to legislate a remedy for this 
        prima facie paradoxical state of affairs, both appear ready to address
        the issue systematically, and‚Äîmore significantly‚Äîwith the input of a wide range of affected
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">constituents</ENAMEX>: <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">librarians</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">patient advocates</ENAMEX>, text-<ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">miners</ENAMEX>,
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">entrepreneurs</ENAMEX>, and more. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science and Technology Committee</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>) report was the product
        of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven-month</TIMEX> investigation, featuring <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">some 127 submissions</NUMEX> of written evidence and <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
        <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">days</TIMEX> of oral testimony from the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nature Publishing Group</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reed Elsevier</ENAMEX>, and
        indeed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Library of Science</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIH</ENAMEX> has promised a period of public comment on its
        plan for implementing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appropriations Committee</ENAMEX>'s requirement before moving forward, in
        addition to the information-gathering meeting of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">publishers</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> and subsequent meetings
        hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Dr.</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zerhouni</ENAMEX>. All told, the current spate of government attention to the issue of
        public access to research results seems methodical, inclusive, and likely to prove
        productive for scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">communities</ENAMEX> and the public.
      
    
  
