
  
    
      
        
        Armed with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">billions</NUMEX> of cells, elaborate <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">circuitry</ENAMEX>, and a seemingly animate anatomy,
        capable of growing as it learns, the brain is a marvelously enigmatic organ. Much to the
        chagrin of those that study it, the brain remains perhaps too mysterious.
        Although genetic information exploded out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Genome Project</ENAMEX>, it has been of
        little consequence to neuroscience‚Äîa discipline still grappling with the boundaries and
        names for distinct brain regions. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States National Institute of Mental</ENAMEX>
        Health <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Director</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Insel</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">over 99%</NUMEX> of the neuroscience literature focuses on <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 1%</NUMEX> of
        the <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">estimated 15,000‚Äì16,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> expressed in the brain. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Van Essen</ENAMEX>, a neurobiologist
        at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">St. Louis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Missouri</ENAMEX>, likens the current genetic map of the
        brain to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17th century</TIMEX> map of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX>. A voyage around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earth</ENAMEX> had already proven it was
        round, but landmass resolution was still vague at best.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magellan</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">benefactors</ENAMEX>, though, never bankrolled a technical advance quite like the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Brain Atlas</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neuroscience</ENAMEX>'s unlikely sugar <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">daddy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Microsoft</ENAMEX> cofounder and the world's
        <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">fifth</NUMEX> wealthiest <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">man</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Allen</ENAMEX>, created the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> dollar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allen Brain Institute</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Washington</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>. The first explicit goal of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">institute</ENAMEX> was to create
        an open-access, visual, searchable online map of genes expressed in the brain, as well as
        of brain circuitry and cell location. <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Roughly one</NUMEX> petabyte of data‚Äîequal to the memory
        necessary to hold the information held in <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 50</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PRODUCT">Libraries of Congress‚</ENAMEX>Äîwill be produced
        as a result.
        In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-December</TIMEX>, the <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> were uploaded. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORG_DESC">team</ENAMEX> plans to
        have <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">as many as 24,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> online. While the ultimate goal is to map the human brain, the
        atlas ushers in a new era of neurogenetics‚Äîan attempt to make connections between
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">anatomical</ENAMEX>, genetic, and behavioral observations.
      
      
        Of <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mice and Men</ENAMEX>
        The initial effort will focus on the standard, inbred <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">lab</ENAMEX> mouse strain known
        affectionately as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">C57BL6</TIMEX>. Like it or not, <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> are remarkably similar to humans‚Äîsharing <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">99%</NUMEX>
        of our <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">Humans</ENAMEX>, at this time, provide too many hurdles‚Äînot the least of which is a
        lack of willing brain <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">donors</ENAMEX> that are the same age. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the C57BL6</TIMEX> strain is inbred, the
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mice</ENAMEX> are also much more uniform than humans‚Äîa key to constructing the most accurate
        representative map possible of <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX>' adult brain.
        With a map of mouse <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in hand, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> will be able to develop informed
        hypotheses about genes that may affect human brain function and dysfunction. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúPeople</ENAMEX> will
        be able to look <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">first</NUMEX> in the mouse atlas, then more selectively focus on human cases,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregor Eichele</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Max Planck Institute for Experimental Endocrinology</ENAMEX> in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannover</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Germany</ENAMEX>. Indeed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">researchers</ENAMEX> may do well to focus their efforts on those specific
        cells in which homologous genes are expressed in the mouse. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Insel</ENAMEX> suggests an initial
        mental health application: find 
        dyspyndin , a gene linked to <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insel</ENAMEX> is banking on the atlas
        to locate <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> linked to conditions including bipolar disorder, <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">schizophrenia</ENAMEX>, and autism.
        Once identified, such critical genes can be examined in detail and used in studies aimed at
        <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">disease cures</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> screens. Presumably, the atlas will be a boon for <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">drug</ENAMEX> discovery and
        development by providing information on drug <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">targets</ENAMEX> present within brain cells.
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">Eichele</NUMEX> points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Brain Atlas</ENAMEX> will eliminate time wasted testing
        fruitless hypotheses. ‚ÄúIf you think gene <ENAMEX TYPE="LAW">X</ENAMEX> may be involved in [<ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">hippocampal-dependent</ENAMEX>]
        memory, but it's not expressed in the hippocampus, you shouldn't bother following that line
        of research,‚Äù he says. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insel</ENAMEX> agrees that where genes are expressed in the brain will be
        most telling. ‚ÄúIn the brain, more than any other organ, function follows form,‚Äù he
        says.
        Cellular resolution of expression patterns will prove necessary to uncover as yet
        unknown relationships between circuitry, cell type, and gene expression in the brain, says
        Atlas <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Lein</ENAMEX>, a neuroscientist at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allen Brain Institute</ENAMEX>, thinks that mapping
        at the cellular scale will also redefine anatomy. Traditionally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neuroanatomists</ENAMEX> have
        delineated brain regions pretty much by eye, identifying clusters of cells and patterns of
        connections that look the same. ‚ÄúWe're starting to redefine boundaries of regions by cell
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">type,‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lein</ENAMEX>, defining cell type by gene expression pattern.
        The difficulty, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allen Brain Institute</ENAMEX> scientific <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">advisor</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Anderson</ENAMEX>, a
        understanding how a gene mutation affects behavior. ‚ÄúIt is impossible without a knowledge
        of the circuits in which a gene is expressed,‚Äù he says. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX> himself studies innate
        behaviors such as fear responses. Specifically, he's most interested in understanding the
        function of different regions of the almond-shaped amygdala. Once he finds genes expressed
        in neurons within regions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">amgydala</ENAMEX> implicated in fear, he plans to determine neuron
        function by creating transgenic <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">animals</ENAMEX> in which specific neuron activity has been
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">silenced</ENAMEX>.
        Thus far, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">laboratory</ENAMEX> has endured the slog of using microarray techniques to
        identify genes with expression patterns linked to fear behavior, followed by in situ
        hybridization, which traditionally involves <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">twenty</TIMEX>-odd complex, error-prone steps, to find
        just some of the genes expressed in different parts of the amygdala. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚ÄúThe Allen Brain Atlas</ENAMEX>
        will identify a whole set of genes that we would have had to spend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">several years</TIMEX> to find,‚Äù
        he says. Indeed, locating where even <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> gene of interest is expressed in the brain eats up
        valuable research time, especially when there are so many potentially interesting genes. In
        most cells, <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">10,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> can be expressed.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eichele</ENAMEX> improved the slow error-prone process into an automated, fast, ‚Äúhigh throughput‚Äù
        method that caught the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allen</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX> because it was capable of meeting the
        needs of such an ambitious project. In situ hybridization uses labeled probes for specific
        <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">messenger RNA sequences</ENAMEX>, allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> to test individual brain tissue samples for
        gene expression.
        Automated in situ hybridization data will be generated for the entire mouse
        transcriptome‚Äîthe full complement of activated <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> in a particular tissue at a particular
        time‚Äîon a genome-wide scale. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> is a young <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">adult</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">56 days old</TIMEX>, free from the
        confounding factors of development. After it is sacrificed, the mouse brain is immediately
        frozen, then sliced very thinly‚Äîto get <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">forty sections</ENAMEX> from each <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">millimeter</NUMEX> of thickness‚Äîso
        that the probes for hybridization can expose gene expression in individual cells.
      
      
        Mining the <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Mind for Riches</ENAMEX>
        The in situ data will be matched in a three-dimensional framework to the reference atlas
        developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>. The resulting images will be turned into a virtual microscope,
        allowing <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> to focus down on <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">genes</ENAMEX> expressed in regions of interest.
        While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Brain Atlas</ENAMEX> is somewhat like other genomics projects in scale, it is
        unique. ‚ÄúNo one's gone into a <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC">3-D</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX> like a tissue and examined it in a systematic
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">way,‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Jones</ENAMEX>, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">director</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allen Brain Atlas Operations</ENAMEX>. In that way, he
        adds, it's a much richer dataset than the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Genome Project</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúAs we're ramping up‚Äîfully
        by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring of next year‚</TIMEX>Äîwe'll be generating <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">about 1,000</NUMEX> microscope slides a day with <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">four</NUMEX>
        mouse brain sections on each slide,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Each day</TIMEX>, those sections are scanned and
        stitched together electronically into <NUMEX TYPE="QUANTITY">300-megabyte</NUMEX> batches. ‚ÄúScaling up a lab process is
        currently the biggest challenge,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúIn effect, we're turning an art form into
        something that gives high-quality data day in and day out,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúIf you are off
        slightly when cutting a <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">2-D</NUMEX> brain slice, it becomes very difficult to map back into a 3-D
        context.‚Äù
        While it is a logical starting point, a spatial understanding of gene expression is just
        <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> way to mine the brain. Other <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">avenues</ENAMEX> currently being pursued explore individual
        variability, development, and comparisons between <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">species</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="CONTACT_INFO">See Box 1</ENAMEX>). The sheer
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">comprehensive</ENAMEX> nature of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Brain Atlas</ENAMEX> will be its crowing achievement, and its
        complement to the other ongoing atlas efforts. However, the magnitude of the project also
        poses its greatest hurdle‚Äîabout which <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">onlookers</ENAMEX> have expressed some concern.
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‚ÄúIt</ENAMEX>'s clear that they want to do a first-rate job of working with all this information,
        but I'm not sure they entirely appreciate how hard it's going to be to manage the
        staggering amount of information they're getting,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Essen</ENAMEX>. As <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">manager</ENAMEX> of his own
        comparative anatomy database, he understands the magnitude of the task. He points out that
        properly digitizing the data in electronic form and registering one particular slice to a
        standardized reference with meaningful coordinates is not trivial.
        ‚ÄúIn an atlas, there will be considerable variability from <NUMEX TYPE="CARDINAL">one</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">individual</ENAMEX> to the
        next‚Äîeven in inbred <ENAMEX TYPE="ANIMAL">mouse</ENAMEX> strains,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Essen</ENAMEX>. Even if it's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">only 20%</NUMEX> variability, it
        is still going to pose challenges for managing experimental data. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Essen</ENAMEX> acknowledges
        that this isn't just an impediment for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">team</ENAMEX>, but for neuroscience as a whole.
        ‚ÄúThese tools, in general, don't emerge from a vacuum. They emerge best when rich,
        challenging datasets are staring <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> in the face,‚Äù he says.
        An even larger problem is communicating the data effectively. Figuring out how to
        navigate the tremendous morass of data will be a bioinformatic stumbling block. Lein
        acknowledges that figuring out how to best annotate the data is one of the bigger
        challenges for the future‚Äîparticularly in cases where gene expression doesn't match the
        agreed-upon boundaries of anatomical regions.
        For now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">users</ENAMEX> will be able to mine the data by gene name only. The initial release
        consists of an image <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">viewer</ENAMEX> to view the in situ hybridization data for one or several genes
        at a time, along with a reference atlas to determine the <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX> in which genes are
        expressed. Future releases will allow the <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">user</ENAMEX> to conduct more sophisticated searches, such
        as by anatomical <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structures</ENAMEX>.
        ‚ÄúNot only is there this <NUMEX TYPE="ORDINAL">3-D</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="FAC_DESC">structure</ENAMEX>, but there are lots of studies where <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> are
        trying to understand what drives the turning on and off of genes,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúAt the end,
        if the atlas has a big impact, it will be in providing the precise coordinates for those
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">people</ENAMEX> to tease apart what specific <ENAMEX TYPE="SUBSTANCE">DNA</ENAMEX> elements drive expression within <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">regions</ENAMEX> or
        structures.‚Äù
        And while the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Brain Atlas</ENAMEX> will provide a fine level of detail, there are
        limitations. Much like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Genome Project</ENAMEX>, the information will be the starting point
        and not the end point of understanding brain function. ‚ÄúIt won't change strategy for doing
        experiments,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="WORK_OF_ART">Nobel</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">laureate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia University</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">neuroscientist</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Kandel</ENAMEX>. ‚ÄúThe
        <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">atlas</ENAMEX> will be a catalyst rather than a direction setter.‚Äù
      
      
        The Final <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frontier</ENAMEX>
        Overall, neuroscience is entering a new era. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Insel</ENAMEX> notes that recent work has proven the
        brain to be extraordinarily dynamic, birthing neurons throughout <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">a lifespan</TIMEX>. Brain
        functions seem more modular than global. And there is no real separation between the mind
        and brain. <ENAMEX TYPE="DISEASE">‚ÄúMental disorders</ENAMEX> are brain disorders,‚Äù he says.
        Over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">the next 5‚Äì10 years</TIMEX>, neurogenomics will fuel a golden age of discovery in
        <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">neuroscience</ENAMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">scientists</ENAMEX> may even reach an overarching <ENAMEX TYPE="PER_DESC">goal‚</ENAMEX>Äîunderstanding how the
        wild card of environment impacts brain function. ‚ÄúWe want predictive genetics able to
        accommodate environmental differences,<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">‚Äù</ENAMEX> says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Williams</ENAMEX>, neurobiologist at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX>
        of <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Tennessee</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="GPE">Memphis</ENAMEX>.
        For <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kandel</ENAMEX>, one thing is certain. ‚ÄúMost of the mysteries of the brain lie ahead of
        us.‚Äù
      
    
  
